{
    "physics": {
        "1": {
            "12907": {
                "ans1": "straight line",
                "ans2": "circle",
                "ans3": "ellipse",
                "ans4": "parabola",
                "question_text": "If an electron has an initial velocity in a direction different from that of an electric field , the path of the electron is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "parabola",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17481": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\frac{m_e}{m_p}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{m_p}{m_e}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated through the same potential difference. The ratio of their de Broglie's wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\lambda_c}{\\lambda_p}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac h{\\sqrt{2m_eev}}}{\\frac h{\\sqrt{2m_pev}}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18860": {
                "ans1": "energy",
                "ans2": "velocity",
                "ans3": "momentum",
                "ans4": "angular momentum",
                "question_text": "If an electron and a photon have same wavelength then they must have same",
                "correct_ans": "momentum",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13547": {
                "ans1": "point of projection",
                "ans2": "highest point",
                "ans3": "aiming point",
                "ans4": "mid way between point of projection and highest point",
                "question_text": "A projectile fired from a gun follows a parabolic path, the speed of the projectile is minimum at",
                "correct_ans": "highest point",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v=\\sqrt{v_x^2+v_y^2}\\;,\\;speed\\;will\\;be\\;least\\;if\\;v_y=0\\\\i.e\\;heighest\\;point\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11961": {
                "ans1": "nature of the surface in contact",
                "ans2": "area of the surface in contact",
                "ans3": "normal reaction  between the surface",
                "ans4": "material of bodies",
                "question_text": "The limiting force of friction between two bodies in contact is independent of",
                "correct_ans": "area of the surface in contact",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12244": {
                "ans1": "mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans2": "half of mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans3": "two third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans4": "one third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "question_text": "The pressure exerted by perfect gas is equal to\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "two third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13806": {
                "ans1": "directly proportional to r\u00b2",
                "ans2": "directly proportional to r",
                "ans3": " inversely proportional to r",
                "ans4": "\\;inversely\\;proportional\\;to\\;r^3",
                "question_text": "The electric intensity due to an infinite cylinder having charge 'q' per unit length at a distance r from it's axis is\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": " inversely proportional to r",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12091": {
                "ans1": "yellow",
                "ans2": "green",
                "ans3": "blue",
                "ans4": "red",
                "question_text": "The deviation of light will be maximum for a prism for",
                "correct_ans": "green",
                "explanation": "As refractive index of red is less than voilet so, red light deviate less",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14136": {
                "ans1": "drift of holes",
                "ans2": "diffusion of charge carries",
                "ans3": "migration of impurity atoms",
                "ans4": "drift of electrons",
                "question_text": "The depletion layer in a P N\u00a0junction is caused by",
                "correct_ans": "diffusion of charge carries",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18777": {
                "ans1": "m_1:m_2",
                "ans2": "r_1:r_2",
                "ans3": "1:1",
                "ans4": "m_1r_1:m_2r_2",
                "question_text": "Two cars of mass\u00a0m_1 and   m_2\n\u00a0are moving along a circular path of radius\u00a0r_1 and \u00a0r_2\u00a0. They take one round in same time. The ratio of angular velocity of two cars will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12115": {
                "ans1": "0.16 m/s",
                "ans2": "0.61 m/s",
                "ans3": "0.1 m/s",
                "ans4": "61 m/s",
                "question_text": "The increase in velocity of sound for 1\u00b0C rise in temperature is (V_o=332 m/s)",
                "correct_ans": "0.61 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10589": {
                "ans1": "decrease",
                "ans2": "increase",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "With increase in temperature , the frequency of the sound in organ pipe\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "increase",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13157": {
                "ans1": "copper iron",
                "ans2": "Bismuth-antimony",
                "ans3": "silver zinc",
                "ans4": "lead tin",
                "question_text": "The thermocouple thermometer will be most sensitive if made by",
                "correct_ans": "Bismuth-antimony",
                "explanation": "Thermocouple thermometer will be more sensitive if distance of two metals in themo electric series increases\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18428": {
                "ans1": "don't attract at all",
                "ans2": "attact each other",
                "ans3": "repel each other",
                "ans4": "deflect perpendicular to plane of beam",
                "question_text": "Two fast streams of protons move parallel to each other in the same direction, then these\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "attact each other",
                "explanation": "Act as parallel plate conductor carrying current in same direction",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15310": {
                "ans1": "Decreases slightly",
                "ans2": "Increases slightly",
                "ans3": "Remain same",
                "ans4": "increases considerable",
                "question_text": "Some quantity of tap water is placed in an open pan and allowed to evaporate. After sometime the temperature of water",
                "correct_ans": "Decreases slightly",
                "explanation": "As water evaporates its temperature falls",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15021": {
                "ans1": "u",
                "ans2": "greater than u",
                "ans3": "less than u",
                "ans4": "may be greater or less depending on amount of humidity",
                "question_text": "The speed of sound in helium is 'u'. The speed of humid helium at the same sound in humid helium temperature will be",
                "correct_ans": "less than u",
                "explanation": "In case of helium, on increasing humidity density increases so velocity of sound decrases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17075": {
                "ans1": "\\frac25R",
                "ans2": "\\frac75R",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac25}R",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac75}R",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The radius of gyration of a sphere about a tangent is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{\\frac75}R",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mk^2=\\frac25mR^2\\;+mR^2\\\\or,k=\\sqrt{\\frac75}R\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16370": {
                "ans1": "half life",
                "ans2": "no. of decayed atom",
                "ans3": "no. of undecayed atom",
                "ans4": "the no. of nucleon in atom",
                "question_text": "RAte of decay of atoms of a radioactive sample is proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "no. of decayed atom",
                "explanation": "Obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18484": {
                "ans1": "\u03bb/4",
                "ans2": "\u03bb/2",
                "ans3": " 2\u03bb",
                "ans4": "4\u03bb",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The de Broglies wavelength of a neutron having kinetic energy E is \u03bb. The de Broglies wavelength of neutron having kinetic 4E is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03bb/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lambda=\\frac h{\\sqrt{2mE}}\\\\\\frac{\\lambda'}\\lambda=\\sqrt{\\frac E{E'}}=1/2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16669": {
                "ans1": "0.6m",
                "ans2": "0.8m",
                "ans3": "0.1m",
                "ans4": "0.12m",
                "question_text": "A progressive wave of frequency 500Hz is travelling with a velocity of 360m/s. The distance between two points at 60\u00b0 out of phase is",
                "correct_ans": "0.12m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lambda=\\frac vf=\\frac{360}{500}=0.72\\;m\\\\\\phi=\\frac{2\\pi x}\\lambda\\\\x=0.12m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10797": {
                "ans1": "1:2",
                "ans2": "2:1",
                "ans3": "1:4",
                "ans4": "4:1",
                "question_text": "Ratio of specific charge of proton to alpha particle is",
                "correct_ans": "2:1",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac em}{\\displaystyle\\frac{2e}{4m}}=2:1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11442": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13313": {
                "ans1": "127\u00b0c  ",
                "ans2": " 227\u00b0c ",
                "ans3": "527\u00b0c  ",
                "ans4": "327\u00b0c",
                "question_text": "An ideal engine exhausting heat at 27\u00b0c has efficiency 25%. It must take heat at",
                "correct_ans": "127\u00b0c  ",
                "explanation": "\\eta=\\left(1-\\frac{T_2}{T_1}\\right)\\times100\\%where T2 =27",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18515": {
                "ans1": "K_o",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "\\frac{K_o}2",
                "ans4": "\\frac{K_o}4",
                "question_text": "For a particle executing SHM, the KE is K is related as K=K_o\\cos^2\\omega t, the maximum value of PE is",
                "correct_ans": "K_o",
                "explanation": "maximum KE = Maximum PE\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18787": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decrease",
                "ans3": "doesn't change",
                "ans4": "first decrease then increase",
                "question_text": "When water is heated from 0\u00b0c to 10\u00b0c, its volume of it",
                "correct_ans": "first decrease then increase",
                "explanation": "volume of water decrease from 0 to 4 and the increases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10448": {
                "ans1": "3h",
                "ans2": "4h",
                "ans3": "6h",
                "ans4": "8h",
                "question_text": "A body is falling from rest has velocity v after falling height h. The distance that fall further when velocity of body become 2v is",
                "correct_ans": "3h",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v^2=2gh\\\\and\\\\(2v)^2=2gh'\\\\or,4.2gn=2gh'\\\\h'=4h\\\\h'-h=3h\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15673": {
                "ans1": "\\frac D4",
                "ans2": "\\frac D2",
                "ans3": "D",
                "ans4": "4D",
                "question_text": "A luminous object is separated from screen at a distance D. The greatest focal length of lens could have to focus the object is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac D4",
                "explanation": "D=4ff=D/4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14385": {
                "ans1": "1:2",
                "ans2": "2:3",
                "ans3": "3:4",
                "ans4": "4:3",
                "question_text": "A closed organ pipe and open organ pipe have their first oertones of same frequency. The ratio of their length is",
                "correct_ans": "3:4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16548": {
                "ans1": "3927 s",
                "ans2": "3727 s",
                "ans3": "860 s",
                "ans4": "540 s",
                "question_text": "The length of a second pendulum increases by 2% then time that it lose in a day is",
                "correct_ans": "860 s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11068": {
                "ans1": "2 times",
                "ans2": "4 times",
                "ans3": "16 times",
                "ans4": "8 times",
                "question_text": "Eight drops of mercury of equal radii possessing equal charges combine to form a big drop. The capacitance of the big drop as compared to the smaller drop is",
                "correct_ans": "16 times",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}C=4\\pi\\varepsilon_or....1\\\\if\\;drops\\;combine,\\\\\\frac{4\\pi}3R^3=\\frac{n4\\pi}3r^3\\\\R=2r\\\\then,\\\\C'=4\\pi\\varepsilon_oR........2\\\\divide\\;1\\;by\\;2\\;\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12958": {
                "ans1": "90\u03a9",
                "ans2": "30\u03a9",
                "ans3": "20\u03a9",
                "ans4": "10\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of resistance 90\u03a9\u00a0is cut in 3 equal parts. If they are now connected in parallel then the resistance of combination will be",
                "correct_ans": "10\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11181": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "90\u00b0",
                "question_text": "The dip at a place where the vertical intensity is\u00a0\\sqrt3\u00a0times the horizontal intensity is",
                "correct_ans": "60\u00b0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11065": {
                "ans1": "3:2",
                "ans2": "1:1",
                "ans3": "2:3",
                "ans4": "1:2",
                "question_text": "Two masses in the ratio of 2 : 3 fall from the same height freely. The ratio of momentum will be",
                "correct_ans": "2:3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}V=\\sqrt{2gh}\\\\\\frac{P_1}{P_2}=\\frac{m_1v}{m_2v}=\\frac23\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11280": {
                "ans1": "2V",
                "ans2": "4V",
                "ans3": "20V",
                "ans4": "10V",
                "question_text": "The CE amplifier has current gain 50, load resistance is 4k\u03a9 and input resistance is 500\u03a9. 10mV ac signal is applied. Peak value of output signal is",
                "correct_ans": "4V",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{V_{out}}{V_{in}}=\\frac{I_cR_{out}}{I_bR_{in}}\\\\V_{out}=\\beta\\times\\frac{4000}{500}\\times10\\times10^{-3}=4V\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17494": {
                "ans1": "interference",
                "ans2": "diffraction",
                "ans3": "dispersion",
                "ans4": "polarization",
                "question_text": "When exposed to sunlight, thin films of oil on water \u00f6ften exhibit colours due to the phenomenon",
                "correct_ans": "interference",
                "explanation": "Oil film is appeared coloured due to interference of light.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17679": {
                "ans1": "Beats",
                "ans2": "Standing waves",
                "ans3": "Resonance",
                "ans4": "Resonance",
                "question_text": "Two waves of same frequency traveling in same medium, but in opposite direction if superposed give to",
                "correct_ans": "Standing waves",
                "explanation": "Two waves of same frequency travelling in opposite direction form stationary wave.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19191": {
                "ans1": "Frequency of incident radiation",
                "ans2": "Intensity of incident radiation",
                "ans3": "Nature of cathode",
                "ans4": "All of above",
                "question_text": "The maximum energy of electrons released in a photo cell is independent of",
                "correct_ans": "Intensity of incident radiation",
                "explanation": "The energy of electron is independent of intensity of radiation.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13062": {
                "ans1": "energy is uniformly distributed",
                "ans2": "energy is minimum at nodes  maximum at antinodes ",
                "ans3": "energy is maximum at nodes and  minimum at antinodes",
                "ans4": "alternating maximum and minimum energy is produced at antinodes & nodes",
                "question_text": "In stationary waves",
                "correct_ans": "energy is maximum at nodes and  minimum at antinodes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16844": {
                "ans1": "1 m",
                "ans2": "2 m",
                "ans3": "10 m",
                "ans4": "5 m",
                "question_text": "The distance of book from 50 Cd bulb so that illuminance on book is 2 lm m^{-2} is",
                "correct_ans": "5 m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}E=\\frac1{r^2}\\\\r=\\sqrt{\\frac{-1}E}=\\sqrt{\\frac{50}2}=5\\;m\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14436": {
                "ans1": "area of orifice",
                "ans2": "height of liquid above orifice",
                "ans3": "density of liquid",
                "ans4": "value of g",
                "question_text": "The volume of liquid flowing per second out of an orifice at the bottom of tank does not depends on",
                "correct_ans": "density of liquid",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Vol/see=\\;Av=A\\sqrt{2gh}\\;\\;\\\\i.e.\\;vol/sec\\;is\\;independent\\;to\\;density\\;of\\;liquid.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11281": {
                "ans1": "ellipse",
                "ans2": "circle",
                "ans3": "parabola",
                "ans4": "hyperbola",
                "question_text": "Cathode rays are projected at right angle to magnetic field then their trajectory is",
                "correct_ans": "circle",
                "explanation": "When cathode rays are projected perpendicular to magnetic field then force is perpendiucular to path & path. is circular.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12766": {
                "ans1": "speed",
                "ans2": "acceleration",
                "ans3": "displacement",
                "ans4": "none of above",
                "question_text": "The quantity that decreases in motion along a straight line with constant retardation is",
                "correct_ans": "speed",
                "explanation": "Speed decreases during retardation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19610": {
                "ans1": "glow brighter",
                "ans2": "glow less brighter",
                "ans3": "equal brightness",
                "ans4": "not glow",
                "question_text": "Bulb of power 50w & 100w are connected in series then 50w bulb will",
                "correct_ans": "glow brighter",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13960": {
                "ans1": "constant internal energy",
                "ans2": "constant entropy",
                "ans3": "constant volume",
                "ans4": "constant volume",
                "question_text": "An isochoric process is one which take place at",
                "correct_ans": "constant volume",
                "explanation": "For isochoric process dv=\u00a00 so volume remain constant.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11806": {
                "ans1": "h/2",
                "ans2": "2h",
                "ans3": "h",
                "ans4": "3h",
                "question_text": "The greatest height to which a man can throw a stone is 'h'. The greatest distance to which he can throw it will be",
                "correct_ans": "2h",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}h=\\frac{u^2}{2g}\\\\or,\\;u\u00b2\\;=\\;2gh\\;\\;\\\\Again\\;R=\\;\\frac{u^2}g=\\frac{\\;2gh}g\\;=\\;2h\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11424": {
                "ans1": "25:1",
                "ans2": "10:1",
                "ans3": "5:1",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "Two satellites are orbiting around the earth in a circular orbits of same radius. One of them is 5 times heavier than other. Then ratio of their time periods will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10070": {
                "ans1": "R/4",
                "ans2": "R/2",
                "ans3": "2R",
                "ans4": "4R",
                "question_text": "A wire of resistance R is stretched to double of its\u00a0length then resistance of wire will be",
                "correct_ans": "4R",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}R=\\frac{\\rho l}A=\\frac{\\rho l^2}V\\\\so,\\;R'=4R\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12847": {
                "ans1": "don't absorb heat",
                "ans2": "don't radiate heat",
                "ans3": "have low thermal conductivity",
                "ans4": "high thermal conductivity",
                "question_text": "Cloudy nights are usually warmer, because clouds",
                "correct_ans": "have low thermal conductivity",
                "explanation": "Due to low thermal conductivity of cloud no heat energy can escape from earth",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19001": {
                "ans1": " 250\u03bcA ",
                "ans2": "20000\u03bcA ",
                "ans3": "80\u03bcA ",
                "ans4": "16000\u03bcA ",
                "question_text": "The amplification factor of transistor is 80 & base current is 250\u03bcA then collector current is",
                "correct_ans": "20000\u03bcA ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19930": {
                "ans1": "E/2",
                "ans2": "E",
                "ans3": "2E",
                "ans4": "4E",
                "question_text": "Electric field intensity due to infinite sheet of charge having surface charge density is E. The electric field due to an infinite conducting sheet of same surface charge density is",
                "correct_ans": "2E",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18902": {
                "ans1": "0.1 A",
                "ans2": "0.2 A",
                "ans3": "0.3 A",
                "ans4": "0.4 A",
                "question_text": "The electric current due to a bulb of 25w emitting light of wavelength 6600\u00c5 having efficiency 3% is",
                "correct_ans": "0.4 A",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}3\\%\\;of\\;P=\\frac{nhC}{t\\lambda}\\\\\\frac nt=\\frac{3\\times25\\times6600\\times10^{-10}}{100\\times6.62\\times10^{-34}\\times3\\times10^8}\\\\I=\\frac{ne}t=2.49\\times10^{18}\\times1.6\\times10^{-19}\\\\\\;\\;\\;=0.398\\;A=0.4\\;A\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17522": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{r_1}{r_2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{r_2}{r_1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{r_1^2}{r_2^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{r_2^2}{r_1^2}",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of radii\u00a0r_1 \u00a0and\u00a0 r_2\u00a0are at same electric potential then ratio of their surface charge densities is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{r_2}{r_1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17962": {
                "ans1": "temperature will decrease",
                "ans2": "volume will remain constant",
                "ans3": "minimum density",
                "ans4": "maximum strain",
                "question_text": "In a given process on an ideal gas, dw = 0 and dQ < 0. Then for the gas",
                "correct_ans": "temperature will decrease",
                "explanation": "We know,dQ = du + dwwhen dw = 0, du < 0i.e. internal energy decrease, so temperature will decrease.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16424": {
                "ans1": "0.1 V",
                "ans2": "0.15 V",
                "ans3": "0.015 V",
                "ans4": "0.0075 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The voltage across collector resistance 2k\u03a9 is 2V. The amplification factor of transistor is 200 and base resistance is 1.5k\u03a9 then input voltage will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.0075 V",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16420": {
                "ans1": "decreases",
                "ans2": "increases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "none of the above",
                "question_text": "A dielectric is introduced between the elements of the condenser kept at a constant potential difference. Then the charge on condenser",
                "correct_ans": "remain same",
                "explanation": "When dielectric slab is introduced then C increases at constant V so Q = CV, increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13008": {
                "ans1": "refraction and absorption",
                "ans2": " dispersion and total internal reflection",
                "ans3": "dispersion and focusing",
                "ans4": "refraction and scattering",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Rainbow is formed due to a combination of",
                "correct_ans": " dispersion and total internal reflection",
                "explanation": "Rainbow is due to dispersion of light in which total internal reflection also takes place.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11344": {
                "ans1": "minimum strain",
                "ans2": "maximum displacement",
                "ans3": "minimum density",
                "ans4": "maximum strain",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In stationary wave, node is the point having",
                "correct_ans": "maximum strain",
                "explanation": "Node are point where particle have minimum displacement so pressure will e maximum. i.e. strain will be maximum.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11373": {
                "ans1": " both cannot be zero",
                "ans2": "one of the two may be zero",
                "ans3": "if one of the two may be zero",
                "ans4": "if one is positive, one other is negative and vice versa",
                "question_text": "The location of a particle has changed. What can we go about the displacement and the distance covered by the particle?",
                "correct_ans": "one of the two may be zero",
                "explanation": "Location of particles changes means distance and displacement both will not e zero.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12943": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remains consatnt",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease depending upon the nature of liquid",
                "question_text": "Surface tension of liquid with increase of temperature is",
                "correct_ans": "decreases",
                "explanation": "Surface tension is due to inter molecuar force of attraction which decreases with increase in temperature",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11122": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decrease",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "depend on material",
                "question_text": "When the temperature of black body is increased, the wavelength of radiation corresponding to the maximum intensity of radiation.",
                "correct_ans": "decrease",
                "explanation": "on increasing temperature wavelength decreases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11464": {
                "ans1": "velocity",
                "ans2": "acceleration",
                "ans3": "centripetal force",
                "ans4": "kinetic energy",
                "question_text": "When a body is moving with constant speed in a horizontal circle. The quantity that remain constant is",
                "correct_ans": "kinetic energy",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16186": {
                "ans1": "5\u03a9",
                "ans2": "15\u03a9",
                "ans3": "30\u03a9",
                "ans4": "45\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of resistance 5\u03a9\u00a0is drawn out so that its new length is 3 times its original lengh then new resistance is",
                "correct_ans": "45\u03a9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{R'}R=\\left(\\frac{3l}l\\right)^2\\\\R'=9\\ast5=45\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19823": {
                "ans1": " both spheres will expand equally",
                "ans2": "hollow sphere will expand more than solid one",
                "ans3": "solid sphere will expand more than hollow one",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of the same size are made of the same metal but one is hollow and the other is solid. They are heated to the same temperature, then",
                "correct_ans": "solid sphere will expand more than hollow one",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\Delta V=V\\gamma\\Delta\\theta\\;\\\\\\;Expansion\\;depends\\;on\\;dimension,\\;nature\\;of\\;mater\\;and\\;change\\;in\\;temperature\\;which\\;remain\\;cons\\tan t..\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15775": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "ans2": "nh",
                "ans3": "\\frac{h}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{n^2h}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "question_text": "Angular momentum of electron in\u00a0n^{th} orbit is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "explanation": "L=mvr=\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10213": {
                "ans1": "remains unchanged",
                "ans2": "Increases ",
                "ans3": "decreases",
                "ans4": "decreases upto latitude of 45\u00b0",
                "question_text": "As we go from the equator tot eh poles, the value of g",
                "correct_ans": "Increases ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}g'=g-R\\omega2cos2\\theta\\\\As\\;we\\;go\\;from\\;equator\\;to\\;pole\\;\\theta\\;increases\\;so\\;value\\;of\\;g\\;also\\;increase.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12988": {
                "ans1": "\u03bb/4",
                "ans2": "\u03bb/2",
                "ans3": "3\u03bb/4",
                "ans4": "\u03bb",
                "question_text": "Minimum distance between two particles in a wave motion vibrating out of phase is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03bb/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16391": {
                "ans1": "short range",
                "ans2": "always attractive",
                "ans3": "charge independent",
                "ans4": "all of above",
                "question_text": "Nuclear force is a\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "all of above",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14423": {
                "ans1": "960 m/s",
                "ans2": "640 m/s",
                "ans3": "480 m/s",
                "ans4": "384 m/s",
                "question_text": "The rms speed of hydrogen molecule at 300K\u00a0is 1920 m/s. The rms speed of oxygen molecule will be",
                "correct_ans": "480 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{C_{O\\_rms}}{C_{H\\_rms}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{M_H}{M_O}}\\;\\\\C_{O\\_rms}=1920\\sqrt{\\frac2{32}}=480m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12534": {
                "ans1": "20%",
                "ans2": "19%",
                "ans3": "5%",
                "ans4": "50%",
                "question_text": "The intensity of sound gets reduced by 10% on passing through slab. The reduction in intensity on passing through two consecutive slabs will be",
                "correct_ans": "19%",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}After\\;passing\\;from1st\\\\I_1=0.9I\\\\After\\;passing\\;from\\;2nd\\;I_2=0.9I_1=0.81I2\\\\\\%reduce=(1-\\frac{I_2}{l_1})\\times100\\%\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14637": {
                "ans1": "Its velocity is constant",
                "ans2": "Its KE is constant",
                "ans3": "Its KE is constant",
                "ans4": "It move in a straight line",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A particle is acted upon by a force of constant",
                "correct_ans": "Its KE is constant",
                "explanation": "When force of constant magnitude act on a body perpendicular to path then speed remain constant.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15208": {
                "ans1": "T_1\\;and\\;T_2\\;should\\;be\\;high",
                "ans2": "T_1\\;and\\;T_2\\;should\\;be\\;low",
                "ans3": "T_1\\;should\\;be\\;low\\;and\\;T_2\\;should\\;be\\;high",
                "ans4": "T_1\\;should\\;be\\;high\\;and\\;T_2\\;should\\;be\\;low",
                "question_text": "A Carnot engine works between a source and sink maintained at constant temperatures T_1 and T_2  . For efficiency to be the greatest",
                "correct_ans": "T_1\\;should\\;be\\;high\\;and\\;T_2\\;should\\;be\\;low",
                "explanation": "Efficiency\\;increases\\;of\\;ratio\\;of\\frac{T1}{T2}\\;\\;\\;is\\;less\\;i.e.\\;T2\\;decreases\\;\\&\\;T1\\;increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18705": {
                "ans1": "decrease density",
                "ans2": "variation in pressure",
                "ans3": "expansion of air",
                "ans4": "height above the surface of earth",
                "question_text": "The temperature of air falls at high altitude due to",
                "correct_ans": "expansion of air",
                "explanation": "In high altitude gas expand adiabatically so temp. fall.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11703": {
                "ans1": " increases then decreases",
                "ans2": "increases then decreases then finally reversed",
                "ans3": " no change at all",
                "ans4": " change appreciably",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If one junction of thermocouple is heated and other is cooled continiously of in same steps, the emf will",
                "correct_ans": "increases then decreases then finally reversed",
                "explanation": "First increases and becomes maximum at neutral temperature then decreases to zero at temperature of inversion then increases in reverse direction.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19697": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt2:1",
                "ans2": "1:1",
                "ans3": "1:\\sqrt{\\;\\;2}\\;\u200b",
                "ans4": "1:2",
                "question_text": "An \u03b1 particle and a proton are accelerated from rest through a same potential difference. The ratio of their final velocities will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:\\sqrt{\\;\\;2}\\;\u200b",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15049": {
                "ans1": "Increases by 10%",
                "ans2": "Decreases by 10%",
                "ans3": "Decreases by 17%",
                "ans4": "Decreases by 21%",
                "question_text": "The distanced between two point charges is increased by 10% the force of interaction.",
                "correct_ans": "Decreases by 17%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15803": {
                "ans1": " increases continuously with mass number",
                "ans2": "decreases continuously with mass number",
                "ans3": "remain constant",
                "ans4": " first increases then decreases with mass number",
                "question_text": "When the no. of nucleons in nucleus increases, the binding energy per nucleon",
                "correct_ans": " first increases then decreases with mass number",
                "explanation": "Use graph of variation of binding energy per nucleon with mass no.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17526": {
                "ans1": "pressure",
                "ans2": "density",
                "ans3": "temperature",
                "ans4": "humidity",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The velocity of sound in air is independent of change in",
                "correct_ans": "pressure",
                "explanation": "Velocity of sound is independent to change in pressure",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18943": {
                "ans1": "2:1",
                "ans2": "4:1",
                "ans3": "8:1",
                "ans4": "16:1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The ratio of area within the orbit of electron for first excited state to ground state for Hydrogen atom is",
                "correct_ans": "16:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17013": {
                "ans1": " Increasing the emf of the cell",
                "ans2": " Increasing length of potentiometer",
                "ans3": " Decreasing the length of potentiometer wire",
                "ans4": "decreasing the emf of the cell",
                "question_text": "Sensitivity of potentiometer can be increased by",
                "correct_ans": " Increasing length of potentiometer",
                "explanation": "Sensitivity increase if potential gradient decreases i.e. length of potentiometer increases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14845": {
                "ans1": "(1/2)(V/d)\\;^{\\;2}",
                "ans2": "(1/2)CV\\;^2",
                "ans3": "Q^2/(2C)",
                "ans4": "1/2\\ast\\epsilon_{o\\;\u200b}V^2/d^2",
                "question_text": "The energy per unit volume for a capacitor having area A and separation 'd' kept at potential difference 'V' is given by",
                "correct_ans": "1/2\\ast\\epsilon_{o\\;\u200b}V^2/d^2",
                "explanation": "E/V=1/2\u2217CV^ \n2\n /(Ad)=1/2\u2217\u03f5 \no\n\u200b\n V ^\n2\n /d ^\n2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17569": {
                "ans1": "Repeal each other",
                "ans2": "attract each other",
                "ans3": "doesn't attract ",
                "ans4": "Both a and b",
                "question_text": "Soap bubble and Air bubble inside water\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Repeal each other",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13196": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\;vt\\;\u200b}T",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\;v^2t\\;\u200b}T",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\;v^2t\\;\u200b}{T^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\;v^2t^2\\;\u200b}{T^2}",
                "question_text": "A body starts from rest and acquires a velocity 'v' in time T. The work done on the body in time t will be proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\;v^2t^2\\;\u200b}{T^2}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v=at=\\frac{\\displaystyle vt}T\u200b\\\\Workdone(w)=\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle2}mv^2\\\\or,w\\propto v^2\\\\or,w\\propto\\frac{v^2t^2}{T^2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15338": {
                "ans1": "2L",
                "ans2": " 4L",
                "ans3": "L/2",
                "ans4": "L/4",
                "question_text": "A particle perform uniform circular motion with an angular momentum L. If the frequency of particle motion is doubled and radius is halved then new angular momentum becomes",
                "correct_ans": "L/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}L=mvr=mr2\\omega\\\\Again,L'=mr'^2\\omega'=m(\\frac{\\displaystyle r}{\\displaystyle2})^2\\times2\\omega=mr^2\\omega\\times\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle2}=\\frac{\\displaystyle L}{\\displaystyle2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11163": {
                "ans1": "w",
                "ans2": "w/2",
                "ans3": "w/4",
                "ans4": "w/8",
                "question_text": "The weight of a body a earth's surface is w. At a depth half way to the centre of the earth, it will be",
                "correct_ans": "w/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}wt=mg=w\\\\Atadepth.\\\\wt=mg'=mg(1-\\frac R2)=\\frac w2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12074": {
                "ans1": "cools the air",
                "ans2": "increases the conductivity of air",
                "ans3": " reduce the mal radiations",
                "ans4": "increases the rate of evaporation",
                "question_text": "Running of fan makes us comfortable during summer because it",
                "correct_ans": "increases the rate of evaporation",
                "explanation": "Running fan increases the rate of evaporation.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12616": {
                "ans1": "2V",
                "ans2": "2.5V",
                "ans3": "4V",
                "ans4": "5V",
                "question_text": "A cell does 5J of work in carrying 2C charge around a closed circuit. The electromotivforce of cell is",
                "correct_ans": "2.5V",
                "explanation": "V=\\frac{W\\;\u200b}{\\;\\;Q\\;}\\;\\;=\\;5/2=2.5V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11398": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\;R\\;\u200b}{\u01b3-1}",
                "ans2": "PV",
                "ans3": "\\frac{PV\\;\u200b}{\u01b3-1}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{rPV\\;\u200b}{\u01b3-1}",
                "question_text": "The ratio of specific heat capacity of gas is \u01b3 then change in internal energy of 1 mole of gas when volume changes from V to 2V at constant pressure P is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{PV\\;\u200b}{\u01b3-1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18163": {
                "ans1": "Bends with A on convex side",
                "ans2": "Bends with A on concave side",
                "ans3": "Does not bends",
                "ans4": "can bend on any side",
                "question_text": ".A bimetallic strip is made of two strips\u00a0A and B.\u00a0If\u00a0A >B\u00a0then on heating, the strip will:",
                "correct_ans": "Bends with A on convex side",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15731": {
                "ans1": " isobaric",
                "ans2": "isothermal",
                "ans3": "adiabatic",
                "ans4": " isochoric",
                "question_text": "Gas in vessels expands so that internal energy of gas decreases. The process is",
                "correct_ans": "adiabatic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15658": {
                "ans1": "6m",
                "ans2": "12m",
                "ans3": "18m",
                "ans4": "24m",
                "question_text": "A car moving with speed of 50 km/hr can be stopped by brakes at least 6m. If same car is moving at a speed of 100 km/hr then minimum distance at which car can be stopped is",
                "correct_ans": "24m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{1\u200b}2\\times mv^2=F_f\u200b\\times s\\\\or,\\frac12\\times mv^2=\\mu mgs\\\\or,s=\\frac{v^2}{2\\mu g}\\\\So,\\frac{s'}s=(\\frac{100}{50})^2=4\\\\s'=6\\times4=24m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12068": {
                "ans1": "100",
                "ans2": "150",
                "ans3": "50",
                "ans4": "75",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In CE configuration Ve = 2V so that base current changes from 100\u00b5A to 200\u00b5A produce a change in collector current 5 mA to 10 mA. The current gain is",
                "correct_ans": "50",
                "explanation": "\\beta=\\;\\frac{\\;\\;\\Delta I_{\\;\\;c}\\;\u200b\\;}{\\;\\;\\Delta I_{\\;\\;b}\\;\u200b}\\;\\;\u200b\\;\\;=\\;\\frac{\\;(10-5)\\times10\\;^{\\;-3\\;\\;}}{\\;(200-100)\\times10\\;^{\\;-6\\;}\\;}\\;\u200b\\;\\;=50",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13436": {
                "ans1": "x/f",
                "ans2": "f/x",
                "ans3": "1+(f/x)",
                "ans4": "1-(f/x)",
                "question_text": "An object is placed at a distance x from principal focus of a mirror of focal length 'f. The magnification of image will be",
                "correct_ans": "f/x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16495": {
                "ans1": " yellow",
                "ans2": " blue",
                "ans3": " green",
                "ans4": "orange",
                "question_text": "The deviation will be maximum through a prism for",
                "correct_ans": " blue",
                "explanation": "so\u00a0\\mu\u03bc\u00a0is maximum for blue due to minimum wavelength so blue will deviate maximum.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12431": {
                "ans1": "potential energy",
                "ans2": "kinetic energy",
                "ans3": "momentum",
                "ans4": "both a and b",
                "question_text": "A shell in flight, explodes into four equal parts. The quantity that conserved is",
                "correct_ans": "momentum",
                "explanation": "Momentum is only conserved in explosion",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10875": {
                "ans1": "increase in sp. Heat capacity",
                "ans2": "decrease in sp. Heat capacity",
                "ans3": " decrease in boiling point",
                "ans4": "increase in boiling point",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Cooking is faster in pressure cooker due to",
                "correct_ans": "increase in boiling point",
                "explanation": "Cooking is boiling at high temperature",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15077": {
                "ans1": "+ve axis",
                "ans2": "-ve x-axis",
                "ans3": "+ve z-axis",
                "ans4": "-ve z-axis",
                "question_text": "Positively charged particle enters in a magnetic field of\u00a0B_j\u200b\u00a0with velocity\u00a0v_k\u200b\u00a0then particle will move along",
                "correct_ans": "-ve x-axis",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13623": {
                "ans1": "Remains constant",
                "ans2": " Decreses",
                "ans3": "increases",
                "ans4": "oscillates",
                "question_text": "What happens to the gravitational potential at the centre of the uniform spherical shell which shrinks gradually?",
                "correct_ans": " Decreses",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10103": {
                "ans1": "pressure",
                "ans2": " density",
                "ans3": " temperature",
                "ans4": "humidity",
                "question_text": "The velocity of sound in air is independent of change in",
                "correct_ans": " density",
                "explanation": "Velocity of sound is independent to change in pressure.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13999": {
                "ans1": " surface tension",
                "ans2": "viscosity",
                "ans3": "density",
                "ans4": "temperature",
                "question_text": "\u00a0When there are no external forces, the shape of a liquid drop is determined by",
                "correct_ans": " surface tension",
                "explanation": "Cooking is faster due to cooking at high boiling point due to increase in pressure.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14238": {
                "ans1": "\\frac Q{6\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans2": "\\frac Q{8\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans3": "\\frac Q{7\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans4": "\\frac Q{3\\varepsilon_o}",
                "question_text": "A charge is placed at the corner of a cube then flux through all six faces of cube is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac Q{8\\varepsilon_o}",
                "explanation": "Charge at corner contribute one eighth\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14627": {
                "ans1": "2g",
                "ans2": "4g",
                "ans3": "g",
                "ans4": "3g",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The value of g on the surface of earth is g. The acceleration due to gravity at same place if earth shrink to half of its radius at constant mass is",
                "correct_ans": "4g",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}g=\\frac{GM}{R^2}\u200b\\\\Ifearth\\;shrink\\;then\\\\g\u2019=\\frac{GM}{(\\frac R2)^2}=4\\times\\frac{GM}{R^2}=4g\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17855": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u221e",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "Dielectric constant for a metal is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12933": {
                "ans1": "10 mA   ",
                "ans2": "10 A",
                "ans3": "1 mA    ",
                "ans4": "1 A",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter reads 80 V and has resistance per volt of 100 \\Omega. The current through voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "10 mA   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14164": {
                "ans1": "Newton\u2019s law of gravitation    ",
                "ans2": "Hooke\u2019s law    ",
                "ans3": "Poiseulle\u2019s law   ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "question_text": "Millikan\u2019s oil drop experiment is based on principle of",
                "correct_ans": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12799": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C",
                "ans3": "2C ",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14835": {
                "ans1": "transverse progressive       ",
                "ans2": "transverse stationary",
                "ans3": "longitudinal progressive      ",
                "ans4": "longitudinal stationary",
                "question_text": "Waves in organ pipe are",
                "correct_ans": "longitudinal stationary",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11882": {
                "ans1": "{}_{82}U^{212}",
                "ans2": "{}_{76}U^{206}",
                "ans3": "{}_{76}U^{212}",
                "ans4": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "question_text": "A particle {}_{92}U^{238} after undergoing 8 alpha decay and 6 beta decay gives",
                "correct_ans": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19640": {
                "ans1": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "ans2": "Newton\u2019s law of viscosity   ",
                "ans3": "Ohm\u2019s law  ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s  law",
                "question_text": "A body oscillating in simple harmonic motion follows",
                "correct_ans": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14545": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C",
                "ans3": "2C ",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13434": {
                "ans1": "zero ",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11498": {
                "ans1": "0.1",
                "ans2": "0.2",
                "ans3": "0.8",
                "ans4": "1.6",
                "question_text": "Two bodies of same temperature and same surface area have their radiation ratio of 1:2. If body \u2018A\u2019 has emissivity of 0.4, the emissivity of body \u2018B\u2019 will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19799": {
                "ans1": "0.21 ns   ",
                "ans2": "\\mu",
                "ans3": "0.47 ns    ",
                "ans4": "\\mu",
                "question_text": "Time taken by sun light to pass through a block 9.5 cm thick having refractive index 1.5 is",
                "correct_ans": "0.47 ns    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17147": {
                "ans1": "free electron    ",
                "ans2": "holes     ",
                "ans3": "bound electrons   ",
                "ans4": "both (a) and (c) ",
                "question_text": "Majority\u00a0 charge carriers in n-type semiconductor are",
                "correct_ans": "free electron    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16944": {
                "ans1": "perfectly elastic   ",
                "ans2": "partially elastic   ",
                "ans3": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "ans4": "partially inelastic",
                "question_text": "When a body collides with other body, it sticks completely. The collision is",
                "correct_ans": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14375": {
                "ans1": "P_1",
                "ans2": "P_1",
                "ans3": "P_1",
                "ans4": "P_1",
                "question_text": "Three resistors are connected in series such that R_1=2R_2=3R_3. If the circuit is connected to supply mains of 220 V, then power consumed will be",
                "correct_ans": "P_1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12865": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14451": {
                "ans1": "1836:1   ",
                "ans2": "(1836)^2:1",
                "ans3": "43:1   ",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated by same kinetic energy. The ratio of associated de-Broglie wavelength is nearly equal to",
                "correct_ans": "43:1   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14038": {
                "ans1": "linear momentum   ",
                "ans2": "force",
                "ans3": "work",
                "ans4": "moment",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is same as impulse?",
                "correct_ans": "linear momentum   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12879": {
                "ans1": "double",
                "ans2": "half",
                "ans3": "one-fourth   ",
                "ans4": "remains same",
                "question_text": "The intensity of incident photons is doubled the kinetic energy of emitted electron will be",
                "correct_ans": "remains same",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16700": {
                "ans1": "Melting point falls with increasing pressure",
                "ans2": "Melting point rises with pressure",
                "ans3": "Heat is rejected to outside",
                "ans4": "Heat is absorbed from outside",
                "question_text": "Two blocks of ice when pressed together join to form one block. This is due to",
                "correct_ans": "Melting point falls with increasing pressure",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11225": {
                "ans1": "neutron into a proton",
                "ans2": "proton into a neutron",
                "ans3": "nucleon into energy",
                "ans4": "position into energy",
                "question_text": "A \u03b2\u2013 particle is emitted by a radioactive nucleus at the time of conversion of",
                "correct_ans": "neutron into a proton",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14905": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remains unchanged",
                "ans4": "becomes maximum",
                "question_text": "If the forward voltage in a semiconductor diode is increased, width of depletion layer",
                "correct_ans": "decreases",
                "explanation": "In forward biasing the majority charge carries are pushed towards junction so width of depletion layer decreases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19878": {
                "ans1": "2P",
                "ans2": "1.4P",
                "ans3": "2.63P",
                "ans4": "P",
                "question_text": "A gas at pressure 'P' is diabatically compressed so that density become double of initial density then pressure of gas will be",
                "correct_ans": "2.63P",
                "explanation": "P2\u200bV2^\u03b3\u200b=P1\u200bV1^\u03b3\u200b\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17953": {
                "ans1": "No change",
                "ans2": "Diffraction bands become narrower and crowded together",
                "ans3": "Band become broader",
                "ans4": "Band disappear",
                "question_text": "Diffraction pattern is obtained using a beam of red light. When red light is replaced by blue light then.",
                "correct_ans": "Diffraction bands become narrower and crowded together",
                "explanation": "Since, \u03bbblue\u200b<\u03bbred\u200b, so\u00a0x\u00a0decrease and band becomes narrower",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19202": {
                "ans1": "16",
                "ans2": "24",
                "ans3": "28",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "Current amplification base transistor is 0.96 then current gain when used in common emitter mode is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "\u03b1=0.96We have,\\beta =\\dfrac {\\alpha}{(1-\\alpha)}= 24",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19207": {
                "ans1": "15 N",
                "ans2": "20 N",
                "ans3": "10 N",
                "ans4": "5 N",
                "question_text": "Force between two charges is\u00a040 N\u00a0in air. The space between charges is filled with glass of dielectric constant 8 then force will be",
                "correct_ans": "5 N",
                "explanation": "Fa\u200b=40N\u0190_r = \\dfrac{F_a}{F_m}F_m = \\dfrac{40}{8} = 5\\;N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16217": {
                "ans1": "doubled",
                "ans2": "halfed",
                "ans3": "remains unchanged",
                "ans4": "becomes 4 times",
                "question_text": "When speed of particle is doubled and angular velocity is halved then centripetal acccleration of particle",
                "correct_ans": "remains unchanged",
                "explanation": "Centripetal acceleration remains unchanged.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12710": {
                "ans1": "Intensity of incident beam",
                "ans2": "frequency of incident beam",
                "ans3": " velocity of incident beam",
                "ans4": "work function of photocathode",
                "question_text": "The photoelectric effect, the number of photoelectrons emitted is proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "Intensity of incident beam",
                "explanation": "The no. of photo electrons emitted are proportional to the intensity of incident radiation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12740": {
                "ans1": "electron",
                "ans2": "positron",
                "ans3": "proton",
                "ans4": "neutron",
                "question_text": "During nuclear reaction of deuteron and\u00a0^6C_{12} a nucleus of\u00a0^7N_{13}\u200b\u00a0is formed then the particle liberated is",
                "correct_ans": "neutron",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10052": {
                "ans1": "(n - 1)f",
                "ans2": "f/n",
                "ans3": "(n + 1)f",
                "ans4": "nf",
                "question_text": "A convex mirror of focal length f produces an image (1/n)th of the size of the object. The distance of the object from mirror is",
                "correct_ans": "(n - 1)f",
                "explanation": "focal length negativev = -uthen use mirror formulawe get,u=(n\u22121)f",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19496": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "first increases",
                "question_text": "When two electrons are bought nearer, the potential energy of the system",
                "correct_ans": "increases",
                "explanation": "On decreasing r , PE increases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18444": {
                "ans1": "with an acceleration",
                "ans2": "with uniform speed",
                "ans3": "with deacceleration",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "A passenger in a moving train tosses a coin. If the coin falls behind him, the train must be moving",
                "correct_ans": "with an acceleration",
                "explanation": "If coin falls behind the person then train must be in acceleration.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12489": {
                "ans1": "20 k\u03a9",
                "ans2": "15 k\u03a9",
                "ans3": "10 k\u03a9",
                "ans4": "1.5 k\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A zener diode V_z = 5V and I_z = 10mA is connected in series with a resistance and 20V is applied across the combination. The maximum resistance one can use without spoiling zener action is",
                "correct_ans": "1.5 k\u03a9",
                "explanation": "R = (V - Vz)/Is = (20 - 5)/(10 \u00d7 10-3) = 1500 ohm = 1.5 k ohm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15789": {
                "ans1": "1000",
                "ans2": "300",
                "ans3": "180",
                "ans4": "250",
                "question_text": "A wave of frequency\u00a0500 Hz\u00a0travel between\u00a0X and\u00a0Y\u00a0at a distance 600 m\u00a0in 2 s. The number of waves between XY\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "1000",
                "explanation": "600m\u00a0is traveled in 2sec\u00a0so in\u00a01sec\u00a0it travel 300m. Hence, 500\u00a0waves are present in 300mtherefore, No. of waves between XY are 2*500 = 1000",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14368": {
                "ans1": "1 m/s",
                "ans2": "1 mm/s",
                "ans3": "10^5\\;m/s",
                "ans4": "3\\;\\times\\;10^8\\;m/s",
                "question_text": "The drift velocity of electrons in of the order of",
                "correct_ans": "1 mm/s",
                "explanation": "The drift velocity of electrons in metal is in the order of mm/s.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12606": {
                "ans1": "t^\\frac12",
                "ans2": "t^\\frac34",
                "ans3": "t^\\frac32",
                "ans4": "t^\\frac14",
                "question_text": "A body is moving along a straight line by a machine delivering a constant power. The distance moved by the body in time t is proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "t^\\frac32",
                "explanation": "P=Fvsince, F =mv/t=ms/t^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10624": {
                "ans1": " First law of motion",
                "ans2": "Second law of motion",
                "ans3": "Third law of motion",
                "ans4": "both a and b",
                "question_text": "The real law of motion is:",
                "correct_ans": "Second law of motion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13706": {
                "ans1": "It's energy levels are too close to each other",
                "ans2": " It's energy levels are too far to eachother",
                "ans3": "It is too small",
                "ans4": "It has single electron",
                "question_text": "Hydrogen atom does not emit X-ray because",
                "correct_ans": "It's energy levels are too close to each other",
                "explanation": "To emit X-ray the difference between two energy level must lie in X-ray region",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10760": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "10",
                "ans3": "12",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "A number of 110 V lamps connected in parallel are fed by a 130 V battery having an internal resistance of 2.6 \u03a9. If the resistance of each lamp is 200 \u03a9\u00a0& resistance of wire is 0.4 \u03a9, the number of lamps are",
                "correct_ans": "12",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11536": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_1+V_2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{V_1}{V_1+V_2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_1}",
                "question_text": "Air filled parallel plate capacitor is charged to potential\u00a0V_1\u200b\u00a0is connected to an unchanged identical parallel plate capacitor of dielectric conslant k then common potential become\u00a0V_2\u200b. The value of K is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18504": {
                "ans1": " decrease",
                "ans2": " increase",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "become uncertain",
                "question_text": "A source of sound and the observer are moving away from each other. The appearance pitch will",
                "correct_ans": " decrease",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17530": {
                "ans1": "546\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "819\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "273\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "1092\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "The temperature at which velocity of sound become double of 0\u00b0C is.",
                "correct_ans": "819\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10879": {
                "ans1": "solid sphere",
                "ans2": "hollow sphere",
                "ans3": "both simultaneously",
                "ans4": "depends on mass of sphere",
                "question_text": "A solid sphere and hollow sphere rolls down an inclined plane without slipping. Which sphere will reach the bottom earlier?",
                "correct_ans": "hollow sphere",
                "explanation": "Here k for solid sphere is less than hollow sphere so 'a' for solid sphere is greater than hollow sphere. Hence solid sphere will reach at bottom faster.\\begin{array}{l}\\alpha=\\frac{g\\;\\sin\\theta}{1+{\\displaystyle\\frac{k^2}{r^2}}}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17677": {
                "ans1": "it gets accelerated",
                "ans2": "it gets retarded",
                "ans3": " it moves with constant speed",
                "ans4": "its path becomes parabolic",
                "question_text": "An electron moving with a finite velocity enters in an electric held parallel to lines of force, then",
                "correct_ans": "it gets retarded",
                "explanation": "Force on electron act in opposite direction of field so they decelerate.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13747": {
                "ans1": "n^\\gamma p",
                "ans2": "n^{-\\gamma}p",
                "ans3": "n^{\\gamma-1}p",
                "ans4": "n^{1-\\gamma}p",
                "question_text": "An ideal gas at pressure p is compressed suddenly so the density of gas become n times the initial value. The final pressure of gas will be",
                "correct_ans": "n^\\gamma p",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11302": {
                "ans1": "2mv",
                "ans2": "\\frac{mv}2",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{mv}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt2mv",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A projectile of mass 'm' is fired with velocity v at an angle 45\u00b0\u00a0with horizontal. The magnitude of change in momentum when projectile arrived on the surface of the earth is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt2mv",
                "explanation": "\u0394P=mvsin45\u2212(\u2212mvsin45)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17911": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{u-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{v-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac{v-f}f\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac{u-f}u\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "Length of a body is L. It is kept at a distance u from concave mirror of focal length 'f' then length of image will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{u-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}use\\;the\\;relation\\\\m=\\frac IO=\\frac vu\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11129": {
                "ans1": "MLT^{-2}",
                "ans2": "MLT^{-1}",
                "ans3": "MLT",
                "ans4": "ML^2T^{-2}",
                "question_text": "The dimensional formula of force is:",
                "correct_ans": "MLT^{-2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19314": {
                "ans1": "0.012mA",
                "ans2": " 0.12 mA",
                "ans3": "0.24mA",
                "ans4": "1.2mA",
                "question_text": "The current gain for a common emitter amplifier is 49. If the emitter current is 6mA then base current is",
                "correct_ans": " 0.12 mA",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14232": {
                "ans1": " l, d",
                "ans2": "2l, d",
                "ans3": "l/2, d",
                "ans4": "2l, d/2",
                "question_text": "A piece of copper is shaped into a conductor of minimum resistance. Its length and diameter should be",
                "correct_ans": "l/2, d",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18265": {
                "ans1": "(n+1)G",
                "ans2": "\\frac G{(n-1)}",
                "ans3": "(n\u22121)G",
                "ans4": "G/n",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter can measure volt 'V' has resistance 'G' then it can be changed into a voltmeter, measuring upto nV then resistance series is",
                "correct_ans": "(n\u22121)G",
                "explanation": "G+R=nG\u00a0or,\u00a0R=(n-1)G",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16314": {
                "ans1": "L",
                "ans2": "L\\frac{\\alpha_s}{\\alpha_r}",
                "ans3": "L\\frac{\\alpha_r}{\\alpha_s}",
                "ans4": "L\\frac{1+\\alpha_s}{1+\\alpha_r}",
                "question_text": "A steel scale measure the length of rod at 20\u00b0c is L. If scale is correct at 20\u00b0c then reading of scale at 21\u00b0c if\u00a0\u03b1_s\u200b\u00a0and\u00a0\u03b1_r be the linear exapansivity of scale & rod respectively",
                "correct_ans": "L\\frac{1+\\alpha_s}{1+\\alpha_r}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12535": {
                "ans1": "2(\\rho_1\u200b+\\rho_2\\;)",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{\\rho_1\\rho_2\\;}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;}2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "Two wires of same dimensions but resistivities\u00a0\u00a0\u03c1_1\u200b\u00a0and     \u00a0\u00a0\u03c1_2\u200b\u00a0 are connected in series. The equivalent resistivity of combination is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;}2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "use R=\u03c1l/A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10893": {
                "ans1": "10 mA   ",
                "ans2": "10 A    ",
                "ans3": "1 mA    ",
                "ans4": "1 A",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter reads 80 V and has resistance per volt of 100 \\Omega. The current through voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "10 mA   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10115": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12514": {
                "ans1": "perfectly elastic   ",
                "ans2": "partially elastic   ",
                "ans3": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "ans4": "partially inelastic",
                "question_text": "When a body collides with other body, it sticks completely. The collision is",
                "correct_ans": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14213": {
                "ans1": "free electron    ",
                "ans2": "holes  ",
                "ans3": "bound electrons   ",
                "ans4": "both (a) and (c) ",
                "question_text": "Majority\u00a0 charge carriers in n-type semiconductor are",
                "correct_ans": "free electron    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12219": {
                "ans1": "Newton\u2019s law of gravitation    ",
                "ans2": "Hooke\u2019s law    ",
                "ans3": "Poiseulle\u2019s law   ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "question_text": "Millikan\u2019s oil drop experiment is based on principle of",
                "correct_ans": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10915": {
                "ans1": "double",
                "ans2": "half",
                "ans3": "one-fourth   ",
                "ans4": "remains same",
                "question_text": "The intensity of incident photons is doubled the kinetic energy of emitted electron will be",
                "correct_ans": "remains same",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10100": {
                "ans1": "linear momentum   ",
                "ans2": "force ",
                "ans3": "work",
                "ans4": "moment",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is same as impulse?",
                "correct_ans": "linear momentum   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14546": {
                "ans1": "0.21 ns   ",
                "ans2": "0.21  ms     ",
                "ans3": "0.47 ns    ",
                "ans4": "0.47 ms   ",
                "question_text": "Time taken by sun light to pass through a block 9.5 cm thick having refractive index 1.5 is",
                "correct_ans": "0.47 ns    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15568": {
                "ans1": "{}_{82}U^{212}",
                "ans2": "{}_{76}U^{206}",
                "ans3": "{}_{76}U^{212}",
                "ans4": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "question_text": "A particle {}_{92}U^{238} after undergoing 8 alpha decay and 6 beta decay gives",
                "correct_ans": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14791": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C ",
                "ans3": "2C",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14212": {
                "ans1": "transverse progressive       ",
                "ans2": "transverse stationary",
                "ans3": "longitudinal progressive      ",
                "ans4": "longitudinal stationary",
                "question_text": "Waves in organ pipe are",
                "correct_ans": "longitudinal stationary",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19803": {
                "ans1": "1836:1   ",
                "ans2": "(1836)^2:1",
                "ans3": "43:1   ",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated by same kinetic energy. The ratio of associated de-Broglie wavelength is nearly equal to",
                "correct_ans": "43:1   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13348": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11992": {
                "ans1": "0.1",
                "ans2": "0.2",
                "ans3": "0.8",
                "ans4": "1.6",
                "question_text": "Two bodies of same temperature and same surface area have their radiation ratio of 1:2. If body \u2018A\u2019 has emissivity of 0.4, the emissivity of body \u2018B\u2019 will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18756": {
                "ans1": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "ans2": "Newton\u2019s law of viscosity   ",
                "ans3": "Ohm\u2019s law  ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s  law",
                "question_text": "A body oscillating in simple harmonic motion follows",
                "correct_ans": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15080": {
                "ans1": "ML^{-1}T^{-2}",
                "ans2": "MLT^{-2}",
                "ans3": "ML^{-1}T^{-1}",
                "ans4": "ML^{-1}T^{2}",
                "question_text": "The dimension of modulus of rigidity is",
                "correct_ans": "ML^{-1}T^{-2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13341": {
                "ans1": "P_1= P_2= P_3   ",
                "ans2": "P_1=4 P_2=16P_3",
                "ans3": "P_1=2P_2=3P_3",
                "ans4": "P_1=2P_2=4P_3",
                "question_text": "Three resistors are connected in series such that R_1=2R_2=3R_3. If the circuit is connected to supply mains of 220 V, then power consumed will be",
                "correct_ans": "P_1=2P_2=3P_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18703": {
                "ans1": "Material of rod",
                "ans2": "Rise in Temperature",
                "ans3": "Length of the rod",
                "ans4": "All of the above",
                "question_text": "When a rod is heated and prevented from expanding then the stress developed is independent of",
                "correct_ans": "Length of the rod",
                "explanation": "stress is independent of the length",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19805": {
                "ans1": "\\frac Q{6\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans2": "\\frac Q{2\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans3": "\\frac Q{12\\varepsilon_o}",
                "ans4": "\\frac Q{\\varepsilon_o}",
                "question_text": "Charge Q is placed at centre of cube then the flux through one of the face of cube will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac Q{6\\varepsilon_o}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12605": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "becomes half",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the acceleration of body in SHM increases then time period of body",
                "correct_ans": "remain same",
                "explanation": "Acceleration increases if displacement increases but time period is independent",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18107": {
                "ans1": "2\\ast10^5\\;\\Omega",
                "ans2": "2\\ast10^6\\;\\Omega",
                "ans3": "200\\ast10^4\\;\\Omega",
                "ans4": "2\\ast10^3\\;\\Omega",
                "question_text": "In reverse biased diode the voltage changes by 1V then the current is found to change by 0.5\u00a0\\mu \u00a0A then the resistance of the diode is",
                "correct_ans": "2\\ast10^6\\;\\Omega",
                "explanation": "R=\\frac{\\Delta V}{\\Delta I}=\\frac1{0.5\\times10^{-6}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12269": {
                "ans1": "radiowaves",
                "ans2": "infrared",
                "ans3": "visible rays",
                "ans4": "x-rays",
                "question_text": "When ultravoilet radiation is incident on a metal surface then no electrons are emitted. When second beam cause photoelectric emission then it must consist",
                "correct_ans": "x-rays",
                "explanation": "If uv radiation doesn't emit electron then radiation to emit electron must be enegetic i.e, x-ray.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12636": {
                "ans1": "\u03c3",
                "ans2": "\u03c3/2",
                "ans3": "\u03c3/\u03b50",
                "ans4": "\u03c3/2\u03b50",
                "question_text": "The surface charge density on the surface of copper sphere is \u2018\\sigma\u2019 then the electric field intensity on the surface of the sphere will be",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c3/\u03b50",
                "explanation": "E=\\frac Q{4{\\mathrm{\u03c0\u03b5}}_0\\mathrm r^2}=\\frac\\sigma{\\varepsilon_o}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16381": {
                "ans1": "\\frac14\\pi",
                "ans2": "8\\pi",
                "ans3": "4\\pi",
                "ans4": "\\frac18\\pi",
                "question_text": "The flux due to source of lcd is",
                "correct_ans": "4\\pi",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11429": {
                "ans1": "a/3",
                "ans2": "a/2",
                "ans3": "a/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "a/2\u221a2",
                "question_text": "A particle executes SHM with an amplitude \u2018a\u2019 . The energy of particle is half kinetic and half potential when its displacement is",
                "correct_ans": "a/\u221a2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}KE=PE\\\\\\frac12mw^2(a^2-y^2)=\\frac12mw^2y^2\\\\or,\\;a^2=2y^2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11824": {
                "ans1": "sin\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos\u03b8",
                "ans3": "g",
                "ans4": "tan\u03b8",
                "question_text": "A block is placed on an inclined plane with slope\u00a0\\theta\u03b8. The block slides down the lane with constant speed. the coefficient of kinetic friction is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "tan\u03b8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11058": {
                "ans1": "2:1",
                "ans2": "1:2",
                "ans3": "\u221a2 :1",
                "ans4": "1 : \u221a2",
                "question_text": "Two bodies have their moments of inertia I and 2I respectively about their axis of rotation. If their KE of rotation are equal, their angular momentum will be in the ratio",
                "correct_ans": "1 : \u221a2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}KE_1=KE_2\\\\or,\\;\\frac{L_1^2}{2I}=\\frac{L_2^2}{2\\ast2I}\\\\or,\\frac{L_1}{L_2}=\\frac1{\\sqrt2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14431": {
                "ans1": "yellow",
                "ans2": "blue",
                "ans3": "green",
                "ans4": "orange",
                "question_text": "The deviation will be maximum through a prism for",
                "correct_ans": "blue",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19706": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16537": {
                "ans1": "electric field intensity doesn't change",
                "ans2": "electric field intensity decreases",
                "ans3": "electric field intensity increases",
                "ans4": "electric field intensity depends upon thickness of slab",
                "question_text": "When a dielectric slab is introduced in parallel plate capacitor then",
                "correct_ans": "electric field intensity decreases",
                "explanation": "on introducing dielectric slab, capacitance increases. So electric field intensity decreases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16907": {
                "ans1": "isotopes",
                "ans2": "isobar",
                "ans3": "isomer",
                "ans4": "isotones",
                "question_text": "The mother and daughter element due to emmison of beta particle is",
                "correct_ans": "isobar",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16826": {
                "ans1": "0\u00b0",
                "ans2": "60\u00b0",
                "ans3": "90\u00b0",
                "ans4": "120\u00b0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow A and\u00a0\\overrightarrow  B are two vectors then\u00a0\\left|\\overrightarrow A+\\overrightarrow B\\right|=\\left|\\overrightarrow A-\\overrightarrow B\\right| then the angle between A and B will be",
                "correct_ans": "90\u00b0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14840": {
                "ans1": "decreases",
                "ans2": "remain same",
                "ans3": "increases",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "When \u00df- is emitted from radioactive nucleus then ratio of no. of neutron and number of proton in resulting nucleus",
                "correct_ans": "decreases",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19598": {
                "ans1": "16:1",
                "ans2": "1:1",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "1:4",
                "question_text": "Oxygen and hydrogrn are at the same temperature T. The ratio of the mean KE if the oxygen molecule to that of the hydrogen molecule will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:1",
                "explanation": "\\frac{KE_o}{KE_H}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac32KT}{\\displaystyle\\frac32KT}=1:1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11467": {
                "ans1": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "ans2": "Backward in both wheel",
                "ans3": "Forward in both wheel",
                "ans4": "Forward in front wheel and backward in rear wheel",
                "question_text": "What is the direction of friction in the wheels of by-cycle when the cycle is pedaled?",
                "correct_ans": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "explanation": "This is because, the rear wheel is constantly being rotated by a external force and hence it must exert forward friction on ground to keep moving, but front wheel is being rotated due to friction of ground which is backward in direction at the lowermost tip of tyre of front wheel.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16190": {
                "ans1": " 25 \u00b0",
                "ans2": "28\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "64.8\u00b0",
                "question_text": "If the polarizing angle of diamond is \u00a067^O, then critical angle for diamond is:",
                "correct_ans": " 25 \u00b0",
                "explanation": "\u03bc=tanip\u200b=tan67 c = \\sin^-1(\\dfrac{1}{\\mu}) = 25.1^{\\circ}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12419": {
                "ans1": "2K",
                "ans2": "K/2",
                "ans3": "K",
                "ans4": "3K/2",
                "question_text": "A spring of force constant\u00a0KK\u00a0is divided into two pieces. The force constant of the individual pieces is",
                "correct_ans": "2K",
                "explanation": "\u00a0Force Constant K\u221d1/length",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12861": {
                "ans1": "18%",
                "ans2": "36%",
                "ans3": "20%",
                "ans4": "64%",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The tension in a stretched vibrating wire is decreased by 36%, then frequency of vibration is decreased by:",
                "correct_ans": "20%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11540": {
                "ans1": "m",
                "ans2": "m/5",
                "ans3": "5m",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "A magnet of pole strength\u00a0'm' is cut into\u00a05\u00a0equal parts along perpendicular to its length. The pole strength of each piece will be:",
                "correct_ans": "m",
                "explanation": "Pole strength \u221d\u00a0Cross sectional area.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14638": {
                "ans1": "Q/8",
                "ans2": "Q/24",
                "ans3": "Q",
                "ans4": "There no net flux through the cube because the charge loses its property",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Electric flux through the side of a cube where a small point charge Q is placed at one of its corner is:",
                "correct_ans": "Q/24",
                "explanation": "We have the net flux through whole cube will beQ/8\u200b\u00a0due to charge at corner.\u00a0\\dfrac{Q}{24}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11631": {
                "ans1": "Taller than actual",
                "ans2": "Shorter than actual",
                "ans3": "Same",
                "ans4": "depends on depth of pond",
                "question_text": "When a person inside pond see tree on the side of pond, then tree will apper:",
                "correct_ans": "Taller than actual",
                "explanation": "Object in rarer medium is seen from denser medium, then it appears taller than its actual height. This is converse for shift in medium.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16083": {
                "ans1": "P",
                "ans2": "2P",
                "ans3": "P/2",
                "ans4": "4P",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two gases A and B having same pressure\u00a0P, volume\u00a0V\u00a0and absolute temperature\u00a0T\u00a0are mixed. If the mixture has the volume\u00a0V\u00a0and temperature\u00a0T\u00a0then pressure of mixture will be",
                "correct_ans": "2P",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19253": {
                "ans1": "500",
                "ans2": "700",
                "ans3": "1000",
                "ans4": "1400",
                "question_text": "In common emitter amplifier , it has current gain\u00a070. The load resistance is 5k\u03a9\u00a0and input resistance is 500\u03a9\u00a0then voltage gain is:",
                "correct_ans": "700",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17724": {
                "ans1": " Interference",
                "ans2": " Diffraction",
                "ans3": "Polarization",
                "ans4": "Total internal reflection",
                "question_text": "Air bubble shines brightly in air because of the phenomenon of",
                "correct_ans": "Total internal reflection",
                "explanation": "Water is denser than air, so total internal reflection is the accounting factor for this phenomenon.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10615": {
                "ans1": "IS",
                "ans2": "I/S",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac IS}",
                "ans4": "\\left(\\frac IS\\right)^2",
                "question_text": "A straight conductor of uniform cross section carries a current of\u00a0I.\u00a0S\u00a0be the specific charge of an electron then momentum of all the free electrons per unit length of conductor due to their drift velocity only is:",
                "correct_ans": "I/S",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11176": {
                "ans1": "Less than 0.1 N",
                "ans2": "More than 0.1 N",
                "ans3": "0.1N",
                "ans4": "less\\;than\\;0.1N\\;if\\;Q_1\\;and\\;Q_2\\;are\\;different\\;in\\;nature",
                "question_text": "Two charges\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0   Q_2repel each other with force of 0.1 N. The force exerted by\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0Q_2\u200b\u00a0when a third charge is placed near them :",
                "correct_ans": "0.1N",
                "explanation": "Force between two charges is always same independent of other charges in their periphery",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13137": {
                "ans1": "Penetration power increases",
                "ans2": "peneteration power decreases",
                "ans3": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "ans4": " intensity of x-ray decreases",
                "question_text": "When current in filament increases then during production of x-ray;",
                "correct_ans": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "explanation": "Intensity of x-ray increases on increasing current through the filament.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19345": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{eht}E",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-mh}{eEt^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{-h}{eE}",
                "question_text": "An electron of mass\u00a0'm' and charge\u00a0e\u00a0initially at rest gets accelerated by electric field\u00a0E. The rate of change in de-Broglie wavelength of electron at time\u00a0\u2032t\u2032\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15098": {
                "ans1": "Amplitude",
                "ans2": "Wavelength",
                "ans3": "Quality",
                "ans4": "frequency",
                "question_text": "Loudness of note increases with increase in:",
                "correct_ans": "Amplitude",
                "explanation": "\u00a0I \\propto a^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10526": {
                "ans1": "12\u03a9",
                "ans2": "3\u03a9",
                "ans3": "6\u03a9",
                "ans4": "2.25\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of 12\u03a9\u00a0is bent into form of circle . The equivalent resistance across any one quarter of its length is:",
                "correct_ans": "2.25\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14647": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1 < \u03b2 always",
                "ans2": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A=B",
                "ans3": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A>B"
            },
            "15896": {
                "ans1": "it collapse",
                "ans2": "its radius increases",
                "ans3": "its radius decreases",
                "ans4": "radius may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "When charge is placed on a soap bubble then",
                "correct_ans": "its radius increases",
                "explanation": "When charge is placed on the soap bubble then radius of it increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15127": {
                "ans1": " 24 \u03bc A",
                "ans2": "25\u03bc A",
                "ans3": "26\u03bc A",
                "ans4": "27\u03bc A",
                "question_text": "A transistor is connected in common emitter configuration. The collector supply is 8 V and voltage drop across resistor of 800\u03a9\u00a0in the collector is 0.5 V. The current gain is 0.96 then base current is",
                "correct_ans": "26\u03bc A",
                "explanation": "I=V\u200b/(R/\u03b2\u200b)=\u00a0\\dfrac{0.5}{800 \\times 24}=\u00a026 \\times 10^{-6}=\u00a026 \\mu A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12792": {
                "ans1": "nR",
                "ans2": "R/n",
                "ans3": "\\frac n{R^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac R{n^2}",
                "question_text": "A wire of resistance R is cut in 'n' equal parts and each parts are placed in parallel then equivalent resistance will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac R{n^2}",
                "explanation": "Resistance of each partR_1 = \\dfrac{R}{n}R_{eq} = \\dfrac{R_1}{n} = \\dfrac{R}{n^2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16372": {
                "ans1": "T",
                "ans2": "T^2",
                "ans3": "T^3",
                "ans4": "T^4",
                "question_text": "Rate of transfer of heat due to radiation is proportional to:",
                "correct_ans": "T^4",
                "explanation": "E=\u03c3\u03f5AT^4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19884": {
                "ans1": "3/2",
                "ans2": "\u221a(3/2)",
                "ans3": "3/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a3",
                "question_text": "The x-component of a vector making an angle of 30\u00b0 with horizontal is 3. Its y-component is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "tan(30\u2218)\u200b=Ay\u200b\u200b/Ax\u200bso\u00a0A_y=\\dfrac{3 \\times 1}{\\sqrt{3}}=\\sqrt{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11860": {
                "ans1": "low specific heat and high conductivity",
                "ans2": " low specific and low conductivity",
                "ans3": "high specific heat and low conductivity",
                "ans4": "high specific and high conductivity",
                "question_text": "The most appropriate material for making a cooking pot is one having",
                "correct_ans": "low specific heat and high conductivity",
                "explanation": "Cooking pot must have low specific heat capacity and high thermal conductivity so minimum\u2019 heat is lost",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16437": {
                "ans1": "M",
                "ans2": "L",
                "ans3": "T",
                "ans4": "T^{-1}",
                "question_text": "The dimensional formula of\u00a0[RC]\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "T",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15886": {
                "ans1": "pressure",
                "ans2": "density",
                "ans3": "temperature",
                "ans4": "humidity",
                "question_text": "The velocity of sound in air is independent of change in",
                "correct_ans": "pressure",
                "explanation": "Velocity of sound is independent to change in pressure.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10471": {
                "ans1": "23/6",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "3/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a23/6",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{2},\\dfrac{1}{3},n) are direction cosines of a line then n=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a23/6",
                "explanation": "sum of their square = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16279": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{Y_1}{Y_2}=\\frac{\\alpha_1}{\\alpha_2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{Y_1}{Y_2}=\\frac{\\alpha_2}{\\alpha_1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{Y_1}{Y_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{\\alpha_1}{\\alpha_2}}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{Y_1}{Y_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{\\alpha_2}{\\alpha_1}}",
                "question_text": "Two rods of different material of linear expansivities\u00a0\\alpha_1\u200b\u00a0and\u00a0\\alpha_2\u200b\u00a0, Young's modulus Y1 & Y2 are fixed between two rigid massive wall. The rods are heated between same temperature and there is no bending on rod then stress will be equal it",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{Y_1}{Y_2}=\\frac{\\alpha_2}{\\alpha_1}",
                "explanation": "T=YA\u03b1\u0394\u03b8\u03c3=Y\u03b1\u0394\u03b8Y\u03b1=\u00a0constant",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11960": {
                "ans1": "transverse",
                "ans2": "geometrical",
                "ans3": "longitudinal",
                "ans4": "both transverse and longitudinal",
                "question_text": "Polarisation phenomenon explains which nature of light?",
                "correct_ans": "transverse",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19320": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "1/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The KE is a free electron is doubled, its be Brogile's wavelength will be",
                "correct_ans": "1/\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18744": {
                "ans1": "2b",
                "ans2": "-2b",
                "ans3": "2bt",
                "ans4": "-2bt",
                "question_text": "The position x of a particle varies with time (t) as x =\u00a0at - bt^2. The acceleration of particle is:",
                "correct_ans": "-2b",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19756": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "remain constant",
                "ans3": "goes on increasing",
                "ans4": "goes on decreasing",
                "question_text": "A mass M is moving wilh a constant velocity along x-axis. Its angular momentum with respect to origin is",
                "correct_ans": "remain constant",
                "explanation": "L= mvr",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15354": {
                "ans1": "0.5 W",
                "ans2": "0 W",
                "ans3": "1.5 W",
                "ans4": "2 W",
                "question_text": "ln an isothermal change of ideal gas\u00a0\u0394W = 0.5. The change in heat energy Q is equal to.",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 W",
                "explanation": "In isothermal, dU = 0so, dQ = dW",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10592": {
                "ans1": "penetration power increases",
                "ans2": "penetration power decreases",
                "ans3": " intensity of x-ray increases",
                "ans4": "intensity of x-ray decreases",
                "question_text": "During x-ray production, the current is increased then",
                "correct_ans": " intensity of x-ray increases",
                "explanation": "The current in anode increases the no. of electrons incident at cathode i.e. intensity of x-ray.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12700": {
                "ans1": "3\u03bb \u200b",
                "ans2": "\u221a3\u03bb \u200b",
                "ans3": "\u03bb \u200b/3",
                "ans4": "\u03bb \u200b/\u221a3",
                "question_text": "The de-Broglie wavelength associated with charged particle accelerated through 100 V is\u00a0\\lambda\u03bb. The de-Broglie wavelength with same charged particle accelerated by 900 V is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03bb \u200b/3",
                "explanation": "\\sqrt(v)\\dfrac{\\lambda'}{\\lambda} = \\sqrt{\\dfrac{v}{v'}}\\lambda'=\\dfrac{\\lambda}{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16443": {
                "ans1": "10 mA   ",
                "ans2": "10 A",
                "ans3": "1 mA    ",
                "ans4": "1 A",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter reads 80 V and has resistance per volt of 100 \\Omega. The current through voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "10 mA   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12245": {
                "ans1": "Newton\u2019s law of gravitation    ",
                "ans2": "Hooke\u2019s law    ",
                "ans3": "Poiseulle\u2019s law   ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "question_text": "Millikan\u2019s oil drop experiment is based on principle of",
                "correct_ans": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14734": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C",
                "ans3": "2C ",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10799": {
                "ans1": "transverse progressive       ",
                "ans2": "transverse stationary",
                "ans3": "longitudinal progressive      ",
                "ans4": "longitudinal stationary",
                "question_text": "Waves in organ pipe are",
                "correct_ans": "longitudinal stationary",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14809": {
                "ans1": "{}_{82}U^{212}",
                "ans2": "{}_{76}U^{206}",
                "ans3": "{}_{76}U^{212}",
                "ans4": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "question_text": "A particle {}_{92}U^{238} after undergoing 8 alpha decay and 6 beta decay gives",
                "correct_ans": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12517": {
                "ans1": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "ans2": "Newton\u2019s law of viscosity   ",
                "ans3": "Ohm\u2019s law  ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s  law",
                "question_text": "A body oscillating in simple harmonic motion follows",
                "correct_ans": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16773": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C",
                "ans3": "2C ",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14868": {
                "ans1": "zero ",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13749": {
                "ans1": "0.1",
                "ans2": "0.2",
                "ans3": "0.8",
                "ans4": "1.6",
                "question_text": "Two bodies of same temperature and same surface area have their radiation ratio of 1:2. If body \u2018A\u2019 has emissivity of 0.4, the emissivity of body \u2018B\u2019 will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16030": {
                "ans1": "0.21 ns   ",
                "ans2": "\\mu",
                "ans3": "0.47 ns    ",
                "ans4": "\\mu",
                "question_text": "Time taken by sun light to pass through a block 9.5 cm thick having refractive index 1.5 is",
                "correct_ans": "0.47 ns    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15526": {
                "ans1": "free electron    ",
                "ans2": "holes     ",
                "ans3": "bound electrons   ",
                "ans4": "both (a) and (c) ",
                "question_text": "Majority\u00a0 charge carriers in n-type semiconductor are",
                "correct_ans": "free electron    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10147": {
                "ans1": "perfectly elastic   ",
                "ans2": "partially elastic   ",
                "ans3": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "ans4": "partially inelastic",
                "question_text": "When a body collides with other body, it sticks completely. The collision is",
                "correct_ans": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18899": {
                "ans1": "P_1",
                "ans2": "P_1",
                "ans3": "P_1",
                "ans4": "P_1",
                "question_text": "Three resistors are connected in series such that R_1=2R_2=3R_3. If the circuit is connected to supply mains of 220 V, then power consumed will be",
                "correct_ans": "P_1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15307": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11405": {
                "ans1": "1836:1   ",
                "ans2": "(1836)^2:1",
                "ans3": "43:1   ",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated by same kinetic energy. The ratio of associated de-Broglie wavelength is nearly equal to",
                "correct_ans": "43:1   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11650": {
                "ans1": "linear momentum   ",
                "ans2": "force",
                "ans3": "work",
                "ans4": "moment",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is same as impulse?",
                "correct_ans": "linear momentum   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12491": {
                "ans1": "double",
                "ans2": "half",
                "ans3": "one-fourth   ",
                "ans4": "remains same",
                "question_text": "The intensity of incident photons is doubled the kinetic energy of emitted electron will be",
                "correct_ans": "remains same",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14614": {
                "ans1": "nature of the gas",
                "ans2": "magnitude of gas",
                "ans3": "atmospheric pressure",
                "ans4": "quantity of gas",
                "question_text": "According to Boyle's law\u00a0PV =c temperature. The magnitude of\u00a0c\u00a0depends on",
                "correct_ans": "quantity of gas",
                "explanation": "PV=nRTn = \\dfrac{m}{M}Also,\u00a0PV = cTherefore,\u00a0c\u00a0depend upon mass and its temperature.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16628": {
                "ans1": "12 N",
                "ans2": "18 N",
                "ans3": "45 N",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 2kg is attached to one end of string of length 1m and rotated in vertical circle such that velocity at highest point is 4m/s. Here tension is",
                "correct_ans": "12 N",
                "explanation": "We know, in circular motion tension.\u00a0T=\\dfrac{mv^2}{r}+mgcos\\theta\\\\T=\\dfrac{mv^2}{r}+mgcos180\\circ\n\n\\\\T= \\frac{mv^2}{r}-mg\n\n\\\\T=\\dfrac{2\\times4^2}{1}-2 \\times 10\n\n\\\\T=32-20 =12N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14186": {
                "ans1": "23/6",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "3/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a23/6",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{2},\\dfrac{1}{3},n) are direction cosines of a line then n=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a23/6",
                "explanation": "sum of their square = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19566": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "11",
                "ans4": "13",
                "question_text": "A bullet loses\u00a0\\dfrac{1}{20}\u00a0of its velocity after penetrating a plank. How many planks are required to stop the bullet ?",
                "correct_ans": "11",
                "explanation": "Let u be the speed of the bullet incident on the first plank. Its speed after passing the first plank\u00a0= u \u2013 \\frac{u}{20} = \\frac{19u}{20}\\\\If x is the thickness of the plank, then using the relation\u00a0v^{2} = u^{2} = 2as we have\\\\\\left( \\dfrac{19u}{20} \\right) ^{2} - u^{2} = 2ax\\\\or,\u00a02 a x = - \\dfrac{39}{400} u^2\\\\Suppose the bullet is stopped after passing through planks. Then distance covered by bullet = nx\\\\Now ,\u00a00 - u^{2} = 2 anx\\\\or,\u00a0n = - \\dfrac{u^{2}}{2ax} = \\dfrac{400}{39} = 10 .3n\\\\No . of planks required = 11",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18224": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3V}{K+2}",
                "ans2": "V/K",
                "ans3": "KV",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Two capacitors C and 2C are connected in parallel and charged with V volt each . Battery is disconnected and then a dielectric of constant K is inserted in C . Find the final p.d\u00a0of each capacitor",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{3V}{K+2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19620": {
                "ans1": "19%",
                "ans2": "91%",
                "ans3": "81%",
                "ans4": "18%",
                "question_text": "The intensity of sound gets reduced by 10%\u00a0on passing through a block. If it passes through two such blocks, then intensity of the outgoing sound is:",
                "correct_ans": "81%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13776": {
                "ans1": "6\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans2": "2\\;\\times10^{-6}m/s",
                "ans3": "6\\;\\times10^{-6}m/s",
                "ans4": "2\\;\\times10^{-8}m/s",
                "question_text": "The critical bright fringe of the interference pattern produced by light of wavelength\u00a06000 A^{\\circ} is shifted to the introducing a thin glass plate of refractive index 1.5 . Then the thickness of the glass plate is",
                "correct_ans": "6\\;\\times10^{-6}m/s",
                "explanation": "(\u03bc\u22121)t=n\u03bb(1.5\u22121)t=5\u00d76000\u00d710^\u2212100.5\u00d7t=3\u00d710^\u22126t=6\u00d710^\u22126\u00a0m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10335": {
                "ans1": "30 cm",
                "ans2": "60 cm",
                "ans3": "50 cm",
                "ans4": "70 cm",
                "question_text": "A source of sound produces waves of\u00a0\u03bb=40\u00a0cm in air. It is moving with a velocity one \u2013 fourth the velocity of sound towards east. The apparent wavelength noted by a man is opposite direction is",
                "correct_ans": "50 cm",
                "explanation": "N\u2032=\u200b\u200b\\dfrac v{v+vo}\u00d7n\\\\So,\u00a0\\lambda^{\\prime}=\\dfrac{v+v_s}{v}\\times\\lambda\\\\=\\dfrac{v+\\dfrac{v}{4}}{4}\\times40=50cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13777": {
                "ans1": "25 Hz",
                "ans2": "50 Hz",
                "ans3": "75 Hz",
                "ans4": "100 Hz",
                "question_text": "In the half wave rectifier circuit operating from 50 Hz, mains frequency, the fundamental frequency inn the ripple would be:",
                "correct_ans": "50 Hz",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15773": {
                "ans1": "5g",
                "ans2": "4g",
                "ans3": "2g",
                "ans4": "3g",
                "question_text": "A vessel has\u00a06 g\u00a0of oxygen at pressure\u00a0P\u00a0and temperature\u00a0400 K. A small hole is made in it so that oxygen leaks out if the final pressure is\u00a0P / 2\u00a0and temperature\u00a0300 K\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "2g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11307": {
                "ans1": "S_1=S_2",
                "ans2": "S_1>S_2"
            },
            "11355": {
                "ans1": "5 mm",
                "ans2": "4.2 mm",
                "ans3": "2.8 mm",
                "ans4": "1.4 mm",
                "question_text": "A square aluminum rod is 1 m long and 5 mm on edge. What must be the radius of another aluminum rod whose length is 1 m and which has the same resistance as the previous rod",
                "correct_ans": "2.8 mm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13885": {
                "ans1": "Paramagnetic",
                "ans2": "diamagnetic",
                "ans3": "ferro magnetic",
                "ans4": "ferri magnetic substance",
                "question_text": "The magnetic susceptibility is negative for .......... is inependent of temperature.",
                "correct_ans": "diamagnetic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18934": {
                "ans1": "transverse",
                "ans2": "geometrical",
                "ans3": "longitudinal",
                "ans4": "both transverse and longitudinal",
                "question_text": "Polarisation phenomenon explains which nature of light?",
                "correct_ans": "transverse",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11645": {
                "ans1": "\\lbrack ML^{-1}T^{-1}\\rbrack",
                "ans2": "\\lbrack ML^{-2}T^{-1}\\rbrack",
                "ans3": "\\lbrack ML^{2}T^{-3}\\rbrack",
                "ans4": "\\lbrack ML^{3}T^{-3}\\rbrack",
                "question_text": "The dimensional formula for coefficient of viscosity is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\lbrack ML^{-1}T^{-1}\\rbrack",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17565": {
                "ans1": " Decreasing the density of the liquid",
                "ans2": "Increasing the temperature of the liquid",
                "ans3": "Decreasing the contact angle between the gaseous and the plate",
                "ans4": "Raising the surface tension of water",
                "question_text": "Detergents in hot water enable grease to be removed from plates by",
                "correct_ans": "Decreasing the contact angle between the gaseous and the plate",
                "explanation": "Detergent may increase or decrease surface tension of liquid depending upon its nature. If detergents are fairly soluble, it increases surface tension but if detergent is not soluble, it decreases surface tension of liquid.\\\\In hot water, temperature is raised which decreases angle of contact. So, grease easily removed after adding detergent in hot water.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17646": {
                "ans1": "3\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans2": "2\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans3": "1.5\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans4": "4\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "question_text": "Refractive index of glass with respect to air is 1.5 , What is velocity of light in the material ?",
                "correct_ans": "2\\;\\times10^8m/s",
                "explanation": "\u00a0v=\\dfrac{c}{\\mu}=\\dfrac{3 \\times 10^8}{1.5}=2 \\times 10^8 \\dfrac{m}{s}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10542": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decrease",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "depend on material",
                "question_text": "When the temperature of black body is increased, the wavelength of radiation corresponding to the maximum intensity of radiation.",
                "correct_ans": "decrease",
                "explanation": "on increasing temperature wavelength decreases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15437": {
                "ans1": " both spheres will expand equally",
                "ans2": "hollow sphere will expand more than solid one",
                "ans3": "solid sphere will expand more than hollow one",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of the same size are made of the same metal but one is hollow and the other is solid. They are heated to the same temperature, then",
                "correct_ans": "solid sphere will expand more than hollow one",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\Delta V=V\\gamma\\Delta\\theta\\;\\\\\\;Expansion\\;depends\\;on\\;dimension,\\;nature\\;of\\;mater\\;and\\;change\\;in\\;temperature\\;which\\;remain\\;cons\\tan t..\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19225": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{r_1}{r_2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{r_2}{r_1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{r_1^2}{r_2^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{r_2^2}{r_1^2}",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of radii\u00a0r_1 \u00a0and\u00a0 r_2\u00a0are at same electric potential then ratio of their surface charge densities is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{r_2}{r_1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18063": {
                "ans1": "velocity",
                "ans2": "acceleration",
                "ans3": "centripetal force",
                "ans4": "kinetic energy",
                "question_text": "When a body is moving with constant speed in a horizontal circle. The quantity that remain constant is",
                "correct_ans": "kinetic energy",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14407": {
                "ans1": "5\u03a9",
                "ans2": "15\u03a9",
                "ans3": "30\u03a9",
                "ans4": "45\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of resistance 5\u03a9\u00a0is drawn out so that its new length is 3 times its original lengh then new resistance is",
                "correct_ans": "45\u03a9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{R'}R=\\left(\\frac{3l}l\\right)^2\\\\R'=9\\ast5=45\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12165": {
                "ans1": " both cannot be zero",
                "ans2": "one of the two may be zero",
                "ans3": "if one of the two may be zero",
                "ans4": "if one is positive, one other is negative and vice versa",
                "question_text": "The location of a particle has changed. What can we go about the displacement and the distance covered by the particle?",
                "correct_ans": "one of the two may be zero",
                "explanation": "Location of particles changes means distance and displacement both will not e zero.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10465": {
                "ans1": "\u03bb/4",
                "ans2": "\u03bb/2",
                "ans3": "3\u03bb/4",
                "ans4": "\u03bb",
                "question_text": "Minimum distance between two particles in a wave motion vibrating out of phase is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03bb/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18377": {
                "ans1": "remains unchanged",
                "ans2": "Increases ",
                "ans3": "decreases",
                "ans4": "decreases upto latitude of 45\u00b0",
                "question_text": "As we go from the equator tot eh poles, the value of g",
                "correct_ans": "Increases ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}g'=g-R\\omega2cos2\\theta\\\\As\\;we\\;go\\;from\\;equator\\;to\\;pole\\;\\theta\\;increases\\;so\\;value\\;of\\;g\\;also\\;increase.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15816": {
                "ans1": "960 m/s",
                "ans2": "640 m/s",
                "ans3": "480 m/s",
                "ans4": "384 m/s",
                "question_text": "The rms speed of hydrogen molecule at 300K\u00a0is 1920 m/s. The rms speed of oxygen molecule will be",
                "correct_ans": "480 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{C_{O\\_rms}}{C_{H\\_rms}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{M_H}{M_O}}\\;\\\\C_{O\\_rms}=1920\\sqrt{\\frac2{32}}=480m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12687": {
                "ans1": "minimum strain",
                "ans2": "maximum displacement",
                "ans3": "minimum density",
                "ans4": "maximum strain",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In stationary wave, node is the point having",
                "correct_ans": "maximum strain",
                "explanation": "Node are point where particle have minimum displacement so pressure will e maximum. i.e. strain will be maximum.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14001": {
                "ans1": "refraction and absorption",
                "ans2": " dispersion and total internal reflection",
                "ans3": "dispersion and focusing",
                "ans4": "refraction and scattering",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Rainbow is formed due to a combination of",
                "correct_ans": " dispersion and total internal reflection",
                "explanation": "Rainbow is due to dispersion of light in which total internal reflection also takes place.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18964": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "ans2": "nh",
                "ans3": "\\frac{h}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{n^2h}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "question_text": "Angular momentum of electron in\u00a0n^{th} orbit is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "explanation": "L=mvr=\\frac{nh}{2\\mathrm\\pi}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10023": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remains consatnt",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease depending upon the nature of liquid",
                "question_text": "Surface tension of liquid with increase of temperature is",
                "correct_ans": "decreases",
                "explanation": "Surface tension is due to inter molecuar force of attraction which decreases with increase in temperature",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17741": {
                "ans1": "decreases",
                "ans2": "increases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "none of the above",
                "question_text": "A dielectric is introduced between the elements of the condenser kept at a constant potential difference. Then the charge on condenser",
                "correct_ans": "remain same",
                "explanation": "When dielectric slab is introduced then C increases at constant V so Q = CV, increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18086": {
                "ans1": "0.1 V",
                "ans2": "0.15 V",
                "ans3": "0.015 V",
                "ans4": "0.0075 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The voltage across collector resistance 2k\u03a9 is 2V. The amplification factor of transistor is 200 and base resistance is 1.5k\u03a9 then input voltage will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.0075 V",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10337": {
                "ans1": "short range",
                "ans2": "always attractive",
                "ans3": "charge independent",
                "ans4": "all of above",
                "question_text": "Nuclear force is a\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "all of above",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16092": {
                "ans1": "temperature will decrease",
                "ans2": "volume will remain constant",
                "ans3": "minimum density",
                "ans4": "maximum strain",
                "question_text": "In a given process on an ideal gas, dw = 0 and dQ < 0. Then for the gas",
                "correct_ans": "temperature will decrease",
                "explanation": "We know,dQ = du + dwwhen dw = 0, du < 0i.e. internal energy decrease, so temperature will decrease.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11251": {
                "ans1": "L",
                "ans2": "L\\frac{\\alpha_s}{\\alpha_r}",
                "ans3": "L\\frac{\\alpha_r}{\\alpha_s}",
                "ans4": "L\\frac{1+\\alpha_s}{1+\\alpha_r}",
                "question_text": "A steel scale measure the length of rod at 20\u00b0c is L. If scale is correct at 20\u00b0c then reading of scale at 21\u00b0c if\u00a0\u03b1_s\u200b\u00a0and\u00a0\u03b1_r be the linear exapansivity of scale & rod respectively",
                "correct_ans": "L\\frac{1+\\alpha_s}{1+\\alpha_r}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18735": {
                "ans1": " l, d",
                "ans2": "2l, d",
                "ans3": "l/2, d",
                "ans4": "2l, d/2",
                "question_text": "A piece of copper is shaped into a conductor of minimum resistance. Its length and diameter should be",
                "correct_ans": "l/2, d",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10332": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{u-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{v-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac{v-f}f\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac{u-f}u\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "Length of a body is L. It is kept at a distance u from concave mirror of focal length 'f' then length of image will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}L\\left(\\frac f{u-f}\\right)\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}use\\;the\\;relation\\\\m=\\frac IO=\\frac vu\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10579": {
                "ans1": "It's energy levels are too close to each other",
                "ans2": " It's energy levels are too far to eachother",
                "ans3": "It is too small",
                "ans4": "It has single electron",
                "question_text": "Hydrogen atom does not emit X-ray because",
                "correct_ans": "It's energy levels are too close to each other",
                "explanation": "To emit X-ray the difference between two energy level must lie in X-ray region",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14510": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "10",
                "ans3": "12",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "A number of 110 V lamps connected in parallel are fed by a 130 V battery having an internal resistance of 2.6 \u03a9. If the resistance of each lamp is 200 \u03a9\u00a0& resistance of wire is 0.4 \u03a9, the number of lamps are",
                "correct_ans": "12",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14293": {
                "ans1": " decrease",
                "ans2": " increase",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "become uncertain",
                "question_text": "A source of sound and the observer are moving away from each other. The appearance pitch will",
                "correct_ans": " decrease",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17484": {
                "ans1": "n^\\gamma p",
                "ans2": "n^{-\\gamma}p",
                "ans3": "n^{\\gamma-1}p",
                "ans4": "n^{1-\\gamma}p",
                "question_text": "An ideal gas at pressure p is compressed suddenly so the density of gas become n times the initial value. The final pressure of gas will be",
                "correct_ans": "n^\\gamma p",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16451": {
                "ans1": "2(\\rho_1\u200b+\\rho_2\\;)",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{\\rho_1\\rho_2\\;}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;}2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "Two wires of same dimensions but resistivities\u00a0\u00a0\u03c1_1\u200b\u00a0and     \u00a0\u00a0\u03c1_2\u200b\u00a0 are connected in series. The equivalent resistivity of combination is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\rho_1+\\rho_2\\;}2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "use R=\u03c1l/A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19533": {
                "ans1": "2mv",
                "ans2": "\\frac{mv}2",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{mv}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt2mv",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A projectile of mass 'm' is fired with velocity v at an angle 45\u00b0\u00a0with horizontal. The magnitude of change in momentum when projectile arrived on the surface of the earth is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt2mv",
                "explanation": "\u0394P=mvsin45\u2212(\u2212mvsin45)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14031": {
                "ans1": " First law of motion",
                "ans2": "Second law of motion",
                "ans3": "Third law of motion",
                "ans4": "both a and b",
                "question_text": "The real law of motion is:",
                "correct_ans": "Second law of motion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17747": {
                "ans1": "0.012mA",
                "ans2": " 0.12 mA",
                "ans3": "0.24mA",
                "ans4": "1.2mA",
                "question_text": "The current gain for a common emitter amplifier is 49. If the emitter current is 6mA then base current is",
                "correct_ans": " 0.12 mA",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13668": {
                "ans1": "solid sphere",
                "ans2": "hollow sphere",
                "ans3": "both simultaneously",
                "ans4": "depends on mass of sphere",
                "question_text": "A solid sphere and hollow sphere rolls down an inclined plane without slipping. Which sphere will reach the bottom earlier?",
                "correct_ans": "hollow sphere",
                "explanation": "Here k for solid sphere is less than hollow sphere so 'a' for solid sphere is greater than hollow sphere. Hence solid sphere will reach at bottom faster.\\begin{array}{l}\\alpha=\\frac{g\\;\\sin\\theta}{1+{\\displaystyle\\frac{k^2}{r^2}}}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19793": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_1+V_2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{V_1}{V_1+V_2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_1}",
                "question_text": "Air filled parallel plate capacitor is charged to potential\u00a0V_1\u200b\u00a0is connected to an unchanged identical parallel plate capacitor of dielectric conslant k then common potential become\u00a0V_2\u200b. The value of K is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{V_1-V_2}{V_2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12254": {
                "ans1": "MLT^{-2}",
                "ans2": "MLT^{-1}",
                "ans3": "MLT",
                "ans4": "ML^2T^{-2}",
                "question_text": "The dimensional formula of force is:",
                "correct_ans": "MLT^{-2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14596": {
                "ans1": "it gets accelerated",
                "ans2": "it gets retarded",
                "ans3": " it moves with constant speed",
                "ans4": "its path becomes parabolic",
                "question_text": "An electron moving with a finite velocity enters in an electric held parallel to lines of force, then",
                "correct_ans": "it gets retarded",
                "explanation": "Force on electron act in opposite direction of field so they decelerate.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14615": {
                "ans1": "546\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "819\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "273\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "1092\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "The temperature at which velocity of sound become double of 0\u00b0C is.",
                "correct_ans": "819\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11970": {
                "ans1": "(n+1)G",
                "ans2": "\\frac G{(n-1)}",
                "ans3": "(n\u22121)G",
                "ans4": "G/n",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter can measure volt 'V' has resistance 'G' then it can be changed into a voltmeter, measuring upto nV then resistance series is",
                "correct_ans": "(n\u22121)G",
                "explanation": "G+R=nG\u00a0or,\u00a0R=(n-1)G",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18666": {
                "ans1": "P",
                "ans2": "2P",
                "ans3": "P/2",
                "ans4": "4P",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two gases A and B having same pressure\u00a0P, volume\u00a0V\u00a0and absolute temperature\u00a0T\u00a0are mixed. If the mixture has the volume\u00a0V\u00a0and temperature\u00a0T\u00a0then pressure of mixture will be",
                "correct_ans": "2P",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17297": {
                "ans1": "12\u03a9",
                "ans2": "3\u03a9",
                "ans3": "6\u03a9",
                "ans4": "2.25\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of 12\u03a9\u00a0is bent into form of circle . The equivalent resistance across any one quarter of its length is:",
                "correct_ans": "2.25\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16963": {
                "ans1": " Interference",
                "ans2": " Diffraction",
                "ans3": "Polarization",
                "ans4": "Total internal reflection",
                "question_text": "Air bubble shines brightly in air because of the phenomenon of",
                "correct_ans": "Total internal reflection",
                "explanation": "Water is denser than air, so total internal reflection is the accounting factor for this phenomenon.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17458": {
                "ans1": "500",
                "ans2": "700",
                "ans3": "1000",
                "ans4": "1400",
                "question_text": "In common emitter amplifier , it has current gain\u00a070. The load resistance is 5k\u03a9\u00a0and input resistance is 500\u03a9\u00a0then voltage gain is:",
                "correct_ans": "700",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19222": {
                "ans1": "Amplitude",
                "ans2": "Wavelength",
                "ans3": "Quality",
                "ans4": "frequency",
                "question_text": "Loudness of note increases with increase in:",
                "correct_ans": "Amplitude",
                "explanation": "\u00a0I \\propto a^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17339": {
                "ans1": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "ans2": "Backward in both wheel",
                "ans3": "Forward in both wheel",
                "ans4": "Forward in front wheel and backward in rear wheel",
                "question_text": "What is the direction of friction in the wheels of by-cycle when the cycle is pedaled?",
                "correct_ans": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "explanation": "This is because, the rear wheel is constantly being rotated by a external force and hence it must exert forward friction on ground to keep moving, but front wheel is being rotated due to friction of ground which is backward in direction at the lowermost tip of tyre of front wheel.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12788": {
                "ans1": "IS",
                "ans2": "I/S",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac IS}",
                "ans4": "\\left(\\frac IS\\right)^2",
                "question_text": "A straight conductor of uniform cross section carries a current of\u00a0I.\u00a0S\u00a0be the specific charge of an electron then momentum of all the free electrons per unit length of conductor due to their drift velocity only is:",
                "correct_ans": "I/S",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11119": {
                "ans1": " 25 \u00b0",
                "ans2": "28\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "64.8\u00b0",
                "question_text": "If the polarizing angle of diamond is \u00a067^O, then critical angle for diamond is:",
                "correct_ans": " 25 \u00b0",
                "explanation": "\u03bc=tanip\u200b=tan67 c = \\sin^-1(\\dfrac{1}{\\mu}) = 25.1^{\\circ}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19493": {
                "ans1": "Q/8",
                "ans2": "Q/24",
                "ans3": "Q",
                "ans4": "There no net flux through the cube because the charge loses its property",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Electric flux through the side of a cube where a small point charge Q is placed at one of its corner is:",
                "correct_ans": "Q/24",
                "explanation": "We have the net flux through whole cube will beQ/8\u200b\u00a0due to charge at corner.\u00a0\\dfrac{Q}{24}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18182": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1 < \u03b2 always",
                "ans2": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A=B",
                "ans3": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A>B"
            },
            "17032": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{eht}E",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-mh}{eEt^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{-h}{eE}",
                "question_text": "An electron of mass\u00a0'm' and charge\u00a0e\u00a0initially at rest gets accelerated by electric field\u00a0E. The rate of change in de-Broglie wavelength of electron at time\u00a0\u2032t\u2032\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11054": {
                "ans1": "Taller than actual",
                "ans2": "Shorter than actual",
                "ans3": "Same",
                "ans4": "depends on depth of pond",
                "question_text": "When a person inside pond see tree on the side of pond, then tree will apper:",
                "correct_ans": "Taller than actual",
                "explanation": "Object in rarer medium is seen from denser medium, then it appears taller than its actual height. This is converse for shift in medium.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17862": {
                "ans1": "2K",
                "ans2": "K/2",
                "ans3": "K",
                "ans4": "3K/2",
                "question_text": "A spring of force constant\u00a0KK\u00a0is divided into two pieces. The force constant of the individual pieces is",
                "correct_ans": "2K",
                "explanation": "\u00a0Force Constant K\u221d1/length",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15340": {
                "ans1": "18%",
                "ans2": "36%",
                "ans3": "20%",
                "ans4": "64%",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The tension in a stretched vibrating wire is decreased by 36%, then frequency of vibration is decreased by:",
                "correct_ans": "20%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12408": {
                "ans1": "m",
                "ans2": "m/5",
                "ans3": "5m",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "A magnet of pole strength\u00a0'm' is cut into\u00a05\u00a0equal parts along perpendicular to its length. The pole strength of each piece will be:",
                "correct_ans": "m",
                "explanation": "Pole strength \u221d\u00a0Cross sectional area.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12290": {
                "ans1": "Penetration power increases",
                "ans2": "peneteration power decreases",
                "ans3": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "ans4": " intensity of x-ray decreases",
                "question_text": "When current in filament increases then during production of x-ray;",
                "correct_ans": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "explanation": "Intensity of x-ray increases on increasing current through the filament.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17443": {
                "ans1": "Less than 0.1 N",
                "ans2": "More than 0.1 N",
                "ans3": "0.1N",
                "ans4": "less\\;than\\;0.1N\\;if\\;Q_1\\;and\\;Q_2\\;are\\;different\\;in\\;nature",
                "question_text": "Two charges\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0   Q_2repel each other with force of 0.1 N. The force exerted by\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0Q_2\u200b\u00a0when a third charge is placed near them :",
                "correct_ans": "0.1N",
                "explanation": "Force between two charges is always same independent of other charges in their periphery",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11684": {
                "ans1": "C/2   ",
                "ans2": "C ",
                "ans3": "2C",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance of \u2018C\u2019. If half separation between the plate is covered with metal sheet, new capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "2C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15994": {
                "ans1": "ML^{-1}T^{-2}",
                "ans2": "MLT^{-2}",
                "ans3": "ML^{-1}T^{-1}",
                "ans4": "ML^{-1}T^{2}",
                "question_text": "The dimension of modulus of rigidity is",
                "correct_ans": "ML^{-1}T^{-2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11499": {
                "ans1": "double",
                "ans2": "half",
                "ans3": "one-fourth   ",
                "ans4": "remains same",
                "question_text": "The intensity of incident photons is doubled the kinetic energy of emitted electron will be",
                "correct_ans": "remains same",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12157": {
                "ans1": "1836:1   ",
                "ans2": "(1836)^2:1",
                "ans3": "43:1   ",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated by same kinetic energy. The ratio of associated de-Broglie wavelength is nearly equal to",
                "correct_ans": "43:1   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11673": {
                "ans1": "transverse progressive       ",
                "ans2": "transverse stationary",
                "ans3": "longitudinal progressive      ",
                "ans4": "longitudinal stationary",
                "question_text": "Waves in organ pipe are",
                "correct_ans": "longitudinal stationary",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14438": {
                "ans1": "{}_{82}U^{212}",
                "ans2": "{}_{76}U^{206}",
                "ans3": "{}_{76}U^{212}",
                "ans4": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "question_text": "A particle {}_{92}U^{238} after undergoing 8 alpha decay and 6 beta decay gives",
                "correct_ans": "{}_{82}U^{206}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19460": {
                "ans1": "10 mA   ",
                "ans2": "10 A    ",
                "ans3": "1 mA    ",
                "ans4": "1 A",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter reads 80 V and has resistance per volt of 100 \\Omega. The current through voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "10 mA   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19121": {
                "ans1": "perfectly elastic   ",
                "ans2": "partially elastic   ",
                "ans3": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "ans4": "partially inelastic",
                "question_text": "When a body collides with other body, it sticks completely. The collision is",
                "correct_ans": "perfectly inelastic  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19198": {
                "ans1": "P_1= P_2= P_3   ",
                "ans2": "P_1=4 P_2=16P_3",
                "ans3": "P_1=2P_2=3P_3",
                "ans4": "P_1=2P_2=4P_3",
                "question_text": "Three resistors are connected in series such that R_1=2R_2=3R_3. If the circuit is connected to supply mains of 220 V, then power consumed will be",
                "correct_ans": "P_1=2P_2=3P_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14256": {
                "ans1": "linear momentum   ",
                "ans2": "force ",
                "ans3": "work",
                "ans4": "moment",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is same as impulse?",
                "correct_ans": "linear momentum   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16787": {
                "ans1": "free electron    ",
                "ans2": "holes  ",
                "ans3": "bound electrons   ",
                "ans4": "both (a) and (c) ",
                "question_text": "Majority\u00a0 charge carriers in n-type semiconductor are",
                "correct_ans": "free electron    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15002": {
                "ans1": "0.21 ns   ",
                "ans2": "0.21  ms     ",
                "ans3": "0.47 ns    ",
                "ans4": "0.47 ms   ",
                "question_text": "Time taken by sun light to pass through a block 9.5 cm thick having refractive index 1.5 is",
                "correct_ans": "0.47 ns    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15962": {
                "ans1": "Newton\u2019s law of gravitation    ",
                "ans2": "Hooke\u2019s law    ",
                "ans3": "Poiseulle\u2019s law   ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "question_text": "Millikan\u2019s oil drop experiment is based on principle of",
                "correct_ans": "Stoke\u2019s law",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18375": {
                "ans1": "0.1",
                "ans2": "0.2",
                "ans3": "0.8",
                "ans4": "1.6",
                "question_text": "Two bodies of same temperature and same surface area have their radiation ratio of 1:2. If body \u2018A\u2019 has emissivity of 0.4, the emissivity of body \u2018B\u2019 will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15296": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16434": {
                "ans1": "-0.64J   ",
                "ans2": "0.65J    ",
                "ans3": "-0.064J    ",
                "ans4": "0.064J",
                "question_text": "A short bar magnet of magnetic moment 0.4 Am^2 is placed in a uniform magnetic field of 0.16T. The magnetic is in stable equilibrium when the potential energy is",
                "correct_ans": "-0.064J    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18382": {
                "ans1": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "ans2": "Newton\u2019s law of viscosity   ",
                "ans3": "Ohm\u2019s law  ",
                "ans4": "Stoke\u2019s  law",
                "question_text": "A body oscillating in simple harmonic motion follows",
                "correct_ans": "Hooke\u2019s law   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18905": {
                "ans1": "4 eV",
                "ans2": "3.1 eV",
                "ans3": "2.5 eV",
                "ans4": "6 eV",
                "question_text": "The maximum wavelength for photoelectrons from a metal is 4000 \u212b. The work function of\u00a0 metal is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3.1 eV",
                "explanation": "W=\\frac{hc}{\\lambda} = \\frac{6.66*10^{-34}*3*10^8}{4000*10^{-10}} * \\frac{1}{1.6*10^{-19}} =3.1 eV",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15477": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{v^2}{2\u03bcsg}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{v^2}{\u03bcsg}",
                "ans3": "(\\frac{v}{\u03bcsg})^2",
                "ans4": "\\frac{v^2}{\u03bcs}",
                "question_text": "A car is moving along a level road with speed 'v' . if the coefficient of static friction between the tyres and the road is\u00a0\\mu_s\u00a0, the shortest distance in which the car can be stopped is :",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{v^2}{2\u03bcsg}",
                "explanation": "\\frac{1}{2}mv^2 = -fs = -umgs\\frac{v^2}{2\\mu_sg}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18884": {
                "ans1": "\\propto p",
                "ans2": "\\propto p^2 ",
                "ans3": "\\propto \\sqrt{P} ",
                "ans4": "V is independent of P",
                "question_text": "How does the speed v of sound in air depends on atmospheric pressure at constant temperature?",
                "correct_ans": "V is independent of P",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19036": {
                "ans1": "both cool at same rate",
                "ans2": "The cube cool down faster than sphere",
                "ans3": "the sphere cool down faster than cube",
                "ans4": "whichever is having more mass cool down faster",
                "question_text": "A cube and sphere of same material have equal surface areas , both are at the same temperature 120^oC then",
                "correct_ans": "The cube cool down faster than sphere",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17150": {
                "ans1": "interference of light",
                "ans2": "dispersion of light",
                "ans3": "scattering of light",
                "ans4": "selective absorption of light",
                "question_text": "The colors of thin films result due to\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "interference of light",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17524": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "1/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If the kinetic energy of a free electons doubles , its de-Broglie wavelength changes by\u00a0the factor",
                "correct_ans": "1/\u221a2",
                "explanation": "\\lambda = \\frac{h}{mv} = \\frac{h}{\\sqrt(2mE_k)}\\lambda' = \\frac{h}{\\sqrt(2m2E_k)}=-\\frac{\\gamma}{\\sqrt(2)}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10751": {
                "ans1": "Hyperbola",
                "ans2": "Circle",
                "ans3": "Straight line",
                "ans4": "Parabola",
                "question_text": "A young's double slit experiment uses a monochomatic source . The shape of the interference fringes formed on a screen is",
                "correct_ans": "Straight line",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12732": {
                "ans1": "doubled",
                "ans2": "less than double",
                "ans3": "more than doubled",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "If the frequency of light incident on metal surface is doubled then kinetic energy of emitted electrons will becomes",
                "correct_ans": "more than doubled",
                "explanation": "E_o = hf_o -w_o2hf_o - w_o = 2hf_o - 2w_o + w_o2(hf_o - w_o) +w_o = 2E_o+w_o\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17273": {
                "ans1": "0 degree",
                "ans2": "60 degree",
                "ans3": "30 degree",
                "ans4": "90 degree",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{A}.\\overrightarrow{B} = \\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}AB\u00a0 , the angle between vectors A and B must be",
                "correct_ans": "30 degree",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow{A}.\\overrightarrow{B} = \\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}AB\\cos\\theta = \\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}AB\\cos\\theta = \\frac{\\sqrt3}{2}\\theta = 30^o",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14810": {
                "ans1": "body is at rest",
                "ans2": "body is in motion",
                "ans3": "acceleration is not zero",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "The net force on a body is zero then the wrong statement is",
                "correct_ans": "acceleration is not zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18070": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{n^2}1",
                "ans2": "1:n",
                "ans3": "n",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{n^2}",
                "question_text": "n equal capacitor are first connected in series and then in parallel. the ration of maximum and minimum capacitance is :",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{n^2}1",
                "explanation": "\\frac{C_{max}}{C_{min}} =\\frac{nC}{C/n}=n^2:1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10813": {
                "ans1": "attract each other",
                "ans2": "repel each other",
                "ans3": "first attract and then repel",
                "ans4": "neither attract nor repel",
                "question_text": "Two parallel beams of protons are moving in the same direction , then they\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "repel each other",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10959": {
                "ans1": "attraction",
                "ans2": "repulsion",
                "ans3": "friction",
                "ans4": "induction",
                "question_text": "A sure test of electrification is",
                "correct_ans": "repulsion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13837": {
                "ans1": "V_d\u221dE^2",
                "ans2": "V_d\u221dE^{1/2}",
                "ans3": "V_d\u221dE^0",
                "ans4": "V_d\u221dE",
                "question_text": "For which of the following dependences of drift velocity\u00a0V_d\u00a0on electric field E is the ohm's law obeyed ?",
                "correct_ans": "V_d\u221dE",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11671": {
                "ans1": "doubled",
                "ans2": "four times",
                "ans3": "one fourth",
                "ans4": "halved",
                "question_text": "A heater coil is cut into two equal parts and only one part is now used in the heater , The heat generated will now be",
                "correct_ans": "doubled",
                "explanation": "H_o = I^2R_ot = \\frac{V_o^2t}{R_o}\\frac{V_o^2}{R}t = \\frac{V_o}{R_o/2}t = 2H_o",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13468": {
                "ans1": "800m",
                "ans2": "1000m",
                "ans3": "100m",
                "ans4": "400m",
                "question_text": "A car is moing on a straight road with a speed of 100m/sec. The distance at which car can be stopped is (\\mu_k = 0.5)",
                "correct_ans": "1000m",
                "explanation": "\\frac{1}{2}mv^2 = -fs = -\\mu mgss=\\frac{1}{2}\\frac{v^2}{\\mu g} = \\frac{1}{2}*\\frac{100*100}{0.5*10} = 1000m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19138": {
                "ans1": "electrons",
                "ans2": "protons",
                "ans3": "neutrons",
                "ans4": "positevely charged ions",
                "question_text": "Canal rays is the name for the beam of\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "positevely charged ions",
                "explanation": "canal ray is anode ray and anode ray is always electropositive charge ion",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14650": {
                "ans1": "Short Ranged",
                "ans2": "Attractive",
                "ans3": "Both",
                "ans4": "Weak",
                "question_text": "Nuclear forces are :",
                "correct_ans": "Both",
                "explanation": "knowledge based",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19307": {
                "ans1": "Ohm",
                "ans2": "Simen",
                "ans3": "Ohm metre",
                "ans4": "Ohm/metre",
                "question_text": "SI unit of conductance\u00a0is :",
                "correct_ans": "Simen",
                "explanation": "SI unit of conductance\u00a0:^{-1}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19861": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\pi}{2}",
                "ans3": "\\pi",
                "ans4": "\\frac{3\\pi}{2}",
                "question_text": "Two waves of same wavelength and amplitude interface to give a minimum when phase difference is :",
                "correct_ans": "\\pi",
                "explanation": "180^oI=I_1-I_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11018": {
                "ans1": "Increases",
                "ans2": "Decreases",
                "ans3": "Same",
                "ans4": "Cannot be predicted",
                "question_text": "If the current sensitivity of the galvanometer increases, then voltage sensitivity?",
                "correct_ans": "Increases",
                "explanation": "We have\u00a0i_s = \\frac{\\theta}{i}V_s = \\frac{\\theta}{iR}V_s \\alpha i_sHense , Voltage sensitivity increases when current sensitivity increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13935": {
                "ans1": "ML^3T^3A^{-2}",
                "ans2": "ML^2T^{-3}A^{-2}",
                "ans3": "L^3T^{-3}A^{-1}",
                "ans4": "MLT^{-2}A^{-3}",
                "question_text": "The dimension of electrical resistance is :",
                "correct_ans": "ML^2T^{-3}A^{-2}",
                "explanation": "R=\\frac{V}{I}=\\frac{W}{QI}[R]=\\frac{[ML^2T^{-2}]}{[AT][A]}=[ML^2T^{-3}A^{-2}]",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17058": {
                "ans1": "perfectly elastic",
                "ans2": "Perfectly inelastic",
                "ans3": "Partially elastic ",
                "ans4": "Partially plastic",
                "question_text": "When a body collides with another body and sticks completely, the collision is :",
                "correct_ans": "Perfectly inelastic",
                "explanation": "knowledge based\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10224": {
                "ans1": "Pressure alone",
                "ans2": "Volume alone ",
                "ans3": "Temperatue alone",
                "ans4": "Both on pressure as well as temperature",
                "question_text": "The internal energy of a gram molecule of an ideal gas depends on :",
                "correct_ans": "Temperatue alone",
                "explanation": "P.E of ideal gas is neglected.So , total of the internal energy is its KEE=\\frac{3}{2}K_BTThus, internal energy is dependent on temperature alone.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15008": {
                "ans1": "vector",
                "ans2": "scalar",
                "ans3": "Dimensionless",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "Current density is a ................ quantity :",
                "correct_ans": "vector",
                "explanation": "Knowledge based",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12047": {
                "ans1": "Coulomb",
                "ans2": "Coulomb/sec",
                "ans3": "Zero resistance",
                "ans4": "Infinity resistance",
                "question_text": "The unit of current is :",
                "correct_ans": "Coulomb/sec",
                "explanation": "\\frac{Charge}{Time} = \\frac{Coulomb}{Sec}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14675": {
                "ans1": "Two nodes and two antinodes.",
                "ans2": "One node and two antinodes.",
                "ans3": "Four nodes and three antinodes",
                "ans4": "Three nodes and three antinodes.",
                "question_text": "The sonometer wire is vibrating in the second overtone. We may say that there are:",
                "correct_ans": "Four nodes and three antinodes",
                "explanation": "For second overtone , the string vibrates in three segments , Hence there are four nodes and three antinodes.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19078": {
                "ans1": "Am",
                "ans2": "Am^2",
                "ans3": "Tesla",
                "ans4": "Henry",
                "question_text": "Unit of pole strength is :",
                "correct_ans": "Am",
                "explanation": "Knowledge based",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19589": {
                "ans1": "High resistance",
                "ans2": "Low resistance",
                "ans3": "Zero resistance ",
                "ans4": "Infinity resistance",
                "question_text": "A reverse biased PN junction diode offers:",
                "correct_ans": "Infinity resistance",
                "explanation": "A reverse biased pn junction diode acts as an open switch which\u00a0 means that it offers an infinite resistance",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14464": {
                "ans1": "Newton",
                "ans2": "Coulomb",
                "ans3": "Debye",
                "ans4": "Electron volt",
                "question_text": "What is the best system to measure dipole moment ?",
                "correct_ans": "Debye",
                "explanation": "Newton is unit of forceCoulomb is unit of chargeDebye is unit of dipole momentElectron volt is unit of energy",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19978": {
                "ans1": "0.02",
                "ans2": "49",
                "ans3": "0.49",
                "ans4": "2.02",
                "question_text": "If the value of\u00a0\\alpha \u00a0in a transistor is 0.98 , what is the value of\u00a0\\beta\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "49",
                "explanation": "\\frac{1}{\\alpha}-\\frac{1}{\\beta} = 1\\beta = \\frac{\\alpha}{1-\\alpha} = \\frac{0.98}{1-0.98}=49",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11388": {
                "ans1": "is doubled",
                "ans2": "is halved",
                "ans3": "Remains unchanged",
                "ans4": "Becomes four times",
                "question_text": "Coefficient of friction between a body and surface, when another block of the same type is added over the body :",
                "correct_ans": "Remains unchanged",
                "explanation": "Coefficient of friction between the two surfaces is independent of mass added to them.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16064": {
                "ans1": "Temperature difference between two sides",
                "ans2": "Thickness of metal plate",
                "ans3": "Area of plate",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of thermal conductivity of a metal depends on :",
                "correct_ans": "None",
                "explanation": "Coefficient of thermal conductivity depends upon the nature of material .",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10695": {
                "ans1": "Dark",
                "ans2": "Red",
                "ans3": "Violet",
                "ans4": "White",
                "question_text": "A white light is used in Young's double slit. The central fringe is:",
                "correct_ans": "White",
                "explanation": "The interference patterns are due to component colours of white light overlapping (incoherently).The central bright fringes for different colors at the same position. Therefore the central fringe is white.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18876": {
                "ans1": "P",
                "ans2": "2P",
                "ans3": "P/2",
                "ans4": "4P",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two gases A and B having same pressure\u00a0P, volume\u00a0V\u00a0and absolute temperature\u00a0T\u00a0are mixed. If the mixture has the volume\u00a0V\u00a0and temperature\u00a0T\u00a0then pressure of mixture will be",
                "correct_ans": "2P",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10716": {
                "ans1": "12\u03a9",
                "ans2": "3\u03a9",
                "ans3": "6\u03a9",
                "ans4": "2.25\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A wire of 12\u03a9\u00a0is bent into form of circle . The equivalent resistance across any one quarter of its length is:",
                "correct_ans": "2.25\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14884": {
                "ans1": " Interference",
                "ans2": " Diffraction",
                "ans3": "Polarization",
                "ans4": "Total internal reflection",
                "question_text": "Air bubble shines brightly in air because of the phenomenon of",
                "correct_ans": "Total internal reflection",
                "explanation": "Water is denser than air, so total internal reflection is the accounting factor for this phenomenon.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16176": {
                "ans1": "500",
                "ans2": "700",
                "ans3": "1000",
                "ans4": "1400",
                "question_text": "In common emitter amplifier , it has current gain\u00a070. The load resistance is 5k\u03a9\u00a0and input resistance is 500\u03a9\u00a0then voltage gain is:",
                "correct_ans": "700",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12924": {
                "ans1": "Amplitude",
                "ans2": "Wavelength",
                "ans3": "Quality",
                "ans4": "frequency",
                "question_text": "Loudness of note increases with increase in:",
                "correct_ans": "Amplitude",
                "explanation": "\u00a0I \\propto a^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16564": {
                "ans1": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "ans2": "Backward in both wheel",
                "ans3": "Forward in both wheel",
                "ans4": "Forward in front wheel and backward in rear wheel",
                "question_text": "What is the direction of friction in the wheels of by-cycle when the cycle is pedaled?",
                "correct_ans": "Forward in rear wheel and backward in front wheel",
                "explanation": "This is because, the rear wheel is constantly being rotated by a external force and hence it must exert forward friction on ground to keep moving, but front wheel is being rotated due to friction of ground which is backward in direction at the lowermost tip of tyre of front wheel.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13377": {
                "ans1": "IS",
                "ans2": "I/S",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac IS}",
                "ans4": "\\left(\\frac IS\\right)^2",
                "question_text": "A straight conductor of uniform cross section carries a current of\u00a0I.\u00a0S\u00a0be the specific charge of an electron then momentum of all the free electrons per unit length of conductor due to their drift velocity only is:",
                "correct_ans": "I/S",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11299": {
                "ans1": " 25 \u00b0",
                "ans2": "28\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "64.8\u00b0",
                "question_text": "If the polarizing angle of diamond is \u00a067^O, then critical angle for diamond is:",
                "correct_ans": " 25 \u00b0",
                "explanation": "\u03bc=tanip\u200b=tan67 c = \\sin^-1(\\dfrac{1}{\\mu}) = 25.1^{\\circ}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19282": {
                "ans1": "Q/8",
                "ans2": "Q/24",
                "ans3": "Q",
                "ans4": "There no net flux through the cube because the charge loses its property",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Electric flux through the side of a cube where a small point charge Q is placed at one of its corner is:",
                "correct_ans": "Q/24",
                "explanation": "We have the net flux through whole cube will beQ/8\u200b\u00a0due to charge at corner.\u00a0\\dfrac{Q}{24}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18542": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1 < \u03b2 always",
                "ans2": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A=B",
                "ans3": "\u03b1<\u03b2 if A>B"
            },
            "11716": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{eht}E",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-mh}{eEt^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{-h}{eE}",
                "question_text": "An electron of mass\u00a0'm' and charge\u00a0e\u00a0initially at rest gets accelerated by electric field\u00a0E. The rate of change in de-Broglie wavelength of electron at time\u00a0\u2032t\u2032\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-h}{eEt^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12092": {
                "ans1": "Taller than actual",
                "ans2": "Shorter than actual",
                "ans3": "Same",
                "ans4": "depends on depth of pond",
                "question_text": "When a person inside pond see tree on the side of pond, then tree will apper:",
                "correct_ans": "Taller than actual",
                "explanation": "Object in rarer medium is seen from denser medium, then it appears taller than its actual height. This is converse for shift in medium.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18890": {
                "ans1": "2K",
                "ans2": "K/2",
                "ans3": "K",
                "ans4": "3K/2",
                "question_text": "A spring of force constant\u00a0KK\u00a0is divided into two pieces. The force constant of the individual pieces is",
                "correct_ans": "2K",
                "explanation": "\u00a0Force Constant K\u221d1/length",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14235": {
                "ans1": "18%",
                "ans2": "36%",
                "ans3": "20%",
                "ans4": "64%",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The tension in a stretched vibrating wire is decreased by 36%, then frequency of vibration is decreased by:",
                "correct_ans": "20%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11114": {
                "ans1": "m",
                "ans2": "m/5",
                "ans3": "5m",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "A magnet of pole strength\u00a0'm' is cut into\u00a05\u00a0equal parts along perpendicular to its length. The pole strength of each piece will be:",
                "correct_ans": "m",
                "explanation": "Pole strength \u221d\u00a0Cross sectional area.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10486": {
                "ans1": "Penetration power increases",
                "ans2": "peneteration power decreases",
                "ans3": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "ans4": " intensity of x-ray decreases",
                "question_text": "When current in filament increases then during production of x-ray;",
                "correct_ans": "intensity of x-ray increases",
                "explanation": "Intensity of x-ray increases on increasing current through the filament.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15704": {
                "ans1": "Less than 0.1 N",
                "ans2": "More than 0.1 N",
                "ans3": "0.1N",
                "ans4": "less\\;than\\;0.1N\\;if\\;Q_1\\;and\\;Q_2\\;are\\;different\\;in\\;nature",
                "question_text": "Two charges\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0   Q_2repel each other with force of 0.1 N. The force exerted by\u00a0Q_1 and\u00a0Q_2\u200b\u00a0when a third charge is placed near them :",
                "correct_ans": "0.1N",
                "explanation": "Force between two charges is always same independent of other charges in their periphery",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10059": {
                "ans1": "yellow",
                "ans2": "green",
                "ans3": "blue",
                "ans4": "red",
                "question_text": "The deviation of light will be maximum for a prism for",
                "correct_ans": "green",
                "explanation": "As refractive index of red is less than voilet so, red light deviate less",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11713": {
                "ans1": "nature of the surface in contact",
                "ans2": "area of the surface in contact",
                "ans3": "normal reaction  between the surface",
                "ans4": "material of bodies",
                "question_text": "The limiting force of friction between two bodies in contact is independent of",
                "correct_ans": "area of the surface in contact",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19262": {
                "ans1": "decrease",
                "ans2": "increase",
                "ans3": "remain unchanged",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "With increase in temperature , the frequency of the sound in organ pipe\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "increase",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16582": {
                "ans1": "0.16 m/s",
                "ans2": "0.61 m/s",
                "ans3": "0.1 m/s",
                "ans4": "61 m/s",
                "question_text": "The increase in velocity of sound for 1\u00b0C rise in temperature is (V_o=332 m/s)",
                "correct_ans": "0.61 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19084": {
                "ans1": "don't attract at all",
                "ans2": "attact each other",
                "ans3": "repel each other",
                "ans4": "deflect perpendicular to plane of beam",
                "question_text": "Two fast streams of protons move parallel to each other in the same direction, then these\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "attact each other",
                "explanation": "Act as parallel plate conductor carrying current in same direction",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14738": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\frac{m_e}{m_p}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{m_p}{m_e}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "question_text": "An electron and a proton are accelerated through the same potential difference. The ratio of their de Broglie's wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\lambda_c}{\\lambda_p}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac h{\\sqrt{2m_eev}}}{\\frac h{\\sqrt{2m_pev}}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{m_p}{m_e}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16962": {
                "ans1": "\\frac25R",
                "ans2": "\\frac75R",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac25}R",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac75}R",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The radius of gyration of a sphere about a tangent is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{\\frac75}R",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mk^2=\\frac25mR^2\\;+mR^2\\\\or,k=\\sqrt{\\frac75}R\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15844": {
                "ans1": "Decreases slightly",
                "ans2": "Increases slightly",
                "ans3": "Remain same",
                "ans4": "increases considerable",
                "question_text": "Some quantity of tap water is placed in an open pan and allowed to evaporate. After sometime the temperature of water",
                "correct_ans": "Decreases slightly",
                "explanation": "As water evaporates its temperature falls",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16982": {
                "ans1": "drift of holes",
                "ans2": "diffusion of charge carries",
                "ans3": "migration of impurity atoms",
                "ans4": "drift of electrons",
                "question_text": "The depletion layer in a P N\u00a0junction is caused by",
                "correct_ans": "diffusion of charge carries",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16247": {
                "ans1": "straight line",
                "ans2": "circle",
                "ans3": "ellipse",
                "ans4": "parabola",
                "question_text": "If an electron has an initial velocity in a direction different from that of an electric field , the path of the electron is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "parabola",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15572": {
                "ans1": "copper iron",
                "ans2": "Bismuth-antimony",
                "ans3": "silver zinc",
                "ans4": "lead tin",
                "question_text": "The thermocouple thermometer will be most sensitive if made by",
                "correct_ans": "Bismuth-antimony",
                "explanation": "Thermocouple thermometer will be more sensitive if distance of two metals in themo electric series increases\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11071": {
                "ans1": "u",
                "ans2": "greater than u",
                "ans3": "less than u",
                "ans4": "may be greater or less depending on amount of humidity",
                "question_text": "The speed of sound in helium is 'u'. The speed of humid helium at the same sound in humid helium temperature will be",
                "correct_ans": "less than u",
                "explanation": "In case of helium, on increasing humidity density increases so velocity of sound decrases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18998": {
                "ans1": "energy",
                "ans2": "velocity",
                "ans3": "momentum",
                "ans4": "angular momentum",
                "question_text": "If an electron and a photon have same wavelength then they must have same",
                "correct_ans": "momentum",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15303": {
                "ans1": "mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans2": "half of mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans3": "two third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "ans4": "one third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "question_text": "The pressure exerted by perfect gas is equal to\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "two third of mean KE per unit volume",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19028": {
                "ans1": "directly proportional to r\u00b2",
                "ans2": "directly proportional to r",
                "ans3": " inversely proportional to r",
                "ans4": "\\;inversely\\;proportional\\;to\\;r^3",
                "question_text": "The electric intensity due to an infinite cylinder having charge 'q' per unit length at a distance r from it's axis is\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": " inversely proportional to r",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13713": {
                "ans1": "point of projection",
                "ans2": "highest point",
                "ans3": "aiming point",
                "ans4": "mid way between point of projection and highest point",
                "question_text": "A projectile fired from a gun follows a parabolic path, the speed of the projectile is minimum at",
                "correct_ans": "highest point",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v=\\sqrt{v_x^2+v_y^2}\\;,\\;speed\\;will\\;be\\;least\\;if\\;v_y=0\\\\i.e\\;heighest\\;point\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11639": {
                "ans1": "m_1:m_2",
                "ans2": "r_1:r_2",
                "ans3": "1:1",
                "ans4": "m_1r_1:m_2r_2",
                "question_text": "Two cars of mass\u00a0m_1 and   m_2\n\u00a0are moving along a circular path of radius\u00a0r_1 and \u00a0r_2\u00a0. They take one round in same time. The ratio of angular velocity of two cars will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14507": {
                "ans1": "Surface Tension of the liquid",
                "ans2": "The density of the liquid",
                "ans3": "The viscosity of liquid",
                "ans4": "The temperature of air only",
                "question_text": "When there are no external forces, the shape of a liquid drop is determined by",
                "correct_ans": "Surface Tension of the liquid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18732": {
                "ans1": "\\alpha-particle",
                "ans2": "\\beta-particle",
                "ans3": "proton",
                "ans4": "photon",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following is not deflected by electric and magnetic field?",
                "correct_ans": "photon",
                "explanation": "Alpha and beta particles are charged.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10837": {
                "ans1": "5A",
                "ans2": "10A",
                "ans3": "10\\sqrt2\\;A",
                "ans4": "\\frac{10}{\\sqrt2}\\;A",
                "question_text": "Rate of heat developed by 10A dc is same as rate of heat developed by ac through same resistor whose peak value of current is",
                "correct_ans": "10\\sqrt2\\;A",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned}\n&I_{d}^{2} R=I_{r m s}^{2} R \\\\\n&\\text { or, } I_{r m s}=10 \\mathrm{~A} \\\\\n&\\therefore \\quad I_{0}=I_{r m s} \\sqrt{2}=10 \\sqrt{2} \\mathrm{~A}\n\\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13289": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{h_1}{h_2}}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{h_2}{h_1}}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\frac{h_1}{h_2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\frac{h_2}{h_1}",
                "question_text": "Two bodies of mass\u00a0m_1\\;and\\;m_2\u00a0are dropped from heights\u00a0h_1\\;and \\;h_2. They reach the ground after time\u00a0t_1\\;and \\; t_2\u00a0then",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{h_1}{h_2}}",
                "explanation": "t=\\sqrt{\\frac{2h}{g}}\\\\\nt\\propto\\sqrt{h}\\\\\n\\frac{t_1}{t_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{h_1}{h_2}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19727": {
                "ans1": "3%",
                "ans2": "4%",
                "ans3": "5%",
                "ans4": "6%",
                "question_text": "What is the % error in the measurement of 'T' of a pendulum if maximum errors in measurments of length and 'g' are 2% and 4% respectively?",
                "correct_ans": "3%",
                "explanation": "T=2\\pi\\sqrt{\\frac{l}{g}}so,\n\\frac{\\triangle T}T\\%=\\frac12\\left(\\frac{\\triangle l}l+\\frac{\\triangle g}g\\right)=3\\%",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13481": {
                "ans1": "current",
                "ans2": "voltage",
                "ans3": "impedance",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "A capacitance is a circuit component that opposses the change in circuit",
                "correct_ans": "voltage",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13170": {
                "ans1": "g",
                "ans2": "\\frac g\\mu",
                "ans3": "\\mu g",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\mu g}2",
                "question_text": "A car is moving on a road with coefficient of friction\u00a0\\mu. If the engine is shut off, the maximum value of retardation developed is",
                "correct_ans": "\\mu g",
                "explanation": "F_r=ma\\\\\nor, \\mu mg=ma\\\\\nor, a=\\mu g",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10299": {
                "ans1": "Convex mirror",
                "ans2": "Concave mirror",
                "ans3": "Concave lens",
                "ans4": "All of the above",
                "question_text": "A virtual image larger than object is produced by",
                "correct_ans": "Concave mirror",
                "explanation": "When object is placed within focus then image is virtual and magnified.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18052": {
                "ans1": "Increase",
                "ans2": "Decrease",
                "ans3": "Become zero",
                "ans4": "Remain constant",
                "question_text": "On increasing the current in semiconductor diode, the contact potential will",
                "correct_ans": "Decrease",
                "explanation": "If current increases then potential at junction decreases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16853": {
                "ans1": "15.8 m/s",
                "ans2": "2.7 m/s",
                "ans3": "5.7 m/s",
                "ans4": "10.8 m/s",
                "question_text": "The maximum speed at which a car can turn around a curve of 30m radius on a level road if the coefficient of friction between the tyres and the road is 0.4 is:",
                "correct_ans": "10.8 m/s",
                "explanation": "v=\\sqrt{\\mu rg}=\\sqrt{0.4*30*9.8}=10.844\\; m/s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18529": {
                "ans1": "Penetration power increases",
                "ans2": "Penetration power decreases",
                "ans3": "Intensity increases",
                "ans4": "Intensity decreases",
                "question_text": "During x-ray production from Collidge tube, if the current is increased, then",
                "correct_ans": "Intensity increases",
                "explanation": "On increasing current the intensity of x-ray increases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13044": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "1/16",
                "ans4": "16",
                "question_text": "The magnitude of charges is doubled and distance is halved then, force become n times.\u00a0Then the value of 'n' is",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned} &\\mathrm{F}=9 \\times 10^{9} \\frac{\\mathrm{Q}_{1} \\mathrm{Q}_{2}}{\\mathrm{r}^{2}} \\\\ &\\mathrm{~F}^{\\prime}=9 \\times 10^{9} \\frac{2 \\mathrm{Q}_{1} \\times 2 \\mathrm{Q}_{2}}{(\\mathrm{r} / 2)^{2}}=16 \\mathrm{~F} \\\\ &\\therefore \\quad \\mathrm{n}=16 \\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16492": {
                "ans1": "Temperature",
                "ans2": "Expansion ratio",
                "ans3": "both (a) and (b)",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Workdone in\u00a0isothermal expansion of a gas depends upon",
                "correct_ans": "both (a) and (b)",
                "explanation": "W=nRT\\;ln(\\frac{V_1}{V_2})\\\\\\therefore",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16348": {
                "ans1": "Position of axis of rotation",
                "ans2": "Distribution of particles",
                "ans3": "Mass",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "Moment of inertia depends upon________",
                "correct_ans": "All of these",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15948": {
                "ans1": "5.5^\\circ C",
                "ans2": "11^\\circ C",
                "ans3": "1^\\circ C",
                "ans4": "2^\\circ C",
                "question_text": "The change in temperature of air at\u00a00^\\circ C\u00a0to change the speed of sound by 1% is",
                "correct_ans": "5.5^\\circ C",
                "explanation": "\\frac{1.01v}v=\\sqrt{\\frac{273+\\theta}{273}}\\\\\n\\Rightarrow 1.01^2=\\frac{273+\\theta}{273}\n\\\\\n\\theta=1.01^2*273-273=5.487^\\circ C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15191": {
                "ans1": "A<2C",
                "ans2": "A=2C",
                "ans3": "A>2C",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "If the critical angle for the medium of a prism is C and the angle of prism is A,then there will be no emergent ray when:",
                "correct_ans": "A>2C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11227": {
                "ans1": "Heat is given out",
                "ans2": "Heat is taken",
                "ans3": "No change in temperature while taking and giving heat",
                "ans4": "All of the above",
                "question_text": "Heat capacity of a substance is infiite. It means",
                "correct_ans": "No change in temperature while taking and giving heat",
                "explanation": "c=\\frac{dQ}{d\\theta}=\\infty,\\; if \\;d\\theta=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19212": {
                "ans1": "increase in melting point",
                "ans2": "decrease in melting point",
                "ans3": "no change in melting point",
                "ans4": "may increases or decreases",
                "question_text": "Substance which expands upon melting, the increases of pressure result in",
                "correct_ans": "increase in melting point",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17384": {
                "ans1": "Light year and wavelength",
                "ans2": "Angular momentum and work",
                "ans3": "Energy and Young's modulus",
                "ans4": "Light year and year",
                "question_text": "The dimensions of quantities in one of the following pairs are the same. The pair is",
                "correct_ans": "Light year and wavelength",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15076": {
                "ans1": "emf",
                "ans2": "potential",
                "ans3": "resistance",
                "ans4": "current",
                "question_text": "Wheat stone bridge is used to measure",
                "correct_ans": "resistance",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17051": {
                "ans1": "\\text{f}/2",
                "ans2": "2\\text{f}",
                "ans3": "f",
                "ans4": "f/4",
                "question_text": "The resonant frequency of a circuit is\u00a0\\text{f}. If the capacitance is made 4 times the initial value, then the resonant frequency becomes",
                "correct_ans": "\\text{f}/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10340": {
                "ans1": "24 m",
                "ans2": "12 m",
                "ans3": "18 m",
                "ans4": "9 m",
                "question_text": "An under water swimmer is at a depth of 12 m below the surface of water. A bird is at a height of 18 m from the surface of water, directly above his eyes. For the swimmer the bird appears to be at a distance from the surface of water equal to (Refractive Index of water is 4/3)",
                "correct_ans": "24 m",
                "explanation": "The apparent height is given by\u00a0\\mu =\\cfrac{h'}{h} \\Rightarrow h'=\\mu h=\\cfrac{4}{3} \\times 18=24\\, \\, cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10778": {
                "ans1": "the pitch of their organ is more",
                "ans2": "they have more energy",
                "ans3": "the amplitude of vibration of their organs is more",
                "ans4": "they have control over their tongue",
                "question_text": "The voice of women is shriller because",
                "correct_ans": "the pitch of their organ is more",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18569": {
                "ans1": "9.5 mA",
                "ans2": "0.5mA",
                "ans3": "10.5mA",
                "ans4": "(200/19)mA",
                "question_text": "The current gain\u00a0\\alpha\u00a0of a transistor is 0.95. The change in emitter current is 10mA. The change in base current is",
                "correct_ans": "0.5mA",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{ll}{\\alpha=0.95} & {\\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{\\mathrm{e}}=10 \\mathrm{mA}} \\\\ {\\text { Now, } \\alpha=\\cfrac{\\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{c}}{\\mathrm{I}_{e}}} & {\\therefore \\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{c}=9.5 \\mathrm{mA}} \\\\ {\\therefore \\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{\\mathrm{b}}=\\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{\\mathrm{e}}=\\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{\\mathrm{e}}-\\Delta \\mathrm{I}_{\\mathrm{c}}=} & {10-9.5=0.5 \\mathrm{mA}}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19594": {
                "ans1": "less than 1 gm",
                "ans2": "1 gm",
                "ans3": "4 gm",
                "ans4": "8 gm",
                "question_text": "A sample contains 16gm of a radioactive material, the half life of which is 2 days. What will be the amount of sample left after 32 days?",
                "correct_ans": "less than 1 gm",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{\\mathrm{m}}{\\mathrm{m}_{0}}=\\left(\\cfrac{1}{2}\\right)^{\\cfrac{t}{T_{1/2}}}\nor, m=16\\left(\\cfrac{1}{2}\\right)^{\\cfrac{32}{2}}=4.8 \\times 10^{-4} \\mathrm{g}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19095": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt{u^{2}+2 g h}",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{2 g h}",
                "ans3": "2gh",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{u^{2}-2 g h}",
                "question_text": "An aeroplane is moving with horizontal velocity u at height 'h'. The velocity of a packet dropped from it on the surface of earth is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{u^{2}+2 g h}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{x}}=\\mathrm{u}} \\\\ {\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{y}}=\\sqrt{2 \\mathrm{gh}}} \\\\ {\\therefore \\mathrm{V}=\\sqrt{\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{x}}^{2}+\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{y}}^{2}}=\\sqrt{\\mathrm{u}^{2}+2 \\mathrm{gh}}}\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19162": {
                "ans1": "10 K",
                "ans2": "27 K",
                "ans3": "273 K",
                "ans4": "373 K",
                "question_text": "The temperature of a substance increases by 27\u00b0C. On the Kelvin scale this increase is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "27 K",
                "explanation": "Temperature change in Celsius scale = Temperature change in Kelvin scale = 27\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13448": {
                "ans1": "267 k",
                "ans2": "200k",
                "ans3": "300k",
                "ans4": "250 k",
                "question_text": "A carnot engine whose source is at 400k, takes 200 calories of heat and rejects 150 calories of heat to the sink. The temperature of sink is",
                "correct_ans": "300k",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{\\mathrm{Q}_{1}=200 \\text { calories }} \\\\{\\mathrm{Q}_{2}=150 \\text { calories }}\\end{array} \\\\\n\\begin{array}{l}{\\eta=1-\\cfrac{Q_{2}}{Q_{1}}=1-\\cfrac{T_{2}}{T_{1}}} \\\\ {\\text { Or, } \\cfrac{150}{200}=\\cfrac{T_{2}}{400}} \\\\ {\\text { Or, } \\mathrm{T}_{2}=300 \\mathrm{K}}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13790": {
                "ans1": "1: 1",
                "ans2": "9: 4",
                "ans3": "4: 9",
                "ans4": "3: 2",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of same material have radii in the ratio 3:2. The heat radiated by them at same temperature will be",
                "correct_ans": "9: 4",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{r_{1}}{r_{2}}=\\cfrac{3}{2}\n\\cfrac{P_{1}}{P_{2}}=\\left(\\cfrac{r_{1}}{r_{2}}\\right)^{2}=\\left(\\cfrac{3}{2}\\right)^{2}=\\cfrac{9}{4}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12289": {
                "ans1": "32.5\\Omega",
                "ans2": "37.5\\Omega",
                "ans3": "52\\Omega",
                "ans4": "63.5\\Omega",
                "question_text": "A 50V, 50Hz ac supply is connected to a resistor of resistance\u00a040\\Omega\u00a0in series with a solenoid whose inductance is 0.2H. The Pd between ends of resistor is found to be 20V. The resistance of wire of solenoid is",
                "correct_ans": "37.5\\Omega",
                "explanation": "\\mathrm{I}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{R}}}{\\mathrm{R}}=\\cfrac{20}{40}=0.5 \\mathrm{A}\n\\mathrm{Z}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{V}}{\\mathrm{I}}=\\cfrac{50}{0.5}=100 \\Omega\nHere, \\mathrm{Z}=\\sqrt{(\\mathrm{R}+\\mathrm{r})^{2}+\\mathrm{X}_{\\mathrm{L}}^{2}}\nor, (\\mathrm{R}+\\mathrm{r})^{2}=\\mathrm{Z}^{2}-\\mathrm{X}_{\\mathrm{L}}^{2}\nor, 40+\\mathrm{r}=\\sqrt{100^{2}-(2 \\pi \\mathrm{fL})^{2}}\nor, \\mathrm{r}=77.7-40=37.7 \\Omega",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17381": {
                "ans1": "1%",
                "ans2": "2%",
                "ans3": "4%",
                "ans4": "16%",
                "question_text": "If the current in an electric bulb drops by 2% then the power decreases by",
                "correct_ans": "4%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11530": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{F l} { 2 A L}",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{F A} { 2 L}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{F L} { 2 A}",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{F L}{2}",
                "question_text": "On stretching a wire, the elastic energy stored per unit volume is",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{F l} { 2 A L}",
                "explanation": "= \\cfrac { 1 } { 2 } \\left( \\cfrac { F } { A } \\right) \\left( \\cfrac { l } { L } \\right) = \\cfrac { F l } { 2 A L }",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10577": {
                "ans1": "1 m",
                "ans2": "5 m",
                "ans3": "10 m",
                "ans4": "20 m",
                "question_text": "Two bodies held 1 m vertically above the other are released simultaneously fall freely under the action of gravity. Their separation after 2 seconds will be",
                "correct_ans": "1 m",
                "explanation": "Two bodies dropped simultaneously will have same difference at any instant",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18759": {
                "ans1": "0.5 A",
                "ans2": "5 A",
                "ans3": "50 A",
                "ans4": "5 \\times 10{}^{8} A",
                "question_text": "In a coil of area\u00a010 cm{}^{2}\u00a0and 10 turns with magnetic field directed perpendicular to the plane and is changing at the rate of\u00a0\u00a0 10{}^{8}\u00a0gauss/second. The resistance of the coil is 20 \\Omega.\u00a0The current in the coil will be",
                "correct_ans": "5 A",
                "explanation": "E=\\cfrac{d \\phi}{d t}=10 \\times 10 \\times 10^{-4} \\times 10^{4}\ni=\\cfrac{E}{R}=\\cfrac{100}{20}=5 \\mathrm{A}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11596": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{2Ee}{3m}",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{3Ee}{2m}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{2m}{3Ee}",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{3m}{2Ee}",
                "question_text": "A charge of magnitude\u00a03e\u00a0and mass\u00a02m\u00a0is moving in an electric field The acceleration imparted to the charge is",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{3Ee}{2m}",
                "explanation": "Acceleration (a) = \\cfrac { Q E } { m } = \\cfrac { ( 3 e ) E } { 2 m }",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17208": {
                "ans1": "The image lies between the pole and the focus",
                "ans2": "The image is diminished in size",
                "ans3": "The image is erect",
                "ans4": "The image is real",
                "question_text": "A convex mirror is used to form the image of an object. Then which of the following statements is wrong",
                "correct_ans": "The image is real",
                "explanation": "The image formed by a convex mirror is always virtual.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18397": {
                "ans1": "340 m/s",
                "ans2": "330 m/s",
                "ans3": "350 m/s",
                "ans4": "360 m/s",
                "question_text": "Sound waves from a whistle of frequency 1000Hz reach a point by two different path when the path differs by 0.12m and 0.48m then there is silence at that point. The speed of sound is",
                "correct_ans": "360 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\mathrm{x}_{2}-\\mathrm{x}_{1}=\\lambda \\lambda=(0.48-0.12)=0.36 \\mathrm{m} v=\\mathrm{f} \\lambda=1000 \\times 0.36=360 \\mathrm{m} / \\mathrm{s} \u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12828": {
                "ans1": "23.0km",
                "ans2": "45km",
                "ans3": "65.0km",
                "ans4": "75.0km",
                "question_text": "The height from which a block of ice must drop so that it completely melt if 75% of energy of fall is converted into heat is",
                "correct_ans": "45km",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{75 \\% \\text { of } \\mathrm{mgh}=\\mathrm{mL}_{\\mathrm{f}}} \\\\ {\\text { or, } \\mathrm{h}=\\cfrac{80 \\times 4200}{0.75 \\times 10}=44.8 \\mathrm{km}}\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16029": {
                "ans1": "satellite of earth",
                "ans2": "fall to earth",
                "ans3": "escape from earth",
                "ans4": "depends on mass of ball",
                "question_text": "A ball is thrown parallel to the surface of earth from the top of Mount Everest with a velocity more than escape velocity. The ball will be",
                "correct_ans": "escape from earth",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16570": {
                "ans1": "\\omega r",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{\\omega r}{2}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{r\\omega }{\\sqrt{2} }",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{\\sqrt{3} }{2} r\\omega",
                "question_text": "In SHM, velocity of particle when displacement is half of amplitude r is",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{\\sqrt{3} }{2} r\\omega",
                "explanation": "\\mathrm{v}=\\omega \\sqrt{r^{2}-(r / 2)^{2}}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{3}}{2} \\mathrm{r} \\omega",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19749": {
                "ans1": "momentum",
                "ans2": "retardation",
                "ans3": "kinetic energy",
                "ans4": "potential energy",
                "question_text": "A ball is projected upwards. As it rises there is increase in its",
                "correct_ans": "potential energy",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10003": {
                "ans1": "2{}^{1/4}",
                "ans2": "2{}^{1/2}",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "2{}^{3/4}",
                "question_text": "A vibration magnetometer consists of two identical bar magnets placed one over the other perpendicularly such that the period of oscillation in a horizontal magnetic field\u00a02{}^{5/4}\u00a0second. One of the magnets is removed and if the other magnet oscillates in the same field, then the time period in second is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "From figure, dipole moment of combinationM^{\\prime}=\\sqrt{2} MThe total moment of inertia of combinationI^{\\prime}=I+I=2 I\nT^{\\prime}=2 \\pi \\sqrt{\\cfrac{I^{\\prime}}{M^{\\prime} B_{H}}} \\Rightarrow T^{\\prime} \\propto \\sqrt{\\cfrac{I^{\\prime}}{M^{\\prime}}} \\\\\nWhen \\ one\\ is\\ removed\\, then\\ T  \\propto \\sqrt{\\cfrac{I}{M}}\n\\cfrac{T^{\\prime}}{T}=\\sqrt{\\cfrac{1}{M} \\times \\cfrac{\\sqrt{2} M}{2 I}} \\\\ \\text { or, } \\cfrac{T^{\\prime}}{2^{5 / 4}} =\\cfrac{1}{2^{1 / 4}} \\\\ \\text { or, } T^{\\prime}=2 s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15690": {
                "ans1": "25, 1",
                "ans2": "25, 2",
                "ans3": "25, 4",
                "ans4": "50 \\pi , 2",
                "question_text": "In a plane progressive wave given by\u00a0y = 25 \\cos ( 2 \\pi t - \\pi x ),\u00a0the amplitude and frequency are respectively",
                "correct_ans": "25, 1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array} { l } { \\text { Comparing the given equation with } y = a \\cos ( \\omega t - k x ) } \\\\ { a = 25 , \\quad \\omega = 2 \\pi n = 2 \\pi \\Rightarrow n = 1 H z } \\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14752": {
                "ans1": "100ev",
                "ans2": "1000ev",
                "ans3": "10000ev",
                "ans4": "10{}^{5}ev",
                "question_text": "The maximum energy of x-ray photon in tube where electrons are accelerated by 10000v is",
                "correct_ans": "10000ev",
                "explanation": "\\mathrm{E}=\\mathrm{eV}=10^{4} \\mathrm{eV}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14684": {
                "ans1": "its length",
                "ans2": "its cross-sectional",
                "ans3": "its dimensions area",
                "ans4": "its material",
                "question_text": "Specific resistance of wire depends up on",
                "correct_ans": "its material",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19107": {
                "ans1": "Twice",
                "ans2": "Half",
                "ans3": "Same as earlier",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "If the diameter of a capillary tube is doubled, then the height of the liquid that will rise is",
                "correct_ans": "Half",
                "explanation": "=\\cfrac{2 T }{r d g}h \\propto \\cfrac { 1 } { r }\\therefore",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10338": {
                "ans1": "peltier effect",
                "ans2": "joule's effect",
                "ans3": "Thomson effect",
                "ans4": "none of above",
                "question_text": "Seeback effect is inverse of",
                "correct_ans": "peltier effect",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18660": {
                "ans1": "1 lumen/m^2",
                "ans2": "1 lumen/cm^2",
                "ans3": "1 candela/m^2",
                "ans4": "1 candela/cm^2",
                "question_text": "Lux is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "1 lumen/m^2",
                "explanation": "Lux is the unit of illuminance which is defined as luminous flux per unit area.^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10132": {
                "ans1": "conduction",
                "ans2": " convection   ",
                "ans3": "radiation",
                "ans4": "both (a) and (b)",
                "question_text": "The temperature ratio of a transformer is 0.1 and its impurity current is 5A. The secondary current of Transformer will be",
                "correct_ans": "radiation",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11437": {
                "ans1": "Zero",
                "ans2": "5V",
                "ans3": "7.5V    ",
                "ans4": "10 V",
                "question_text": "The reading of voltmeter if 50 \\Omega\u00a0is short circuited is",
                "correct_ans": "Zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14245": {
                "ans1": "electrons ",
                "ans2": "holes",
                "ans3": "both (a) and (b)   ",
                "ans4": "depends upon n-type impurity",
                "question_text": "The majority charge carriers of npn transistor are",
                "correct_ans": "electrons ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14630": {
                "ans1": "25 W bulb gets fused   ",
                "ans2": "100 W bulb gets fused  ",
                "ans3": "both bulb  will get fused   ",
                "ans4": "circuit will operate property",
                "question_text": "Two bulbs 25 W, 110 V and 100 W, 110 V are connected in series with 220 V source then",
                "correct_ans": "25 W bulb gets fused   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18785": {
                "ans1": "Increases by 100%\t",
                "ans2": "decreases by 100%",
                "ans3": "Increases by 125%",
                "ans4": "decreases by 125% ",
                "question_text": "The momentum of a body is increased by 50% , its associated kinetic energy",
                "correct_ans": "Increases by 125%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18043": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "hf ",
                "ans3": "hf/c   ",
                "ans4": "h/ \u03bbc",
                "question_text": ". Dynamic mass of a photon is",
                "correct_ans": "h/ \u03bbc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13866": {
                "ans1": "length of wire   ",
                "ans2": "shape of cross section of wire  ",
                "ans3": "natural of  material",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "Breaking stress of a wire depends upon",
                "correct_ans": "natural of  material",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17894": {
                "ans1": "temperature increases",
                "ans2": "temperature decreases ",
                "ans3": "volume  decreases",
                "ans4": "volume increases",
                "question_text": "If dW = 0, dQ<0 then which of the following is true?",
                "correct_ans": "temperature decreases ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17133": {
                "ans1": "inverted & virtual    ",
                "ans2": "inverted & real ",
                "ans3": "upright & virtual    ",
                "ans4": "upright & real",
                "question_text": "When converging beam of light falls on plane mirror, the image formed is",
                "correct_ans": "upright & real",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18862": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3      ",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/4 ",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/6",
                "question_text": ". If \\overrightarrow{\\vert a}\\;\\times\\;\\overrightarrow b\\vert=\\overrightarrow a\\;.\\overrightarrow b, angle between \\overrightarrow a and \\overrightarrow b\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/4 ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10996": {
                "ans1": "500 A",
                "ans2": "50 A",
                "ans3": "0.5 A    ",
                "ans4": "0.05 A",
                "question_text": "The transformation ratio of a transformer is 0.1 and its primary current is 5 A. The secondary current of transformer will be",
                "correct_ans": "50 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11767": {
                "ans1": "1:1   ",
                "ans2": "1:2",
                "ans3": "2:1",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The ratio of total intensities of magnetic field at the equator and the poles will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:1   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17899": {
                "ans1": "transverse progressive",
                "ans2": "transverse stationary   ",
                "ans3": "longitudinal  progressive",
                "ans4": "longitudinal stationary",
                "question_text": "Waves produced in sonometer are",
                "correct_ans": "transverse stationary   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14045": {
                "ans1": "K    ",
                "ans2": "2K",
                "ans3": "4K ",
                "ans4": "K/2",
                "question_text": ". A stone is thrown at an angle of 45^0\u00a0to horizontal with kinetic energy \u2018K\u2019. The kinetic energy at highest point\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "K/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18821": {
                "ans1": "phasor",
                "ans2": "scalar  ",
                "ans3": "vector",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Impedance is a",
                "correct_ans": "phasor",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11916": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "1/4",
                "question_text": "The intensity of spherical point source at 0.5 m is \u2018n\u2019 times the intensity at 1 m. The value of \u2018n\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16033": {
                "ans1": "1:1   ",
                "ans2": "2:1    ",
                "ans3": "3:1",
                "ans4": "4:1",
                "question_text": "A proton and an alpha particle are accelerated by same kinetic energy. The ratio of associated de-Broglie wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "2:1    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11693": {
                "ans1": "Force & vertical velocity",
                "ans2": "Acceleration and horizontal velocity",
                "ans3": "Kinetic energy and acceleration",
                "ans4": "Acceleration and momentum",
                "question_text": "During projectile motion the quantities that remain unchanged are",
                "correct_ans": "Acceleration and horizontal velocity",
                "explanation": "Incase of projectile motion the horizontal component of velocity (ucos@), acceleration(g) and mechanical energy remains constant",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16291": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "less than 1",
                "ans3": "greater than 1\t",
                "ans4": "very large",
                "question_text": ". Value of relative permeability of diamagnetic substance is",
                "correct_ans": "less than 1",
                "explanation": "The relative permeability of diamagnetic substance is less than unity.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16115": {
                "ans1": "Interference",
                "ans2": "diffraction",
                "ans3": "polarization",
                "ans4": "photoelectric ",
                "question_text": "Which of the following phenomenon support the quantum nature of light",
                "correct_ans": "photoelectric ",
                "explanation": "Photoelectric effect support quantum nature of light",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18466": {
                "ans1": "C",
                "ans2": "2C",
                "ans3": "C/2",
                "ans4": "Infinite",
                "question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor has capacitance C. The plates of capacitor are joined bu a conducting wire,then capacitance becomes",
                "correct_ans": "Infinite",
                "explanation": "Capacitance becomes infinite due to application of conductiong wires on the plates of parallel plate capacitor",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16251": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "one",
                "ans3": "infinite",
                "ans4": "less than one",
                "question_text": "Boiling water is changing into steam . Under this condition the specific heat of water is",
                "correct_ans": "infinite",
                "explanation": "specific heat capacity of water changing into steam is infinite .",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16531": {
                "ans1": "Gas thermometer",
                "ans2": "liguid thermometer",
                "ans3": "pyrometer",
                "ans4": "resistance thermometer",
                "question_text": "Which of the following thermometer is used to measure very high temperature",
                "correct_ans": "pyrometer",
                "explanation": "Pyrometer is used to measure very high temperature",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11009": {
                "ans1": "radius of orbit",
                "ans2": "shape of orbit",
                "ans3": "value of g on orbit",
                "ans4": "mass of satellite",
                "question_text": "The speed needed to put a satellite in orbit doesnt depend upon",
                "correct_ans": "mass of satellite",
                "explanation": "It is independent of mass of satellite",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16127": {
                "ans1": "n^2",
                "ans2": "1/n",
                "ans3": "n",
                "ans4": "1/n^2",
                "question_text": "n capacitor of equal capacitance are first connected in series and then in parallel. the ratio of maximum to minimum capacitance is",
                "correct_ans": "n^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19063": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{RC}",
                "ans2": "\\frac RL",
                "ans3": "\\frac CL",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{\\sqrt{LC}}",
                "question_text": "If L, C and R represent inductance, capacitance and resistance respectively, then which of the following does not represent dimensions of frequency?",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{RC}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}f=\\frac1{2\\pi\\sqrt{LC}}\\\\Therefore,\\left(\\frac CL\\right)doesn't\\;represent\\;the\\;dimension\\;of\\;frequency\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10087": {
                "ans1": "2/5\t",
                "ans2": "3/5",
                "ans3": "3/7",
                "ans4": "5/7",
                "question_text": "When an ideal diatomic gas is heated at constant pressure the fraction of heat energy supplied which increases the internal energy of the gas is",
                "correct_ans": "5/7",
                "explanation": "Fraction\\;of\\;energy\\;=\\frac{\\triangle U}Q=\\frac{nC_v\\triangle T}{nC_p\\triangle T}=\\frac{C_v}{C_p}=\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\frac52}R}{{\\displaystyle\\frac72}R}=\\frac57",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17309": {
                "ans1": "Up thrust",
                "ans2": "surface tension ",
                "ans3": "air resistance ",
                "ans4": "viscous force exerted by air",
                "question_text": "The velocity of falling rain drop attains limiting value because of",
                "correct_ans": "viscous force exerted by air",
                "explanation": "It is because of viscous force exerted by air",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16498": {
                "ans1": "KE of ice molecules decreases",
                "ans2": "PE of ice molecules decreases",
                "ans3": "PE of ice molecules increase",
                "ans4": "The energy of ice molecule does\u2019t change",
                "question_text": "When a ice cube is placed in table and its melts then which is correct",
                "correct_ans": "PE of ice molecules increase",
                "explanation": "Ice melts when it gains heat in the form of energy.So,PE increases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17376": {
                "ans1": "\\left(u+gt\\right)t",
                "ans2": "Ut",
                "ans3": "\\frac12gt^2",
                "ans4": "ut-\\frac12gt^2",
                "question_text": "If a ball is thrown vertically upwards with speed u, the distance covered during the last t seconds of its ascent is",
                "correct_ans": "Ut",
                "explanation": "\\frac{x(4)}{x(5)}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac g2(2\\times4-1)}{\\displaystyle\\frac g2(2\\times5-1)}=\\frac79\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\lbrack\\;S_{nth_{}}=u+\\frac a2(2n-1)\\rbrack",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17062": {
                "ans1": "Increases ",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "no change ",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "On heating liquid the refractive index generally.",
                "correct_ans": "decreases",
                "explanation": "On heating liquid,Volume increases = density increases i.e. R.I decreases",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18422": {
                "ans1": "Nodes",
                "ans2": "anti nodes",
                "ans3": "Both node and antinode",
                "ans4": "neither nodes nor antinodes",
                "question_text": "In a longitudinal stationary wave produced in a gas , ressure is maximum at",
                "correct_ans": "Nodes",
                "explanation": "Pressure is maximum at node",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15172": {
                "ans1": "High specific resistance & high melting point",
                "ans2": "low specific resistance & high melting point",
                "ans3": "High specific resistance & low melting point",
                "ans4": "low specific resistance &low melting point",
                "question_text": "The heating element of an electric heater should be made with a material which should be\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "High specific resistance & high melting point",
                "explanation": "Obiously,Heating element must have\u00a0High specific resistance & high melting point",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18918": {
                "ans1": "16",
                "ans2": "24",
                "ans3": "20",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "The current amplification of common base pNp transistor is 0.96 the current gain in common emitter amplifies is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\alpha=0.96\\\\So,\\beta=\\frac\\alpha{1-\\alpha}=\\frac{0.96}{1-0.96}=\\frac{0.96}{0.04}=24\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10575": {
                "ans1": "F",
                "ans2": "F/2",
                "ans3": "F/8",
                "ans4": "F/4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two identical spheres having charges q and \u20132q experiences a force F at a certain distance. If the spheres are kept in contact and then placed at same distance, find force between them.",
                "correct_ans": "F/8",
                "explanation": "F = \\cfrac{1}{4 \\pi \\epsilon _0} \\cfrac{q(2q)}{r^2}After keeping in contact and then separating, the charge on each sphereq' = \\cfrac{q-2q}{2} = \\cfrac{-q}{2} \\\\\n\\therefore F' = \\cfrac{1}{4 \\pi \\epsilon _0} \\cfrac{q'q'}{r^2}\\\\ \\quad = \\cfrac{1}{4 \\pi \\epsilon _0} \\left( \\cfrac{q}{2} \\right) ^2 \\cfrac{1}{r^2} = \\cfrac{F}{2} \\times \\cfrac{1}{4}\n\\therefore F' = \\cfrac{F}{8}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17356": {
                "ans1": "Am",
                "ans2": "Am{}^{2}",
                "ans3": "Am{}^{-2}",
                "ans4": "Am{}^{-1}",
                "question_text": "The unit of magnetic pole strength is",
                "correct_ans": "Am",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16454": {
                "ans1": "6.2 V",
                "ans2": "10.5 V",
                "ans3": "12.5V",
                "ans4": "15.6 V",
                "question_text": "Upon a six fold increase in the external resistance of a circuit, the voltage across the terminals of the battery has increased 5 V to 10 V. Find the emf of the battery.",
                "correct_ans": "12.5V",
                "explanation": "E-\\cfrac{E}{R+r} \\times r=5 \\\\\nOr, E\\left(\\cfrac{R+r-r}{R+r}\\right)=5\\\\\nOr, E \\cfrac{R}{R+r}=5 \\ldots \\ldots \\ldots (1)\\\\\n\n\nAnd, E - \\cfrac{E}{6R+r} \\times r = 10\\\\\nOr, E \\left(\\cfrac{6R+r-r}{6R+r}\\right) = 10\\\\\nOr,E \\cfrac{6R}{6R+r} = 10 \\cdots \\cdots (2)\\\\\nDividing equation (2) by (1), we get: \\\\\n\n\nOr, 6 R+6 r=12 R+2 r \\\\\nOr, 6 r-2 r=12 R-6 R \\\\\nOr, 4 r=6 R \\\\\\therefore \\, 2 r=3 R \\\\\n\\Rightarrow r=\\cfrac{3}{2} R\\\\\nNow, putting value of r in (1), we get,\n\nE . \\cfrac{R}{R+\\cfrac{3}{2}R} = 5\nOr, E \\cfrac{1}{5/2} = 5\nOr, E \\times \\cfrac{2}{5} = 5\n\\Rightarrow E = 12.5 V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14051": {
                "ans1": "1 rad",
                "ans2": "2 rad",
                "ans3": "3 rad",
                "ans4": "4 rad",
                "question_text": "What will be the angular width of central maxima in Fraunhofer diffraction when light of wavelength\u00a06000 A\u00a0is used and slit width is\u00a0\u00a0 12 \\times 10 ^ { - 5 } \\mathrm { cm }?",
                "correct_ans": "1 rad",
                "explanation": "Angular\\space width = \\cfrac { 2 \\lambda } { d } = \\cfrac { 2 \\times 6000 \\times 10 ^ { - 10 } } { 12 \\times 10 ^ { - 5 } \\times 10 ^ { - 2 } } = 1 rad.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14867": {
                "ans1": "0^0",
                "ans2": "60^0",
                "ans3": "90^0",
                "ans4": "180^0",
                "question_text": "A boy of mass 40 kg is hanging from a horizontal branch of a tree. The tension in arms will be maximum if angle between arms is",
                "correct_ans": "180^0",
                "explanation": "A and B are position of hand on branch and P is a point at which man is hanging then\\begin{array}{l}{2 \\mathrm{T} \\cos \\theta=\\mathrm{Mg}} \\\\ {\\mathrm{T}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{mg}}{2 \\cos \\theta}}\\end{array}\\begin{array}{l}{\\text { T will be maximum if } \\cos \\theta \\text { is least i.e. }} \\\\ {\\qquad \\begin{aligned} \\cos \\theta &=0 \\\\ &=\\cos 90^{\\circ} \\end{aligned}}\\end{array}\\begin{array}{l}{\\text { or, } \\theta=90^{\\circ}} \\\\ {\\therefore \\text { Angle between arm } 2 \\theta=180^{\\circ}} \\\\ {\\qquad \\quad=\\pi}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16903": {
                "ans1": "9 cm",
                "ans2": "6 cm",
                "ans3": "3 cm",
                "ans4": "2 cm",
                "question_text": "A capillary tube when immersed vertically in liquid records a rise of 3\u00a0cm. If the tube is immersed in the liquid at an angle of 60\u00b0 with the vertical. The length of the liquid column along the tube is",
                "correct_ans": "6 cm",
                "explanation": "Vertical height of the water in the tube remains constant l = \\cfrac { h } { \\cos \\theta } = \\cfrac { 3 } { \\cos 60 ^ { \\circ } } = 6 \\mathrm { cm }\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19033": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 86400 } rad/ sec",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 3600 } rad/ sec",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 6400 } rad/ sec",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 1440 } rad/ sec",
                "question_text": "What is the angular velocity of earth?",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 86400 } rad/ sec",
                "explanation": " = \\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { T } = \\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 24 } r a d / h r = \\cfrac { 2 \\pi } { 86400 } r a d / s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12675": {
                "ans1": "1.44 \\times 10{}^{-2\\ }m",
                "ans2": "1.44 \\times 10{}^{-3\\ }m",
                "ans3": "1.44 \\times 10{}^{-4} m",
                "ans4": "1.44 \\times 10{}^{-5} m",
                "question_text": "Two parallel plates of 4cm long are held 3cm apart in vacuum one is above the other. Upper plate is at 300V and lower is earthed. Electrons with 10{}^{7}\u00a0m/s are injected horizontal midway between plates parallel to 4cm edge then vertical deflection will be",
                "correct_ans": "1.44 \\times 10{}^{-2\\ }m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned} \\mathrm{y} &=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\cfrac{\\mathrm{Ee}}{\\mathrm{m}} \\cfrac{\\mathrm{x}^{2}}{v^{2}}=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\cfrac{\\mathrm{V}}{\\mathrm{d}} \\cfrac{\\mathrm{e}}{\\mathrm{m}} \\cfrac{\\mathrm{x}^{2}}{v^{2}} \\\\ &=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\times \\cfrac{300}{3 \\times 10^{-2}} \\times 1.8 \\times 10^{11} \\times \\cfrac{\\left(4 \\times 10^{-2}\\right)}{\\left(10^{7}\\right)^{2}} \\\\ &=0.0144 \\mathrm{m}=1.4 \\times 10^{-2} \\mathrm{m} \\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19490": {
                "ans1": "2\\times10{}^{18}",
                "ans2": "0.75\\times10{}^{18}",
                "ans3": "Can not be predicted",
                "ans4": "None of above",
                "question_text": "1 milligram radium has 2.68\\times10{}^{18}\u00a0atoms. Its half-life is 1620 yrs. How many radium atoms will disintegrate from 1 milligram of pure radium in 3240 yrs?",
                "correct_ans": "2\\times10{}^{18}",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{\\mathrm{N}}{\\mathrm{N}_{\\mathrm{o}}}=\\left(\\cfrac{1}{2}\\right)^{\\cfrac{t}{T_{1/2}}}\\\\\nor, \\mathrm{N}=2.68 \\times 10^{18}\\left(\\cfrac{1}{2}\\right)^{\\cfrac{3440}{1620}}\\\\\n\\qquad=6.7 \\times 10^{17}\\\\\nNo. of atom disintegrated (\\mathrm{N})=\\mathrm{N}_{\\circ}-\\mathrm{N}\\\\\n=2.68 \\times 10^{18}-6.7 \\times 10^{17}\\\\\n=2.01 \\times 10^{18}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10101": {
                "ans1": "50w",
                "ans2": "100 w",
                "ans3": "200 w",
                "ans4": "400 w",
                "question_text": "A 100w -220v bulb is used in a line of 440v, power will be",
                "correct_ans": "400 w",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18574": {
                "ans1": "0{}^{0}c",
                "ans2": "0k",
                "ans3": "\\mathrm{\\infty }",
                "ans4": "equal to source",
                "question_text": "The efficiency of a heat engine will be 100% if the temperature of sink is",
                "correct_ans": "0k",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11971": {
                "ans1": "Water equivalent",
                "ans2": "Thermal capacity",
                "ans3": "Entropy",
                "ans4": "Specific heat",
                "question_text": "Amount of heat required to raise the temperature of a body through 1K\u00a0is called its",
                "correct_ans": "Thermal capacity",
                "explanation": "Q = m . c . \\Delta \\theta ; \\text { if } \\Delta \\theta = 1 K \\text { then } Q = m c = \\text { Thermal } \\text { capacity. }",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14041": {
                "ans1": "0.01 volt",
                "ans2": "0.02 volt",
                "ans3": "0.03 volt",
                "ans4": "0.04 volt",
                "question_text": "A coil of mean area 500cm{}^{2}{}_{~}and having 1000 turns is held perpendicular to a uniform field of 0.4 gauss. The coil is turned through 180{}^{0}\u00a0in 1/10 second. Calculate the average induced emf.",
                "correct_ans": "0.04 volt",
                "explanation": "Since plane of coil is perpendicular to field hence angle between B and A is\u00a00\u00ba.\\begin{aligned} \\phi_{1} &=\\mathrm{BA} \\cos 0^{\\circ}=\\mathrm{BA} \\\\ \\phi_{2} &=\\mathrm{BA} \\cos 180^{\\circ}=-\\mathrm{BA} \\\\ \\mathrm{E} &=-\\mathrm{N} \\cfrac{\\Delta \\phi}{\\Delta t}=\\cfrac{2 \\mathrm{NBA}}{t} \\\\ &=\\cfrac{2 \\times 1000 \\times 0.4 \\times 10^{-4} \\times 500 \\times 10^{-4}}{\\left(\\cfrac{1}{10}\\right)} \\\\ \\mathrm{E} &=0.04 \\mathrm{volt} \\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16541": {
                "ans1": "6 V",
                "ans2": "2.1 V",
                "ans3": "3.9 V",
                "ans4": "8.1 V",
                "question_text": "Photons of energy 6 eV are incident on a potassium surface of work function 2.1 eV. What is cut off potential?",
                "correct_ans": "3.9 V",
                "explanation": "From Einstein's equation,h f=\\phi_{0}+\\mathrm{K} \\mathrm{E}6 \\mathrm{eV}=2.1 \\mathrm{eV}+\\mathrm{KE}3.9 \\mathrm{eV}=\\mathrm{K.E.}Again, P.E. =\\mathrm{K.E.}e V_{c}=\\mathrm{K} \\mathrm{E}V_{c}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{K.E.}}{e}=\\cfrac{3.9 \\times 1.6 \\times 10^{-19}}{1.6 \\times 10^{-19}}\\qquad=3.9 volt\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19719": {
                "ans1": "100 J",
                "ans2": "300 J",
                "ans3": "600 J",
                "ans4": "900 J",
                "question_text": "The kinetic energy and momentum of a body are 100 J and 10 NS respectively. If momentum of the body is increased to 30 NS, then new KE of body will be",
                "correct_ans": "900 J",
                "explanation": "K E=\\cfrac{P^{2}}{2 m}m=\\cfrac{10^{2}}{2 \\times 100}=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\mathrm{kg}2nd\u00a0case,K E^{\\prime}=\\cfrac{P^{2}}{2 m}=\\cfrac{30^{2}}{2 \\times 0.5}=900 \\mathrm{J}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "10998": {
                "ans1": "49{}^{o} to\\space the\\space horizontal",
                "ans2": "90{}^{o} to\\space the\\space vertical",
                "ans3": "49{}^{o} to\\space the\\space vertical",
                "ans4": "Along the horizontal",
                "question_text": "The refractive index of water is 1.33. The direction in which a man under water should look to see the setting sun is",
                "correct_ans": "49{}^{o} to\\space the\\space vertical",
                "explanation": "Ray from the setting sun will be refracted at angle equal to critical angle.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19360": {
                "ans1": "smaller for heavier car",
                "ans2": "smaller for lighter car",
                "ans3": "same for both",
                "ans4": "depends on volume of car",
                "question_text": "Two cars of unequal mass use similar tyres. If they are moving at same initial speed, the minimum stopping distance is",
                "correct_ans": "same for both",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14011": {
                "ans1": "forward biased",
                "ans2": "reverse biased",
                "ans3": "positive biased",
                "ans4": "negative biased",
                "question_text": "The current through a\u00a0\\text{p-n}\u00a0junction is negligible when the junction is",
                "correct_ans": "reverse biased",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "11115": {
                "ans1": "4 sec",
                "ans2": "5 sec",
                "ans3": "6 sec",
                "ans4": "7 sec",
                "question_text": "A balloon is going up at steady velocity of 20 m/s. When it was 60 m above ground, an object is dropped from it. The time taken by object to reach ground is",
                "correct_ans": "6 sec",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{\\mathrm{h}=-\\mathrm{ut}+\\cfrac{1}{2} \\mathrm{gt}^{2}} \\\\ {\\text { or, } 60=-20 \\mathrm{t}+\\cfrac{1}{2} \\times \\mathrm{gt}^{2}} \\\\ {\\text { or, } 5 \\mathrm{t}^{2}-20 \\mathrm{t}-60=0} \\\\ {\\text { or, } \\mathrm{t}^{2}-4 \\mathrm{t}-12=0} \\\\ {\\text { or, } \\mathrm{t}(\\mathrm{t}-6)+2(\\mathrm{t}-6)=0} \\\\ {\\text { or, }(\\mathrm{t}-6)(\\mathrm{t}+2)=0} \\\\ {\\text { or, } \\mathrm{t}=6 \\text { or } \\mathrm{t}=-2} \\\\ {\\therefore \\mathrm{t}=6 \\mathrm{sec}}\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13633": {
                "ans1": "176.7{}^{0} F",
                "ans2": "189.7{}^{0} F",
                "ans3": "215.2{}^{0} F",
                "ans4": "312.5{}^{0} F",
                "question_text": "At what temperature the Kelvin scale will be double of that of Fahrenheit scale",
                "correct_ans": "176.7{}^{0} F",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{A=2 x, F=x} \\\\ {\\cfrac{A-273}{100}=\\cfrac{F-32}{180}}\\end{array}\n\\cfrac{2 x-273}{5}=\\cfrac{x-23}{9}\n\\begin{aligned} 18 x-2457 &=5 x-160 \\\\ x &=\\cfrac{2457-160}{13} \\\\ &=176.6^{0} F \\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "12800": {
                "ans1": "A is more elastic than B",
                "ans2": "B is more elastic than A.",
                "ans3": "A and B are equally elastic",
                "ans4": "A is elastic & B is plastic",
                "question_text": "Two identical wires of material A and B. On applying equal stretching force on them along length the elongation of A is more than B then",
                "correct_ans": "B is more elastic than A.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14494": {
                "ans1": "2.2 \\times 10{}^{-7}m",
                "ans2": "2.4 \\times 10{}^{-7}m",
                "ans3": "4.4 \\times 10{}^{-7}m",
                "ans4": "8.4 \\times 10{}^{-7}m",
                "question_text": "Retarding potential of 3.38v is required to stop the emission of electron from metallic surface by radiation of 2000\\mathring{A}. The threshold wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "4.4 \\times 10{}^{-7}m",
                "explanation": "\\phi=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{hc}}{\\lambda}-\\mathrm{KE}\\\\\nor, \\cfrac{\\mathrm{hc}}{\\lambda_{0}}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{hc}}{\\lambda}-\\mathrm{ev_s}\\\\\nor, \\lambda_{0}=\\cfrac{\\mathrm{hc}}{\\left(\\cfrac{\\mathrm{hc}}{\\lambda}-\\mathrm{ev_s}\\right)}\\\\\n=\\cfrac{6.62 \\times 10^{-34} \\times 3 \\times 10^{8}}{\\left(\\cfrac{6.62 \\times 10^{-34} \\times 3 \\times 10^{8}}\\\\\n{2000 \\times 10^{-10}}-1.6 \\times 10^{-19} \\times 3.38\\right)}\\\\\n=4.4 \\times 10^{-7} \\mathrm{m}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "15104": {
                "ans1": "9.34\\times10{}^{-3}J",
                "ans2": "3.54\\times10{}^{-3}J",
                "ans3": "9.84\\times10{}^{-4} J",
                "ans4": "3.45\\times10{}^{-4}J",
                "question_text": "The work done in blowing a drop of mercury of radius 4cm is\n[Surface Tension of mercury =464\u00a0dynes/cm]",
                "correct_ans": "9.34\\times10{}^{-3}J",
                "explanation": "\\mathrm{W}=\\mathrm{T} \\cdot \\mathrm{A}=\\mathrm{T} \\times 4 \\pi \\mathrm{R}^{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17888": {
                "ans1": "1: 2",
                "ans2": "2: 1",
                "ans3": "4: 1",
                "ans4": "1: 4",
                "question_text": "Two wire of same material and lengths are stretched by equal force then ratio of elongation if radius is 2: 1",
                "correct_ans": "1: 4",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{e_{1}}{e_{2}}=\\cfrac{\\cfrac{F L}{Y A_{1}}}{\\cfrac{F L}{Y A_{2}}}=\\cfrac{A_{2}}{A_{1}}=\\left(\\cfrac{r_{2}}{r_{1}}\\right)^{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18895": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "Decreases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "first increases then decreases",
                "question_text": "Water evaporate under atmospheric condition. Now water is placed in vacuum then rate of evaporation will\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "increases",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "19427": {
                "ans1": "25 m",
                "ans2": "20 m",
                "ans3": "15m",
                "ans4": "10m",
                "question_text": "Two sinusoidal wave with same wavelength and amplitude travel in opposite direction along a string with speed 10 m/s. The minimum time interval between instant when string is flat is 0.5s then wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "10m",
                "explanation": "String become flat means\\cfrac{T}{2}=0.5\\\\\nor, T=1 sec\\\\\nf=\\cfrac{1}{T}=1 H z\\\\\n\\lambda=\\cfrac{V}{f}=10 m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "17731": {
                "ans1": "0.03",
                "ans2": "0.025",
                "ans3": "0.012",
                "ans4": "0.018",
                "question_text": "The focal length of lens for red and violet colour are 16.2cm and 16cm respectively. The dispersive power of lens will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.012",
                "explanation": "\\omega=\\cfrac{f_{r}-f_{v}}{f}=\\cfrac{16.2-16}{\\sqrt{16.2 \\times 16}}=0.012",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "18539": {
                "ans1": "outwards pull on them",
                "ans2": "inertia",
                "ans3": "changing in momentum",
                "ans4": "change in acceleration",
                "question_text": "Passengers standing in a bus are thrown outwards when the bus takes a sudden turn. This happen because of",
                "correct_ans": "inertia",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "16399": {
                "ans1": "Mean square velocity",
                "ans2": "Motion of the molecule",
                "ans3": "Both (a) and (b)",
                "ans4": "None of the above",
                "question_text": "Absolute temperature can be calculated by",
                "correct_ans": "Mean square velocity",
                "explanation": "\\overline { v ^ { 2 } } \\propto T (Kelvin\\space Scale).\\therefore",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "13686": {
                "ans1": "0.33g/cc",
                "ans2": "0.46g/cc",
                "ans3": "0.66g/cc",
                "ans4": "0.769g/cc",
                "question_text": "Wooden block is found to float with 2/3 of volume inside water. The density of wood is",
                "correct_ans": "0.66g/cc",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{\\text { wt }=\\text { upthrust }} \\\\ {\\text { or, } \\operatorname{vpg}=2 / 3 \\mathrm{v} \\sigma_{\\mathrm{w}} \\mathrm{g}} \\\\ {\\therefore \\rho=\\cfrac{2}{3} \\sigma_{w}}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "14427": {
                "ans1": "2 MeV",
                "ans2": "1.5 MeV",
                "ans3": "1 MeV",
                "ans4": "0.5 MeV",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If mass equivalent to mass of electron is completely converted into energy then energy released during the process is",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 MeV",
                "explanation": "\\text{E} = \\Delta\\text{mc}{}^{2} mass of \\text{e}{}^{-} is 9.1 \\times 10{}^{-31} kg\n\\begin{array}{l}{=9.1 \\times 10^{-31}\\left(3 \\times 10^{8}\\right)^{2} \\mathrm{J}} \\\\ {=\\cfrac{9.1 \\times 10^{-31}\\left(3 \\times 10^{8}\\right)^{2}}{1.6 \\times 10^{-19} \\times 10^{6}} \\mathrm{MeV}} \\\\ {=0.51 \\mathrm{MeV}}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        },
        "2": {
            "29207": {
                "ans1": "68.3\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "-204.8\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "204.8\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "136.6\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "The temperature at which rms speed of gas molecule become half of 0\u00b0C\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "204.8\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "C_{rms\\;}\\alpha\\sqrt T",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22469": {
                "ans1": "11 mH",
                "ans2": "16mH",
                "ans3": "22mH",
                "ans4": "33mH",
                "question_text": "A long solenoid connected to a 12V de source passes a steady current of 2A. When solenoid is connected to an ac source of 12V at 50Hz. the current is found 1A the inductance of solenoid is",
                "correct_ans": "33mH",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;dc,\\\\R=\\frac VI=\\frac{12}1=12\\\\For\\;ac,\\\\Z=\\sqrt{R^2+X_L^2}=10.4\\\\2\\pi fL=10.4\\\\or,\\;L=33mH\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28937": {
                "ans1": "2.75 \u00d7 10\u00b9\u00b9m",
                "ans2": "2.1 \u00d7 10\u00b3m",
                "ans3": "8.25 x 10\u00b3 m",
                "ans4": "1.12 x 10 m",
                "question_text": "In young double slit experiment, interference pattern are obtained on screen at a distance of Im from slits separated by 0.05 cm and illuminted by light of 5893\u00c5.The distance between 4th bright fringe on one side and 3rd bright fringe on other side of central bright fringe is",
                "correct_ans": "8.25 x 10\u00b3 m",
                "explanation": "x=7\\beta=\\frac{7D\\lambda}d=8.25\\times10^{-3}m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21310": {
                "ans1": "18cm towards",
                "ans2": "36 cm towards",
                "ans3": "36cm away",
                "ans4": "18cm away",
                "question_text": "\u00a0An object is placed at 40cm from a concave mirror of focal length 15cm. If the object is displaced 20cm towards the mirror the displacement of image from mirror is",
                "correct_ans": "36cm away",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}1st\\;case:\\\\v=\\frac{fu}{u-f}=\\frac{15\\times40}{40-15}=24cm\\\\2nd\\;case:\\\\v'=\\frac{fu'}{u'-f}=60cm\\\\then\\;v'-v=36\\;cm\\;away\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22073": {
                "ans1": "0.4 m",
                "ans2": "4.9 m",
                "ans3": "19.6 m",
                "ans4": "20 m",
                "question_text": "A ballon is ascending vertically with an acceleration of 0.2 m/s^2. Two stones are dropped from it at an interval of 2 sec. The distance between them when the second stone dropped is (g = 9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
                "correct_ans": "20 m",
                "explanation": "h=\\frac12a_rt^2=\\frac12(g+a)\\times2^2=20",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20654": {
                "ans1": "773.5\t\u00c5",
                "ans2": "825.2\t\u00c5",
                "ans3": "973.5\t\u00c5",
                "ans4": "1212.5 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "A photon fall on hydrogen atom in ground state and excited to 4th energy level then wavelength of photon is",
                "correct_ans": "973.5\t\u00c5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}E_4-E_1=\\frac{hc}\\lambda\\\\\\lambda=\\frac{6.62\\times10^{-34}\\times3\\times10^8}{\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac{-13.6}{16}}+13.6\\right)1.6\\times10^{-19}}=970\\;\u00c5\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26937": {
                "ans1": "800\\;\\Omega",
                "ans2": "790 \u03a9",
                "ans3": "810 \u03a9",
                "ans4": "1190 \u03a9",
                "question_text": "A potentiometer of length 100cm has resistance 100. A source of 2V is connected across it then a source of 10mV is balance by the length of 40cm on potentiometer. The value of resistance needed in series of potentiometer is",
                "correct_ans": "790 \u03a9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}R=\\frac{10}{100}\\times40=4\\;\\Omega\\\\now,\\;\\frac{10\\;\\times10^{-3}}4=\\frac2{R+10}\\\\or,\\;R\\;=\\;790\\Omega\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21670": {
                "ans1": "927.3 \u00c5    ",
                "ans2": "966.8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "958.2 \u00c5    ",
                "ans4": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of a photon required to excite electron from ground state of hydrogen atom to its fourth excited state is",
                "correct_ans": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28207": {
                "ans1": "0.01%",
                "ans2": "0.1%",
                "ans3": "0.02%",
                "ans4": "0.2%",
                "question_text": "A sphere is taken to bottom of sea 1km deep then the volume of sphere decreases by, if Bulk modulus is 4.9 *10^{10}N/m\u00b2\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "0.2%",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\triangle V}V=\\frac PB=\\frac{\\rho gh}B=0.02\\%",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24077": {
                "ans1": "576 Hz",
                "ans2": "580 Hz",
                "ans3": "584 Hz",
                "ans4": "588 Hz",
                "question_text": "A fork is in unison with a sonometer wire 73\u00a0cm long. If 4 beats are heard on s shortening the wire by 5mm then the frequency of fork is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "584 Hz",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29093": {
                "ans1": "2.5",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "7.5",
                "ans4": "8.5",
                "question_text": "When a slab of insulating material 4mm thick is introduced between the plates of parallel plate capacitor then distance between plates has to be raised by 3.2mm to restore same capacity. The dielectric constant of material is",
                "correct_ans": "8.5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20865": {
                "ans1": "164 J",
                "ans2": "274J",
                "ans3": "374J",
                "ans4": "400J",
                "question_text": "A cylinder of fixed capacity 44.8 Its contains helium gas at standard temperature and pressure. The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of gas in cylinder by 15\u00b0C\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "374J",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}n=\\frac{44.8}{22.4}=2\\\\dQ=nC_vdT=2\\times\\frac32R\\times15=374\\;J\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29617": {
                "ans1": "1225 N",
                "ans2": "3050 N",
                "ans3": "1825 N",
                "ans4": "2550N",
                "question_text": "A stone of mass 5kg falls from the top of cliff of 50m high and buries Im deep in sand. The average resistance offered by sand is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "2550N",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}While\\;falling\\;,\\\\v^2=0^2+2gh\\\\v=\\sqrt{2\\ast10\\ast50}=\\sqrt{1000}\\\\In\\;sand,\\\\u=\\sqrt{1000}\\;,\\;v=0\\;,\\;s=1m\\\\v^2=u^2+2as\\\\a=-500m/s^2\\\\now,\\;F-mg=ma\\\\or,F=2250\\;N\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26060": {
                "ans1": "1m",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt2}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "2m",
                "question_text": "A small hole is made at a height of \\frac1{\\sqrt2}m from bottom of cylindrical tank at a depth of h = \u221a2 m from upper level of water. The distance at which water entering will strike the ground is",
                "correct_ans": "2m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v=\\sqrt{2g\\sqrt2}\\\\t=\\sqrt{\\frac{2h}g}=\\sqrt{\\frac2{\\sqrt2g}}\\\\R=vt=2\\;m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21692": {
                "ans1": "1.4 cc",
                "ans2": "2.4 cc",
                "ans3": "3.2 cc",
                "ans4": "2.8 cc",
                "question_text": "A piece of gold of density 19.3 g/cc is\nsuspected to be hollow inside. If weighs\n38.25g in air and 33.865g in water the volume\nof hollow portion is",
                "correct_ans": "2.4 cc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22156": {
                "ans1": "5N",
                "ans2": "10N",
                "ans3": "15N",
                "ans4": "20N",
                "question_text": "Two force whose magnitude are in the ratio of 3:5 act at an angle of 60\u00b0 and have resultant of 35N. The magnitude of smaller force is",
                "correct_ans": "15N",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}R=\\sqrt{F_1^2+2F_1F_2\\cos\\theta+F_2^2}\\\\35^2=(3x)^2+2\\times3x\\times5x\\times\\frac12+\\left(5x\\right)^2\\\\or,\\;x=5\\\\therefore\\;,\\;F_1=3x=15\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22300": {
                "ans1": "1 MeV",
                "ans2": "2 MeV",
                "ans3": "4 MeV",
                "ans4": "0.5 MeV",
                "question_text": "A proton of mass 'm' and charge te is moving in a circular path in magnetic field having energy 1Mev. The energy of a particle that can revolve in a circle of same radius is",
                "correct_ans": "1 MeV",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Bev=\\frac{mv^2}r\\\\Ber=\\sqrt{2mE}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20930": {
                "ans1": "306 m/s",
                "ans2": "340 m/s",
                "ans3": "331 m/s",
                "ans4": "360m/s",
                "question_text": "Two waves of wavelengths 50cm and 51cm\nproduce 12 beats/s then velocity of wave is\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "306 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21581": {
                "ans1": "13.6 eV",
                "ans2": "10.2 eV",
                "ans3": "12.09 eV",
                "ans4": "3.4 eV",
                "question_text": "The energy required to take an electron from ground state to 2nd excited state in Hydrogen atom is",
                "correct_ans": "12.09 eV",
                "explanation": "E=E_3-E_1=\\left(-\\frac{13.6}9+13.6\\right)eV=12.08\\;eV",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22154": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "10",
                "ans3": "12",
                "ans4": "14",
                "question_text": "In Young's double slit experiment. We\nobserve 10th maxima for light of 7000\u00c5\u00a0at\ncertain point. The order of maxima at same\npoint if light is replaced by 5000\u00c5\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}n_1\\lambda_1=n_2\\lambda_2\\\\n_1=14\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22465": {
                "ans1": "2\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans2": "2.12\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans3": "2.4\\times10^8m/s",
                "ans4": "2.5\\times10^8m/s",
                "question_text": "Angle of minimum deviation of a prism of refracting angle 60\u00b0 is 30\u00b0. The velocity of light in prism is",
                "correct_ans": "2.12\\times10^8m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\mu=\\frac{\\sin{\\displaystyle\\frac{A+d_{min}}2}}{\\sin{\\displaystyle\\frac A2}}=\\frac{\\sin\\;45}{\\sin30}=\\sqrt2\\\\\\mu=\\frac cv\\\\or,v=2.12\\times10^8m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23689": {
                "ans1": "0.15 V",
                "ans2": "1.5 V",
                "ans3": "0.15 mV",
                "ans4": "1.5 mV",
                "question_text": "A 10m long copper wire while remaining in the east west horizontal direction is falling\u00a0down with 5m/s. The horizontal component of earths magnetic field is 3\\times10^{-5}T\n then emf developed across end of wire is",
                "correct_ans": "1.5 mV",
                "explanation": "E=Blv",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26106": {
                "ans1": "12 \u00c5",
                "ans2": "4 \u00c5",
                "ans3": "0.31 \u00c5",
                "ans4": "0.124 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of most energetic x-ray emitted when metal target is bombarded by 100 KeV\u00a0electron is",
                "correct_ans": "0.124 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}E=\\frac{hc}{\\lambda_{min}}\\\\\\lambda_{min\\;}=\\frac{hc}E\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22953": {
                "ans1": "6.4\\times10^6m",
                "ans2": "1.92\\times10^6m",
                "ans3": "1.2\\times10^6m",
                "ans4": "2.1\\times10^6m",
                "question_text": "The depth from surface of earth at which acceleration due to gravity become 70% of its value on the surface of earth of radius R=6.4\\times10^6m",
                "correct_ans": "1.92\\times10^6m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}70\\%\\;of\\;g\\;=g\\left(1-\\frac xR\\right)\\\\or,\\frac7{10}=\\left(1-\\frac xR\\right)\\\\or,\\;x=1.92\\;\\times10^6m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25098": {
                "ans1": "20\u03a9",
                "ans2": "32\u03a9",
                "ans3": "48\u03a9",
                "ans4": "50\u03a9",
                "question_text": "The deflection of the galvanometer falls from 50 divisions to 10 divisions when a 12\u03a9 shunt is added. The resistance of the galvanometer is",
                "correct_ans": "48\u03a9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}S=\\frac{I_gG}{5I_g-I_g}=\\frac{I_gG}{4I_g}\\\\or,\\;G=4\\times12=48\\Omega\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26213": {
                "ans1": "2.5\\times10^{-3}A",
                "ans2": "1.5\\times10^{-3}A",
                "ans3": "3.1\\times10^{-3}A",
                "ans4": "3.7\\times10^{-3}A",
                "question_text": "A circuit consists a resistance of 10\u03a9 and capacitance of 0.1 \u00b5F. An emf of 100V, 50Hz is applied then current in circuit is",
                "correct_ans": "3.1\\times10^{-3}A",
                "explanation": "I=\\frac VZ=\\frac{100}{\\sqrt{R^2+X_c^2}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29043": {
                "ans1": "66%",
                "ans2": "50%",
                "ans3": "17%",
                "ans4": "33%",
                "question_text": "Pressure of gas increases by 50% at constant\ntemperature then volume of gas decreases by",
                "correct_ans": "33%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25323": {
                "ans1": "5 s",
                "ans2": "8 s",
                "ans3": "10 s",
                "ans4": "12 s",
                "question_text": "Two trains of 120m & 80m in length are\nrunning in opposite direction with velocity 42\nkm/hr and 30 km/hr then time in which they\ncross each other is",
                "correct_ans": "10 s",
                "explanation": "t=\\frac{l_1+l_2}{v_1+v_2}=\\frac{200}{20}=10\\;s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22122": {
                "ans1": "2m",
                "ans2": "3m",
                "ans3": "4m",
                "ans4": "6m",
                "question_text": "The electric potential at certain point is 600V and electric field strength at that point is 150 N/C. The distance of point is",
                "correct_ans": "4m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}E=\\frac Vd\\\\d=\\frac VE=\\frac{600}{150}=4m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22656": {
                "ans1": "(\\frac n{n+1})\\;mgR",
                "ans2": "(\\frac n{n-1})\\;mgR",
                "ans3": "n gmR",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\;mgR}n",
                "question_text": "The change in gravitational potential energy of a body of mass 'm' raised to a height nR from surface of earth of radius R is",
                "correct_ans": "(\\frac n{n+1})\\;mgR",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\triangle PE\\;=\\frac{\\displaystyle-GMm}{R+h}-\\;\\left(-\\frac{\\displaystyle GMm}R\\right)\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=GMm\\left[\\frac{\\displaystyle1}R-\\frac1{R+nR}\\right]\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{\\displaystyle GMm}R\\left[\\frac{n+1-1}{n+1}\\right]\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;\\frac{gR^2m}R\\times\\frac n{n+1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle n}{\\displaystyle n+1}\\right)mgR\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23238": {
                "ans1": "340 m/s",
                "ans2": "330 m/s",
                "ans3": "360 m/s",
                "ans4": "320 m/s",
                "question_text": "The apparent frequency of a note is 200Hz when a listener is moving with a velocity of 40m/s towards stationary source. When moves away from same source with same speed apparent frequency is 160Hz. The velocity of sound is",
                "correct_ans": "360 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26020": {
                "ans1": "0.15 V",
                "ans2": "1.5 V",
                "ans3": "0.15 mV",
                "ans4": "1.5 mV",
                "question_text": "A 10m long copper wire while remaining in the east west horizontal direction is falling\u00a0down with 5m/s. The horizontal component of earths magnetic field is 3\\times10^{-5}T\n then emf developed across end of wire is",
                "correct_ans": "1.5 mV",
                "explanation": "E=Blv",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26139": {
                "ans1": "4 sec",
                "ans2": "2 sec",
                "ans3": "8 sec",
                "ans4": "10 sec",
                "question_text": "The moment of inertia of body is\u00a01.2kgm^2 which is initially at rest. On applying angular acceleration of\u00a025 rad/s^2 the time taken by it to require rotational KE of 1500J is",
                "correct_ans": "2 sec",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22627": {
                "ans1": "2.5g",
                "ans2": "3.7g",
                "ans3": "6.3g",
                "ans4": "1.35g",
                "question_text": "A sample of 10g initially decay then mass after two mean lives is",
                "correct_ans": "1.35g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20284": {
                "ans1": "5s",
                "ans2": "10s",
                "ans3": "90s",
                "ans4": "100s",
                "question_text": "A thief is running on straight road with 9m/s. A policeman chase him on a motorcycle with 10m/s from the instant when separation is 100m. The time in which policeman catch the thief is",
                "correct_ans": "100s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21519": {
                "ans1": "2Kv",
                "ans2": "5Kv",
                "ans3": "7Kv",
                "ans4": "10Kv",
                "question_text": "A magnetic field of 20T is applied normal to coil of 100 turns & area 10^{-2}m\u00b2. If coil is removed from magnetic field in 2ms then induced emf will be",
                "correct_ans": "10Kv",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21898": {
                "ans1": "1.2 cm",
                "ans2": "1.5 cm",
                "ans3": "1.8 cm",
                "ans4": "2 cm",
                "question_text": "An air bubble of radius 1cm at bottom of pond at 7\u00b0C temperature & 5.6 atmospheric pressure rises to surface at 27\u00b0C then radius of bubble will be",
                "correct_ans": "1.8 cm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\displaystyle P_1V_1}{T_1}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\;P_2V_2}{T_2}\\;\\\\\\frac{\\displaystyle\\;5.6A}{280}\\times\\frac{\\displaystyle\\;4\\pi}3r_1^3\\;=\\frac{A\\times4\\pi}{300\\times3}r_2^3\\\\\\frac{\\displaystyle5.6\\;\\times\\;1\\;}{280}=\\frac{\\displaystyle r_2^3}{300}\\;\\\\\\;r_2=1.8\\;cm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22077": {
                "ans1": "0.1V",
                "ans2": "0.3V",
                "ans3": "0.5V",
                "ans4": "1.1V",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of light incident on a metal surface changes from 2100\u00c5 to 2000\u00c5 then change in stopping potential is",
                "correct_ans": "0.3V",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22276": {
                "ans1": "60 Ohm",
                "ans2": "47 Ohm",
                "ans3": "57 Ohm",
                "ans4": "35 Ohm",
                "question_text": "A wire of length 100cm is connected to a cell of 2V & negligible internal resistance. The resistance of wire is 3 Ohm\u00a0then additional resistance needed to produce a Pd of 1mv per cm is",
                "correct_ans": "57 Ohm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22462": {
                "ans1": "4.4 cm",
                "ans2": "9.8 cm",
                "ans3": "15 cm",
                "ans4": "20 cm",
                "question_text": "A 5cm square slide is to be projected on a screen 2m square. The distance between slide and screen is 4.1m then focal length of projecting lens is",
                "correct_ans": "9.8 cm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}m=\\frac IO=\\frac2{0.05}=40=\\frac vu\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;v=40u\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;41u=4.1\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;u=0.1m\\;\\&\\;v=4m\\;\\\\f=\\frac{uv}{u+v}=\\frac{0.1\\times4}{0.1+4}=0.097m=9.7cm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27362": {
                "ans1": "0.6 mm",
                "ans2": "1.5 mm",
                "ans3": "3 mm",
                "ans4": "4.5 mm",
                "question_text": "Two slits separated by a distance of 1mm are illuminated with light of wavelength 6\\times10^{-7}m. The interference fringes observed on a screen placed at 1m from slit. The distance between third dark fringe and 5th bright fringe is",
                "correct_ans": "1.5 mm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2.5\\beta=2.5\\frac{D\\lambda}d\\\\=\\frac{2.5\\times1\\times6\\times10^{-7}}{10^{-3}}\\\\=1.5\\times10^{-3}m\\\\=1.5mm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26807": {
                "ans1": "4m",
                "ans2": "7m",
                "ans3": "3m",
                "ans4": "6m",
                "question_text": "A large block of ice 10m thick has a vertical hole drilled through it the block is floating in lake then minimum length of rope required to scoop up a bucket full of water through hole is, if relative density of ice is 0.7",
                "correct_ans": "3m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Wt.=\\;upthrust\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;A\\times10\\times700g=A(10-x)\\times1000g\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;7=(10-x)\\;\\\\or,\\;x=\\;3m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28967": {
                "ans1": "8dB",
                "ans2": "5.6 dB",
                "ans3": "10.5 dB",
                "ans4": "25 dB",
                "question_text": "A loud speaker produces a sound of intensity level of 8 dB\u00a0above a certain reference level at a point 40m from it. The intensity level at 30m from loud speaker is",
                "correct_ans": "10.5 dB",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}L_2-L_1=10\\;\\log\\left(\\frac{r_1}{r_2}\\right)^2\\\\L_2=8+20\\log\\left(\\frac{40}{30}\\right)=10.5\\;db\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28408": {
                "ans1": "20 cm",
                "ans2": "14 cm",
                "ans3": "43/3 cm",
                "ans4": "6 cm",
                "question_text": "Two immiscible transparent liquid of refractive index 1.5 and 4/3 are arranged one above another of 8cm first and 12cm\u00a02^{nd}\u00a0layer. The apparent depth of mark at bottom is",
                "correct_ans": "43/3 cm",
                "explanation": "apparent\\;depth\\;=\\frac{t_1}{\\mu_1}+\\frac{t_2}{\\mu_2}=\\frac8{1.5}+\\frac{12}{4/3}=\\frac{43}3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25956": {
                "ans1": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans2": "11\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans3": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-20}J",
                "ans4": "7.5\\;\\times10^{-18}J",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The radiation of wavelength 180mm ejects photo electrons from a plate of potassium of work function 2eV. The maximum KE of emitted electrons will be",
                "correct_ans": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "explanation": "KE=\\frac{hc}\\lambda-\\phi",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29929": {
                "ans1": "2.5 PF to 250 PF",
                "ans2": "5 PF to 500 PF",
                "ans3": "7.5 PF to 750 PF",
                "ans4": "10 PF to 1000 PF",
                "question_text": "A radio tunner has frequency range from 500k Hz to 5 MHz. The LC circuit has effective inductance 400H\u00a0then range of capacitor is",
                "correct_ans": "2.5 PF to 250 PF",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24724": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/5 s",
                "ans2": "2\u03c0 s",
                "ans3": "20\u03c0 s",
                "ans4": "5\u03c0 s",
                "question_text": "The KE of a particle of mass 5.12kg and amplitude of oscillation is 25cm is 16J\u00a0at mean position .The oscillation is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/5 s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}KE=\\frac12m\\omega^2r^2\\\\\\omega=\\sqrt{\\frac{2\\ast16}{5.1\\ast0.25^2}}=\\frac{2\\pi}T\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27718": {
                "ans1": "-2.5 D",
                "ans2": "-6.25 D",
                "ans3": "+2.5 D",
                "ans4": "+1.5 D",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A person cannot see the objects clearly placed at a distance more than 40cm. The power of lens used by him",
                "correct_ans": "-2.5 D",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20835": {
                "ans1": "200W",
                "ans2": "25W",
                "ans3": "100W",
                "ans4": "300W",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}In\\;an\\;ac\\;circuit\\;the\\;instantaneous\\\\\\;value\\;of\\;emf\\;and\\;current\\;are\\\\\\;E\\;=\\;400\\sin314t\\;'V'\\;and\\\\\\;I=\\sin(314t+\\pi/3)A\\;then\\\\\\;average\\;power\\;\\;consumed\\;is\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "100W",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}P=I_{rms}V_{rms}\\cos\\varnothing\\\\\\;\\;=\\frac{I_0}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac{v_0}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\cos\\frac\\pi3\\\\\\;\\;=\\frac1{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac{400}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac12=100w\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28386": {
                "ans1": "3.95 H",
                "ans2": "15.8 H",
                "ans3": "3.95 H",
                "ans4": "31.2 H",
                "question_text": "The inductance of a coil 40cm\u00a0in length and 8cm in diameter having 1000 turns is",
                "correct_ans": "15.8 H",
                "explanation": "L=\\frac{\\mu_oN^2A}l",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23891": {
                "ans1": "0.66 A",
                "ans2": "0.99 A",
                "ans3": "0.33 A",
                "ans4": "0.15 A",
                "question_text": "\u00a04 cells of emf 1.5v and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0are connected in parallel. The combination is connected with 4\u03a9\u00a0resistance, value of current is",
                "correct_ans": "0.33 A",
                "explanation": "I=\\frac E{R+r/4}=\\frac{1.5}{4+2/4}=0.33\\;A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20764": {
                "ans1": "nV",
                "ans2": "n^2V",
                "ans3": "V/n",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "A soap bubble of radius r is charged to a potential 'V'. If the radius is increased to\u00a0nr. the potential on the bubble will be",
                "correct_ans": "V/n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27821": {
                "ans1": "102\u03a9",
                "ans2": "288\u03a9",
                "ans3": "300\u03a9",
                "ans4": "412\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A milli ammeter of resistance 12\u03a9\u00a0can give full scale deflection for a current of 0.01A. The resistance needed in series to convert it into a voltmeter of full scale deflection 3V\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "288\u03a9",
                "explanation": "R=\\frac V{I_g}-G=\\frac3{0.01}-12=288\\Omega ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28691": {
                "ans1": "9 m/s",
                "ans2": "12 m/s",
                "ans3": "15 m/s",
                "ans4": "18 m/s",
                "question_text": "A shell explodes into three fragments of equal masses. Two fragments fly of at right angles to each other with speed of 9 m/s and 12 m/s then speed of 3^{rd}\u00a0fragment is",
                "correct_ans": "15 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mv=\\sqrt{(9m)^2+(12m)^2}\\\\v=\\sqrt{81+144}=15\\;m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20261": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "75\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A particle is projected from the ground with 25m/s. After 2s it just clear a wall of 5m high. The angle of projection is",
                "correct_ans": "30\u00b0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}h=u\\;\\sin\\theta t-\\frac12gt^2\\\\5=25\\;\\times\\sin\\theta\\;\\times2-\\frac12\\times10\\times2^2\\\\\\theta=30\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26687": {
                "ans1": "0.96\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "1.02\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "1.16\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "0.23\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Water falls from a height of 500m then difference in temperature between bottom & top of water fall is",
                "correct_ans": "1.16\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mgh=msd\\theta\\\\d\\theta=\\frac{9.8\\ast500}{4200}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27891": {
                "ans1": " 0.034 mm",
                "ans2": "0.34 mm",
                "ans3": "3.4 mm",
                "ans4": "34 mm",
                "question_text": "In Young's double slit experiment, the distance from centre of interference pattern to tenth bright fringe on either side is 3.44cm. The distance of slit from one screen is 2m for light of wavelength 5.89*10^{-7} m then slit separation is",
                "correct_ans": "0.34 mm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}3.44\\times10\\;^{\\;-2}\\;\\;=10\\times\\beta=10\\times D\\ast\\;\\lambda/d\\\\\\;\u200b\\;\\;\\;\\;So\\;d=0.342\\;mm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28553": {
                "ans1": "100 Hz",
                "ans2": "150 Hz",
                "ans3": "200 Hz",
                "ans4": "300 Hz",
                "question_text": "An open pipe is suddenly closed the with result that the second overtone of the closed pipe is found to be higher in frequency by 100HZ than first overtone of original pipe. The fundamental frequency of open pipe will be",
                "correct_ans": "200 Hz",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Foropen\\;f_o=\\frac v{2l}fo\u200b=\\frac{\\displaystyle v}{2l}\u200b\\\\Forclosed\\;f_c=\\frac v{4l}=\\frac{fo}2\\\\\u200b\u200bNow,5f_c-2f_o=100\\\\or,5\\frac{fo}2-2f_o=100\\\\or,fo=200Hz\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20082": {
                "ans1": "50N",
                "ans2": "25N",
                "ans3": "20N",
                "ans4": "30N",
                "question_text": "The blocks A & B of mass 10kg and 15kg are placed on smooth horizontal table in contact with each other. A horizontal force of 50N is applied on A and B would exert force on A is given by",
                "correct_ans": "30N",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20554": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "48",
                "ans4": "72",
                "question_text": "A number of capacitors each of capacitance 1\u03bcF and each one gets punctured if potential difference exceeds 500v. The capacitor of capacitance 2\u03bcF across which 3000V is applied then no. of capacitors are",
                "correct_ans": "72",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25620": {
                "ans1": "6ohm",
                "ans2": "6kohm",
                "ans3": "500ohm",
                "ans4": "6.6 kohm",
                "question_text": "A galvanometer has 30 divisions and sensitivity 16\u00b5A/div. It can be converted into a voltmeter to read 3V by connecting a resistance of",
                "correct_ans": "6kohm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Ig\u200b=480\u00b5A\\\\R=\\frac V{I_g}=\\frac3{480\\times10^{-6}}=6250\\Omega=6.2k\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28172": {
                "ans1": "12:5",
                "ans2": "5:12",
                "ans3": "1:2",
                "ans4": "2:1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two capillaries of an 64. Two capillaries of same diameter are dipped into liquids of specific gravity 0.4 & 0.8 respectively. If their surface tensions are in the ratio 6:5, then the ratio of heights of liquids in them will be",
                "correct_ans": "12:5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\displaystyle2T2}{\u200b2T1\u200b}\u200b=\\frac{\\displaystyle\u200br\\rho1\u200bgh1\u200br}{\\rho2\u200bgh2}\\\\\u200bHence\\frac{h_1}{h_2}=\\frac{T_1}{T_2}\\times\\frac{\\rho_2}{\\rho_1}=\\frac{12}5\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22884": {
                "ans1": "2.34 mm",
                "ans2": "1.67 mm",
                "ans3": "4.68 mm",
                "ans4": " 9.34 mm",
                "question_text": "A red light of 6500\u00c5 from distant source falls on a slit of 0.5mm wide. The distance between two dark bands on each side of central bright band of diffraction pattern on screen placed at 1.8m from slit will be.",
                "correct_ans": "4.68 mm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac xD\u200b=\\frac{\\lambda\u200b}d\\\\x=D\\times\\frac\\lambda d\\\\\u200bSinceitisdistancebetweendarkbands;\\\\so2x=2\\times D\\times\\frac\\lambda d=4.68\\times10^{-3}m=4.68mm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23580": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "In Young\u2019s double experiment is used for light of 600 nm and 480 nm where nth order of 1st concide with\u00a0(n + 1)^{th}  order of second then value of n is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{xd}D\\;\u200b\\;\\;=n\\times\\lambda_1=(n+1)\\times\\lambda_2\\\\Hence,\\;n=4\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22056": {
                "ans1": "200 m/s",
                "ans2": "400 m/s",
                "ans3": " 600 m/s",
                "ans4": "700 m/s",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two paper sereen 'A' and B' separated by a distance of 200m. A bullet pierces \u2018A' and then 'B'. The hole in B is 40cm below the hole in 'A' then velocity of bullet at A is",
                "correct_ans": "700 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}t=\\sqrt{\\frac{\\displaystyle2h}g}\u200b\u200b=\\sqrt{\\frac{\\displaystyle2\\ast0.4}{10}}\u200b\u200b=0.28sec\\\\v=\\frac{\\displaystyle x}{\\displaystyle t}=\\frac{\\displaystyle200}{\\displaystyle0.28}=707m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28025": {
                "ans1": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans2": "11\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans3": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-20}J",
                "ans4": "7.5\\;\\times10^{-18}J",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The radiation of wavelength 180mm ejects photo electrons from a plate of potassium of work function 2eV. The maximum KE of emitted electrons will be",
                "correct_ans": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "explanation": "KE=\\frac{hc}\\lambda-\\phi",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24434": {
                "ans1": "1000 V",
                "ans2": "141.4 V",
                "ans3": "282.8 V",
                "ans4": " 70.7 V",
                "question_text": "In series of LCR circuit R=10000 ohm, L= 2 H and C=1 \u03bcF is supplied with a source of emf E=100\u221a2 sin1000t V then potential difference across 'R' will be",
                "correct_ans": " 70.7 V",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}z=\\sqrt{R^2+(XL\u200b-XC\u200b)^2}\u200b=1000\\sqrt2\u200bohm\\\\V_{rms}=\\frac{V_o}{\\sqrt2}=100V\\\\I=\\frac{Vrms}z\u200b=\\frac1{10\\sqrt2}\u200b\\\\V_R=IR=70.7V\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25057": {
                "ans1": "5N",
                "ans2": "6N",
                "ans3": "4N",
                "ans4": "8N",
                "question_text": "On horizontal surface of truck a block of mass 1kg is placed having coefficient of friction 0.6 then truck accelerate at 5 m/s then frictional force on block will be",
                "correct_ans": "5N",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Forceduetoinertia,F=ma=1\\times5=5N\\\\Limitingforceoffriction,F_l=\\mu sR=0.6\\times mg=0.6\\times10=6N\\\\F<F_l\u200bso\\\\Frictionalforce(F_r)=F=5N\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28546": {
                "ans1": "95.8 ohm",
                "ans2": " 173.2 ohm",
                "ans3": "84.5 ohm",
                "ans4": " 99.1 ohm",
                "question_text": "A 25.4 micro F capacitor, a 0.1H inductor and a 25ohm resistor are connected in series with an ac whose emf is V = 310 sin3 /4t then impedence of circuit is.",
                "correct_ans": " 99.1 ohm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28564": {
                "ans1": "5g",
                "ans2": "4g",
                "ans3": "2g",
                "ans4": "3g",
                "question_text": "A vessel has 6g of oxygen at pressure P and temperature 400K. A small hole is made on it so the oxygen leaks out. The mass of oxygen leak out if pressure drops to P/2 at temperature 300K is",
                "correct_ans": "2g",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}1stcase:P_1v=m_1rT_1\\\\2ndcase.P_2v=m_2rT_2\\\\or,\\frac{P_2}{P_1}=\\frac{m_2}{m_1}\\times\\frac{T_2}{T_1}\\Rightarrow m_2=4g\\\\\\text{mass leak}=6-4=2g\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27545": {
                "ans1": "-10 cm",
                "ans2": "-20 cm",
                "ans3": "-30 cm",
                "ans4": "-40 cm",
                "question_text": "A diverging lens is placed on the axis of a e concave mirror of focal length 15 cm at a distance of 15 cm from mirror. When an object placed at 30 cm from lens and its inverted image coincide, then focal length of lens is",
                "correct_ans": "-30 cm",
                "explanation": "Light incident normally on mirror so If focus at c i.e. r=2f=2\u00d715=30\u00a0cm and\u00a0v=-(30 \u2013 15) = -15v=\u2212(30\u201315)=\u221215\u00a0cm;\\dfrac{uv}{(u+v)}so\u00a0f=-30 cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23237": {
                "ans1": "7m/s^2",
                "ans2": "6m/s^2",
                "ans3": "5m/s^2",
                "ans4": "4m/s^2",
                "question_text": "A force of 5N can produce an acceleration of 8\u00a0m/s^2on a body of mass\u00a0m_1m1\u200b\u00a0and same force can produce an acceleration of 24m/s^2\u00a0on mass\u00a0m_2. The acceleration on both mass tied together by same force is",
                "correct_ans": "6m/s^2",
                "explanation": "\\dfrac{F}{a} = \\dfrac{5}{8} \\dfrac{F}{a} = \\dfrac{5}{24}(m_1+m_2)a \\dfrac{5}{\\dfrac{5}{8}+ \\dfrac{5}{24}}=6 m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27133": {
                "ans1": "619/1000",
                "ans2": "9/200",
                "ans3": "14/205",
                "ans4": "5/214",
                "question_text": "A parallel beam of white light falls on a convex lens. Images of blue, yellow and red light are formed on the other side of the lens at distance 20 cm, 20.5 cm and 21.4 cm respectively. The dispersive power of the material of the lens is",
                "correct_ans": "14/205",
                "explanation": "fr\u200b=21.4\u00a0cmfb=20 cmfy=20.5 cmw=\\dfrac{(f_r-f_b)}{(f_y)}=\\dfrac{14}{205}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24372": {
                "ans1": "+3%",
                "ans2": "+3.2%",
                "ans3": "-3.2%",
                "ans4": "-3%",
                "question_text": "A piano string of diameter 0.90 mm is replaced by another wire of same material of diameter 0.93 mm then % change in fundamental frequency is.",
                "correct_ans": "-3.2%",
                "explanation": "(\\dfrac{f'}{f}-1)\\times 100\\%=-3.2\\%",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27445": {
                "ans1": "18 m",
                "ans2": "9m",
                "ans3": "5 m",
                "ans4": "2 m",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The thickness of layer of ice on surface of lake is 20 m. A hole is made in ice layer. Then minimum length of rope required to take a bucket full of water is (Density of ice= 900\u00a0kg/m^3\u00a0)",
                "correct_ans": "2 m",
                "explanation": "wt = upthrustor,A\u00d7L\u00d7\u03c1ig\u200b=A\u00d7(20\u2212x)\u00d7\u03c1wg\u200bor, 20\u00d7900=(20\u2212x)\u00d71000or, 18=20\u2212xor,x=2\u00a0m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22985": {
                "ans1": "12 m",
                "ans2": "8 m",
                "ans3": "6 m",
                "ans4": "4 m",
                "question_text": "A point source of y radiation has half life 30min. The initial count rate by GM counter at 4m is 360 counts/s then after 1.5 hrs the distance is altered and count rate become 5 counts/s. The distance between source &counter is changed by",
                "correct_ans": "8 m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20718": {
                "ans1": "2  (\u03bc  1 \u200b  +\u03bc  2 \u200b  ) / (\u03bc  1 \u200b  \u03bc  2 \u200b  ) \u200b  ",
                "ans2": " (\u03bc  1 \u200b  \u03bc  2 \u200b  ) \u200b/2(\u03bc  1 \u200b  +\u03bc  2 \u200b  )",
                "ans3": "t   (\u03bc  1 \u200b  +\u03bc  2 \u200b  ) \u200b/(2\u03bc  1 \u200b  \u03bc  2 \u200b)  ",
                "ans4": "2t   (\u03bc  1 \u200b  +\u03bc  2 \u200b  ) \u200b /(\u03bc  1 \u200b  \u03bc  2 \u200b  )",
                "question_text": "A vessel of depth 'l' is half filled with water of refractive index \u03bc1\u200b, and the other half is filled with a liquid of refractive index \u03bc2\u200b. The apparent depth of vessel as seen from above is",
                "correct_ans": "t   (\u03bc  1 \u200b  +\u03bc  2 \u200b  ) \u200b/(2\u03bc  1 \u200b  \u03bc  2 \u200b)  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25281": {
                "ans1": "\u221a7 R",
                "ans2": "\u221a3 R",
                "ans3": "2R",
                "ans4": "8R",
                "question_text": "The magnetic flux density at centre of circular coil of radius 'R' is Bo then flux density at a point on axis is\u00a0B_o/8 then distance of point from centre will be",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 R",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28491": {
                "ans1": "1.7 V",
                "ans2": "1.6 V",
                "ans3": "1.5 V",
                "ans4": "1 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The threshold wavelength of metal is 4000 \u00c5 then the light of wavelength 3000 \u00c5 incident on metal then stopping potential will be",
                "correct_ans": "1 V",
                "explanation": "KE=hc\u200b/\u03bb\u2212\u200bhc/\u03bbo\u200b=1.65\u00d710^\u221219\u00a0J\u00a0V_s = \\dfrac{KE}{e} = 1V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20773": {
                "ans1": "1 cm",
                "ans2": "2 cm",
                "ans3": "4 cm",
                "ans4": "8 cm",
                "question_text": "A small object is placed on rotating horizontal turntable just slip when it is placed 4 cm from axis of rotation. If angular speed of turntable is doubled then object slips when the distance of the object from the axis of rotation is",
                "correct_ans": "2 cm",
                "explanation": "\u00a0\\omega^2\\dfrac{r_2}{r_1}=(\\dfrac{\\omega}{2\\omega})^2\u200b=1\u00a0cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22003": {
                "ans1": "2.5 mA",
                "ans2": "5\u221a2 mA",
                "ans3": "s mA",
                "ans4": "5/\u221a2 mA",
                "question_text": "Emf of a source is\u00a0E = 50\\sqrt{2} \\sin(100t)\u00a0is connected across the capacitor of 1\u03bcF\u00a0then ammeter reading will be",
                "correct_ans": "s mA",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28309": {
                "ans1": "1:2",
                "ans2": "2:1",
                "ans3": "9:1",
                "ans4": "1:3",
                "question_text": "Two capacitors of capacitance in the ratio of 1:2 are connected in series to a source of emf 180V. The ratio of energy stored by capacitor is",
                "correct_ans": "2:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27592": {
                "ans1": "0.4\u03a9",
                "ans2": "0.3\u03a9",
                "ans3": "0.2\u03a9",
                "ans4": "0.1\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A galvanometer of resistance 100\u03a9\u00a0is converted into a voltmeter of range 10 V by connecting a resistance of 10 k\u03a9. The resistance required to convert the galvanometer into ammeter of range 1A is",
                "correct_ans": "0.1\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23163": {
                "ans1": "5 cm",
                "ans2": "10 cm",
                "ans3": "20 cm",
                "ans4": "40 cm",
                "question_text": "A luminous object is placed at 20cm from surface of convex and a plane mirror is set so that virtual image of two mirror coincide. The plane mirror is at 12cm from object then the focal length of convex mirror is",
                "correct_ans": "5 cm",
                "explanation": "f=uV\u200b/(u+V)=\u22125\u00a0cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28949": {
                "ans1": "29 min",
                "ans2": "30 min",
                "ans3": "32 min",
                "ans4": "40 min",
                "question_text": "The half of a substance when one-eighteen count is remained after 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": "29 min",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20137": {
                "ans1": "20000 V/m     ",
                "ans2": "10000 V/m     ",
                "ans3": "500 V/m",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Two plates of potential 10 V and -10 V are separated at distance of 0.1 cm. The electric field produced between plates is",
                "correct_ans": "20000 V/m     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20426": {
                "ans1": "230^0 C ",
                "ans2": "120^0 C ",
                "ans3": "100^0 C ",
                "ans4": "80^0 C ",
                "question_text": "1 gm of steam at 100^0\n C and 1 gm of ice at 0^0 C are mixed. The resulting temperature of mixture is",
                "correct_ans": "100^0 C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25782": {
                "ans1": "2000/3 ohm",
                "ans2": "1000/3 ohm",
                "ans3": "500/3 ohm",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The equivalent resistance of the given circuit is",
                "correct_ans": "2000/3 ohm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25740": {
                "ans1": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-5 T",
                "ans2": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-4 T",
                "ans3": "5.56 \u00d7 10-3 T",
                "ans4": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "question_text": "The magnetic field at center of circular\u00a0 coil of radius 10 cm having 500 turns of coil and carrying current 18 A is",
                "correct_ans": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21665": {
                "ans1": "2MR^2",
                "ans2": "MR^2/2",
                "ans3": "3MR^2\\2",
                "ans4": "MR^2",
                "question_text": "In a rotational motion,\u00a0 a solid cylinder of mass \u2018M\u2019 and radius \u2018R\u2019 is rotated about its tangent to its axis. Moment of Inertia of solid cylinder is",
                "correct_ans": "3MR^2\\2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22864": {
                "ans1": "1.5 cm",
                "ans2": "3 cm",
                "ans3": "4.5 cm",
                "ans4": "6 cm",
                "question_text": "Velocity of light in glass vessel is 2 \u00d7\u00a010^8 m/s and 3 \u00d7 10^8 m/s in air. If a glass slab of thickness 9 cm is kept\u00a0 covering ink dot\u00a0 at its bottom, the height through which the ink dot will be appeared to be raised by in slab is",
                "correct_ans": "3 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27281": {
                "ans1": "7 \u00c5   ",
                "ans2": "8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "9 \u00c5   ",
                "ans4": "10 \u00c5   ",
                "question_text": "The de Broglie wavelength of an electron in third orbit of H-atom is",
                "correct_ans": "10 \u00c5   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24029": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The magnification of a convex lens of focal length 20 cm when an object is placed at 10 cm in front of lens is",
                "correct_ans": "infinity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22113": {
                "ans1": "10 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "20 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "30 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "40 m/s   ",
                "question_text": "A bucket full of water has a hole at its bottom. If the pressure at the bottom is 3 atm, the velocity of efflux from hole is",
                "correct_ans": "20 m/s   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28457": {
                "ans1": "484.08 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "466.28 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "458.42 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "452.82 m/s",
                "question_text": "The density of Nitrogen gas at STP is 1.293 Kg/m^3. The root mean square speed of oxygen molecule at STP is",
                "correct_ans": "452.82 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27525": {
                "ans1": "50.76^0",
                "ans2": "39.23^0",
                "ans3": "23.57^0",
                "ans4": "11.67^0",
                "question_text": "60% of original kinetic energy of a projectile is lost when it reaches at top of trajectory. The angle of projection of projectile is",
                "correct_ans": "50.76^0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24660": {
                "ans1": "+60.06 KV   ",
                "ans2": "-60.06 KV   ",
                "ans3": "+62.06 KV   ",
                "ans4": "-62.06 KV   ",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of emitted electron from a metal surface after striking of photon on it is 0.2 \u00c5. The stopping potential required for this electron is",
                "correct_ans": "-62.06 KV   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26170": {
                "ans1": "0.158 m^3",
                "ans2": "0.125 m^3   ",
                "ans3": "0.034 m^3",
                "ans4": "0.001 m^3",
                "question_text": "A rock weighs 1400 N in air weighs 300 N in a liquid of density 900 Kg/m^3. The volume of rock is",
                "correct_ans": "0.125 m^3   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29062": {
                "ans1": "1 mV",
                "ans2": "10 mV",
                "ans3": "1 V",
                "ans4": "10 V",
                "question_text": "A railway tracks separated by\u00a01m\u00a0are connected to a voltmeter. The horizontal component of earths magnetic field is\u00a00.2wb/m^2 and speed of train is 180km/hr\u00a0then reading of voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "10 V",
                "explanation": "E=Blv",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20071": {
                "ans1": "1 : \u221a2",
                "ans2": "\u221a2 : 1",
                "ans3": "1 : 2",
                "ans4": "2 : 1",
                "question_text": "Doubly ionized helium atom and hydrogen ions are accelerated from rest, through the same potential difference. The ratio of final velocities of helium and hydrogen is",
                "correct_ans": "1 : 2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23384": {
                "ans1": "0.05 s",
                "ans2": "0.1 s",
                "ans3": "0.2 s",
                "ans4": "0.4 s",
                "question_text": "The string of length\u00a00.4m\u00a0and mass\u00a010^{-2} kg is clamped at its ends. The tension in the string is\u00a01.6 N when pulse travel along the string, the shape of string is found to be same after\u00a0t\u00a0and\u00a0t + \u0394t\u00a0then value of \u0394t\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0.1 s",
                "explanation": "f=\\frac1{2l}\\sqrt{\\frac{lT}M}\\;=\\;10\\;Hz",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29560": {
                "ans1": "2t",
                "ans2": "4t/\u221a3",
                "ans3": "\u221a3 t",
                "ans4": "t",
                "question_text": "A block released on 60\u00b0\u00a0smooth inclined plane at certain height reaches the ground in time 't'. If the block is released on a 30\u00b0\u00a0smooth inclined plane from same height then time taken to slide down will be",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 t",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23367": {
                "ans1": "3:2",
                "ans2": "2:3",
                "ans3": "9:4",
                "ans4": "4:9",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of cubical expansion of brass and iron are\u00a054 \\times 10^{-6} \u00b0 C and\u00a036 \\times 10^{-6} \u00b0 C\u00a0respectively. If brass and iron rods show the same difference of length at all temperatures, their lengths are in the ratio of",
                "correct_ans": "2:3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24641": {
                "ans1": "0.5\u03a9",
                "ans2": "1\u03a9",
                "ans3": "1.5\u03a9",
                "ans4": "2\u03a9",
                "question_text": "When a resistance of 2\u03a9\u00a0is connected across the terminal of a cell then current is 0.5A. When resistance increases to\u00a0 5\u03a9\u00a0then current become\u00a00.25A. The internal resistance of cell is",
                "correct_ans": "1\u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23752": {
                "ans1": "60\\;\\times\\;10^{-4}cm",
                "ans2": "10\\;\\times\\;10^{-4}cm",
                "ans3": "10\\;\\times\\;10^{-5}cm",
                "ans4": "6\\;\\times\\;10^{-5}cm",
                "question_text": "Two coherent sources are at 0.9\u00a0mm a part and fringes are observed at\u00a01m\u00a0away. The second dark fringe is at\u00a01mm\u00a0from center then wavelength is",
                "correct_ans": "6\\;\\times\\;10^{-5}cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24845": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{GMm}{6R^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{GMm}{6R}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{GMm}{4R^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{GMm}{8R}",
                "question_text": "Energy required to move a body of mass\u00a0mm\u00a0from an orbit of radius\u00a02R\u00a0to\u00a03R\u00a0around earth of radius\u00a0R\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{GMm}{6R}",
                "explanation": "E=\\triangle E\\;=\\left[\\frac{-GMm}{r_1}-\\frac{-GMm}{r_2}\\right]",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24042": {
                "ans1": "4h",
                "ans2": "3h",
                "ans3": "6h",
                "ans4": "8h",
                "question_text": "A body is falling from rest has a velocity\u00a0v\u00a0after it falls at a height\u00a0h. The distance it has to fall down further for its velocity to become double is",
                "correct_ans": "3h",
                "explanation": "v=\u221a2gh2v=\u221a2gh'divide both equation and find the value of h'",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22757": {
                "ans1": "2 kg",
                "ans2": "4 kg",
                "ans3": "1.5 kg",
                "ans4": "2.5 kg",
                "question_text": "A block rests on a rough inclined plane making an angle of\u00a030\u00b0\u00a0with the horizontal. The coefficient of static friction between the block and plane is\u00a00.8\u00a0and frictional force on block is\u00a010N, then mass of block is",
                "correct_ans": "2 kg",
                "explanation": "\u00a0orbodiesatrest,Fstaticfriction\u200b=Fapplied\u200bForbodiesoninclinedplane,Fapplied\u200b=Fgravity\u200b=mgsin\u03b8_{static\\,friction} = mg\\sin \\theta m = \\dfrac{10}{10 \\times \\sin {30} }= 2kg",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26345": {
                "ans1": "1 :1",
                "ans2": "2 : 3",
                "ans3": "2 : 1",
                "ans4": "4 : 1",
                "question_text": "Two cells are connected in series and the balancing length in the potentiometer wire is\u00a0500cm. If one of the cell is reversed the balancing length is reduced to\u00a0300cm. The ratio of emf \u00a0of the cells is",
                "correct_ans": "4 : 1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20770": {
                "ans1": "120\u03bcC",
                "ans2": "600\u03bcC",
                "ans3": "480\u03bcC",
                "ans4": "24\u03bcC",
                "question_text": "An air capacitor of capacity\u00a0C = 10\u03bcF\u00a0is connected to a constant voltage battery of\u00a012V. Space between plates is filled by liquid of dielectric constants 5 then the additional charge that flows from battery to capacitor is",
                "correct_ans": "480\u03bcC",
                "explanation": "Q1\u200b=CV=10\u221710\u22126\u221712=120\u03bcCC' = 5CQ_2 = C'V = 5 x 10 x 10^-6 x 12 = 600 \\mu C\\Delta Q = Q_2 \u2013 Q_1 = 600 - 120 = 480 \\mu C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28413": {
                "ans1": "11160",
                "ans2": "12850",
                "ans3": "8225",
                "ans4": "9252",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of first member of Paschen series is\u00a018800\\;A_o then shortest wavelength is same series is ....... in A_o",
                "correct_ans": "8225",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28568": {
                "ans1": "3.95\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans2": "15.8\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans3": "7.9\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans4": "2.5\\times10^{-3}J",
                "question_text": "A particle of mass 40g executes in SHM of amplitude 2cm. If the frequency is 5Hz the totaal Mechanical energy of the system is",
                "correct_ans": "7.9\\times10^{-3}J",
                "explanation": "E_T=\\frac12mr^2\\omega^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23075": {
                "ans1": "g/4",
                "ans2": "g/2",
                "ans3": "3g/4",
                "ans4": "g/8",
                "question_text": "A fireman wants to slide down a rope. The breaking load for the rope is (3/4)th of the weight of man . The minimum acceleration of fireman to slide down is:",
                "correct_ans": "g/4",
                "explanation": "mg\u2212R=maor,\u00a0mg \u2013 3/4 mg = maor,\u00a0mg \\times 1/4 = maso,\u00a0a = g/4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20751": {
                "ans1": "3 cm",
                "ans2": "3.3 cm",
                "ans3": "6 cm",
                "ans4": "6.6 cm",
                "question_text": "The length of pipe at both end is 48cm and its fundamental frequency is 320Hz. The diameter of pipe if vel. of sound is 320 m/s is",
                "correct_ans": "3.3 cm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}f_o=\\frac v{2(l+2e)}\\\\on\\;solving\\;,\\;e=0.01\\\\then\\;D=0.01/0.3=3.3\\;cm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22770": {
                "ans1": "30",
                "ans2": "10",
                "ans3": "20",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "A rocket going upward has mass 100kg emitting gas at 5kg/s at a speed 400m/s. The acceleration of rocket is .....\u00a0m/s^2.",
                "correct_ans": "10",
                "explanation": "a=\\left(\\frac{dm}{dt}\\times\\frac vM\\right)-g\\;=10\\;m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22692": {
                "ans1": "2m",
                "ans2": "6m",
                "ans3": "8m",
                "ans4": "10m",
                "question_text": "Ablock of mass 5kg is moving horizontally at a speed of 1.5m/s. A force 5N act on it vertically upward then displacement of block after 4sec from point where force act is",
                "correct_ans": "10m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24318": {
                "ans1": "6 W",
                "ans2": "27/8 W",
                "ans3": "4 W",
                "ans4": "16/3 W",
                "question_text": "In order to light a 6W - 6V bulb at rated power a battery of cmf 6V and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0 is used. The bulb will light at",
                "correct_ans": "27/8 W",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28052": {
                "ans1": "3 \u03bcF",
                "ans2": "2 \u03bcF",
                "ans3": "1.5 \u03bcF",
                "ans4": "1 \u03bcF",
                "question_text": "Three identical capacitors in series have an effective capacitance of 0.67\u00a0\u03bcF. One of them is removed and connected in parallel with other two, capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "3 \u03bcF",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26711": {
                "ans1": "20 N",
                "ans2": "20.5 N",
                "ans3": "28 N",
                "ans4": "26 N",
                "question_text": "A steel wire of length 40cm of diameter 0.025cm vibrates transversely in unison with a tube open at each end of effective length 60cm when each sound in fundamental node at 27\u00b0C. The tension on wire is, if velocity of sound at 0\u00b0C=331m/s, density of steel=7800 kg/m^3.",
                "correct_ans": "20.5 N",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24773": {
                "ans1": "0.09 mm",
                "ans2": "0.18 mm",
                "ans3": "0.09  \u00b5m",
                "ans4": "0.18  \u00b5m",
                "question_text": "An electron enters an electric field 2 kV/m perpendicular to it with a speed 10 m/s. The displacement of electron beam after 1ns is",
                "correct_ans": "0.18 mm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28368": {
                "ans1": " twice initial energy",
                "ans2": "thrice initial energy",
                "ans3": "four times initial energy",
                "ans4": "equal to initial energy",
                "question_text": "The energy that should be added to an electron to reduce its de-Brogile wavelength from\u00a010^{-10}\u00a0m to\u00a00.5 *10^{-10} m will be",
                "correct_ans": "thrice initial energy",
                "explanation": "Since energy is inversely proportional to square of wavelength, hence\\dfrac{E_2}{E_1}=\\dfrac{(1 \\times 10^{-10})^2}{(0.5 \\times 10^{-10})^2} E_2-E_1=3E_1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27035": {
                "ans1": "2 sin A",
                "ans2": "2 cos A",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\cos\\;A",
                "ans4": "tan A",
                "question_text": "A prism of angle A has one surface silvered. Light rays falling at an angle of incidence 2A on first surface return back through the same path after suffering reflection at second silvered surface. The refractive index of material is",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27635": {
                "ans1": "0.5 m",
                "ans2": "0.25 m",
                "ans3": "0.125 m",
                "ans4": "1 m",
                "question_text": "A block is resting on a piston which is executing vertical SHM with period is 1sec. The amplitude of motion for which block and piston just separate is",
                "correct_ans": "0.25 m",
                "explanation": "a_\\text{max}=gor,\u00a0r \\omega^2\u00a0= g",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21506": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{4\\lambda}",
                "ans2": "4\\lambda",
                "ans3": "4\\lambda",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two radioactive sources A and B decay constants\u00a05\u03bb\u00a0and \u03bb\u00a0respectively. They have same no. of nuclei initially. The ratio of number of nuclei of A and B will be\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{e})^2\u00a0after a time.",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22552": {
                "ans1": "1 A",
                "ans2": "2 A",
                "ans3": "3 A",
                "ans4": "4 A",
                "question_text": "A conductor of length 2cm is bent into arc OA a circle of radius 1cm. A magnetic field of 2*10^{-4}T is developed at centre then the current is",
                "correct_ans": "1 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27309": {
                "ans1": "1 A",
                "ans2": "2 A",
                "ans3": "3 A",
                "ans4": "4 A",
                "question_text": "A conductor of length 2cm is bent into arc OA a circle of radius 1cm. A magnetic field of 2*10^{-4}T is developed at centre then the current is",
                "correct_ans": "1 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24745": {
                "ans1": "6 W",
                "ans2": "27/8 W",
                "ans3": "4 W",
                "ans4": "16/3 W",
                "question_text": "In order to light a 6W - 6V bulb at rated power a battery of cmf 6V and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0 is used. The bulb will light at",
                "correct_ans": "27/8 W",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28951": {
                "ans1": "29 min   ",
                "ans2": "30 min   ",
                "ans3": "32 min   ",
                "ans4": "40 min",
                "question_text": "The half of a substance when one-eighteen count is remained after 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": "29 min   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24717": {
                "ans1": "2 sin A",
                "ans2": "2 cos A",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\cos\\;A",
                "ans4": "tan A",
                "question_text": "A prism of angle A has one surface silvered. Light rays falling at an angle of incidence 2A on first surface return back through the same path after suffering reflection at second silvered surface. The refractive index of material is",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21061": {
                "ans1": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-5 T",
                "ans2": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-4 T",
                "ans3": "5.56 \u00d7 10-3 T",
                "ans4": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "question_text": "The magnetic field at center of circular\u00a0 coil of radius 10 cm having 500 turns of coil and carrying current 18 A is",
                "correct_ans": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26111": {
                "ans1": "0.09 mm",
                "ans2": "0.18 mm",
                "ans3": "0.09  \u00b5m",
                "ans4": "0.18  \u00b5m",
                "question_text": "An electron enters an electric field 2 kV/m perpendicular to it with a speed 10 m/s. The displacement of electron beam after 1ns is",
                "correct_ans": "0.18 mm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20885": {
                "ans1": "+60.06 KV   ",
                "ans2": "-60.06 KV   ",
                "ans3": "+62.06 KV   ",
                "ans4": "-62.06 KV",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of emitted electron from a metal surface after striking of photon on it is 0.2 \u00c5. The stopping potential required for this electron is",
                "correct_ans": "-62.06 KV",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26436": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{4\\lambda}",
                "ans2": "4\\lambda",
                "ans3": "4\\lambda",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two radioactive sources A and B decay constants\u00a05\u03bb\u00a0and \u03bb\u00a0respectively. They have same no. of nuclei initially. The ratio of number of nuclei of A and B will be\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{e})^2\u00a0after a time.",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29696": {
                "ans1": " twice initial energy",
                "ans2": "thrice initial energy",
                "ans3": "four times initial energy",
                "ans4": "equal to initial energy",
                "question_text": "The energy that should be added to an electron to reduce its de-Brogile wavelength from\u00a010^{-10}\u00a0m to\u00a00.5 *10^{-10} m will be",
                "correct_ans": "thrice initial energy",
                "explanation": "Since energy is inversely proportional to square of wavelength, hence\\dfrac{E_2}{E_1}=\\dfrac{(1 \\times 10^{-10})^2}{(0.5 \\times 10^{-10})^2} E_2-E_1=3E_1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23380": {
                "ans1": "20000 V/m     ",
                "ans2": "10000 V/m   ",
                "ans3": "500 V/m   ",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Two plates of potential 10 V and -10 V are separated at distance of 0.1 cm. The electric field produced between plates is",
                "correct_ans": "20000 V/m     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28272": {
                "ans1": "484.08 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "466.28 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "458.42 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "452.82 m/s",
                "question_text": "The density of Nitrogen gas at STP is 1.293 Kg/m^3. The root mean square speed of oxygen molecule at STP is",
                "correct_ans": "452.82 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25493": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "unity",
                "question_text": "The magnification of a convex lens of focal length 20 cm when an object is placed at 10 cm in front of lens is",
                "correct_ans": "unity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21865": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23321": {
                "ans1": "7 \u00c5   ",
                "ans2": "8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "9 \u00c5   ",
                "ans4": "10 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The de Broglie wavelength of an electron in third orbit of H-atom is",
                "correct_ans": "10 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23805": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "Two identical steel wires have fundamental frequency of vibrations of 400Hz. The tension in one of the wire is increased by 2% and both wires are plucked then no. of beats heard per second are",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27293": {
                "ans1": "10 V",
                "ans2": "-10 V",
                "ans3": "+2.5  V",
                "ans4": "-2.5 V",
                "question_text": "The current passing through an inductor of 5H is decreasing at the rate of 2 A/s. The emf developed across the coil is",
                "correct_ans": "10 V",
                "explanation": "E=\\;-L\\frac{dI}{dt}=-5(-2)=10V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26749": {
                "ans1": "\\sin^{-1}e^x+c",
                "ans2": "\\cos^{-1}e^x+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}e^x+c",
                "ans4": "\\sec^{-1}e^x+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{\\sqrt{e^{2x}-1}}\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "\\sec^{-1}e^x+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23329": {
                "ans1": "3mgR",
                "ans2": "5/6 mgR",
                "ans3": "2mgR",
                "ans4": "1/5 mgR",
                "question_text": "The minimum energy required to launch a satellite of 'm' from surface of earth to an orbit at a height '2R' from surface of earth of radius R is",
                "correct_ans": "5/6 mgR",
                "explanation": "\u00a0\\frac{-GMm}{R+2R}\u200b\u00a0-\u00a0\\frac{-GMm}{R} +\u00a0\\frac{m}{2}\\frac{GM}{r}=\u00a0\\frac{5}{6}mgR",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22017": {
                "ans1": "8258\u00c5",
                "ans2": "970\u00c5",
                "ans3": "1632\u00c5",
                "ans4": "14680\u00c5",
                "question_text": "Series limit of Balmer series is 3670\u00c5 then series limit of Paschen series is",
                "correct_ans": "8258\u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29616": {
                "ans1": "0.09\u00b0",
                "ans2": "0.18\u00b0",
                "ans3": "0.36\u00b0",
                "ans4": "0.72\u00b0",
                "question_text": "Light of wavelength 6328\u00c5 is incident on a slit having width 0.2mm. The width of central maxima from minimum to minimum is",
                "correct_ans": "0.36\u00b0",
                "explanation": " 2\\dfrac{\u03bb}{d} = 0.36^o",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28073": {
                "ans1": "0N",
                "ans2": "10 N",
                "ans3": "20 N",
                "ans4": "5 N",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 1kg and volume 2 x\u00a010^{-3}m^3\u00a0is tied to a string. The other end of string is fastened to the bottom of a container containing water with mass immersed in water. Tension on string will be.",
                "correct_ans": "10 N",
                "explanation": "T=upthrust\u2212wt=(2\u00d710^{\u22123}\u00d710^3\u00d710)\u221210=10N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24337": {
                "ans1": "4500 \u00c5",
                "ans2": "5000 \u00c5",
                "ans3": "5500 \u00c5",
                "ans4": "6000 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In Young's double slit experiment, fringes of 1 mm are obtained on screen. The screen is moved by 5 \\times 10^{-2}m. The slits are at 0.03mm then wavelength of light is",
                "correct_ans": "6000 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "\u00a0\u03b2=D\u028e/d\u200b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29276": {
                "ans1": "13.86s",
                "ans2": "6.48 s",
                "ans3": "3.24 s",
                "ans4": "20.5 s",
                "question_text": "A capacitor of 4microFarad is connected with resistance of 2.5M\u03a9\u00a0across a battery of 12V having negligible internal resistance. The time after which the potential across capacitor becomes three times the potential across resistor is",
                "correct_ans": "13.86s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26613": {
                "ans1": "+3.0%",
                "ans2": "+3.2%",
                "ans3": "-3.0%",
                "ans4": "-3.2%",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A piano wire of diameter 0.9 mm is replaced by another wire of 0.93 mm. Then the percentage change in frequency of piano wire is",
                "correct_ans": "-3.2%",
                "explanation": "f/f\u2032\u200b=d/d'\u200b=0.9/0.93\u200bHence,change=(f'/f\u200b\u22121)\u2217100\u00a0=\u22123.2%",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28732": {
                "ans1": " 0.23\u2103",
                "ans2": "2.3\u2103",
                "ans3": "0.46\u2103",
                "ans4": "4.6\u2103",
                "question_text": "A piece of iron falls from a height of 1 km then rise in temperature. If sp heat capacity of iron is 0.1 kcal/kg\u2103 & 10% energy is converted into heat then heat produced is:",
                "correct_ans": "2.3\u2103",
                "explanation": "10% of mgh = msd\u03b8or, d\u03b8 =\u00a0\\dfrac{0.1\\times 10\\times 100}{420}\u200b\u00a0= 2.3^oC",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26130": {
                "ans1": "3 sec",
                "ans2": "6 sec",
                "ans3": "9 sec",
                "ans4": "12 sec",
                "question_text": "Earth receive\u00a08.4\\frac{J}{min.m^2}\u00a0 energy from sun. When the solar energy falls on\u00a010 \\times 10^4m^2 area is concentrated in cup having 100g water at 0^ooC. The time in which water boil is",
                "correct_ans": "3 sec",
                "explanation": "8.4\u2217A\u2217t/60\u200b=msd\u03b8or,t=3sec",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23295": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{n^2}{2n-1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2n^2}{2n-1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{n^2}{n-1}",
                "ans4": "n",
                "question_text": "A bullet loses\u00a0\\frac{1}{n}^{th}\u00a0of its velocity while passing through a plank. The number of planks required to stop it is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{n^2}{2n-1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28923": {
                "ans1": "7/12 \u03a9",
                "ans2": "12/7\u03a9",
                "ans3": "9/10 \u03a9",
                "ans4": "10/9 \u03a9",
                "question_text": "The potential difference between terminals of a cell in open circuit is 2.2V. When a 5ohm resistor is placed then potential difference become 1.8V. The internal resistance of source is",
                "correct_ans": "10/9 \u03a9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22053": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "90\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Light travels in two media A and B with1.2 \\times 10^8 m/s\u00a0and\u00a02.4\\times 10^8 m/srespectively. The critical angle between them is:",
                "correct_ans": "30\u00b0",
                "explanation": "sinC=Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0denser\u00a0medium\u200b/ Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0rarer\u00a0medium=1/2C=sin\u22121(1/2)=30\u2218",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23445": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "12",
                "question_text": "Two masses 10kg and 20kg are connected by a massless spring. A force of 200N act on 20kg mass. The acceleration of 10kg mass is\u00a012 m/s^2. Then acceleration of 20kg mass will be:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "For 10 kg\\\\F = ma = 10\u00a0\\times\u00d7\u00a012 = 120 N\\\\For 20 kg 200 - F = 20a\\\\or a =\u00a0\\dfrac{200-120}{20} = 4 m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22140": {
                "ans1": "1.7 V",
                "ans2": "1.6 V",
                "ans3": "1.5 V",
                "ans4": "1 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The threshold wavelength of metal is 4000 \u00c5 then the light of wavelength 3000 \u00c5 incident on metal then stopping potential will be",
                "correct_ans": "1 V",
                "explanation": "KE=hc\u200b/\u03bb\u2212\u200bhc/\u03bbo\u200b=1.65\u00d710^\u221219\u00a0J\u00a0V_s = \\dfrac{KE}{e} = 1V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25612": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3h}{m_oc}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2h}{m_oc}",
                "ans3": "\u221e",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "What will be the de-Broglie wavelength of a particle of rest mass\u00a0m_o\u200b, if it moves with speed of light?",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\u03bb=\u200bh/moc\u200b\u22610",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27656": {
                "ans1": "0.05^o",
                "ans2": "0.9^o",
                "ans3": "1.2^o",
                "ans4": "0.4^o",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 2kg is dragged on a horizontal surface with constant speed 2m/s. If coefficient of friction(\u03bc) between the body and the surface is 0.2, then rise in temperature after 5 sec will be of body if specific heat capacity is 0.1cal/g\u2218C",
                "correct_ans": "0.05^o",
                "explanation": "Work done against friction = Heat developed\\\\\nor, \\mu mg (vt) = ms d\\theta \\\\ or, d\\theta = \\dfrac{Mgvt}{S} = 0.047^o C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22923": {
                "ans1": "18 kg",
                "ans2": "27 kg",
                "ans3": "36 kg",
                "ans4": "72 kg",
                "question_text": "A segment of wire vibrates with fundamental frequency of 450Hz under a tension of 9kg. The tension at which fundamental frequency become 900Hz is",
                "correct_ans": "36 kg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21497": {
                "ans1": "6s",
                "ans2": "6.5s",
                "ans3": "7s",
                "ans4": "7.5s",
                "question_text": "A stone is dropped from certain height which can reach the ground in 5s. It is stopped after 3 seconds of its fall and then is again released. The total time taken by the stone to reach the ground will be:",
                "correct_ans": "7.5s",
                "explanation": "t1\u200b=3s,\u00a0t=5s\u00a0then\\\\t^2=t_1^2+t_2^2 \\\\ so, t_2= \\sqrt{5^2-3^2} = 4s \\\\t2=t12\u200b+t22\u200bso,t2\u200b=52\u221232\u200b=4s. Thus,\u00a0t=t_1+t_2 = 3+4 = 7s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20883": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3V}{K+2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{V}{3K+2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{3V}{2K+2}",
                "question_text": "Two capacitors of capacitance C and 2C are connected in parallel and charged to a potential difference V. The battery is disconnected and region between the plates of capacitor C is completely filled with a material of dielectric constant K. The potential difference across the capacitors will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "explanation": "Q=(C+2C)V=3CV\nwhen dielectric is placed then, Q = (KC + 2C) V' \\\\ or, V'= \\dfrac{3CV}{C(K+2)} = \\dfrac{3V}{K+2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23739": {
                "ans1": "4500 Angstrom",
                "ans2": "3000 Angstrom",
                "ans3": "5000 Angstrom",
                "ans4": "6000 Angstrom",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In Young's double slit experiment with monochromatic light the fringes are obtained on screen placed at some distance from slit. If screen is moved by\u00a05\\times 10^{-2}\u00a0towards slit, the fringe width changes by\u00a03\\times 10^{-5}. The separation of slit is\u00a010^{-3}m, then wavelength of light is:",
                "correct_ans": "3000 Angstrom",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20801": {
                "ans1": "5 cm/s",
                "ans2": "25 cm/s",
                "ans3": "45 cm/s",
                "ans4": "90 cm/s",
                "question_text": "27 drops of equal size are falling through air with steady velocity 5cm/s coalesce to form a single drop then velocity of single drop will be:",
                "correct_ans": "45 cm/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22778": {
                "ans1": " 1:2:3",
                "ans2": "3:2:1",
                "ans3": "1:6:27",
                "ans4": "27:6:1",
                "question_text": "The masses of three wires of copper are in ratio 1:2:3 and lengths are in ratio 3:2:1. The ratio of their electrical resistances is:",
                "correct_ans": "27:6:1",
                "explanation": "\n\u200b\n \n\\\\ R_1:R_2:R_3 = 9: 2: 1/3 = 27: 6: 1\n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25514": {
                "ans1": "12 m",
                "ans2": "8 m",
                "ans3": "6 m",
                "ans4": "4 m",
                "question_text": "A point source of y radiation has half life 30min. The initial count rate by GM counter at 4m is 360 counts/s then after 1.5 hrs the distance is altered and count rate become 5 counts/s. The distance between source &counter is changed by",
                "correct_ans": "8 m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20406": {
                "ans1": "1cm",
                "ans2": "5/3 cm",
                "ans3": "4/3 cm",
                "ans4": "4/5 cm",
                "question_text": "A point source of light is placed inside the liquid of refractive index 5/3. The radius of greatest circle on the surface is 1cm then depth of the source is:",
                "correct_ans": "4/3 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29284": {
                "ans1": "1km/hr",
                "ans2": "3km/hr",
                "ans3": "4km/h",
                "ans4": "5km/h",
                "question_text": "A boat which has a speed of 5km/hr in still water crosses a river of width 1km along the shortest path in 15min. The velocity of water in river is",
                "correct_ans": "3km/hr",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26015": {
                "ans1": "4 kV",
                "ans2": "6 kV",
                "ans3": "9 kV",
                "ans4": "10 kV",
                "question_text": "A capacitor of capacitance 1 \u03bcF and break down voltage 6 kV is connected in series with another capacitor of capacitance 2 \u03bcF and breakdown voltage 4 kV. The breakdown when they are in series is",
                "correct_ans": "9 kV",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27632": {
                "ans1": "100 ohm",
                "ans2": "200 ohm",
                "ans3": "10 ohm",
                "ans4": "50ohm",
                "question_text": "The reading of voltmeter in fig. 5V the resistance of voltmeter is",
                "correct_ans": "100 ohm",
                "explanation": "As voltmeter reading=5V\\dfrac{(R_v \\times 100)}{(R_v+100)}=50hence\u00a0R_v=100 ohm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22620": {
                "ans1": "30 cm",
                "ans2": "15 cm",
                "ans3": "10 cm",
                "ans4": "5 cm",
                "question_text": "A bullet is fired on a wooden block. It\u2018s velocity reduces by 50% on penetrating 30cm. the further distance it covered before coming to rest is",
                "correct_ans": "10 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28842": {
                "ans1": "-2\\times10^{-3}",
                "ans2": "1\\times10^{-3}",
                "ans3": "2\\times10^{-3}",
                "ans4": "-1\\times10^{-3}",
                "question_text": "A uniform metal rod is used as a bar pendulum of the room temperature rises by 10\u00b0C and coefficient of linear expansion of metal is\u00a02 \\times 10^{-6} \u00b0C then % change in time period of pendulum is",
                "correct_ans": "1\\times10^{-3}",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\Delta T}T\\times100\\%\\;=\\;\\frac12\\times\\alpha\\times\\Delta\\theta\\times100\\;=\\;10^{-3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21928": {
                "ans1": "2 V",
                "ans2": "3 V",
                "ans3": "3.5 V",
                "ans4": "1.5 V",
                "question_text": "The stopping potential for light of wavelength 4000A is 2V. The wavelength of radiation changes to 3000A then stopping potential will be",
                "correct_ans": "3 V",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24521": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "An air filled parallel plate capacitor has a capacity of 2PF. The separation of the plates is doubled and interspace between plates is filled with wax. The capacity become 6PF then dielectric constant of wax is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "C=\\frac{\\epsilon_0\u200bA\\;}d=2PFC'=\\frac{\\epsilon_0\\epsilon_r\u200bA\\;}{2d}\\\\or,\\;6\\;=\\;\\epsilon_r\\ast2/2\\\\\\epsilon_r=6",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25005": {
                "ans1": "16 s",
                "ans2": "32 s",
                "ans3": "48 s",
                "ans4": "60 s",
                "question_text": "Two rods of same length and same material transfer a given amount of heat in 12s when they are joined side by side when rods are placed end to end then they will conduct same heat in same condition",
                "correct_ans": "48 s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24867": {
                "ans1": "60kg",
                "ans2": "72kg",
                "ans3": "12kg",
                "ans4": "128kg",
                "question_text": "A boat having length 3m, breath 2m is floating on a lake. The boat sinks by 1cm when a man gets in. The mass of man is",
                "correct_ans": "60kg",
                "explanation": "change in wt = change in upthrustor,mg = \u0394 v\u03c3gm=l\u00d7b\u00d7\u0394h\u00d71000=60kg",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23684": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\mu_o}{17}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2\\frac{\\mu_o}\\pi",
                "ans3": "\\frac32\\frac{\\mu_o}\\pi",
                "ans4": "\\frac12\\frac{\\mu_o}\\pi",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two parallel wires P and Q are held perpendicular to the plane of paper at a distance 5m between them. If P carry current of 2.5A and Q carry and current of 5A in same direction then magnetic field at a point halfway between the wires is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac12\\frac{\\mu_o}\\pi",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23339": {
                "ans1": "30.2 MeV",
                "ans2": "25.8 MeV",
                "ans3": "23.6 MeV",
                "ans4": "19.2 MeV",
                "question_text": "Binding energy of deuteron is 2.2 Mev and\u00a02He_4 is 28 Mev. If two deuterons are fuse to form\u00a02H_4' then energy released is",
                "correct_ans": "23.6 MeV",
                "explanation": "Energy released(E)=28\u20132\u00d72.2\u00a0= 23.6 Mev",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26754": {
                "ans1": "97.1 m/s",
                "ans2": "50 m/s",
                "ans3": "30 m/s",
                "ans4": "25 m/s",
                "question_text": "A man fires a rifle at a height 1.7m above the ground The bullet hit the window 30m above ground. The bullet left the rifle at 100m/s then greatest speed with which it hit the window is",
                "correct_ans": "97.1 m/s",
                "explanation": "v^2=u^2\u22122gh;v^2=100^2\u22122\u00d79.8\u00d7(30\u22121.3)hence v=97.1m/s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29359": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{10\\lambda}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{11\\lambda}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{11}{10\\lambda}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{9\\lambda}",
                "question_text": "Two source of decay constants 10\u03bb\u00a0and \u03bb\u00a0have same number of nuclei initially. The ratio of number of nuclei will be\u00a0\\dfrac{1}{e}\u200b\u00a0after time of",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{9\\lambda}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26493": {
                "ans1": "28 W",
                "ans2": "88 W",
                "ans3": "112 W",
                "ans4": "140 W",
                "question_text": "Luminous efficiency of lamp is 5 lm/w. If luminous intensity of lamp is 35cd then power of lamp is",
                "correct_ans": "88 W",
                "explanation": "\u03b7=\u03d5\u200b/PP = \\dfrac{4 \\pi I}{\\eta} = \\dfrac{(4 \\times \\pi \\times 35)}{5}= 88 w",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22883": {
                "ans1": "29 min",
                "ans2": "30 min",
                "ans3": "32 min",
                "ans4": "40 min",
                "question_text": "The half of a substance when one-eighteen count is remained after 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": "29 min",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26517": {
                "ans1": "20000 V/m     ",
                "ans2": "10000 V/m     ",
                "ans3": "500 V/m",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Two plates of potential 10 V and -10 V are separated at distance of 0.1 cm. The electric field produced between plates is",
                "correct_ans": "20000 V/m     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20868": {
                "ans1": "230^0 C ",
                "ans2": "120^0 C ",
                "ans3": "100^0 C ",
                "ans4": "80^0 C ",
                "question_text": "1 gm of steam at 100^0\n C and 1 gm of ice at 0^0 C are mixed. The resulting temperature of mixture is",
                "correct_ans": "100^0 C ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25962": {
                "ans1": "2000/3 ohm",
                "ans2": "1000/3 ohm",
                "ans3": "500/3 ohm",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The equivalent resistance of the given circuit is",
                "correct_ans": "2000/3 ohm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23048": {
                "ans1": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-5 T",
                "ans2": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-4 T",
                "ans3": "5.56 \u00d7 10-3 T",
                "ans4": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "question_text": "The magnetic field at center of circular\u00a0 coil of radius 10 cm having 500 turns of coil and carrying current 18 A is",
                "correct_ans": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20840": {
                "ans1": "2MR^2",
                "ans2": "MR^2/2",
                "ans3": "3MR^2\\2",
                "ans4": "MR^2",
                "question_text": "In a rotational motion,\u00a0 a solid cylinder of mass \u2018M\u2019 and radius \u2018R\u2019 is rotated about its tangent to its axis. Moment of Inertia of solid cylinder is",
                "correct_ans": "3MR^2\\2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27467": {
                "ans1": "1.5 cm",
                "ans2": "3 cm",
                "ans3": "4.5 cm",
                "ans4": "6 cm",
                "question_text": "Velocity of light in glass vessel is 2 \u00d7\u00a010^8 m/s and 3 \u00d7 10^8 m/s in air. If a glass slab of thickness 9 cm is kept\u00a0 covering ink dot\u00a0 at its bottom, the height through which the ink dot will be appeared to be raised by in slab is",
                "correct_ans": "3 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27582": {
                "ans1": "7 \u00c5   ",
                "ans2": "8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "9 \u00c5   ",
                "ans4": "10 \u00c5   ",
                "question_text": "The de Broglie wavelength of an electron in third orbit of H-atom is",
                "correct_ans": "10 \u00c5   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29579": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The magnification of a convex lens of focal length 20 cm when an object is placed at 10 cm in front of lens is",
                "correct_ans": "infinity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29283": {
                "ans1": "10 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "20 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "30 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "40 m/s   ",
                "question_text": "A bucket full of water has a hole at its bottom. If the pressure at the bottom is 3 atm, the velocity of efflux from hole is",
                "correct_ans": "20 m/s   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28392": {
                "ans1": "484.08 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "466.28 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "458.42 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "452.82 m/s",
                "question_text": "The density of Nitrogen gas at STP is 1.293 Kg/m^3. The root mean square speed of oxygen molecule at STP is",
                "correct_ans": "452.82 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21737": {
                "ans1": "50.76^0",
                "ans2": "39.23^0",
                "ans3": "23.57^0",
                "ans4": "11.67^0",
                "question_text": "60% of original kinetic energy of a projectile is lost when it reaches at top of trajectory. The angle of projection of projectile is",
                "correct_ans": "50.76^0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22284": {
                "ans1": "+60.06 KV   ",
                "ans2": "-60.06 KV   ",
                "ans3": "+62.06 KV   ",
                "ans4": "-62.06 KV   ",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of emitted electron from a metal surface after striking of photon on it is 0.2 \u00c5. The stopping potential required for this electron is",
                "correct_ans": "-62.06 KV   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26936": {
                "ans1": "0.158 m^3",
                "ans2": "0.125 m^3   ",
                "ans3": "0.034 m^3",
                "ans4": "0.001 m^3",
                "question_text": "A rock weighs 1400 N in air weighs 300 N in a liquid of density 900 Kg/m^3. The volume of rock is",
                "correct_ans": "0.125 m^3   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28031": {
                "ans1": "\\style{font-size:11px}{48\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans2": "\\style{font-size:11px}{12\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans3": "\\style{font-size:11px}{96\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans4": "\\style{font-size:11px}{192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "question_text": "A liquid drop of radius \u2018R\u2019 breaks into 64 tiny\u00a0droplets each of radius \u2018r\u2019. If the surface tension of the\u00a0liquid is \u2018T\u2019 then gain in energy is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\style{font-size:11px}{192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "explanation": "Let the density of the liquid be \u00a0\u03c1.Mass of the liquid drops must be equal to the total mass of the droplets.\\style{font-size:11px}{Change\\;in\\;surface\\;area\\;\\Delta A=64\\times4\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2-4\\mathrm{\u03c0R}^2}\\style{font-size:11px}{\\\\\\therefore\\triangle\\mathrm A\\;=\\;64\\times4\\mathrm\\pi\\times\\mathrm r^{2\\;\\;}-4\\mathrm\\pi{(4\\mathrm r)}^2=192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\\\\\therefore\\;\\mathrm{Gain}\\;\\mathrm{in}\\;\\mathrm{energy}\\;\\mathrm E\\;=\\;\\mathrm T\\triangle\\mathrm A\\;=\\;192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25648": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt n}=\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_1}}+\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_2}}+\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_3}}",
                "ans3": "n=n_1+n_2+n_3",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt n=\\sqrt{n_1}+\\sqrt{n_2}+\\sqrt{n_3}",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0n_1\u200b,\u00a0n_2\u200b,\u00a0n_3\u200b\u00a0are the fundamental frequencies of three segments into which a string is divided. The original fundamental frequency of wire is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}",
                "explanation": "n_1=\\frac v{2l_1}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_1}\\\\n_2=\\frac v{2l_2}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_2}\\\\n_3=\\frac v{2l_3}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_2}\\\\Total\\;length(l)\\;=\\;l_1+l_2+l_3\\\\l=\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}\\\\Now, the original fundamental frequency of the wire,n=\\frac v{2l}\\\\n=\\frac v{2\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}}\\right)}\\\\\\\\\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24805": {
                "ans1": "3*10^{-15}",
                "ans2": "1.5*10^{-15}",
                "ans3": "6*10^{-15}",
                "ans4": "4.5*10^{-15}",
                "question_text": "The radius of a nucleus with nucleon number 16 is \u00a03 \\times 10^{-15}. What would be the radius of other nucleus with nucleon no. 128.",
                "correct_ans": "6*10^{-15}",
                "explanation": "Radius R of nucleus changes with the nucleon number A of the nucleus as\u00a01.3 * 10^{-15} * A^{1/3} mHence ,\u00a0\\frac{R_2}{R_1}=\\frac{A_2}{A_1^{1/3}} = (\\frac{128}{16^{1/3}})=(8)^{1/3} = 2R_2 = 2R_1 = 2(3*10^{-15})m = 6*10^{-15}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24256": {
                "ans1": "0.4 m",
                "ans2": "0.8 m",
                "ans3": "1 m",
                "ans4": "2.4 m",
                "question_text": "A disc of siren has 80 holes and it is rotated at speed 240 rpm. When a jet of air is blown then a tone is produced. The wavelength of tone is air if speed of sound in air is 320 m/ s",
                "correct_ans": "1 m",
                "explanation": "f = angular speed * no of holesf\\;=\\;\\frac{80\\;\\times240}{60}\\;=\\;320Hz\\lambda\\;=\\frac vf=\\frac{320}{320}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28834": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "If an object is placed unsymmetrically between two plane mirrors inclined plane at an angle 72\u2218, then the total number of image formed is:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "n = \\frac{360^o}{\\theta} -1Given ,\u00a0\\theta = 72^o\nn = \\frac{369^o}{72^o} -1=5-1=4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29828": {
                "ans1": "100 mA",
                "ans2": "20 mA",
                "ans3": "40 mA",
                "ans4": "80 mA",
                "question_text": "An alternating voltage\u00a0E ( \\text{ in volts}) = 200 \\sqrt2 \\sin 100t is connected to one micro farad capacitor through and a.c. ammeter. The reading of the ammeter shall be:",
                "correct_ans": "20 mA",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28482": {
                "ans1": "1 sec",
                "ans2": "3\\sqrt3\\;sec",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt3\\;sec",
                "ans4": "3 sec",
                "question_text": "A body is released from top of the smooth inclined plane having inclination of 30 degree and takes\u00a03\\sqrt{3}\u200b\u00a0sec to reach bottom. If the angle of inclination is doubled keeping the height same. What will be time for same process?",
                "correct_ans": "3 sec",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29914": {
                "ans1": "1:4",
                "ans2": "1:16",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "16:1",
                "question_text": "The ratio of total energy of an electron in hydrogen atom in n = 1 and n = 4 orbits (i.e., E1: E2) is",
                "correct_ans": "1:16",
                "explanation": "find the ration of respective energy.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28153": {
                "ans1": "4:1",
                "ans2": "1:4",
                "ans3": "2:1",
                "ans4": "3:4",
                "question_text": "The ratio of time periods of oscillation of two magnets of same moment of inertia suspended in a magnetic field is\u00a01 : 2. The ratio of their magnetic moment is:",
                "correct_ans": "4:1",
                "explanation": "Ratio\u00a0 of time period of oscillation = 2:1Magnetic field same\u00a0Magnetic moment equal\u00a0T = 2\\pi \\sqrt{\\frac{I}{mB}}\nm_1=m_2\nB_1=B_2\\frac{T_1}{T_2} = \\frac{2}{1}=\\sqrt{\\frac{I_1}{I_2}}\\frac{I_1}{I_2}=\\frac{4}{1}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26637": {
                "ans1": "1840 eV",
                "ans2": "1 eV",
                "ans3": "1 MeV",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Proton has a mass 1840 times that of an electron. If a proton is accelerated from rest by a p.d of 1 volt, its KE is:",
                "correct_ans": "1 eV",
                "explanation": "KE=qV= 1eV",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20848": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "500N",
                "ans3": "1000N",
                "ans4": "2000N",
                "question_text": "A rocket has a mass 100 kg, 90% of which is fuel. It ejects fuel vapour at the rate of 1 kg/s with a velocity 500m/s relative to rocket. The initial thrust on rocket in out of gravitational field is",
                "correct_ans": "500N",
                "explanation": "F=(m/t)/v=1*500=500N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23193": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac14\\right)\\\\",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac13\\right)\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac12\\right)\\\\",
                "question_text": "A\u00a0cyclist is moving with a velocity of 18km/hr around a circular path of 15\u00a0m. The angle at which he turns with vertical is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "explanation": "v=18km/hr=\\frac{18\\ast10000}{60\\ast60}m/s\\\\=5\\;m/sR=15m\\theta\\tan\\theta=\\frac{v^2}{Rg}=\\frac{5^2}{15\\ast10}=\\frac16\\\\\\theta=\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22804": {
                "ans1": "Solid sphere will expand more than hollow sphere",
                "ans2": "Hollow sphere will expand more than solid sphere",
                "ans3": " Both spheres expand equally",
                "ans4": "Sphere with higher coefficient of expansion expands more",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of same size are made of same metal but one is hollow and the other is solid. If they are heated with same temperature, then",
                "correct_ans": " Both spheres expand equally",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26617": {
                "ans1": "5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "ans2": "1.2*10^{-4} N/m^2",
                "ans3": "0.83*10^{-4} N/m^2",
                "ans4": "30 N/m^2",
                "question_text": "The density of gas is\u00a06 \\times 10^{-2} kg / m ^{3} and RMS speed\u00a0of gas molecule is 500m/s\u00a0then pressure exerted by gas on wall of container will be:",
                "correct_ans": "5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "explanation": "p = \\frac{1}{3}\\delta v^2= \\frac{1}{3}*(6*10^{-2} ) * 500^2)\n= 5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21669": {
                "ans1": "9 m/s",
                "ans2": "12 m/s",
                "ans3": "15 m/s",
                "ans4": "18 m/s",
                "question_text": "A shell explodes into three fragments of equal masses. Two fragments fly of at right angles to each other with speed of 9 m/s and 12 m/s then speed of 3^{rd}\u00a0fragment is",
                "correct_ans": "15 m/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mv=\\sqrt{(9m)^2+(12m)^2}\\\\v=\\sqrt{81+144}=15\\;m/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27729": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "75\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A particle is projected from the ground with 25m/s. After 2s it just clear a wall of 5m high. The angle of projection is",
                "correct_ans": "30\u00b0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}h=u\\;\\sin\\theta t-\\frac12gt^2\\\\5=25\\;\\times\\sin\\theta\\;\\times2-\\frac12\\times10\\times2^2\\\\\\theta=30\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22239": {
                "ans1": "0.96\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "1.02\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "1.16\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "0.23\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Water falls from a height of 500m then difference in temperature between bottom & top of water fall is",
                "correct_ans": "1.16\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}mgh=msd\\theta\\\\d\\theta=\\frac{9.8\\ast500}{4200}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28675": {
                "ans1": "nV",
                "ans2": "n^2V",
                "ans3": "V/n",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "A soap bubble of radius r is charged to a potential 'V'. If the radius is increased to\u00a0nr. the potential on the bubble will be",
                "correct_ans": "V/n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29571": {
                "ans1": "20 cm",
                "ans2": "14 cm",
                "ans3": "43/3 cm",
                "ans4": "6 cm",
                "question_text": "Two immiscible transparent liquid of refractive index 1.5 and 4/3 are arranged one above another of 8cm first and 12cm\u00a02^{nd}\u00a0layer. The apparent depth of mark at bottom is",
                "correct_ans": "43/3 cm",
                "explanation": "apparent\\;depth\\;=\\frac{t_1}{\\mu_1}+\\frac{t_2}{\\mu_2}=\\frac8{1.5}+\\frac{12}{4/3}=\\frac{43}3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23021": {
                "ans1": "8dB",
                "ans2": "5.6 dB",
                "ans3": "10.5 dB",
                "ans4": "25 dB",
                "question_text": "A loud speaker produces a sound of intensity level of 8 dB\u00a0above a certain reference level at a point 40m from it. The intensity level at 30m from loud speaker is",
                "correct_ans": "10.5 dB",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}L_2-L_1=10\\;\\log\\left(\\frac{r_1}{r_2}\\right)^2\\\\L_2=8+20\\log\\left(\\frac{40}{30}\\right)=10.5\\;db\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20077": {
                "ans1": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans2": "11\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "ans3": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-20}J",
                "ans4": "7.5\\;\\times10^{-18}J",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The radiation of wavelength 180mm ejects photo electrons from a plate of potassium of work function 2eV. The maximum KE of emitted electrons will be",
                "correct_ans": "7.8\\;\\times10^{-19}J",
                "explanation": "KE=\\frac{hc}\\lambda-\\phi",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24921": {
                "ans1": "-2.5 D",
                "ans2": "-6.25 D",
                "ans3": "+2.5 D",
                "ans4": "+1.5 D",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A person cannot see the objects clearly placed at a distance more than 40cm. The power of lens used by him",
                "correct_ans": "-2.5 D",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26180": {
                "ans1": "2.5 PF to 250 PF",
                "ans2": "5 PF to 500 PF",
                "ans3": "7.5 PF to 750 PF",
                "ans4": "10 PF to 1000 PF",
                "question_text": "A radio tunner has frequency range from 500k Hz to 5 MHz. The LC circuit has effective inductance 400H\u00a0then range of capacitor is",
                "correct_ans": "2.5 PF to 250 PF",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21521": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/5 s",
                "ans2": "2\u03c0 s",
                "ans3": "20\u03c0 s",
                "ans4": "5\u03c0 s",
                "question_text": "The KE of a particle of mass 5.12kg and amplitude of oscillation is 25cm is 16J\u00a0at mean position .The oscillation is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/5 s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}KE=\\frac12m\\omega^2r^2\\\\\\omega=\\sqrt{\\frac{2\\ast16}{5.1\\ast0.25^2}}=\\frac{2\\pi}T\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22479": {
                "ans1": "200W",
                "ans2": "25W",
                "ans3": "100W",
                "ans4": "300W",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}In\\;an\\;ac\\;circuit\\;the\\;instantaneous\\\\\\;value\\;of\\;emf\\;and\\;current\\;are\\\\\\;E\\;=\\;400\\sin314t\\;'V'\\;and\\\\\\;I=\\sin(314t+\\pi/3)A\\;then\\\\\\;average\\;power\\;\\;consumed\\;is\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "100W",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}P=I_{rms}V_{rms}\\cos\\varnothing\\\\\\;\\;=\\frac{I_0}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac{v_0}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\cos\\frac\\pi3\\\\\\;\\;=\\frac1{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac{400}{\\sqrt2}\\times\\frac12=100w\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22166": {
                "ans1": "102\u03a9",
                "ans2": "288\u03a9",
                "ans3": "300\u03a9",
                "ans4": "412\u03a9",
                "question_text": "A milli ammeter of resistance 12\u03a9\u00a0can give full scale deflection for a current of 0.01A. The resistance needed in series to convert it into a voltmeter of full scale deflection 3V\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "288\u03a9",
                "explanation": "R=\\frac V{I_g}-G=\\frac3{0.01}-12=288\\Omega ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27819": {
                "ans1": "0.66 A",
                "ans2": "0.99 A",
                "ans3": "0.33 A",
                "ans4": "0.15 A",
                "question_text": "\u00a04 cells of emf 1.5v and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0are connected in parallel. The combination is connected with 4\u03a9\u00a0resistance, value of current is",
                "correct_ans": "0.33 A",
                "explanation": "I=\\frac E{R+r/4}=\\frac{1.5}{4+2/4}=0.33\\;A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29218": {
                "ans1": "3.95 H",
                "ans2": "15.8 H",
                "ans3": "3.95 H",
                "ans4": "31.2 H",
                "question_text": "The inductance of a coil 40cm\u00a0in length and 8cm in diameter having 1000 turns is",
                "correct_ans": "15.8 H",
                "explanation": "L=\\frac{\\mu_oN^2A}l",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28432": {
                "ans1": "1 A",
                "ans2": "2 A",
                "ans3": "3 A",
                "ans4": "4 A",
                "question_text": "A conductor of length 2cm is bent into arc OA a circle of radius 1cm. A magnetic field of 2*10^{-4}T is developed at centre then the current is",
                "correct_ans": "1 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28835": {
                "ans1": "2 sin A",
                "ans2": "2 cos A",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\cos\\;A",
                "ans4": "tan A",
                "question_text": "A prism of angle A has one surface silvered. Light rays falling at an angle of incidence 2A on first surface return back through the same path after suffering reflection at second silvered surface. The refractive index of material is",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22249": {
                "ans1": "3.95\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans2": "15.8\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans3": "7.9\\times10^{-3}J",
                "ans4": "2.5\\times10^{-3}J",
                "question_text": "A particle of mass 40g executes in SHM of amplitude 2cm. If the frequency is 5Hz the totaal Mechanical energy of the system is",
                "correct_ans": "7.9\\times10^{-3}J",
                "explanation": "E_T=\\frac12mr^2\\omega^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26691": {
                "ans1": "2m",
                "ans2": "6m",
                "ans3": "8m",
                "ans4": "10m",
                "question_text": "Ablock of mass 5kg is moving horizontally at a speed of 1.5m/s. A force 5N act on it vertically upward then displacement of block after 4sec from point where force act is",
                "correct_ans": "10m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21314": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{4\\lambda}",
                "ans2": "4\\lambda",
                "ans3": "4\\lambda",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two radioactive sources A and B decay constants\u00a05\u03bb\u00a0and \u03bb\u00a0respectively. They have same no. of nuclei initially. The ratio of number of nuclei of A and B will be\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{e})^2\u00a0after a time.",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28356": {
                "ans1": "g/4",
                "ans2": "g/2",
                "ans3": "3g/4",
                "ans4": "g/8",
                "question_text": "A fireman wants to slide down a rope. The breaking load for the rope is (3/4)th of the weight of man . The minimum acceleration of fireman to slide down is:",
                "correct_ans": "g/4",
                "explanation": "mg\u2212R=maor,\u00a0mg \u2013 3/4 mg = maor,\u00a0mg \\times 1/4 = maso,\u00a0a = g/4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21174": {
                "ans1": "6 W",
                "ans2": "27/8 W",
                "ans3": "4 W",
                "ans4": "16/3 W",
                "question_text": "In order to light a 6W - 6V bulb at rated power a battery of cmf 6V and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0 is used. The bulb will light at",
                "correct_ans": "27/8 W",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28784": {
                "ans1": "0.09 mm",
                "ans2": "0.18 mm",
                "ans3": "0.09  \u00b5m",
                "ans4": "0.18  \u00b5m",
                "question_text": "An electron enters an electric field 2 kV/m perpendicular to it with a speed 10 m/s. The displacement of electron beam after 1ns is",
                "correct_ans": "0.18 mm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27379": {
                "ans1": "30",
                "ans2": "10",
                "ans3": "20",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "A rocket going upward has mass 100kg emitting gas at 5kg/s at a speed 400m/s. The acceleration of rocket is .....\u00a0m/s^2.",
                "correct_ans": "10",
                "explanation": "a=\\left(\\frac{dm}{dt}\\times\\frac vM\\right)-g\\;=10\\;m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20626": {
                "ans1": "0.5 m",
                "ans2": "0.25 m",
                "ans3": "0.125 m",
                "ans4": "1 m",
                "question_text": "A block is resting on a piston which is executing vertical SHM with period is 1sec. The amplitude of motion for which block and piston just separate is",
                "correct_ans": "0.25 m",
                "explanation": "a_\\text{max}=gor,\u00a0r \\omega^2\u00a0= g",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20621": {
                "ans1": "3 cm",
                "ans2": "3.3 cm",
                "ans3": "6 cm",
                "ans4": "6.6 cm",
                "question_text": "The length of pipe at both end is 48cm and its fundamental frequency is 320Hz. The diameter of pipe if vel. of sound is 320 m/s is",
                "correct_ans": "3.3 cm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}f_o=\\frac v{2(l+2e)}\\\\on\\;solving\\;,\\;e=0.01\\\\then\\;D=0.01/0.3=3.3\\;cm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23472": {
                "ans1": "20 N",
                "ans2": "20.5 N",
                "ans3": "28 N",
                "ans4": "26 N",
                "question_text": "A steel wire of length 40cm of diameter 0.025cm vibrates transversely in unison with a tube open at each end of effective length 60cm when each sound in fundamental node at 27\u00b0C. The tension on wire is, if velocity of sound at 0\u00b0C=331m/s, density of steel=7800 kg/m^3.",
                "correct_ans": "20.5 N",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26839": {
                "ans1": "3 \u03bcF",
                "ans2": "2 \u03bcF",
                "ans3": "1.5 \u03bcF",
                "ans4": "1 \u03bcF",
                "question_text": "Three identical capacitors in series have an effective capacitance of 0.67\u00a0\u03bcF. One of them is removed and connected in parallel with other two, capacitance will be",
                "correct_ans": "3 \u03bcF",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27497": {
                "ans1": " twice initial energy",
                "ans2": "thrice initial energy",
                "ans3": "four times initial energy",
                "ans4": "equal to initial energy",
                "question_text": "The energy that should be added to an electron to reduce its de-Brogile wavelength from\u00a010^{-10}\u00a0m to\u00a00.5 *10^{-10} m will be",
                "correct_ans": "thrice initial energy",
                "explanation": "Since energy is inversely proportional to square of wavelength, hence\\dfrac{E_2}{E_1}=\\dfrac{(1 \\times 10^{-10})^2}{(0.5 \\times 10^{-10})^2} E_2-E_1=3E_1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20890": {
                "ans1": "18 kg",
                "ans2": "27 kg",
                "ans3": "36 kg",
                "ans4": "72 kg",
                "question_text": "A segment of wire vibrates with fundamental frequency of 450Hz under a tension of 9kg. The tension at which fundamental frequency become 900Hz is",
                "correct_ans": "36 kg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28094": {
                "ans1": "1.7 V",
                "ans2": "1.6 V",
                "ans3": "1.5 V",
                "ans4": "1 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The threshold wavelength of metal is 4000 \u00c5 then the light of wavelength 3000 \u00c5 incident on metal then stopping potential will be",
                "correct_ans": "1 V",
                "explanation": "KE=hc\u200b/\u03bb\u2212\u200bhc/\u03bbo\u200b=1.65\u00d710^\u221219\u00a0J\u00a0V_s = \\dfrac{KE}{e} = 1V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27867": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "12",
                "question_text": "Two masses 10kg and 20kg are connected by a massless spring. A force of 200N act on 20kg mass. The acceleration of 10kg mass is\u00a012 m/s^2. Then acceleration of 20kg mass will be:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "For 10 kg\\\\F = ma = 10\u00a0\\times\u00d7\u00a012 = 120 N\\\\For 20 kg 200 - F = 20a\\\\or a =\u00a0\\dfrac{200-120}{20} = 4 m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28946": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "90\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Light travels in two media A and B with1.2 \\times 10^8 m/s\u00a0and\u00a02.4\\times 10^8 m/srespectively. The critical angle between them is:",
                "correct_ans": "30\u00b0",
                "explanation": "sinC=Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0denser\u00a0medium\u200b/ Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0rarer\u00a0medium=1/2C=sin\u22121(1/2)=30\u2218",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21050": {
                "ans1": "4500 Angstrom",
                "ans2": "3000 Angstrom",
                "ans3": "5000 Angstrom",
                "ans4": "6000 Angstrom",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In Young's double slit experiment with monochromatic light the fringes are obtained on screen placed at some distance from slit. If screen is moved by\u00a05\\times 10^{-2}\u00a0towards slit, the fringe width changes by\u00a03\\times 10^{-5}. The separation of slit is\u00a010^{-3}m, then wavelength of light is:",
                "correct_ans": "3000 Angstrom",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22827": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3h}{m_oc}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2h}{m_oc}",
                "ans3": "\u221e",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "What will be the de-Broglie wavelength of a particle of rest mass\u00a0m_o\u200b, if it moves with speed of light?",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\u03bb=\u200bh/moc\u200b\u22610",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20148": {
                "ans1": "5 cm/s",
                "ans2": "25 cm/s",
                "ans3": "45 cm/s",
                "ans4": "90 cm/s",
                "question_text": "27 drops of equal size are falling through air with steady velocity 5cm/s coalesce to form a single drop then velocity of single drop will be:",
                "correct_ans": "45 cm/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21698": {
                "ans1": "6s",
                "ans2": "6.5s",
                "ans3": "7s",
                "ans4": "7.5s",
                "question_text": "A stone is dropped from certain height which can reach the ground in 5s. It is stopped after 3 seconds of its fall and then is again released. The total time taken by the stone to reach the ground will be:",
                "correct_ans": "7.5s",
                "explanation": "t1\u200b=3s,\u00a0t=5s\u00a0then\\\\t^2=t_1^2+t_2^2 \\\\ so, t_2= \\sqrt{5^2-3^2} = 4s \\\\t2=t12\u200b+t22\u200bso,t2\u200b=52\u221232\u200b=4s. Thus,\u00a0t=t_1+t_2 = 3+4 = 7s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26210": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3V}{K+2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{V}{3K+2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{3V}{2K+2}",
                "question_text": "Two capacitors of capacitance C and 2C are connected in parallel and charged to a potential difference V. The battery is disconnected and region between the plates of capacitor C is completely filled with a material of dielectric constant K. The potential difference across the capacitors will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "explanation": "Q=(C+2C)V=3CV\nwhen dielectric is placed then, Q = (KC + 2C) V' \\\\ or, V'= \\dfrac{3CV}{C(K+2)} = \\dfrac{3V}{K+2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29052": {
                "ans1": " 1:2:3",
                "ans2": "3:2:1",
                "ans3": "1:6:27",
                "ans4": "27:6:1",
                "question_text": "The masses of three wires of copper are in ratio 1:2:3 and lengths are in ratio 3:2:1. The ratio of their electrical resistances is:",
                "correct_ans": "27:6:1",
                "explanation": "\n\u200b\n \n\\\\ R_1:R_2:R_3 = 9: 2: 1/3 = 27: 6: 1\n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23972": {
                "ans1": "0.05^o",
                "ans2": "0.9^o",
                "ans3": "1.2^o",
                "ans4": "0.4^o",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 2kg is dragged on a horizontal surface with constant speed 2m/s. If coefficient of friction(\u03bc) between the body and the surface is 0.2, then rise in temperature after 5 sec will be of body if specific heat capacity is 0.1cal/g\u2218C",
                "correct_ans": "0.05^o",
                "explanation": "Work done against friction = Heat developed\\\\\nor, \\mu mg (vt) = ms d\\theta \\\\ or, d\\theta = \\dfrac{Mgvt}{S} = 0.047^o C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23523": {
                "ans1": "1cm",
                "ans2": "5/3 cm",
                "ans3": "4/3 cm",
                "ans4": "4/5 cm",
                "question_text": "A point source of light is placed inside the liquid of refractive index 5/3. The radius of greatest circle on the surface is 1cm then depth of the source is:",
                "correct_ans": "4/3 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27544": {
                "ans1": "12 m",
                "ans2": "8 m",
                "ans3": "6 m",
                "ans4": "4 m",
                "question_text": "A point source of y radiation has half life 30min. The initial count rate by GM counter at 4m is 360 counts/s then after 1.5 hrs the distance is altered and count rate become 5 counts/s. The distance between source &counter is changed by",
                "correct_ans": "8 m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21401": {
                "ans1": " twice initial energy",
                "ans2": "thrice initial energy",
                "ans3": "four times initial energy",
                "ans4": "equal to initial energy",
                "question_text": "The energy that should be added to an electron to reduce its de-Brogile wavelength from\u00a010^{-10}\u00a0m to\u00a00.5 *10^{-10} m will be",
                "correct_ans": "thrice initial energy",
                "explanation": "Since energy is inversely proportional to square of wavelength, hence\\dfrac{E_2}{E_1}=\\dfrac{(1 \\times 10^{-10})^2}{(0.5 \\times 10^{-10})^2} E_2-E_1=3E_1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24187": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "unity",
                "question_text": "The magnification of a convex lens of focal length 20 cm when an object is placed at 10 cm in front of lens is",
                "correct_ans": "unity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24828": {
                "ans1": "+60.06 KV   ",
                "ans2": "-60.06 KV   ",
                "ans3": "+62.06 KV   ",
                "ans4": "-62.06 KV",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of emitted electron from a metal surface after striking of photon on it is 0.2 \u00c5. The stopping potential required for this electron is",
                "correct_ans": "-62.06 KV",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22784": {
                "ans1": "484.08 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "466.28 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "458.42 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "452.82 m/s",
                "question_text": "The density of Nitrogen gas at STP is 1.293 Kg/m^3. The root mean square speed of oxygen molecule at STP is",
                "correct_ans": "452.82 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28332": {
                "ans1": "20000 V/m     ",
                "ans2": "10000 V/m   ",
                "ans3": "500 V/m   ",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Two plates of potential 10 V and -10 V are separated at distance of 0.1 cm. The electric field produced between plates is",
                "correct_ans": "20000 V/m     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24511": {
                "ans1": "0.09 mm",
                "ans2": "0.18 mm",
                "ans3": "0.09  \u00b5m",
                "ans4": "0.18  \u00b5m",
                "question_text": "An electron enters an electric field 2 kV/m perpendicular to it with a speed 10 m/s. The displacement of electron beam after 1ns is",
                "correct_ans": "0.18 mm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27318": {
                "ans1": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-5 T",
                "ans2": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-4 T",
                "ans3": "5.56 \u00d7 10-3 T",
                "ans4": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "question_text": "The magnetic field at center of circular\u00a0 coil of radius 10 cm having 500 turns of coil and carrying current 18 A is",
                "correct_ans": "5.56 \u00d7 10^-2 T",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20542": {
                "ans1": "29 min   ",
                "ans2": "30 min   ",
                "ans3": "32 min   ",
                "ans4": "40 min",
                "question_text": "The half of a substance when one-eighteen count is remained after 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": "29 min   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28983": {
                "ans1": "6 W",
                "ans2": "27/8 W",
                "ans3": "4 W",
                "ans4": "16/3 W",
                "question_text": "In order to light a 6W - 6V bulb at rated power a battery of cmf 6V and internal resistance 2\u03a9\u00a0 is used. The bulb will light at",
                "correct_ans": "27/8 W",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28400": {
                "ans1": "zero",
                "ans2": "v/L     ",
                "ans3": "v/2L   ",
                "ans4": "v/4L",
                "question_text": "If a given open organ pipe of length \u2018L\u2019 is dropped in water such that water fills its half length. The change in its fundamental frequency is (v=velocity of sound)",
                "correct_ans": "zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23460": {
                "ans1": "1 A",
                "ans2": "2 A",
                "ans3": "3 A",
                "ans4": "4 A",
                "question_text": "A conductor of length 2cm is bent into arc OA a circle of radius 1cm. A magnetic field of 2*10^{-4}T is developed at centre then the current is",
                "correct_ans": "1 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29621": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{4\\lambda}",
                "ans2": "4\\lambda",
                "ans3": "4\\lambda",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Two radioactive sources A and B decay constants\u00a05\u03bb\u00a0and \u03bb\u00a0respectively. They have same no. of nuclei initially. The ratio of number of nuclei of A and B will be\u00a0(\\dfrac{1}{e})^2\u00a0after a time.",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{2\\lambda}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24866": {
                "ans1": "7 \u00c5   ",
                "ans2": "8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "9 \u00c5   ",
                "ans4": "10 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The de Broglie wavelength of an electron in third orbit of H-atom is",
                "correct_ans": "10 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26542": {
                "ans1": "2 sin A",
                "ans2": "2 cos A",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\cos\\;A",
                "ans4": "tan A",
                "question_text": "A prism of angle A has one surface silvered. Light rays falling at an angle of incidence 2A on first surface return back through the same path after suffering reflection at second silvered surface. The refractive index of material is",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28183": {
                "ans1": "0.4 m",
                "ans2": "0.8 m",
                "ans3": "1 m",
                "ans4": "2.4 m",
                "question_text": "A disc of siren has 80 holes and it is rotated at speed 240 rpm. When a jet of air is blown then a tone is produced. The wavelength of tone is air if speed of sound in air is 320 m/ s",
                "correct_ans": "1 m",
                "explanation": "f = angular speed * no of holesf\\;=\\;\\frac{80\\;\\times240}{60}\\;=\\;320Hz\\lambda\\;=\\frac vf=\\frac{320}{320}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23296": {
                "ans1": "\\style{font-size:11px}{48\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans2": "\\style{font-size:11px}{12\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans3": "\\style{font-size:11px}{96\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "ans4": "\\style{font-size:11px}{192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "question_text": "A liquid drop of radius \u2018R\u2019 breaks into 64 tiny\u00a0droplets each of radius \u2018r\u2019. If the surface tension of the\u00a0liquid is \u2018T\u2019 then gain in energy is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\style{font-size:11px}{192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "explanation": "Let the density of the liquid be \u00a0\u03c1.Mass of the liquid drops must be equal to the total mass of the droplets.\\style{font-size:11px}{Change\\;in\\;surface\\;area\\;\\Delta A=64\\times4\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2-4\\mathrm{\u03c0R}^2}\\style{font-size:11px}{\\\\\\therefore\\triangle\\mathrm A\\;=\\;64\\times4\\mathrm\\pi\\times\\mathrm r^{2\\;\\;}-4\\mathrm\\pi{(4\\mathrm r)}^2=192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\\\\\therefore\\;\\mathrm{Gain}\\;\\mathrm{in}\\;\\mathrm{energy}\\;\\mathrm E\\;=\\;\\mathrm T\\triangle\\mathrm A\\;=\\;192\\mathrm{\u03c0r}^2\\mathrm T}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22706": {
                "ans1": "1840 eV",
                "ans2": "1 eV",
                "ans3": "1 MeV",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Proton has a mass 1840 times that of an electron. If a proton is accelerated from rest by a p.d of 1 volt, its KE is:",
                "correct_ans": "1 eV",
                "explanation": "KE=qV= 1eV",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27508": {
                "ans1": "Solid sphere will expand more than hollow sphere",
                "ans2": "Hollow sphere will expand more than solid sphere",
                "ans3": " Both spheres expand equally",
                "ans4": "Sphere with higher coefficient of expansion expands more",
                "question_text": "Two spheres of same size are made of same metal but one is hollow and the other is solid. If they are heated with same temperature, then",
                "correct_ans": " Both spheres expand equally",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28014": {
                "ans1": "10m/s",
                "ans2": "5m/s",
                "ans3": "15m/s",
                "ans4": "20m/s",
                "question_text": "A particle is moving along a circular path of radius 2m with uniform speed of 5m/s. The change in velocity when the particle completes half of the revolution is",
                "correct_ans": "10m/s",
                "explanation": "At half revolutionsVelocity are in opposite directionsSo change in velocity = 5-(-5)=10m/s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22421": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "500N",
                "ans3": "1000N",
                "ans4": "2000N",
                "question_text": "A rocket has a mass 100 kg, 90% of which is fuel. It ejects fuel vapour at the rate of 1 kg/s with a velocity 500m/s relative to rocket. The initial thrust on rocket in out of gravitational field is",
                "correct_ans": "500N",
                "explanation": "F=(m/t)/v=1*500=500N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28952": {
                "ans1": "100 mA",
                "ans2": "20 mA",
                "ans3": "40 mA",
                "ans4": "80 mA",
                "question_text": "An alternating voltage\u00a0E ( \\text{ in volts}) = 200 \\sqrt2 \\sin 100t is connected to one micro farad capacitor through and a.c. ammeter. The reading of the ammeter shall be:",
                "correct_ans": "20 mA",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26708": {
                "ans1": "1:4",
                "ans2": "1:16",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "16:1",
                "question_text": "The ratio of total energy of an electron in hydrogen atom in n = 1 and n = 4 orbits (i.e., E1: E2) is",
                "correct_ans": "1:16",
                "explanation": "find the ration of respective energy.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25350": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "If an object is placed unsymmetrically between two plane mirrors inclined plane at an angle 72\u2218, then the total number of image formed is:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "n = \\frac{360^o}{\\theta} -1Given ,\u00a0\\theta = 72^o\nn = \\frac{369^o}{72^o} -1=5-1=4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21907": {
                "ans1": "5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "ans2": "1.2*10^{-4} N/m^2",
                "ans3": "0.83*10^{-4} N/m^2",
                "ans4": "30 N/m^2",
                "question_text": "The density of gas is\u00a06 \\times 10^{-2} kg / m ^{3} and RMS speed\u00a0of gas molecule is 500m/s\u00a0then pressure exerted by gas on wall of container will be:",
                "correct_ans": "5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "explanation": "p = \\frac{1}{3}\\delta v^2= \\frac{1}{3}*(6*10^{-2} ) * 500^2)\n= 5*10^3 N/m^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27822": {
                "ans1": "3*10^{-15}",
                "ans2": "1.5*10^{-15}",
                "ans3": "6*10^{-15}",
                "ans4": "4.5*10^{-15}",
                "question_text": "The radius of a nucleus with nucleon number 16 is \u00a03 \\times 10^{-15}. What would be the radius of other nucleus with nucleon no. 128.",
                "correct_ans": "6*10^{-15}",
                "explanation": "Radius R of nucleus changes with the nucleon number A of the nucleus as\u00a01.3 * 10^{-15} * A^{1/3} mHence ,\u00a0\\frac{R_2}{R_1}=\\frac{A_2}{A_1^{1/3}} = (\\frac{128}{16^{1/3}})=(8)^{1/3} = 2R_2 = 2R_1 = 2(3*10^{-15})m = 6*10^{-15}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20241": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt n}=\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_1}}+\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_2}}+\\frac1{\\sqrt{n_3}}",
                "ans3": "n=n_1+n_2+n_3",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt n=\\sqrt{n_1}+\\sqrt{n_2}+\\sqrt{n_3}",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0n_1\u200b,\u00a0n_2\u200b,\u00a0n_3\u200b\u00a0are the fundamental frequencies of three segments into which a string is divided. The original fundamental frequency of wire is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}",
                "explanation": "n_1=\\frac v{2l_1}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_1}\\\\n_2=\\frac v{2l_2}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_2}\\\\n_3=\\frac v{2l_3}\\Rightarrow l_1=\\frac v{2n_2}\\\\Total\\;length(l)\\;=\\;l_1+l_2+l_3\\\\l=\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}\\\\Now, the original fundamental frequency of the wire,n=\\frac v{2l}\\\\n=\\frac v{2\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}+\\frac v{2n_1}}\\right)}\\\\\\\\\\frac1n=\\frac1{n_1}+\\frac1{n_2}+\\frac1{n_3}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28439": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac14\\right)\\\\",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac13\\right)\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac12\\right)\\\\",
                "question_text": "A\u00a0cyclist is moving with a velocity of 18km/hr around a circular path of 15\u00a0m. The angle at which he turns with vertical is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "explanation": "v=18km/hr=\\frac{18\\ast10000}{60\\ast60}m/s\\\\=5\\;m/sR=15m\\theta\\tan\\theta=\\frac{v^2}{Rg}=\\frac{5^2}{15\\ast10}=\\frac16\\\\\\theta=\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac16\\right)\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23187": {
                "ans1": "4:1",
                "ans2": "1:4",
                "ans3": "2:1",
                "ans4": "3:4",
                "question_text": "The ratio of time periods of oscillation of two magnets of same moment of inertia suspended in a magnetic field is\u00a01 : 2. The ratio of their magnetic moment is:",
                "correct_ans": "4:1",
                "explanation": "Ratio\u00a0 of time period of oscillation = 2:1Magnetic field same\u00a0Magnetic moment equal\u00a0T = 2\\pi \\sqrt{\\frac{I}{mB}}\nm_1=m_2\nB_1=B_2\\frac{T_1}{T_2} = \\frac{2}{1}=\\sqrt{\\frac{I_1}{I_2}}\\frac{I_1}{I_2}=\\frac{4}{1}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26726": {
                "ans1": "130^oC",
                "ans2": "140^oC",
                "ans3": "170^oC",
                "ans4": "150^oC",
                "question_text": "A bullet strikes a wall with 250m/s and becomes dead.What is rise in temperature of the bullet if 60% of energy is used as heat and specific heat is 0.03\u00a0cal/g^oC",
                "correct_ans": "150^oC",
                "explanation": "\\triangle \\theta = ?mc\\triangle \\theta = 0.6 * \\frac{1}{2}mv^2\\triangle \\theta = \\frac{0.3 * 250^2}{0.03*4200}=148.8^oC = 150^o C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22318": {
                "ans1": "\\R",
                "ans2": "\\fac{2R}{3}",
                "ans3": "\\fac{R}{3}",
                "ans4": "\\fac{R}{2}",
                "question_text": "The resistance of a galvanometer coil is R. What is the shunt resistance required to convert in to into an ammeter of range 4 times:",
                "correct_ans": "\\fac{R}{3}",
                "explanation": "Shunt resistance is given by:S=\\frac{i_g G}{i-i_g}=\\frac{i_g}{4i_g-i_g}*R=\\frac{R}{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28807": {
                "ans1": "0.01A",
                "ans2": "0.02A",
                "ans3": "0.8A",
                "ans4": "0.08A",
                "question_text": "A voltmeter reads 80V and resistance per unit volt is 100 ohm Then current through it is :",
                "correct_ans": "0.01A",
                "explanation": "V = 80VR = 100*80=8000 ohm\\frac{V}{R}=\\frac{80}{8000}=0.01A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22116": {
                "ans1": "1.284g",
                "ans2": "0.944g",
                "ans3": "4.72g",
                "ans4": "0.472g",
                "question_text": "A man runs in a circular road of 70 m. If the speed of man is 18m/s. Find the acceleration of man in terms of g.",
                "correct_ans": "0.472g",
                "explanation": "R = 70cmV = 18m/s\\frac{v^2}{R}\\frac{18^2}{70}m/s^2=4.63/9.8 g=0.472 g",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26027": {
                "ans1": "0.002",
                "ans2": "0.001",
                "ans3": "0.003",
                "ans4": "0.01",
                "question_text": "Longitudinal stress of\u00a01kg/mm^2\u00a0is applied on a wire . The percentage increase in length is (Y=10^{11} N/m^2.)",
                "correct_ans": "0.001",
                "explanation": "Young's modulus = \\frac{Stress}{Longitudinal strain}Strain = \\frac{1*10^6}{10^{11}}=10^{-5}10^{-5} * 100",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27833": {
                "ans1": "15cm behind lens",
                "ans2": "15cm in front of lens",
                "ans3": "At the focus",
                "ans4": "Infinity",
                "question_text": "An object is at distance 30cm form the convex lens such that focal length of convex lens is 30 cm. Then the\u00a0image will be formed at:(IOE 2077)",
                "correct_ans": "Infinity",
                "explanation": "u= 30 cmf = 30cmimage distance (v) = ?we have ,\\frac{1}{u}+\\frac{1}{v}=\\frac{1}{f}\\frac{1}{30}+\\frac{1}{v}=\\frac{1}{30}\\frac{1}{v}=0v= \\inftyimage is formed at infinityalternative,when an object is at focus of a convex lens , image is formed at infinity.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20070": {
                "ans1": "0.8V/m",
                "ans2": "1.2V/m",
                "ans3": "0.4V/m",
                "ans4": "2.4V/m",
                "question_text": "A wire of length 6m and resistance 6 ohm is connected with resistor 3 ohm in series . If emf of 4V is connected to the cirvuit having internal resistance 1 ohm potential gradient of wire is :",
                "correct_ans": "0.4V/m",
                "explanation": "I=\\frac{V}{R}=\\frac{4}{6+3+1} = 0.4Avoltage drop = I*6=0.4*6=2.4Vpotential=\\frac{2.4}{6}=0.4V/m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27862": {
                "ans1": "h",
                "ans2": "h^2",
                "ans3": "\\frac{h}{2 \\pi }",
                "ans4": "\\frac{2h}{ \\pi }",
                "question_text": "Energy of hydrogen in excited energy state is -3.4eV. Then angular momentum on that state is:",
                "correct_ans": "h",
                "explanation": "E_n = -\\frac{13.6}{n^2}eV-3.4 = -\\frac{13.6}{n^2}n=2n^{th}\\frac{nh}{2 \\pi }=\\frac{2h}{2 \\pi } = \\frac{h}{2 \\pi } since h=\\frac{h}{2\\pi}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26424": {
                "ans1": "36^o",
                "ans2": "32^o",
                "ans3": "46^o",
                "ans4": "306^o",
                "question_text": "If the translational KE of air molecule is 0.04eV . Then temperature will be : (K=1.38*20^{-23})",
                "correct_ans": "36^o",
                "explanation": "KE= \\frac{3}{2}KT0.04 * 1.6*10^{-10} = \\frac{3}{2}*1.38*10^{-23}*TT=309.17K36^oC",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29550": {
                "ans1": "28s",
                "ans2": "23s",
                "ans3": "29s",
                "ans4": "21s",
                "question_text": "The car has maximum acceleration of\u00a010m/s^2\u00a0and maximum decceleration of\u00a015m/s^2.If car has to stop in 1600m.Time taken is :",
                "correct_ans": "23s",
                "explanation": "V^2= 2a_1s_1s_1=\\frac{V^2}{20}Again ,s_2=\\frac{V^2}{30}Solving these\u00a0V= 138.56m/salsoV=a_1t_1 = t_1 = \\frac{138.56}{10}t_1 = 13.85sV =a_2t_2t_2 = \\frac{138.56}{15}=9.23sTotal_{time}=t_1t_2=23s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21862": {
                "ans1": "2.5\\mu F",
                "ans2": "4.9\\mu F",
                "ans3": "6.2\\mu F",
                "ans4": "9.8\\mu F",
                "question_text": "The equivalent capacitance of similar capacitors when connected in series is 4\\mu F\u00a0 and when connected in parallel is\u00a06 \\mu F\u00a0find each capacitance",
                "correct_ans": "4.9\\mu F",
                "explanation": "\\frac{C}{n}4=\\frac{C}{n}n=\\frac{C}{4}when connected in parallelEquivalent resistance = nC6=\\frac{C}{4}*CC^2 = 24C = 4.89 = 4.94F",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28844": {
                "ans1": "1.25s",
                "ans2": "0.69s",
                "ans3": "0.35s",
                "ans4": "1s",
                "question_text": "A ball of radius 1cm oscillates in a bowl of radius 4cm in SHM.Find the period of oscillation . (g=980cm/s^2).",
                "correct_ans": "0.35s",
                "explanation": "In this SHM , the center of bowl acts like point of suspension , Thus equivalent length of simple pendulum=(R-r)l=(4-1)l=3cm2\\pi \\sqrt{\\frac{l}{g}}2\\pi \\sqrt{\\frac{3}{980}}= 0.35sec",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22963": {
                "ans1": "+20cm and -20cm",
                "ans2": "+20cm and -25cm",
                "ans3": "-15cm and +20cm",
                "ans4": "+15cm and -20cm",
                "question_text": "The dispersive powers of the materials of two lenses are in ratio 4:3 . If achromatic combination of these two lenses in contact is a convex lens of focal length 60 cm , then the focal lengths of component lenses are:",
                "correct_ans": "+15cm and -20cm",
                "explanation": "Ratio of dispersive power,\\frac{w_1}{w_2}=-\\frac{f_1}{f_2}=\\frac{4}{3}f_1 = -\\frac{4}{3}f_2Also , \n\\frac{1}{f_1}+\\frac{1}{f_2}=\\frac{1}{60}- \\frac{3}{4}f_2+\\frac{1}{f_2}=\\frac{1}{60}f_2=15cmf_1=-\\frac{4}{3}*15=-20cm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22190": {
                "ans1": "6.8*10^6 m/s",
                "ans2": "9.8*10^5 m/s",
                "ans3": "5.9*10^6 m/s",
                "ans4": "6.3*10^5 m/s",
                "question_text": "The velocity of an electron moving in an electric field of voltage 100V is : ( The specific charge ratio of electron in\u00a01.76*10^{11}\u00a0)",
                "correct_ans": "5.9*10^6 m/s",
                "explanation": "qV = \\frac{1}{2}mv^2eV = \\frac{1}{2}mv^2V = \\sqrt{\\frac{2eV}{m}}\\sqrt{2*1.76*10^11*100}5.9*10^6 m/s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29543": {
                "ans1": "18 kg",
                "ans2": "27 kg",
                "ans3": "36 kg",
                "ans4": "72 kg",
                "question_text": "A segment of wire vibrates with fundamental frequency of 450Hz under a tension of 9kg. The tension at which fundamental frequency become 900Hz is",
                "correct_ans": "36 kg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25186": {
                "ans1": "1.7 V",
                "ans2": "1.6 V",
                "ans3": "1.5 V",
                "ans4": "1 V",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The threshold wavelength of metal is 4000 \u00c5 then the light of wavelength 3000 \u00c5 incident on metal then stopping potential will be",
                "correct_ans": "1 V",
                "explanation": "KE=hc\u200b/\u03bb\u2212\u200bhc/\u03bbo\u200b=1.65\u00d710^\u221219\u00a0J\u00a0V_s = \\dfrac{KE}{e} = 1V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25324": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "12",
                "question_text": "Two masses 10kg and 20kg are connected by a massless spring. A force of 200N act on 20kg mass. The acceleration of 10kg mass is\u00a012 m/s^2. Then acceleration of 20kg mass will be:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "For 10 kg\\\\F = ma = 10\u00a0\\times\u00d7\u00a012 = 120 N\\\\For 20 kg 200 - F = 20a\\\\or a =\u00a0\\dfrac{200-120}{20} = 4 m/s^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20434": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "45\u00b0",
                "ans3": "60\u00b0",
                "ans4": "90\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Light travels in two media A and B with1.2 \\times 10^8 m/s\u00a0and\u00a02.4\\times 10^8 m/srespectively. The critical angle between them is:",
                "correct_ans": "30\u00b0",
                "explanation": "sinC=Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0denser\u00a0medium\u200b/ Velocity\u00a0in\u00a0rarer\u00a0medium=1/2C=sin\u22121(1/2)=30\u2218",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20059": {
                "ans1": "4500 Angstrom",
                "ans2": "3000 Angstrom",
                "ans3": "5000 Angstrom",
                "ans4": "6000 Angstrom",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In Young's double slit experiment with monochromatic light the fringes are obtained on screen placed at some distance from slit. If screen is moved by\u00a05\\times 10^{-2}\u00a0towards slit, the fringe width changes by\u00a03\\times 10^{-5}. The separation of slit is\u00a010^{-3}m, then wavelength of light is:",
                "correct_ans": "3000 Angstrom",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23685": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3h}{m_oc}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2h}{m_oc}",
                "ans3": "\u221e",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "What will be the de-Broglie wavelength of a particle of rest mass\u00a0m_o\u200b, if it moves with speed of light?",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\u03bb=\u200bh/moc\u200b\u22610",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25294": {
                "ans1": "5 cm/s",
                "ans2": "25 cm/s",
                "ans3": "45 cm/s",
                "ans4": "90 cm/s",
                "question_text": "27 drops of equal size are falling through air with steady velocity 5cm/s coalesce to form a single drop then velocity of single drop will be:",
                "correct_ans": "45 cm/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27518": {
                "ans1": "6s",
                "ans2": "6.5s",
                "ans3": "7s",
                "ans4": "7.5s",
                "question_text": "A stone is dropped from certain height which can reach the ground in 5s. It is stopped after 3 seconds of its fall and then is again released. The total time taken by the stone to reach the ground will be:",
                "correct_ans": "7.5s",
                "explanation": "t1\u200b=3s,\u00a0t=5s\u00a0then\\\\t^2=t_1^2+t_2^2 \\\\ so, t_2= \\sqrt{5^2-3^2} = 4s \\\\t2=t12\u200b+t22\u200bso,t2\u200b=52\u221232\u200b=4s. Thus,\u00a0t=t_1+t_2 = 3+4 = 7s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22195": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3V}{K+2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{V}{3K+2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{3V}{2K+2}",
                "question_text": "Two capacitors of capacitance C and 2C are connected in parallel and charged to a potential difference V. The battery is disconnected and region between the plates of capacitor C is completely filled with a material of dielectric constant K. The potential difference across the capacitors will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{3V}{K+5}",
                "explanation": "Q=(C+2C)V=3CV\nwhen dielectric is placed then, Q = (KC + 2C) V' \\\\ or, V'= \\dfrac{3CV}{C(K+2)} = \\dfrac{3V}{K+2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22702": {
                "ans1": " 1:2:3",
                "ans2": "3:2:1",
                "ans3": "1:6:27",
                "ans4": "27:6:1",
                "question_text": "The masses of three wires of copper are in ratio 1:2:3 and lengths are in ratio 3:2:1. The ratio of their electrical resistances is:",
                "correct_ans": "27:6:1",
                "explanation": "\n\u200b\n \n\\\\ R_1:R_2:R_3 = 9: 2: 1/3 = 27: 6: 1\n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24699": {
                "ans1": "0.05^o",
                "ans2": "0.9^o",
                "ans3": "1.2^o",
                "ans4": "0.4^o",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 2kg is dragged on a horizontal surface with constant speed 2m/s. If coefficient of friction(\u03bc) between the body and the surface is 0.2, then rise in temperature after 5 sec will be of body if specific heat capacity is 0.1cal/g\u2218C",
                "correct_ans": "0.05^o",
                "explanation": "Work done against friction = Heat developed\\\\\nor, \\mu mg (vt) = ms d\\theta \\\\ or, d\\theta = \\dfrac{Mgvt}{S} = 0.047^o C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25984": {
                "ans1": "1cm",
                "ans2": "5/3 cm",
                "ans3": "4/3 cm",
                "ans4": "4/5 cm",
                "question_text": "A point source of light is placed inside the liquid of refractive index 5/3. The radius of greatest circle on the surface is 1cm then depth of the source is:",
                "correct_ans": "4/3 cm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29723": {
                "ans1": "12 m",
                "ans2": "8 m",
                "ans3": "6 m",
                "ans4": "4 m",
                "question_text": "A point source of y radiation has half life 30min. The initial count rate by GM counter at 4m is 360 counts/s then after 1.5 hrs the distance is altered and count rate become 5 counts/s. The distance between source &counter is changed by",
                "correct_ans": "8 m",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29139": {
                "ans1": "1m",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt2}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "2m",
                "question_text": "A small hole is made at a height of \\frac1{\\sqrt2}m from bottom of cylindrical tank at a depth of h = \u221a2 m from upper level of water. The distance at which water entering will strike the ground is",
                "correct_ans": "2m",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}v=\\sqrt{2g\\sqrt2}\\\\t=\\sqrt{\\frac{2h}g}=\\sqrt{\\frac2{\\sqrt2g}}\\\\R=vt=2\\;m\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20002": {
                "ans1": "18cm towards",
                "ans2": "36 cm towards",
                "ans3": "36cm away",
                "ans4": "18cm away",
                "question_text": "\u00a0An object is placed at 40cm from a concave mirror of focal length 15cm. If the object is displaced 20cm towards the mirror the displacement of image from mirror is",
                "correct_ans": "36cm away",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}1st\\;case:\\\\v=\\frac{fu}{u-f}=\\frac{15\\times40}{40-15}=24cm\\\\2nd\\;case:\\\\v'=\\frac{fu'}{u'-f}=60cm\\\\then\\;v'-v=36\\;cm\\;away\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29838": {
                "ans1": "11 mH",
                "ans2": "16mH",
                "ans3": "22mH",
                "ans4": "33mH",
                "question_text": "A long solenoid connected to a 12V de source passes a steady current of 2A. When solenoid is connected to an ac source of 12V at 50Hz. the current is found 1A the inductance of solenoid is",
                "correct_ans": "33mH",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;dc,\\\\R=\\frac VI=\\frac{12}1=12\\\\For\\;ac,\\\\Z=\\sqrt{R^2+X_L^2}=10.4\\\\2\\pi fL=10.4\\\\or,\\;L=33mH\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20170": {
                "ans1": "0.4 m",
                "ans2": "4.9 m",
                "ans3": "19.6 m",
                "ans4": "20 m",
                "question_text": "A ballon is ascending vertically with an acceleration of 0.2 m/s^2. Two stones are dropped from it at an interval of 2 sec. The distance between them when the second stone dropped is (g = 9.8 m/s\u00b2)",
                "correct_ans": "20 m",
                "explanation": "h=\\frac12a_rt^2=\\frac12(g+a)\\times2^2=20",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29175": {
                "ans1": "68.3\u00b0C",
                "ans2": "-204.8\u00b0C",
                "ans3": "204.8\u00b0C",
                "ans4": "136.6\u00b0C",
                "question_text": "The temperature at which rms speed of gas molecule become half of 0\u00b0C\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "204.8\u00b0C",
                "explanation": "C_{rms\\;}\\alpha\\sqrt T",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26984": {
                "ans1": "2.5",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "7.5",
                "ans4": "8.5",
                "question_text": "When a slab of insulating material 4mm thick is introduced between the plates of parallel plate capacitor then distance between plates has to be raised by 3.2mm to restore same capacity. The dielectric constant of material is",
                "correct_ans": "8.5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "24982": {
                "ans1": "927.3 \u00c5    ",
                "ans2": "966.8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "958.2 \u00c5    ",
                "ans4": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of a photon required to excite electron from ground state of hydrogen atom to its fourth excited state is",
                "correct_ans": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25998": {
                "ans1": "0.01%",
                "ans2": "0.1%",
                "ans3": "0.02%",
                "ans4": "0.2%",
                "question_text": "A sphere is taken to bottom of sea 1km deep then the volume of sphere decreases by, if Bulk modulus is 4.9 *10^{10}N/m\u00b2\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "0.2%",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\triangle V}V=\\frac PB=\\frac{\\rho gh}B=0.02\\%",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27165": {
                "ans1": "773.5\t\u00c5",
                "ans2": "825.2\t\u00c5",
                "ans3": "973.5\t\u00c5",
                "ans4": "1212.5 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "A photon fall on hydrogen atom in ground state and excited to 4th energy level then wavelength of photon is",
                "correct_ans": "973.5\t\u00c5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}E_4-E_1=\\frac{hc}\\lambda\\\\\\lambda=\\frac{6.62\\times10^{-34}\\times3\\times10^8}{\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac{-13.6}{16}}+13.6\\right)1.6\\times10^{-19}}=970\\;\u00c5\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21809": {
                "ans1": "800\\;\\Omega",
                "ans2": "790 \u03a9",
                "ans3": "810 \u03a9",
                "ans4": "1190 \u03a9",
                "question_text": "A potentiometer of length 100cm has resistance 100. A source of 2V is connected across it then a source of 10mV is balance by the length of 40cm on potentiometer. The value of resistance needed in series of potentiometer is",
                "correct_ans": "790 \u03a9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}R=\\frac{10}{100}\\times40=4\\;\\Omega\\\\now,\\;\\frac{10\\;\\times10^{-3}}4=\\frac2{R+10}\\\\or,\\;R\\;=\\;790\\Omega\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21336": {
                "ans1": "2.75 \u00d7 10\u00b9\u00b9m",
                "ans2": "2.1 \u00d7 10\u00b3m",
                "ans3": "8.25 x 10\u00b3 m",
                "ans4": "1.12 x 10 m",
                "question_text": "In young double slit experiment, interference pattern are obtained on screen at a distance of Im from slits separated by 0.05 cm and illuminted by light of 5893\u00c5.The distance between 4th bright fringe on one side and 3rd bright fringe on other side of central bright fringe is",
                "correct_ans": "8.25 x 10\u00b3 m",
                "explanation": "x=7\\beta=\\frac{7D\\lambda}d=8.25\\times10^{-3}m",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27416": {
                "ans1": "1225 N",
                "ans2": "3050 N",
                "ans3": "1825 N",
                "ans4": "2550N",
                "question_text": "A stone of mass 5kg falls from the top of cliff of 50m high and buries Im deep in sand. The average resistance offered by sand is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "2550N",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}While\\;falling\\;,\\\\v^2=0^2+2gh\\\\v=\\sqrt{2\\ast10\\ast50}=\\sqrt{1000}\\\\In\\;sand,\\\\u=\\sqrt{1000}\\;,\\;v=0\\;,\\;s=1m\\\\v^2=u^2+2as\\\\a=-500m/s^2\\\\now,\\;F-mg=ma\\\\or,F=2250\\;N\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20055": {
                "ans1": "164 J",
                "ans2": "274J",
                "ans3": "374J",
                "ans4": "400J",
                "question_text": "A cylinder of fixed capacity 44.8 Its contains helium gas at standard temperature and pressure. The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of gas in cylinder by 15\u00b0C\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "374J",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}n=\\frac{44.8}{22.4}=2\\\\dQ=nC_vdT=2\\times\\frac32R\\times15=374\\;J\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26902": {
                "ans1": "576 Hz",
                "ans2": "580 Hz",
                "ans3": "584 Hz",
                "ans4": "588 Hz",
                "question_text": "A fork is in unison with a sonometer wire 73\u00a0cm long. If 4 beats are heard on s shortening the wire by 5mm then the frequency of fork is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "584 Hz",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26592": {
                "ans1": "130^oC",
                "ans2": "140^oC",
                "ans3": "170^oC",
                "ans4": "150^oC",
                "question_text": "A bullet strikes a wall with 250m/s and becomes dead.What is rise in temperature of the bullet if 60% of energy is used as heat and specific heat is 0.03\u00a0cal/g^oC",
                "correct_ans": "150^oC",
                "explanation": "\\triangle \\theta = ?mc\\triangle \\theta = 0.6 * \\frac{1}{2}mv^2\\triangle \\theta = \\frac{0.3 * 250^2}{0.03*4200}=148.8^oC = 150^o C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28612": {
                "ans1": "2s",
                "ans2": "3s",
                "ans3": "4s",
                "ans4": "5s",
                "question_text": "A stone is dropped from a certain height which can reach the ground in 5 sec. If the stone is stopped after 3 second of its fall and then allowed to fall again, then time in which stone reach the ground by travelling remaining distance is",
                "correct_ans": "4s",
                "explanation": "t^{2}=t_{1}^{2}+t_{2}^{2}\\\\\nor, \\;5^{2}=3^{2}+t_{2}^{2}\\\\\nor, t_{2}=\\sqrt{5^{2}-3^{2}}=4 \\mathrm{sec}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21819": {
                "ans1": "0.5mV",
                "ans2": "0.25mV",
                "ans3": "0.75mV",
                "ans4": "1mV",
                "question_text": "The\u00a0 aerial of 1m long in a car moving east to west with velocity 100km/hr. The horizontal component of earth 's magnetic field is 0.18gauss. The induced emf is",
                "correct_ans": "0.5mV",
                "explanation": "E=Blv=0.18\\times10^{-4}\\times1\\times\\frac{100\\times1000}{3600}\\\\=5\\times10^{-4}V=0.5mV",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22609": {
                "ans1": "2 J",
                "ans2": "3.8 J",
                "ans3": "5.2 J",
                "ans4": "2.6 J",
                "question_text": "A body of mass 3kg is under the action of force causing displacements S=\\left(\\frac{t^{2}}{3}\\right) \\mathrm{m}. The work done by force in \u00a02\\mathrm{sec} will be",
                "correct_ans": "2.6 J",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned} &s=\\frac{t^{2}}{3} \\\\ &\\frac{d s}{d t}=v=\\frac{2 t}{3} \\\\ &\\therefore a=\\frac{2}{3} \\mathrm{~m} / \\mathrm{s}^{2} \\end{aligned}\\begin{aligned} \\therefore W &=\\int_{0}^{2} F d s=\\int_{0}^{2} m a d s=\\int_{0}^{2} 3 \\times \\frac{2}{3} \\times \\frac{2}{3} t d t \\\\ &=\\frac{4}{3}\\left(\\frac{t^{2}}{2}\\right)_{0}^{2}=\\frac{4}{6}\\left(2^{2}-0^{2}\\right)=\\frac{16}{6}=2.66 \\mathrm{~J} \\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23776": {
                "ans1": "9/16",
                "ans2": "25/16",
                "ans3": "4/5",
                "ans4": "5/4",
                "question_text": "A mass M is suspended from a spring of negligible mass. The spring is pulled a little and then released so that mass execute SHM of time period T. If mass increased by 'm', then time period become \\frac{5 T}{4}\u00a0then ratio of\u00a0\\frac{m}{M}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "9/16",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned}\n&\\frac{T_{2}}{T_{1}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{M+m}{M}} \\\\\n&\\text { or, } \\frac{5 T}{4 T}=\\sqrt{\\frac{M+m}{M}} \\\\\n&\\text { or, } \\frac{25}{16}=\\frac{M+m}{M} \\\\\n&\\text { or, } 16 M+16 m=25 M \\\\\n&\\text { or, } 16 m=9 M \\\\\n&\\text { or, } \\frac{m}{M}=\\frac{9}{16}\n\\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21679": {
                "ans1": "54",
                "ans2": "64",
                "ans3": "74",
                "ans4": "84",
                "question_text": "In Young's double slit experiment using light of wavelength 5893A. 62 fringes are observed in the field of view a source of lightof wavelength 4355A replace the first source the number of fringes in same field of view is",
                "correct_ans": "84",
                "explanation": "n_1\\lambda_1=n_2\\lambda_2\\\\or,\\;n_2=\\frac{62\\times5893}{4358}=84",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28556": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "The number of bulb of 50w and 100v can be connected in parallel across 120v battery ofinternal resistance 10\\Omega\u00a0so that each glow with full power is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "R=\\frac{v^2}p=\\frac{100^2}{50}=200\\Omega\\;\\\\I=\\frac PV=\\frac{50}{100}=0.5A\\;\\\\To\\;glow\\;with\\;full\\;power,\\;current\\;throught\\;each\\;bulb\\;must\\\\be\\;0.5A\\;so\\;nI=\\frac V{r+{\\displaystyle\\frac Rn}}or,\\;0.5n\\;=\\frac{120}{10+{\\displaystyle\\frac{200}n}}\\\\or,0.5n=\\frac{120n}{10n+200}0r,\\;5n+100=120\\;or,5n=20\\\\\\therefore n=4\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23083": {
                "ans1": "2cm",
                "ans2": "3cm",
                "ans3": "4cm",
                "ans4": "6cm",
                "question_text": "Two soap bubbles of radii 2cm and 4cm comes in contact then radius of common interface is:",
                "correct_ans": "4cm",
                "explanation": "r=\\frac{r_{1} r_{2}}{r_{2}-r_{1}}=\\frac{2 \\times 4}{4-2}=4 \\mathrm{~cm}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20004": {
                "ans1": "V",
                "ans2": "4V",
                "ans3": "8V",
                "ans4": "16V",
                "question_text": "Sixty four charged drops of capacity C and potential V are put together to form a bigger drop. The potential of bigger drop will be",
                "correct_ans": "16V",
                "explanation": "\\begin{aligned}\n\\frac{\\mathrm{V}_{2}}{\\mathrm{~V}_{1}} &=(\\mathrm{n})^{2 / 3} \\\\\n\\text { or, } \\quad \\mathrm{V}_{2} &=(64)^{2 / 3} \\mathrm{~V}=16 \\mathrm{~V}\n\\end{aligned}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23459": {
                "ans1": "38^\\circ C",
                "ans2": "33.3^\\circ C",
                "ans3": "30^\\circ C",
                "ans4": "36^\\circ C",
                "question_text": "A metal ball cools from 50^{\\circ} \\mathrm{C}\u00a0to 40^{\\circ} \\mathrm{C}\u00a0in 5 \\mathrm{~min}. If temperature of room is\u00a020^{\\circ} \\mathrm{C} then temperature in next 5 min will be",
                "correct_ans": "33.3^\\circ C",
                "explanation": "\\frac{\\left(\\frac{d \\theta}{d t}\\right)_{1}}{\\left(\\frac{d \\theta}{d t}\\right)_{2}}=\\frac{\\theta_{1}-\\theta_{0}}{\\theta_{2}-\\theta_{0}}or, \\frac{\\frac{10}{5}}{\\frac{40-\\theta}{5}}=\\frac{45-20}{\\frac{40+\\theta}{2}-20}\\\\\nor, \\frac{10}{40-\\theta}=\\frac{25 \\times 2}{\\theta}\\\\\nor, 20-5 \\theta=\\theta\\\\\nor, \\theta=\\frac{200}{6}=33.3^{\\circ} \\mathrm{C}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26461": {
                "ans1": "1V",
                "ans2": "125.6V",
                "ans3": "64.1V",
                "ans4": "250V",
                "question_text": "The inductance of choke coil is 0.2H and its resistance is 0.5\\Omega\u00a0.If alternating current of 2A and frequency 50Hz is\u00a0passed then potential difference across it is",
                "correct_ans": "125.6V",
                "explanation": "z=\\sqrt{R^2+{X^2}_L}=\\sqrt{0.5^2+\\left(2\\pi fL\\right)^2}\\\\=\\sqrt{0.5^2+\\left(2\\pi\\times50\\times0.2\\right)^2}=62.8\\Omega\\\\V=I_{rms}Z=2\\times62.8=125.6V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21467": {
                "ans1": "1.6 days",
                "ans2": "16.4 days",
                "ans3": "20 days",
                "ans4": "76 days",
                "question_text": "Half\u00a0 life of radioactive radon is 3.8 days. The time at the end of which\u00a0\\left(\\frac1{20}\\right)^{th}\u00a0of radon sample will remain un-decayed is",
                "correct_ans": "16.4 days",
                "explanation": "\\frac N{N_0}=\\left(\\frac12\\right)^\\frac t{T_{\\displaystyle\\frac12}}\\\\or,\\frac1{20}=\\left(\\frac12\\right)^\\frac t{3.8}\\\\or,\\;ln\\;\\left(\\frac1{20}\\right)=\\frac t{3.8}ln\\left(\\frac12\\right)\\\\0r,t=\\frac{ln\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac1{20}}\\right)}{ln\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac12}\\right)}\\times3.8=16.4\\;days",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29923": {
                "ans1": "8\\times10^5m/s",
                "ans2": "2\\times10^6m/s",
                "ans3": "8\\times10^6m/s",
                "ans4": "2\\times10^7m/s",
                "question_text": "The threshold frequency for a certain metal is\u00a0f_0. when light of frequency 2f_0\u00a0incident on it then the maximum velocity of photo electrons\u00a0is\u00a04\\times10^6m/s\u00a0.The velocity of electron due to a photon of frequency 5f_0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "8\\times10^6m/s",
                "explanation": "hf-\\phi=\\frac12mv^2\\;or,\\;h\\times2f_0-hf_0=\\frac12mv^2\\\\or,hf_0\\frac12mv^2\\dots\\left(i\\right)\\;Again,\\;hf-\\phi=\\frac12mv^2or,h5f_0-hf_0=\\frac12mv^2\\\\or,\\;4hf_0=\\frac12mv^2\\dots\\left(ii\\right)\\;Dividing\\;\\left(ii\\right)\\;by\\left(i\\right)\\\\\\left(\\frac{v'}v\\right)^2=4\\;\\therefore v'=2\\times v=2\\times4\\times10^6=8\\times10^6m/s",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27888": {
                "ans1": "100V",
                "ans2": "200V",
                "ans3": "\\frac{200}3V",
                "ans4": "\\frac{400}3V",
                "question_text": "The parallel plate capacitors of capacitance 1\u00b5F and 5\u00b5F are charged separately to the same potential of 100V . The positive plate of the\u00a0first is connected to negative plate of\u00a02^{nd}\u00a0then potential across them will be",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{200}3V",
                "explanation": "when\\;+ve\\;of\\;one\\;is\\;connected\\;with\\;-v\\;plate\\;of\\;another\\\\capacitor\\;\\;then\\;\\\\Q_{2-}Q_1=\\left(C_{1+}C_2\\right)V\\\\or,\\;V=\\frac{C2V_2-C_1V_1}{C_1+C_2}\\\\=\\frac{5\\times10^{-6}\\times100-1\\times10^{-6}\\times100}{1\\times10^{-6}+5\\times10^{-6}}=66.6V",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27738": {
                "ans1": "334.5 KJ   ",
                "ans2": "-334.5 KJ   ",
                "ans3": "337.5 KJ    ",
                "ans4": "-337.5 KJ",
                "question_text": "1 kg of ice is heated and volume is found to be decreased by 0.005 m3 at 3 atmospheric pressures while melting. The change in internal energy of ice is (Lt=80 cal/gm)",
                "correct_ans": "337.5 KJ    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22010": {
                "ans1": "10000 K    ",
                "ans2": "2515 K    ",
                "ans3": "402 K   ",
                "ans4": "300 K",
                "question_text": "The root mean square velocity of Hydrogen gas is one fifth of the escape velocity on surface of earth at temperature of",
                "correct_ans": "402 K   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29888": {
                "ans1": "6 sec     ",
                "ans2": "8 sec      ",
                "ans3": "10 sec     ",
                "ans4": "12 sec",
                "question_text": "A stone is dropped from a balloon rising with the velocity of 19.6 m/s from height 294 m. The time at which stone will strike ground is (g=9.8 m/s2)",
                "correct_ans": "10 sec     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23529": {
                "ans1": "t",
                "ans2": "\u00bd",
                "ans3": "1/\u221a2",
                "ans4": "1/\u221a3  ",
                "question_text": "A tank is filled with water up to and hole at the bottom is unplugged, it takes time \u2018t\u2019 to empty the tank. If the tank is half filled, the time taken to empty it is",
                "correct_ans": "1/\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27403": {
                "ans1": "0.2 A   ",
                "ans2": "0.4 A    ",
                "ans3": "0.6 A   ",
                "ans4": "0.8 A",
                "question_text": "Four cells each 2 V, 2\\Omega\u00a0are connected in parallel and connected to an external resistor of 2 \\OmegaThe current through external resistor is",
                "correct_ans": "0.8 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "20375": {
                "ans1": "0.667 m   ",
                "ans2": "0.667 cm   ",
                "ans3": "0.667 mm    ",
                "ans4": "0.667 \u03bcm",
                "question_text": "An electron is moving in a circular path having uniform magnetic field of 0.5 T with velocity equal to accelerated through applied voltage of 10 KV. The radius of circular path travelled by electron is (specific charge of electron=1.8\\;\\times\\;10^{11})",
                "correct_ans": "0.667 mm    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27803": {
                "ans1": "99.47\\;MJ/m^3\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "99.47\\;mJ/m^3\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "99.47\\;\u03bcJ/m^3\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "99.47\\;nJ/m^3\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "If B=5 \\overrightarrow j, gauss in a region in space. The energy density at that region is",
                "correct_ans": "99.47\\;mJ/m^3\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22959": {
                "ans1": "1.25\\;\\times\\;10^{20}\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "1.5\\;\\times\\;10^{20}\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "1.875\\;\\times\\;10^{20}\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "2.5\\;\\times\\;10^{20}\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "Two charged sphere with identical dimensions have charges 20 C and 40 C are touched and separated by some distance. The number of electrons in each charged sphere is finally",
                "correct_ans": "1.875\\;\\times\\;10^{20}\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28123": {
                "ans1": "24 cm   ",
                "ans2": "18 cm",
                "ans3": "12 cm    ",
                "ans4": "8 cm",
                "question_text": "A concave mirror produces erect image which is three times bigger than object. If focal length of mirror is 18 cm, object distance is",
                "correct_ans": "12 cm    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28856": {
                "ans1": "0.1 V/m   ",
                "ans2": "0.2 V/m   ",
                "ans3": "1 V/m   ",
                "ans4": "2 V/m",
                "question_text": "A 10 m long potentiometer wire with resistance 2\\Omega\u00a0is connected in series with battery of emf 3 V and 10\\Omega\u00a0resistance. The potential gradient across potentiometer wire is",
                "correct_ans": "0.2 V/m   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23332": {
                "ans1": "3000^0\\;C\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "2727^0\\;C\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "333.33^0\\;C\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "60.33^0\\;C\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "The efficiency of carrot engines is same for source and sink temperature of 600 K and 200 K & 1000 K and T K. The value of \u2018T\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "60.33^0\\;C\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23933": {
                "ans1": "12.67 m/s   ",
                "ans2": "300 m/s   ",
                "ans3": "332 m/s   ",
                "ans4": "400 m/s",
                "question_text": "The velocity of sound in mixture of 1 mole of helium and 2 moles of oxygen gas at \u00a027^0C\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "400 m/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29788": {
                "ans1": "mgR ",
                "ans2": "mgR/2    ",
                "ans3": "mgR/3",
                "ans4": "3mgR/2",
                "question_text": "The acceleration due to gravity at each surface a is \u2018g\u2019. Work done required to lift body of mass \u2018m\u2019 through height equal to radius of earth \u2018R \u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "mgR/2    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "28920": {
                "ans1": "927.3 \u00c5    ",
                "ans2": "966.8 \u00c5   ",
                "ans3": "958.2 \u00c5    ",
                "ans4": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of a photon required to excite electron from ground state of hydrogen atom to its fourth excited state is",
                "correct_ans": "949.5 \u00c5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27087": {
                "ans1": "1:4 ",
                "ans2": "4:1",
                "ans3": "1:1",
                "ans4": "3:1",
                "question_text": "Velocity of sound is measured in hydrogen and oxygen at a given temperature. The ratio of two velocities (V_H\\;and\\;V_o ) will be",
                "correct_ans": "1:4 ",
                "explanation": "\\frac{V_o}{V_H}=\\sqrt{\\frac{m_h}{m_o}}=\\sqrt{\\frac1{16}}=\\frac14",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26271": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt{\\frac{10gh}7}",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{gh}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{2gh}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac{4gh}3}",
                "question_text": "A homogeneous sphere is rolling down an inclined plane of height \u2018h\u2019 then the velocity of sphere while reaching to bottom of plane is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{\\frac{10gh}7}",
                "explanation": " \\begin{array}{l}V^2=\\frac{2gh}{1+{\\displaystyle\\frac{K^2}{R^2}}}\\\\For\\;a\\;sphere\\;\\frac{K^2}{R^2}=\\frac{2\\;}5\\\\Now,\\;v^2=\\frac{2gh}{1+{\\displaystyle\\frac25}}=\\frac{10gh}7\\\\Therefore,V=\\sqrt{\\frac{10gh}7}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21626": {
                "ans1": "2\\;\\times10^{-2}",
                "ans2": "3\\;\\times10^{-2}",
                "ans3": "4\\;\\times10^{-2}",
                "ans4": "1\\;\\times10^{-2}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}Two\\;metallic\\;spheres\\;of\\;radii\\;1\\;cm\\;\\&\\;2cm\\;are\\;given\\;changes\\;10^{-2}C\\;and\\;5\\;x\\;10^{-2\\;C}\\\\respectively.\\;If\\;they\\;are\\;connected\\;by\\;a\\;conducting\\;wire\\;then\\;final\\;charge\\;on\\;smaller\\\\sphere\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2\\;\\times10^{-2}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Final\\;charge\\;on\\;smaller\\;sphere\\;(q1)\\;=\\frac{R_1}{R_1+R_2}.q_{net}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{1\\;}{1+2}(10^{-2}+5\\;x10^{-2})\\;=2\\;x10^{-2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23084": {
                "ans1": "5s",
                "ans2": "10s",
                "ans3": "15s",
                "ans4": "20s",
                "question_text": "Two springs of spring constants 2\u00a0N/m and 4 N/m are connected in series . A mass of 2 kg is attached to this combination then the period of oscillation be",
                "correct_ans": "10s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac1{K_{eq}}=\\frac12+\\frac14=\\frac34\\\\or,K_{eq}=2\\pi\\sqrt{\\frac m{K_{eq}}}\\;=\\;2\\pi\\sqrt{2\\times\\frac43}=10.23\\;sec\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23893": {
                "ans1": "0.5% ",
                "ans2": "1% ",
                "ans3": "2% ",
                "ans4": "4%",
                "question_text": "When cylinder is heated, its length increases by 2 % . The area of base increase by",
                "correct_ans": "4%",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\triangle l}l=0.02\\\\or,\\alpha\\triangle\\theta=0.02\\\\Now,\\;\\frac{\\triangle A}A=\\beta\\triangle\\theta=2\\alpha\\triangle\\theta=0.04\\\\i.e.\\;4\\%\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "26838": {
                "ans1": "1689.2J           ",
                "ans2": "-1933.5J        ",
                "ans3": "-2763.9J               ",
                "ans4": "2763.9J",
                "question_text": "At 27 C two moles of ideal mono-atomic gas occupy volume V is expanded adiabatically to volume 2V . The work done by the gas during this process is",
                "correct_ans": "2763.9J",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "29286": {
                "ans1": "1.5",
                "ans2": "1.66",
                "ans3": "1.33",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "In a plano convex lens , he radius of curvature of the convex surface is 10cm and the focal length 30. The Refractive index\u00a0of materials of the lens will be",
                "correct_ans": "1.33",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;plano\\;convex\\;lens\\;R_2=\\infty,R_1=R\\\\\\frac1f=(\\mu-1)\\left(\\frac1R+\\frac1\\infty\\right)\\\\Or,\\frac1{0.03}=(\\mu-1)\\left(\\frac{1\\;}R+\\frac1\\infty\\right)\\\\therefore,\\;\\mu=1+\\frac{0.1\\;}{0.3}=1.33\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "23570": {
                "ans1": "15 cm",
                "ans2": "30 cm",
                "ans3": "5.5 cm",
                "ans4": "7.5 cm",
                "question_text": "The equation of stationary wave is y=4\\sin\\frac{\\pi x}{15}\\cos40\\pi t, the distance between node-antinode is if x is in cm",
                "correct_ans": "7.5 cm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Here,y=4\\sin\\frac{\\pi x}{15}\\cos40\\pi t\\\\K=\\frac\\pi{15}\\\\or,\\;\\lambda=\\frac{2\\pi}K=30\\;cm\\\\The\\;dis\\tan ce\\;between\\;node\\;and\\;anti\\;node\\;is\\;\\frac\\lambda4=7.5\\;cm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25035": {
                "ans1": "2TL  ",
                "ans2": "4TL  ",
                "ans3": "8TL  ",
                "ans4": "10TL  ",
                "question_text": "A square frame of side L is dipped in a liquid soap. When it is taken out of the liquid a soap film is formed on it. If the surface tension of soap is T, then the force acting on frame is,",
                "correct_ans": "8TL  ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Force(F)=(T\\;.\\;Perimeter)x2\\;(\\;DUE\\;TO\\;SOAP\\;SOLUTION)\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;T.4L\\;X\\;2\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=8TL\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27663": {
                "ans1": "4:1",
                "ans2": "1:4",
                "ans3": "2:1",
                "ans4": "1:2",
                "question_text": "Two circular coils of radius 20 cm and 40cm are made of similar wires are connected in parallel . the ratio of the magnetic field at their centres",
                "correct_ans": "2:1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}B\\alpha\\frac1R\\\\i.e\\;\\frac{B_1}{B_2}=\\frac{R_2}{R_1}=\\frac{40}{20}=2:1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "22771": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "15",
                "ans3": "30",
                "ans4": "60",
                "question_text": "A parallel beam of light of wavelength 5000 \u00c5\u00a0is incident normally on a single slit of width 0.001mm. The light is focused by a convex lens on a screen placed in focal plane . The first minima is formed for the angle of diffraction equal to",
                "correct_ans": "30",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;first\\;minima\\;(n=1)\\\\d\\sin\\theta=n\\lambda\\\\i.e.\\;\\sin\\theta=\\frac\\lambda n=0.5\\\\or,\\;\\theta=\\sin^{-1}0.5=30^\\circ\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "27734": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}2.77\\;m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac5{30}\\;m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac16\\;m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac5{108}\\;m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "A ship is moving in a straight line due north at a velocity of 6km/hr . after one minute its velocity changes to 8 km/hr eastward. Average acceleration is,",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac5{108}\\;m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Average\\;Velocity\\;=\\sqrt{6^2+8^2}=10\\;km/hr\\\\\\triangle V=\\frac{10\\;x\\;1000}{3600}m/sec\\;=\\;\\frac{25}9m/sec\\\\Therefore,\\;Average\\;Acceleration\\;=\\frac{\\triangle V}{\\triangle t}=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac{25}9}{60}=\\frac5{108}m/s^2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "25809": {
                "ans1": "1:5",
                "ans2": "1:4       ",
                "ans3": "1:2    ",
                "ans4": "1:1",
                "question_text": "Light of two different frequencies whose photons have energies 1 eV\u00a0and 2.5 eV\u00a0respectively successively illuminate a metal work function 0.5 eV . The ratio of maximum speeds of emitted electron is",
                "correct_ans": "1:2    ",
                "explanation": "We\\;have,\\;\\frac{V_1}{V_2}=\\sqrt{\\frac{E_1-\\phi}{E_2-\\phi}}=\\sqrt{\\frac{1-0.5}{2.5-0.5}}=1:2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "21237": {
                "ans1": "6.4",
                "ans2": "64",
                "ans3": "640",
                "ans4": "4800",
                "question_text": "The radius in kilometer to which the present radius of earth [R = 6400 Km] is to be compressed so that escape velocity is decreased to 10 times is",
                "correct_ans": "64",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}V_e=\\sqrt{2gR}\\\\now,\\;V'=\\frac{V_e}{10}=\\sqrt{2gR'}\\\\i.e.\\frac{V'}{V_e}=\\sqrt{\\frac{R'}R}\\Rightarrow\\frac1{10}=\\sqrt{\\frac{R'}{6400}}\\\\therefore,\\;R'=64\\;Km\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        }
    },
    "mathematics": {
        "1": {
            "31213": {
                "ans1": "point",
                "ans2": "pair of lines",
                "ans3": "sphere",
                "ans4": "a pair of planes",
                "question_text": "In a three dimensional xyz space , the equation\u00a0x^2-5x+6=0 represents",
                "correct_ans": "a pair of planes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33753": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\pi",
                "ans3": "\\frac\\pi{180}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{180}\\pi",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin x^o}xis",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac\\pi{180}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39728": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\cos^{-1}x-\\sin^{-1}x\\;=\\;\\frac\\pi6,\\\\\\;then\\;x\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac\\pi2-2\\;\\sin^{-1}x=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle6}\\\\x=\\sin^{-1}\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle6}=\\frac12\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37666": {
                "ans1": "\\log_e(1+x^2)+c",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac12\\log_e\\left(1+x^2\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac x{1+x^4}dx\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38912": {
                "ans1": "36",
                "ans2": "144",
                "ans3": "574",
                "ans4": "754",
                "question_text": "The number of words that can be formed out of the word ARTICLE so that the vowels occupy only even places is",
                "correct_ans": "144",
                "explanation": "By using basic principle of counting,4*3*3*2*5*1=144",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32079": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The length of latus rectum of the parabola\u00a04x^2-4x-2y+3=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33034": {
                "ans1": "vertices of equilateral triangle",
                "ans2": "concylic",
                "ans3": "vertices of rt. angled triangle",
                "ans4": "collinear",
                "question_text": "The points (a,b+c) , (b,c+a) and (c,a+b) are",
                "correct_ans": "collinear",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37657": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac23",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}3",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac13",
                "ans4": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac32",
                "question_text": "Angle between x=2 and x-3y=6 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36044": {
                "ans1": "-1/3 , 2/3 , -2/3",
                "ans2": "1/3 , 2/3 ,2/3",
                "ans3": "-1/3 , -2/3, -2/3",
                "ans4": "1/3, -2/3, -2/3",
                "question_text": "The direction cosines of the line passing through the point (-1,2,5) and (-2,4,3) are",
                "correct_ans": "-1/3 , 2/3 , -2/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Direction\\;ratios\\;of\\;line\\;joining\\;(-1,2,5)\\;and\\;(-2,4,3)\\;are\\\\-2-(-1),4-2,3-5\\rightarrow-1,2,-2\\\\dcs\\;are\\;-\\frac13,\\frac23.-\\frac23\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31557": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25a^2c^2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}6ca=25b^2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25ac\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}6c^2=25ab\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;condition\\;that\\;the\\;roots\\\\\\;of\\;ax^2+bx+c=0\\;are\\\\\\;in\\;the\\;ratio\\;2:3\\;is\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25ac\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Let\\;roots\\;are\\;2K\\;and\\;3K\\;\\\\sum\\;of\\;roots\\;=2K\\;+3K\\;=\\;-\\frac ba\\rightarrow K=-\\frac b{5a}\\\\Product\\;of\\;roots\\;=\\;2K.3K\\;=\\frac ca\\rightarrow K^2=\\frac c{6a}\\\\or,\\left(-\\frac b{5a}\\right)^2=\\frac c{6a}\\rightarrow6b^2=25ac\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32400": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;is\\;parallel\\;to\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;is\\;perpendicular\\;to\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;or\\;\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;is\\;a\\;null\\;vector\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "such relation doesn't hold",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\overrightarrow aand\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;are\\;two\\;vectors\\\\such\\;that\\;\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow a.\\overset\\rightharpoonup b=0\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b=0\\;,\\\\then\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;or\\;\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;is\\;a\\;null\\;vector\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36032": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "value\\;of\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow o}\\frac{\\left|x\\right|}x=",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "In LHL its value is -1 and in RHL its value is 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35026": {
                "ans1": "diagonal matrix",
                "ans2": "scalar matrix",
                "ans3": "symmetric matrix",
                "ans4": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "question_text": "The inverse of diagonal matrix is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "diagonal matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35850": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\omega\\;is\\;a\\;non\\;real\\;cube\\;root\\\\\\;of\\;unity\\;,\\;then\\;\\vert1-\\omega\\vert\\;is\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt3",
                "explanation": "\\left|1-\\frac{-1+\\sqrt3i}2\\right|=\\sqrt{\\frac94+\\frac34}=\\sqrt3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31402": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "17",
                "question_text": "The smallest value of\u00a05\\cos\\theta+12 is",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36497": {
                "ans1": "an even function",
                "ans2": "an odd function",
                "ans3": "neither even nor odd ",
                "ans4": "a costant function",
                "question_text": "The function f(x) =\u00a0(x^2+\\cos x+1)\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "an even function",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38450": {
                "ans1": "\\cos\\theta=A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2",
                "ans2": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{(A_1+B_1+C_1)(A_2+B_2+C_2)}",
                "ans3": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}",
                "ans4": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{\\sqrt{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;angle\\;between\\;two\\;planes\\;\\\\A_1x\\;+B_1y+C_1z+D_1=0\\;and\\\\\\;\\;A_2x\\;+B_2y+C_2z+D_2=0\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{\\sqrt{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}}",
                "explanation": "Fundamental formula",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32085": {
                "ans1": "\\left[-\\frac13,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans2": "\\left[0,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans3": "\\left[-1,1\\right]",
                "ans4": "\\left[-1,\\frac13\\right]",
                "question_text": "The range of the function f(x)=\\cos\\;\\frac x3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\left[-1,1\\right]",
                "explanation": "obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36083": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "10",
                "question_text": "If A=\u00a0 \u00a0\\begin{bmatrix}0&2&3\\\\4&5&6\\\\7&8&9\\end{bmatrix} \u00a0 is a 3 X 3 matrix , then trace of A is",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "Trace means sum of elements of main diagonal.So, 0+9+5=14",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31522": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "ans4": "-\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\overrightarrow a=k\\widehat a,\\;then\\;k\\;equals\\;",
                "correct_ans": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37770": {
                "ans1": "A",
                "ans2": "B'",
                "ans3": "A-B",
                "ans4": "null",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;A\\subseteq B\\;then\\\\\\;B'-A'\\;equals\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "null",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33129": {
                "ans1": "3x\u00b2-5x+7=0",
                "ans2": "5x\u00b2 + 7x-3=0",
                "ans3": "7x\u00b2 + 3x - 5=0",
                "ans4": "3x\u00b2 - 7x + 5 =0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the root are the reciprocal of the roots of the equation\u00a07x^2-5x+3=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "3x\u00b2-5x+7=0",
                "explanation": "replace x by 1/x in the given equation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35501": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/2",
                "question_text": "The angle between\u00a0 the asymptotes of hyperbola\u00a0x^2-y^2=16 is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/2",
                "explanation": "y=\\pm xso angle between them is 90.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33841": {
                "ans1": "(-2,-1)",
                "ans2": "(-2,1)",
                "ans3": "(2,-1)",
                "ans4": "(2,1)",
                "question_text": "The center of the ellipse4x^2+9y^2+16x-18y-11=0is",
                "correct_ans": "(-2,1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36161": {
                "ans1": "C(18,6)",
                "ans2": "C(18,6)\\;3^6",
                "ans3": "C(18,6)\\;3^{-6}",
                "ans4": "\\;3^6",
                "question_text": "The term independent of x in the expansion of\u00a0\\left(x-\\frac3{x^2}\\right)^{18} is",
                "correct_ans": "C(18,6)\\;3^6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38966": {
                "ans1": "an even function",
                "ans2": "an odd function",
                "ans3": "neither odd nor even ",
                "ans4": "a constant function",
                "question_text": "If f(x) =\u00a0x^5+cos x\u00a0then , f(x) is",
                "correct_ans": "neither odd nor even ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30309": {
                "ans1": "1/4",
                "ans2": "3/4",
                "ans3": "-3/4",
                "ans4": "1/16",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\cos\\left(\\frac12\\cos^{-1}\\frac18\\right)=",
                "correct_ans": "3/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34433": {
                "ans1": "2/7,-3/7,6/7",
                "ans2": "2,-3,6",
                "ans3": "1/7,2/4,3/7",
                "ans4": "1/6,-3/7,6/6",
                "question_text": "The dc's of the normal to the plane 2x-3y+6z=7 are",
                "correct_ans": "2/7,-3/7,6/7",
                "explanation": "The dr's of the normal are 2,-3,6So dc's are2/7,-3/7,6/7",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30139": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac x{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "\\cos^{-1}x",
                "question_text": "Derivative of\u00a0\\sin^{-1}x\\;w.r.t.\\;\\cos^{-1}\\sqrt{1-x^2}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39578": {
                "ans1": "1/A",
                "ans2": "A+I",
                "ans3": "I-A",
                "ans4": "A",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0A^2-A+I=0\\;then\\;A^{-1}\\;equals",
                "correct_ans": "I-A",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}I=A-A^2\\\\A^{-1}=A^{-1}A-A^{-1}AA=I-A\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33574": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0+2",
                "ans3": "2/\u03c0",
                "ans4": "-2/\u03c0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{X\\rightarrow1}\\;(1-x)\\tan\\left(\\frac{\\pi x}2\\right)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2/\u03c0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36725": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/1",
                "ans4": "\u03c0",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;y=\\sin^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x+1}{\\sqrt x-1}\\\\+sec^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x-1}{\\sqrt x+1}then\\;\\\\\\frac{dy}{dx}\\;equals\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;y=\\sin^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x+1}{\\sqrt x-1}+sec^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x-1}{\\sqrt x+1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\sin^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x+1}{\\sqrt x-1}+\\cos^{-1}\\frac{\\sqrt x+1}{\\sqrt x-1}=\\frac\\pi2\\end{array}derivative of constant is 0.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34421": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0/3",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow b\\; are unit vectors such that\u00a0\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;+\\;\\overrightarrow b\\; is also a unit vector then the angle between\u00a0\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2\u03c0/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32273": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\vert x\\vert",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Left hand limit is not equal to right hand limit",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37238": {
                "ans1": "x\\;\\log_e\\left(\\frac xe\\right)\\;+c",
                "ans2": "x\\;\\log_ex\\;+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\log_ex}x+c",
                "ans4": "x\\;\\log_e\\left(\\frac ex\\right)\\;+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\log_ex\\;dx\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "x\\;\\log_e\\left(\\frac xe\\right)\\;+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39317": {
                "ans1": "(2n+1)\\frac\\pi6",
                "ans2": "2n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi6",
                "ans3": "n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi4",
                "ans4": "(4n+1)\\frac\\pi{12}",
                "question_text": "tanx +tan2x +tanx tan2x =1 has general solution equals to\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "(4n+1)\\frac\\pi{12}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\tan(x+2x)=1=\\tan\\frac\\pi4\\\\i.e.\\;3x\\;=\\;n\\pi+\\frac\\pi4\\\\x=(4n+1)\\frac\\pi{12}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30694": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/6",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\infty\\frac1{9+x^2}\\operatorname dx\\;equals",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/6",
                "explanation": "\\int_0^\\infty\\frac1{9+x^2}\\operatorname dx\\;={\\left[\\frac13\\tan^{-1}\\frac x3\\right]^\\infty}_0^{}=\\mathrm\\pi/6",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34053": {
                "ans1": "R",
                "ans2": "(2,\u221e)",
                "ans3": "R-(-2,2)",
                "ans4": "R-[-2,2]",
                "question_text": "The value of 'k' for which the equation\u00a0x^2+kxy+y^2=0\u00a0represents a pair of distinct real lines is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "R-[-2,2]",
                "explanation": "h^2\\geq ab",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38907": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "-4",
                "question_text": "The Y-coordinates of a point on line joining (1,3,-5) and (9,1,7) is 5. The Z-coordinate of point is",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Let\\;point\\;divides\\;line\\;in\\;k:1\\;internally\\\\Y-coordinates\\;=\\frac{k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\\\\\;\\;5\\;=\\frac{\\;k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\;\\Rightarrow k=1:3\\;\\\\Now,\\;Z-coordinates=\\;\\frac{1\\times7+3\\times\\;(-5)}{1+3}=-2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39114": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{\\sqrt{14}}",
                "ans2": "\\frac2{\\sqrt{14}}",
                "ans3": "\\frac3{\\sqrt{14}}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{14}",
                "question_text": "The projection of vector\u00a02\\overrightarrow i+3\\overrightarrow j+2\\overrightarrow k on the vector\u00a0\\overrightarrow i+2\\overrightarrow j+3\\overrightarrow k \u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{14}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33495": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt6",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt14",
                "ans4": "2\\sqrt14",
                "question_text": "If 1, 2, 3 be projection of line along axes then length of line in",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt14",
                "explanation": "Length=\\sqrt{1^2+2^2+3^2}=\\sqrt{14}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30224": {
                "ans1": "\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans2": "-\\frac{5\\pi}3",
                "ans3": "-\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans4": "\\frac{4\\pi}3",
                "question_text": "The principal value of\u00a0\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\sin\\frac{5\\pi}3\\;)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac\\pi3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\sin\\frac{5\\pi}3\\;)=\\sin^{-1}\\;\\{(\\sin2\\pi-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\;)\\}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\sin\\frac{\\displaystyle-\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\;)\\\\Principal\\;value=\\frac{\\displaystyle-\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\;which\\;lies\\;in\\;\\left[\\frac{\\displaystyle-\\pi}{\\displaystyle2},\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle2}\\right]\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39209": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "Value\\;of\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\infty}x\\tan\\frac1x\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\infty}x\\tan\\frac1x\\;=\\;\\lim_{\\frac1x\\rightarrow0}\\;\\frac{\\displaystyle\\tan\\left(\\frac1x\\right)}{\\displaystyle\\frac1x}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37593": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "infinite",
                "question_text": "The\\;value\\;of\\;\\\\\\log(\\frac pq)+\\;\\log(\\frac qr)\\;+\\log(\\frac rp)",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30741": {
                "ans1": "2^9",
                "ans2": "9^2",
                "ans3": "3^2",
                "ans4": "2^3",
                "question_text": "If A ={x:x is an even number less than 8} and\u00a0B = {x: x is a prime number less than 7},\u00a0then number of relations from A to B is:",
                "correct_ans": "2^9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}A=\\{2,4,6\\},\\;B=\\{2,3,5\\}\\\\\\;n(A\\;\\times\\;B)=9\\;\\;\\\\No.\\;of\\;relations\\;from\\;A\\;to\\;B\\;=\\;No.\\;of\\;subsets\\;of\\;(A\\;\\times\\;B)=2^9\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37547": {
                "ans1": "9x^2+4y^2=1",
                "ans2": "16x^2+25y^2=1",
                "ans3": "16x^2+9y^2=1",
                "ans4": "4x^2+y^2=1",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is horizontal ellipse",
                "correct_ans": "16x^2+25y^2=1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33843": {
                "ans1": "whatever be the sign of b, signs of a and c should be opposite",
                "ans2": "signs of a, b and c should be alike",
                "ans3": "signs of a and c should be alike and opposite to the sign of b",
                "ans4": "signs of b and c should be alike and opposite to the sign of a",
                "question_text": "If\\;the\\;roots\\;of\\;the\\;equation\\\\\\;ax^2\\;+\\;bx+c=0\\;\\;are\\\\\\;both\\;positive,\\;then:",
                "correct_ans": "signs of a and c should be alike and opposite to the sign of b",
                "explanation": "Obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36714": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0/3",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;are\\;mutually\\\\\\;perpendicular\\;vectors\\\\\\;of\\;equal\\;magnitude,\\\\\\;then\\;angle\\;between\\;\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;+\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;is:",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36444": {
                "ans1": "1/12",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "1/10",
                "ans4": "10",
                "question_text": "The\\;minimum\\;value\\;of\\\\\\;\\frac{\\displaystyle1\\;}{3\\sin x-4\\cos x\\;+5}",
                "correct_ans": "1/10",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Minimum\\;value=\\frac1{\\;max\\;value}\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac1{\\sqrt{3^2+4^2+5}}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac1{10}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32127": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow3}\\frac{x-3}{3\\vert x-3\\vert}",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow3^+}\\frac{x-3}{x-3}=1,\\lim_{x\\rightarrow3^-}\\frac{\\displaystyle-(x-3)}{\\displaystyle x-3}=-1\\\\So,\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow3}\\frac{\\displaystyle x-3}{\\displaystyle3\\vert x-3\\vert}\\;does\\;not\\;exist\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36467": {
                "ans1": "\\log_e(1-x+x^2-x^2+.....\\infty)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log_e(1-x+x^2+x^3+.....\\infty)+c",
                "ans3": "\\log_e(1+x+x^2+x^2+.....\\infty)+c",
                "ans4": "-\\log_e(1-x+x^2+x^2+.....\\infty)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int(1+x+x\u00b2+x\u00b2+...\\infty)\\;dx\\\\\\;for\\;\\vert x\\vert<\\;1\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\log_e(1+x+x^2+x^2+.....\\infty)+c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int(1+x+x\u00b2+x\u00b2+...\\infty)\\;dx\\;\\\\=\\int\\frac1{(1+x)}\\;dx\\\\=-\\log_e(1-x)+c\\\\=\\;\\log_e(1+x+x\u00b2+x\u00b2+...\\infty)\\;+c\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33670": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The focal distance of a point P on the parabola y\u00b2= 12x if the ordinate of P is 6, is:",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "y^2\\;=12x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35640": {
                "ans1": "A.P.",
                "ans2": "G.P.",
                "ans3": "H.P.",
                "ans4": "A.G.P",
                "question_text": "If x, y, z are in G.P. then logx, logy, logz are in",
                "correct_ans": "A.P.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30625": {
                "ans1": "\\left(1\\right)^{2n-1}",
                "ans2": "\\left(-1\\right)^n",
                "ans3": "\\left(-1\\right)^{n-1}",
                "ans4": "\\left(-1\\right)^{2n-1}",
                "question_text": "The\\;product\\;of\\;\\\\n^{th}\\;roots\\;of\\;unity\\;is;",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(-1\\right)^{n-1}",
                "explanation": "Obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32540": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "logx",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;y=e^{1+\\log_ex},\\;then\\;the\\;value\\;of\\;\\frac{dy}{dx}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "e",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}y=e.e^{{}^{\\log_ex}}=ex\\\\\\frac{dy}{dx}=e\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34331": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "log 3",
                "ans4": "e",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;value\\;\\\\of\\;1-\\;\\log2\\;+\\;\\frac{(\\log2)^2\\\\\\;}{2!}-\\\\\\frac{(\\log2)^3}{3!}+........\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}e^{-\\log2}=e^{\\log\\left(\\frac12\\right)}=\\frac12\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39677": {
                "ans1": "\\log(x+\\sqrt{x^2-a^2})+c",
                "ans2": "\\log(x-\\sqrt{x^2-a^2})+c",
                "ans3": "\\sin^{-1}\\left(\\frac xa\\right)+c",
                "ans4": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac xa\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac1{\\sqrt{x^2-a^2}}dx",
                "correct_ans": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac xa\\right)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31244": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans4": "\u03c0",
                "question_text": "If\\;y=\\;\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\cos x),\\;then\\\\\\;\\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}y=\\;\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\cos x)\\\\\\;\\;\\;=\\sin^{-1}\\;(\\sin(\\frac\\pi2-x))\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;=(\\frac\\pi2-x)\\\\\\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=-1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34867": {
                "ans1": "2x^2\\;=\\;2y(2x+y)",
                "ans2": "x^2\\;=(3-y^2)",
                "ans3": "2x^2\\;=y(2x-y^2)",
                "ans4": "x^2\\;=(2x-y^2)",
                "question_text": "Which of the following represents a pair of perpendicular lines?",
                "correct_ans": "2x^2\\;=\\;2y(2x+y)",
                "explanation": "ax^2\\;+\\;2hxy\\;+\\;by^2\\;=\\;0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35605": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{bmatrix}2&3\\\\4&6\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{bmatrix}6&-3\\\\-4&2\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{bmatrix}-2&3\\\\4&-6\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "The inverse of coefficient matrix of the system of equation2x+3y=14x+6y=3",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{bmatrix}-2&3\\\\4&-6\\end{bmatrix}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Coefficient\\;matrix\\;(A)=\\begin{bmatrix}2&3\\\\4&6\\end{bmatrix}\\\\\\vert A\\vert=0\\;\\\\So,\\;A^{-1}\\;does\\;not\\;exist.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37873": {
                "ans1": "R",
                "ans2": "\u03d5",
                "ans3": "{0}",
                "ans4": "{x : x \u2265 0}",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function\u00a0f(x) = \\dfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x - |x|}} is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03d5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34039": {
                "ans1": "7x + y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans2": "7x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans3": "7x + y - 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans4": "7x + y + 5z - 75 = 0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Let P(-7, 1, -5) be a point on a plane and let O be origin. If OP is normal to the plane, then it's equation is",
                "correct_ans": "7x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "explanation": "Solution:Eqn of plane-7(x + 7) + 1(y - 1) - 5(z + 5) = 07x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39335": {
                "ans1": "A^{-2}",
                "ans2": "A+I",
                "ans3": "I\u2212A",
                "ans4": "A\u2212I",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0A^2 - A + I = 0, then inverse of the matrix A is",
                "correct_ans": "I\u2212A",
                "explanation": "A(I\u2212A)=IA^{-1} =I\u2212A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39687": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "The number of functions from {a,b,c} into {1,2} is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "No. of functions =n(B)^{n(A)}\n =2^{3}\n =8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35760": {
                "ans1": "2n\\pi+\\pi",
                "ans2": "2n\\pi+\\frac{7\\pi}6",
                "ans3": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}4",
                "ans4": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}3",
                "question_text": "The general values of x satisfying the equation cosec x = -\u00a0\\sqrt{2}\u200b\u00a0, and cot x = 1 both is",
                "correct_ans": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}4",
                "explanation": "cotx=1x = \\dfrac{\\pi}{4}Cosine of an angle is negative and contingent of same angle is positive. It lies in the 3rd quadrant.\u00a0\\pi + \\dfrac{\\pi}{4}\u00a0=\u00a0\\dfrac{5\\pi}{4}and the general value =\u00a02n \\pi + \\dfrac{5\\pi}{4}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39525": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{i+1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-1}{i-1}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{1}{i-1}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If conjugate of a complex number is\u00a0\u00a0\\dfrac{1}{i - 1}\u00a0then the complex number is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36876": {
                "ans1": " (1,-3)",
                "ans2": "(-1,3)",
                "ans3": " (1,3)",
                "ans4": " (-1.-3)",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The centre of circle x=-1+2cos(\u03b8) and y=3+2sin(\u03b8) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-1,3)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31335": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0/3",
                "question_text": "The acute angle between the lines x-\u221a3 = 0 and x = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}x=0\\;means\\;Y-axis\\;\\;\\\\Slope\\;=\\;\\tan\\;\\theta\\;=\\;-1/-\\surd3\\;\\rightarrow\\;\\theta\\;=\\;30^\\circ\\;with\\;x-axis\\\\\\;\\;i.e\\;with\\;Y-axis,\\;\\theta\\;=\\;60^\\circ\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39225": {
                "ans1": "\\frac25tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{10}\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans3": "\\frac45\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans4": "\\frac15\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "question_text": "\\int\\;\\frac1{\\;\\;(4x^{\\;\\;2\\;}\\;+25)}\\;dx\\;\u200b\\;\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{10}\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "explanation": "Use standard formula.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34667": {
                "ans1": "are only additive inverse of each other",
                "ans2": " are only multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans3": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans4": "have same argument",
                "question_text": "Two complex numbers -i and i",
                "correct_ans": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "explanation": "i-i = 0 and \u2013i*i=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38933": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2\u2212\u03b1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0+\u03b1",
                "ans4": " \\pi/2+\\alpha\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "question_text": "The inclination of the line x cos\u03b1+ y sin\u03b1=p with positive x-axis is",
                "correct_ans": " \\pi/2+\\alpha\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}slope=-cos\\alpha/sin\\alpha=-cot\\alpha=tan(\\pi/2+\\alpha)\\\\henceangle=\\pi/2+\\alpha\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31297": {
                "ans1": "z",
                "ans2": "x",
                "ans3": "y",
                "ans4": "x and y",
                "question_text": "For unit (x, y, z) moves parallel to XY-plane which of the three variable x, y, z remains fixed?",
                "correct_ans": "z",
                "explanation": "When a point (x, y, z) moves parallel xy-plane, only z-coordinate remains fixed.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32046": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "\\int_{-7}^7(\\sin\\;x)^7dx",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Since it is odd, hence the integration is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35922": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/2",
                "ans4": "\u03c0 \u200b/6",
                "question_text": "Ify=sin^{-1}x+cos^{-1}x,\\frac{dy}{dx}\u200bis",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}y=sin^{-1}x+cos^{-1}x\\\\y=\\frac\\pi2\\\\\u200b\\frac{dy}{dx}=0\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38850": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "ans2": "\u03b2x-\u03b1y=0",
                "ans3": " x+y=0",
                "ans4": "\u03b2x+\u03b1y=0",
                "question_text": "If a circle has center at (\u03b1,\u03b2), and passes through origin , then equation of the tangent at origin is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Slopeofradius=\\beta/\\alpha;Eqnoftangentatorigin,\\\\y-0=-\\frac\\alpha\\beta\\times(x-0\\;so\\;\\alpha x+\\beta y=0\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31518": {
                "ans1": "1/|x|",
                "ans2": "1/x",
                "ans3": "|x|",
                "ans4": "e ",
                "question_text": "\\frac{\\displaystyle d}{dx}\\;\\log\\mid x\\mid",
                "correct_ans": "1/x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36857": {
                "ans1": "\u221e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "lim\\;\\;x\\rightarrow\\infty\\;\u200b\\;\\;(\\;\\sqrt{\\;x^{\\;\\;2}\\;+2x+1}-x)",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30356": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": " \u221e",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": " \\lim_{x \\to \\infty} \u200b x tan(1/x) is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "lim x\u2192\u221e \u200b xtan(1/x)= \\lim_{1/x \\to 0}lim 1/x\u21920 \u200b tan(1/x)/(1/x)=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35778": {
                "ans1": "(4, 5]",
                "ans2": " (4, 5)",
                "ans3": " [4, 5)",
                "ans4": " [4, 5]",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}LetA=\\{x:x\\;\\epsilon\\;R,x\\geq4\\}\\;and\\\\\\;B=\\{x\\;\\epsilon\\;R:x<5\\}\\;Then\\ A\\cap B\\;\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": " [4, 5)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32802": {
                "ans1": "A polynomial function is always continuous",
                "ans2": "A continuous function is always differentiable",
                "ans3": " A differentiable function is always continuous",
                "ans4": "ex in continuous for all x.",
                "question_text": "Which of the follow is not true ?",
                "correct_ans": "A continuous function is always differentiable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31562": {
                "ans1": "c^2/2ab",
                "ans2": "ab/2c",
                "ans3": "ab/2x^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans4": "c/2ab",
                "question_text": "The area of triangle formed by the line ax + by = c with co-ordinate axes is",
                "correct_ans": "c^2/2ab",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}x-interceptofline=c/a\\\\y-interceptofline=c/b\\\\areaof\\Delta withco-ordinate\\;axes\\\\\\frac12c/a\\times c/b\\\\c^2/2ab\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36358": {
                "ans1": "-1,-1,1",
                "ans2": "1,1,1",
                "ans3": "2,-2,1",
                "ans4": "1,2,3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The direction ratios of the diagonals of a cube which joins the origin to the opposite corner are",
                "correct_ans": "1,1,1",
                "explanation": "If side of cube is 'a', then co-ordinates of corner. opposite to origin (0, 0, 0) are (a, a, a)direction ratios of diagonal joining origin and opposite corner are: a - 0, a - 0, a, a, a,i.e. proportional to 1, 1, 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32584": {
                "ans1": "e^3",
                "ans2": "e^5",
                "ans3": "e^4",
                "ans4": "e",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\infty}\\left[\\frac{\\left(x+4\\right)}{(x+1)}\\right]^{(x+5)}",
                "correct_ans": "e^3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30523": {
                "ans1": "tan^2x.secx+c",
                "ans2": "tan^4x.secx+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^5\\frac x5+c",
                "ans4": "\\tan^{\\;\\;2\\;\\;}x.sec^{\\;\\;2\\;\\;}x+c",
                "question_text": "\\int sin^4x.sec^6x\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^5\\frac x5+c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int sin^4x.sec^6xdx\\\\\\int tan^4x.sec^2x\\\\tan^5x/5+c\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34090": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans3": "\u03c0",
                "ans4": "3\u03c0/2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If z is any non-zero complex number, then  arg(z) + arg(\\bar{z}) is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34095": {
                "ans1": "x",
                "ans2": "-x",
                "ans3": "y",
                "ans4": "-y",
                "question_text": "If y=1-x+x^2/2!-x^3/3!+x^4/4!-....., then d^3(y)/dx^3 equals",
                "correct_ans": "-y",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39457": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{i+1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-1}{i-1}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{1}{i-1}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If conjugate of a complex number is\u00a0\u00a0\\dfrac{1}{i - 1}\u00a0then the complex number is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30253": {
                "ans1": "2 \u221a 2 \u200b",
                "ans2": "4\u221a2",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The length of latus rectum of hyperbola xy=4 is",
                "correct_ans": "4\u221a2",
                "explanation": "For\\;hyperbola\\;xy=c^2\\;has\\;latus\\;rectum\\;length\\;as\\;2\\sqrt2c.So,here\\;c=2;hence4\\sqrt2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36671": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\displaystyle-1}{\\displaystyle(1-x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\displaystyle-x}{\\displaystyle(1-x)^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle(1-x)^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\displaystyle x}{\\displaystyle(1-x)^2}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0y = 1 + 1/x + 1/x^2 + \u2026.. +\u221e\u00a0and |x|>1 then\u00a0dy/dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\displaystyle-1}{\\displaystyle(1-x)^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34221": {
                "ans1": "arc\\cos(\\frac{\\displaystyle x^2}2\\;)+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac12arc\\cos(\\frac{\\displaystyle x^2}2\\;)+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac12arc\\sin(\\frac{\\displaystyle x^2}2\\;)+c",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0\u222b(x/\\sqrt{(4-x^4)})\u00a0dx equals",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac12arc\\sin(\\frac{\\displaystyle x^2}2\\;)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37001": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\left|x\\right|}x=",
                "correct_ans": "doesn't exist",
                "explanation": "left hand limit is not equal to right hand limit\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31668": {
                "ans1": "\u03a6",
                "ans2": "A",
                "ans3": "B",
                "ans4": "AUB",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If A and B are two sets such that AUB = A then AnB =",
                "correct_ans": "B",
                "explanation": "AUB=AB is proper subset of Aso AnB= B",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33275": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "\u221e",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Value of\u00a0\u00a0lim_{\\theta \\to \\pi/2} \\dfrac{\\pi/2 - \\theta}{cot \\theta}",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36959": {
                "ans1": "y^2-8x=0",
                "ans2": "4x^2+y^{\\;2}\\;=12",
                "ans3": "xy=5",
                "ans4": "x\\;^{\\;2\\;}\\;-y^{\\;\\;2\\;}\\;=0",
                "question_text": "Which of the following doesn't represent a conic",
                "correct_ans": "x\\;^{\\;2\\;}\\;-y^{\\;\\;2\\;}\\;=0",
                "explanation": "(x+y)(x\u2212y)=0\u00a0represents a pair of straight lines.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35041": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "\u2212\u03c0/2",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0sec^{-1} x = cosec^{-1} y, then\u00a0\u00a0cos^{-1}1/x + cos^{-1} 1/y\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}sec^{-1}x=cosec^{-1}y\\\\cos^{-1}1/x=\\pi/2-cos^{-1}1/y\\\\cos^{-1}1/x+cos^{-1}1/y=\\pi/2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38169": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "\u221a3",
                "question_text": "If \\overrightarrow a and \\overrightarrow b are unit vectors such that \\left|\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b\\right|=1 then \\left|\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b\\right| equals",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38682": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\u221a3",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\vec{a},\\vec{b}, \\vec{c}\u00a0are three mutually orthogonal unit vectors, then\u00a0|\\vec{a} + \\vec{b} + \\vec{c}|\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39686": {
                "ans1": "\\{x:x\\;\\varepsilon\\;I\\;,\\;x<1\\}",
                "ans2": "\\{x:x\\;\\varepsilon\\;I\\;,\\;x^2+1=0\\}",
                "ans3": "\\{x:x\\;\\varepsilon\\;I\\;,\\;x>1\\}",
                "ans4": "\\{x:x\\;=0\\}",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is a null set ?",
                "correct_ans": "\\{x:x\\;\\varepsilon\\;I\\;,\\;x^2+1=0\\}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37640": {
                "ans1": " |B|",
                "ans2": "k |B|",
                "ans3": "k^n\\times\\;\\vert B\\vert",
                "ans4": "n |B|",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If A is a square matrix of order n and\u00a0A=kB where k is a scalar then\u00a0|A|=",
                "correct_ans": "k^n\\times\\;\\vert B\\vert",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30487": {
                "ans1": "n+1",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "2n-1",
                "ans4": "2n+1",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of\u00a0\u00a0(x^2 + 2 + \\dfrac{1}{x^2})^n\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2n+1",
                "explanation": "So, no. of terms = 2n+1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32895": {
                "ans1": "x+\\frac{\\displaystyle1\\;\u200b}x",
                "ans2": "x^2-1",
                "ans3": "x^2-2",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0f(x+\\dfrac{1}{x}) = x^2 + \\dfrac{1}{x^2} ( x\u22600 ) then\u00a0f(x)\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "x^2-2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33960": {
                "ans1": "are only additive inverse of each other",
                "ans2": "are only multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans3": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans4": "have same argument",
                "question_text": "Two complex numbers -i and i",
                "correct_ans": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "explanation": "\u2013i\u00d7i=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35342": {
                "ans1": "n\u03c0+\u03c0/3",
                "ans2": "n\u03c0+\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "n\u03c0-\u03c0/4",
                "ans4": "n\u03c0+\u03c0/2",
                "question_text": "The general solution of the trigonometric equation\u00a0\\tan(x) = 2 - cot(x)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "n\u03c0+\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "tan(x)+cot(x)=2;(tan(x)\u22121)^2=0;so,\u00a0tanx=1hence x=n\u03c0+\u03c0\u200b/4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37066": {
                "ans1": "i",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "e^{-\\pi/2}",
                "ans4": "e^{\\pi/2}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0i^i",
                "correct_ans": "e^{-\\pi/2}",
                "explanation": "\u00a0(cos \\pi/2 + i sin \\pi/s)^i(e^{i \\pi/2})^ie^{-\\pi/2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33687": {
                "ans1": "(4n+1)\\frac\\pi4",
                "ans2": "(4n+1)\\frac\\pi{12}",
                "ans3": "(4n-1)\\frac\\pi{12}",
                "ans4": "(4n-1)\\frac\\pi4",
                "question_text": "The general solution of\u00a0tan3x\u22121=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "(4n+1)\\frac\\pi{12}",
                "explanation": "tan3x=13x = n\\pi + \\dfrac{\\pi}{4}(4n + 1)\\dfrac{\\pi}{12}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31751": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "undefined",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0 tan^{-1}x + tan^{-1}y = \\dfrac{\\pi}{2}\u00a0then\u00a0xy =xy=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "tan\u22121(1\u2212xy)(x+y)\u200b=2\u03c0\u200b\n\n\\dfrac{(x+y)}{(1-xy)} = tan ( \\dfrac{\\pi}{2})\u2192 1-xy=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39816": {
                "ans1": "-1,-1,1",
                "ans2": "1,1,1",
                "ans3": "2,-2,1",
                "ans4": "1,2,3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The direction ratios of the diagonals of a cube which joins the origin to the opposite corner are",
                "correct_ans": "1,1,1",
                "explanation": "If side of cube is 'a', then co-ordinates of corner. opposite to origin (0, 0, 0) are (a, a, a)direction ratios of diagonal joining origin and opposite corner are: a - 0, a - 0, a, a, a,i.e. proportional to 1, 1, 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34665": {
                "ans1": "\\dfrac{(a-b)}{(b-c)}",
                "ans2": "\\dfrac{(a-b)}{(c-b)}",
                "ans3": "\\dfrac{(b-a)}{(b-c)}",
                "ans4": "\\dfrac{(a+b)}{(b+c)}",
                "question_text": "If 1 is a root ot the equation\u00a0(b - c)x^2+(c-a)x+(a-b)=0\u00a0then the other root is",
                "correct_ans": "\\dfrac{(a-b)}{(b-c)}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Productofroots=\\frac{(a-b)}{(b-c)}\\\\so,\\alpha=\\frac{(a-b)}{(b-c)}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37708": {
                "ans1": "e<1",
                "ans2": "e>1",
                "ans3": "e=1",
                "ans4": "e=\u221e",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If e is the eccentricity of parabola, then",
                "correct_ans": "e=1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38665": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The possible no. of different matrix can have when it has 16 elements",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "Following orders are possible,\u00a016 \\times 1, 1 \\times 16, 2 \\times 8, 8 \\times 2, 4 \\times 416\u00d71,1\u00d716,2\u00d78,8\u00d72,4\u00d74",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31855": {
                "ans1": "\u03d5",
                "ans2": "B",
                "ans3": "A",
                "ans4": "AUB",
                "question_text": "If A and B are two sets such that AUB = A\u00a0 then\u00a0A\\bigcap B =",
                "correct_ans": "B",
                "explanation": "AUB=A \u2192 B is proper subset of A so AnB= B",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39196": {
                "ans1": "\u00b11",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "+1",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The product of a matrix and its transpose is an identity matrix. The value of determiant of this matrix is",
                "correct_ans": "\u00b11",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30587": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j}{\\sqrt2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k}{\\sqrt3}",
                "ans3": "\\vert\\overrightarrow i.\\overrightarrow j\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow k",
                "question_text": "A unit vector perpendicular to\u00a0\\vec{i}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{j}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow k",
                "explanation": "\\vec{k}.\\vec{i} = \\vec{j}.\\vec{k} = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39736": {
                "ans1": " vertex is at equidistant from focus and directrix",
                "ans2": " it is represented by a homogenous equation of second degree",
                "ans3": "directrix is perpendicular to axis of symmetry",
                "ans4": "latus rectum is parallel to directrix.",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following is not true about parabola?",
                "correct_ans": " it is represented by a homogenous equation of second degree",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39560": {
                "ans1": "1/n",
                "ans2": "1/n!",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "n",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If \u00a0t_i = 1 \u2013 \\dfrac{1}{i}be general term of a sequence then\u00a0t_2.t_3.... t_n\u200b\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "1/n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37991": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-e",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0y = 1 \u2013 \\dfrac{x}{1!} + \\dfrac{x^2}{2!} \u2013 \\dfrac{x^3}{3!} + \u2026 +\u221e \u00a0then\u00a0\\dfrac{dy}{dx} at x=0 is:",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "y=e^{\u2212x}\\dfrac{dy}{dx} = -e^{-x}at x=0,\u00a0\\dfrac{dy}{dx} = -1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38097": {
                "ans1": "Hyperbola",
                "ans2": "Parabola",
                "ans3": "Ellipse",
                "ans4": "Circle",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The equation\u00a0xy=c^2\u00a0represents",
                "correct_ans": "Hyperbola",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39153": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "ans2": "\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/6",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "question_text": "The acute angle between the lines\u00a0x-\\sqrt{3}y = 0and x = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37126": {
                "ans1": "2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "3 sq. units   ",
                "ans3": "6 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "12 sq. units   ",
                "question_text": "The area between the region (0+0i), (0+3i) and (4+0i) is",
                "correct_ans": "6 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}It\\;is\\;right\\;angle\\;triangle.\\\\\\;\\;area=\\frac12\\times\\;base\\;\\times\\;height\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=2\\times4\\;\\times\\;3\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=6\\;sq.\\;units\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32835": {
                "ans1": "m/n",
                "ans2": "n/m",
                "ans3": "2mn",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}=",
                "correct_ans": "m/n",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}\\\\Applying\\;L'Hospital's\\;rule\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\cos mx\\times m}{sec^2nx\\times n}\\\\=\\frac{\\cos0\\times m}{sec^20\\times n}=\\frac mn\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32396": {
                "ans1": "15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans2": "-15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans3": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "ans4": "-15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of bisectors of 3x^2-15xy+2y^2=0 are",
                "correct_ans": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35220": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}x+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac1{(x+1)}",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2+2x+2}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33342": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x\\\\Applying\\;L'\\;Hospitals'\\;rule,\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}\\times\\cos x-0}1\\\\=\\frac{e^0\\times1-0}1=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37719": {
                "ans1": "(-\ua699,\ua699)",
                "ans2": "[-a,a]    ",
                "ans3": "[0, \ua699)    ",
                "ans4": "(-a,a)",
                "question_text": "The domain of function \\log_e\\left(a^2-x^2\\right) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-a,a)",
                "explanation": "For\\;\\log\\;(a\u00b2-x\u00b2)\\;to\\;be\\;valid\\;a\u00b2-x\u00b2>0\\;This\\;only\\;valids\\;for\\;x\\;\\in\\;(-a,\\;a)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34593": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The non-empty proper subsets of a set are 30. The cardinality of set is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Number\\;of\\;non-empty\\;proper\\;subsets=\\;30\\;\\\\or,\\;2^n-2=30\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;2^n=32\\;\\;\\\\i.e.\\;n\\;=\\;5\\;\\\\Hence\\;cardinality\\;of\\;set\\;is\\;5.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31998": {
                "ans1": "720",
                "ans2": "360",
                "ans3": "180",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The number of ways on which the word \u2018PEOPLE\u2019 can be arranged are",
                "correct_ans": "180",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}As\\;there\\;are\\;two\\;P's\\;and\\;two\\;E's,\\;the\\;number\\;of\\;ways\\;of\\;arrangement\\;=\\;\\frac{6!}{2!2!}\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;180\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39973": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}\\\\Applying\\;L'Hospital's\\;rule\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac4{2\\times{\\displaystyle\\frac1{2\\sqrt x}}}\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}4\\sqrt x\\\\=4\\sqrt{\\frac14}=2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37529": {
                "ans1": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "ans2": " -\\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans3": " \\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "If y= \\frac\\pi2-\\cos^{-1}x+\\sin^{-1}x , \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32027": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3",
                "ans3": "\u00bd ",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4sec^2x\\;dx\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\vert(\\tan x)\\vert_0^{\\textstyle\\frac\\pi4}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\tan\\frac\\pi4-\\tan0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39529": {
                "ans1": "x^2+2",
                "ans2": "x^2-1",
                "ans3": "x^2+3",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If f(x-1)=x+2 then f(x^2) equals",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35899": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "a-b",
                "ans4": "a+b",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x=",
                "correct_ans": "a-b",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Here,\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x\\\\Applying\\;L'\\;Hospitals'\\;rule,\\\\=\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}\\times a-e^{bx}\\times b}1\\\\=\\frac{e^0\\times a-e^0\\times b}1\\\\=a-b\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33085": {
                "ans1": "3Im(z)   ",
                "ans2": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "ans3": "2 Re(z)   ",
                "ans4": "2i Re(z)",
                "question_text": "If z be any complex number then z-\\overline z =",
                "correct_ans": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Here,\\;z\\;=\\;a\\;+ib\\;\\&\\;z=a-ib\\;\\\\Hence\\;z\\;-z\\;=\\;(a\\;+\\;ib)\\;-\\;(a-ib)\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2i\\;b\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2i\\;Im\\;(z)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34483": {
                "ans1": "diagonal matrix",
                "ans2": "scalar matrix",
                "ans3": "symmetric matrix",
                "ans4": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "question_text": "The inverse of diagonal matrix is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "diagonal matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31794": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "question_text": "If x^y=a then \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35343": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "-4",
                "question_text": "The Y-coordinates of a point on line joining (1,3,-5) and (9,1,7) is 5. The Z-coordinate of point is",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Let\\;point\\;divides\\;line\\;in\\;k:1\\;internally\\\\Y-coordinates\\;=\\frac{k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\\\\\;\\;5\\;=\\frac{\\;k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\;\\Rightarrow k=1:3\\;\\\\Now,\\;Z-coordinates=\\;\\frac{1\\times7+3\\times\\;(-5)}{1+3}=-2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33107": {
                "ans1": "\\log\\left(\\cos x\\right)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{c\\mathrm{os}x}\\right)+c",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(secx\\right)+c",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin x\\;\\cos x\\;dx}{2\\cos^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37599": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "2\u221a3    ",
                "ans4": "3\u221a2    ",
                "question_text": "If a=b=3 and \\angle B= 45^0in \u0394ABC then c=",
                "correct_ans": "3\u221a2    ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}As\\;a=\\;b\\Rightarrow\\;\\angle A=\\angle B=45^\\circ\\;\\\\i.e.\\;\\angle C\\;=\\;90^\\circ\\\\\\;for\\;right\\;angle\\;at\\;\\angle C,\\;c=\\sqrt{a^2+b^2}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\sqrt{3^2+3^3}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=3\\sqrt2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39870": {
                "ans1": "90^0",
                "ans2": "60^0",
                "ans3": "45^0",
                "ans4": "30^0",
                "question_text": "The smallest angle of a \u0394ABC whose sides are a=7, b=4\\sqrt3\u00a0and c=\\sqrt3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "30^0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;angle\\;corresponding\\;to\\;smallest\\;side\\;is\\;smallest\\;one\\;in\\;a\\;triangle\\;\\\\i.e.\\;\\angle C\\;is\\;smallest\\;\\\\\\;Hence,\\;\\cos\\;C=\\frac{a^2+b^2-c^2}{2ab}\\;\\\\or,\\;\\cos\\;C=\\frac{7\u00b2+\\;(4\\surd3)\u00b2-(\\surd3)\u00b2}{2\\times\\;7\\;\\times\\;4\\surd3\\;}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;\\cos\\;C\\;=\\surd3\\\\\\;C=30^\\circ\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37512": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a matrix has 6 elements, then number of possible orders of the matrix can be",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "as 6 \u2192 1 \u00d7 6, 2 \u00d7 3, 3 \u00d7 2, 6 \u00d7 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33105": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "4/5",
                "ans4": "1/5",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\sin\\left({\\sin^{-1} (\\frac{1}{5})} + \\cos^{-1} x\\right) =1 then\u00a0x =",
                "correct_ans": "1/5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37085": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt{1+\\frac ba}",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{1+\\frac ab}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{1+\\frac{b^2}{a^2}}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{1+\\frac{a^2}{b^2}}",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of hyperbola ax^2-by^2=k, where k<0, is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{1+\\frac ba}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32825": {
                "ans1": "no roots",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinite roots",
                "question_text": "The quadratic equation\u00a08\\sec^2 x-6\\sec x+1=0\u00a0has",
                "correct_ans": "no roots",
                "explanation": "8sec^2x\u22124secx\u22122secx+1=0\\sec x= \\frac{1}{2}, \\frac{1}{4}but both of them are not possible",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38888": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "If A =\u00a0\\begin{bmatrix}1&2k-3\\\\k+2&1\\end{bmatrix} is a symmetric matrix, then the value of k is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "52k\u22123=k+2k = 5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39251": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "\u221a3",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "\u221a2",
                "question_text": "Modulus of sum of three mutually perpendicular unit vectors is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "\u2223a+b+c\u2223^2=a^2+b^2+c^2+2(a.b+b.c+c.a)= 1 + 1 + 1 + 0 = 3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31186": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{bc}{2\\triangle{}}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2r}{bcs}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{bcs}{2r}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{2rs}{bc}",
                "question_text": "In triangle\u00a0ABC, sin A =",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{2rs}{bc}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31569": {
                "ans1": "\u221a23",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "3\u221a3",
                "ans4": "2\u221a3",
                "question_text": "The radius of the circle\u00a0x^2+y^2-8x+6y-2=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "3\u221a3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35202": {
                "ans1": " it is continuous at x = 0",
                "ans2": "differentiable at x = 0",
                "ans3": "continuous at two points",
                "ans4": "differentiable for x \u2208 R",
                "question_text": "A function is said to be continuous for x \u2208 R, if",
                "correct_ans": "differentiable for x \u2208 R",
                "explanation": "as differentiable functions is continuous also.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34514": {
                "ans1": "K\u2223A\u2223",
                "ans2": "K^{2\\;}\\mid A\\mid",
                "ans3": "K^{3\\;}\\mid A\\mid",
                "ans4": "2K\u2223A\u2223",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Let A be a square matrix of order 2 \u00d7 2, then |KA| is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "K^{2\\;}\\mid A\\mid",
                "explanation": "\u2223kA\u2223=k^n\u2223A\u2223where n is the order of square matrix A.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35906": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "Area bounded by the curve y = sin x and the x-axis between x = 0 and x = 2\u03c0 is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34234": {
                "ans1": "\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k",
                "ans2": "\\overrightarrow i-\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j-\\overrightarrow k",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow i-\\overrightarrow j-\\overrightarrow k",
                "question_text": "The vector inclined equally to all axis is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k",
                "explanation": "Direction cosines =\u00a01,1,1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36920": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "3/2",
                "question_text": "The sum to infinity of the series\u00a0\\begin{array}{l}\\\\1-\\frac12+\\frac14-\\frac18+...\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2/3",
                "explanation": "\u00a0S\u221e\u200b=1\u2212r/a\u200b=1/(1+1\u200b/2)\u200b=2/3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37514": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The order of differential equation of all circle with radius 5 is:",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "As center (h,k) is arbitrary, we should differentiate twice to get this value. Hence the order is 2.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37343": {
                "ans1": "144",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "64",
                "question_text": "Set A has 3 elements and the set B has 4 elements. Then the number of injective functions that can be defined from set A to set B is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "total injective mappings/functions= 4P3\u200b=4!=24.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36598": {
                "ans1": "cot x \u2013 x + C",
                "ans2": "cot x + x + C",
                "ans3": "-cot x + x + C",
                "ans4": "-cot x \u2013 x + C",
                "question_text": "\u222bcot\u00b2x dx equals to",
                "correct_ans": "cot x + x + C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36922": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "a^2",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "\\vec{a}.(\\vec{b} \\times \\vec{a}) =\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "a.(b x a) = 0, therefore ( b x a ) is perpendicular to both a & b.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35562": {
                "ans1": "10",
                "ans2": "\u221a3",
                "ans3": "10\u221a3",
                "ans4": "10/3",
                "question_text": "The side of an equilateral triangle is increasing at the rate of 2 cm/s. The rate at which area increases when the side is 10 is",
                "correct_ans": "10/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30704": {
                "ans1": "first",
                "ans2": "second",
                "ans3": "third",
                "ans4": "fourth",
                "question_text": "The vertex of parabola\u00a0y^2+2y+x=0\u00a0lies in the quadrant",
                "correct_ans": "fourth",
                "explanation": "(y+1)^2=\u2212(x\u22121)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39935": {
                "ans1": "[-1,1]",
                "ans2": "(-1,1)",
                "ans3": "[\u2212\u03c0/2,\u03c0/2]",
                "ans4": "(\u2212\u03c0/2,\u03c0/2)",
                "question_text": "What is the domain of the function\u00a0sin^{-1} x ?",
                "correct_ans": "[-1,1]",
                "explanation": "-1 \u2264 x \u2264 1 or\u00a0[-1, 1]",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31672": {
                "ans1": "cd",
                "ans2": "-cd",
                "ans3": "c",
                "ans4": "-c",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\Delta_1\u200b\u00a0=det(\\begin{bmatrix}0 & 1\\\\c & d\\end{bmatrix}) then the value of \u00a0\\Delta_1=",
                "correct_ans": "-c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36827": {
                "ans1": "n+1",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "2n-1",
                "ans4": "2n+1",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of\u00a0(\\frac{x^2 + 2 + 1}{x^2})^n\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2n+1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38287": {
                "ans1": "m=3",
                "ans2": "m=-\\frac12",
                "ans3": "m=2",
                "ans4": "m= -4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0For what value of m two vector\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a} =\u00a0\\overrightarrow{i}-2\\overrightarrow{j}+4\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0= 2\\overrightarrow{i}-7\\overrightarrow{j}+m\\overrightarrow{k} are orthogonal?",
                "correct_ans": "m= -4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36691": {
                "ans1": " a and b are equal in magnitude but opposite in sign",
                "ans2": " a and b are equal",
                "ans3": "a and b are opposite in sign",
                "ans4": "a and b are reciprocal to each other.",
                "question_text": "ax^2\u00a0+ 2hxy + by^2\u00a0= 0 represents a pair of perpendicular lines if",
                "correct_ans": " a and b are equal in magnitude but opposite in sign",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38862": {
                "ans1": "-4",
                "ans2": "\u2264  \u221a13 \u200b",
                "ans3": "\u2264 5",
                "ans4": "|5|",
                "question_text": "The equation 2cos\u00a0\u03b8\u00a0- 3sin\u00a0\u03b8\u00a0= k has real solution in \u03b8\u00a0then k =",
                "correct_ans": "\u2264  \u221a13 \u200b",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36106": {
                "ans1": "2:1",
                "ans2": "3:2",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "5:2",
                "question_text": "The ratio in which yz plane divided the join of (4, 6, 7) and (-1, 2, 5) is",
                "correct_ans": "4:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35607": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}2",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}5",
                "ans3": "\\frac{21}{25}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sqrt{29}}2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of\u00a025x^{2}\u00a0+ 4y^{2}\u00a0= 100 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}5",
                "explanation": "e=\\sqrt{1-\\frac4{25}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36021": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2\u2212\u03b1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0+\u03b1",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "question_text": "The inclination of the line x cos\u03b1+ y sin\u03b1=p with positive x-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "explanation": "slope=-cos\u03b1/sin\u03b1=-cot\u03b1=tan(\u03c0/2+\u03b1)hence angle= \u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37636": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{a-b}{b-c}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2c}{a+b}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{a-b}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0x = 1\u00a0is a root of the equation\u00a0(b\u2212c)x \n^2\n +(c\u2212a)x+(a\u2212b)=0 then the other root is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{a-b}{b-c}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33343": {
                "ans1": "are only additive inverse of each other",
                "ans2": "are only multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans3": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans4": "have same argument",
                "question_text": "Two complex numbers -i and i",
                "correct_ans": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "explanation": "i-i = 0 and \u2013i*i=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36093": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{3e}{4!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{4e^2}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of\u00a0x^3 in the expansion of\u00a0e^{2x+3} is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\u00a0e^{2x+3}=e^3.e^{2x}\u00a0\\frac{8e^3}{3!}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32337": {
                "ans1": "30",
                "ans2": "60",
                "ans3": "45",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The angle between the pair of lines\u00a0x^2 - y^2 - 2y + 1 = 0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "Coeff. of\u00a0x^2+ Coeff. of\u00a0y^2\n\n= 1 - 1\n\n= 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38538": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "ans2": "\u03b2x-\u03b1y=0",
                "ans3": "x+y=0",
                "ans4": "\u03b2x+\u03b1y=0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a circle has center at (\u03b1,\u03b2), and passes through origin , then equation of the tangent at origin is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "explanation": "y-0=-\\dfrac{\u03b1}{\u03b2}\\times (x-0)so ,\u00a0\u00a0\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35316": {
                "ans1": "|x|",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\vert x\\vert^2}2",
                "ans3": "\\frac{x\\vert x\\vert}2",
                "ans4": "\\frac{x^2}2",
                "question_text": "\\int\\vert x\\vert\\;dx\\;is\\;equal\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x\\vert x\\vert}2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32024": {
                "ans1": "31",
                "ans2": "60",
                "ans3": "61",
                "ans4": "81",
                "question_text": "Number of distinct terms in the expansion of\u00a0(1+ 2x + x^2 )^{30}\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "61",
                "explanation": "(1+2x+x^2)^{30}= (1+x)^{60}= number of terms= 61",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34673": {
                "ans1": "ceentroid",
                "ans2": "orthocentre",
                "ans3": "in-centre",
                "ans4": "circumcentre",
                "question_text": "If (0,0),(3,0) and (0,3) are vertices of triangle then origin is",
                "correct_ans": "orthocentre",
                "explanation": "(0,0),(3,0), (0,3) are vertices of a rt. angled triangle, so origin is orthocentre",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36349": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac xy",
                "ans2": "-\\frac{x^n}{y^n}",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{x^{n-1}}{y^{n-1}}",
                "ans4": "\\frac yx",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0x^n + y^n =c^n then the value of\u00a0dy/dx\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{x^{n-1}}{y^{n-1}}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33471": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "-2",
                "ans3": "-6",
                "ans4": "3.5",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the inverse doesn't exist for given matrix\u00a0\\begin{bmatrix} 6&a-2\\\\3&a \\end{bmatrix}\u00a0then value of a is",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "determinant is zero, so , its value is -2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33277": {
                "ans1": "x",
                "ans2": "x^2",
                "ans3": "2x",
                "ans4": "3x+7",
                "question_text": "A function f : R\u00a0\u2192\u00a0R is defined by\u00a0f(x)=(7x\u22123)\u00a0then\u00a0\u00a0ff^{-1} (x)",
                "correct_ans": "x",
                "explanation": "ff^{\u22121}(x)=x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30266": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\;\\frac{\\left(1+x\\right)^6-1}{(1+x)^2-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34804": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The non-empty proper subsets of a set are 30. The cardinality of set is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38262": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\sin(\\frac1x)=",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38705": {
                "ans1": "(-\ua699,\ua699)",
                "ans2": "[-a,a]    ",
                "ans3": "[0, \ua699)    ",
                "ans4": "(-a,a)",
                "question_text": "The domain of function \\log_e\\left(a^2-x^2\\right) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-a,a)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36991": {
                "ans1": "15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans2": "-15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans3": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "ans4": "-15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of bisectors of 3x^2-15xy+2y^2=0 are",
                "correct_ans": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35738": {
                "ans1": "90^0",
                "ans2": "60^0",
                "ans3": "45^0",
                "ans4": "30^0",
                "question_text": "The smallest angle of a \u0394ABC whose sides are a=7, b=4\\sqrt3\u00a0and c=\\sqrt3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "30^0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34417": {
                "ans1": "\\log\\left(\\cos x\\right)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{c\\mathrm{os}x}\\right)+c",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(secx\\right)+c",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin x\\;\\cos x\\;dx}{2\\cos^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30590": {
                "ans1": "3Im(z)   ",
                "ans2": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "ans3": "2 Re(z)   ",
                "ans4": "2i Re(z)",
                "question_text": "If z be any complex number then z-\\overline z =",
                "correct_ans": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30895": {
                "ans1": "2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "3 sq. units  ",
                "ans3": "6 sq.units  ",
                "ans4": "12 sq. units",
                "question_text": "The area between the region (0+0i), (0+3i) and (4+0i) is",
                "correct_ans": "6 sq.units  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37180": {
                "ans1": "x^2+2",
                "ans2": "x^2-1",
                "ans3": "x^2+3",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If f(x-1)=x+2 then f(x^2) equals",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37177": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33653": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": " 4   ",
                "ans3": "-2  ",
                "ans4": "-4",
                "question_text": "The Y-coordinates of a point on line joining (1,3,-5) and (9,1,7) is 5. The Z-coordinate of point is",
                "correct_ans": "-2  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38117": {
                "ans1": "m/n    ",
                "ans2": "n/m   ",
                "ans3": "2mn",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}=",
                "correct_ans": "m/n    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37077": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}x+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac1{(x+1)}",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2+2x+2}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37509": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "question_text": "If x^y=a then \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30757": {
                "ans1": "720",
                "ans2": "360",
                "ans3": "180",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The number of ways on which the word \u2018PEOPLE\u2019 can be arranged are",
                "correct_ans": "180",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33400": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "2\u221a3",
                "ans4": "3\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If a=b=3 and \u2220B=45^0 in \u0394ABC then c=",
                "correct_ans": "3\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39810": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "a-b   ",
                "ans4": "a+b",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x=",
                "correct_ans": "a-b   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32312": {
                "ans1": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "ans2": " -\\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans3": " \\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "If y= \\frac\\pi2-\\cos^{-1}x+\\sin^{-1}x , \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37262": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3   ",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "\u00bd",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38152": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34400": {
                "ans1": "y",
                "ans2": "y-1",
                "ans3": "y+1",
                "ans4": "y^2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0y = x + \\dfrac{x^2}{2!} + \\dfrac{x^3}{3!} + \u2026 then\u00a0\\dfrac{dy}{dx}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "y+1",
                "explanation": "y=e^x\u22121\\dfrac{dy}{dx} = e^x= y + 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37111": {
                "ans1": " a pair of lines are at right angles",
                "ans2": "a rectangular hyperbola",
                "ans3": " a pair of parallel lines",
                "ans4": "a parabola",
                "question_text": "The equation xy - 4y + 12 = 0 represents",
                "correct_ans": " a pair of lines are at right angles",
                "explanation": "(x\u22124)(y\u22123)=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35116": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\u00a0\\lim_{x \\to 1}\\dfrac{x^2-1}{x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36149": {
                "ans1": "\u00b11",
                "ans2": "\u00b12",
                "ans3": "\u00b13",
                "ans4": "\u00b15",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If A =\u00a0[\\begin{matrix} m & 2 \\\\ -2 & m \\end{matrix}]\u00a0and Det (A^3) = 125, then m =",
                "correct_ans": "\u00b11",
                "explanation": "Det(A^3)=(DetA)^3So,m^2 + 4 = 5or,\u00a0m = \\pm 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39082": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "\u221a7",
                "ans3": "\u221a13",
                "ans4": "\u221a17",
                "question_text": "The length of the intercept made by the line 2x - 3y + 6 = 0 between the coordinate axes is:",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a13",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37620": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "\u221a5",
                "ans3": "\u221a10",
                "ans4": "\u221a13",
                "question_text": "The length of the perpendicular from (1, -2, 3) on the y-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a10",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32688": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "\u221a3",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a and b are unit vectors such that |a+b| =1 then |a-b|=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36743": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "If a=2i+j+2k and b=5i-3j+k then projection of b on a is",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36295": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans2": "5\u03c0/6",
                "ans3": "7\u03c0/6",
                "ans4": "-5\u03c0/6",
                "question_text": "The principal value of\u00a0\\arcsin \\sin{\\dfrac{5 \\pi}{6}}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/6",
                "explanation": "sin 5\u03c0/6\u200b=1/2So,\u00a0\\arcsin\\dfrac{1}{2}=\\dfrac{\\pi}{6}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36744": {
                "ans1": "x=\\pi+\\frac\\pi2+\\alpha",
                "ans2": "x=2n\\pi+\\frac\\pi2+\\alpha",
                "ans3": "\\pi\\pm(\\pi-\\alpha)",
                "ans4": "x=n\\pi\\pm\\left(\\frac\\pi2-\\alpha\\right)",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If \u00a0\\tan^2x = \\cot^2\\alpha, then x =",
                "correct_ans": "x=n\\pi\\pm\\left(\\frac\\pi2-\\alpha\\right)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38540": {
                "ans1": " \u03bb<0.25",
                "ans2": "\u03bb>0.25",
                "ans3": "\u03bb=4",
                "ans4": "\u03bb=1",
                "question_text": "The straight line y=2x+\u03bb does not meet the parabola\u00a0y^2=2x if",
                "correct_ans": "\u03bb>0.25",
                "explanation": "c>\\frac{a}{m} \\Rightarrow \u03bb>\\frac{1}{4}\\Rightarrow \u03bb>0.25",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39037": {
                "ans1": "\u03d5",
                "ans2": "{3,2,14}",
                "ans3": "{3}",
                "ans4": "{4}",
                "question_text": "The set A={x:x\\in R,x^2=16\\;and\\;2x=6} is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03d5",
                "explanation": "x^2=16x=\u00b142x=6x=3 There is no value of x which satisfies both the equations. Thus A=\u03d5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38729": {
                "ans1": "r^2\\cos\\;2\\theta=2c^2",
                "ans2": "r^2\\sin\\;2\\theta=2c^2",
                "ans3": "r^2=2c^2\\cos\\;2\\theta",
                "ans4": "r^2=2c^2\\sin\\;2\\theta",
                "question_text": "The polar representation of the rectangular hyperbola\u00a0xy = c^2 is",
                "correct_ans": "r^2\\sin\\;2\\theta=2c^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36123": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "The derivative of f(x)=|x| at x=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "doesn't exist",
                "explanation": "f'(x) doesn't exist",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31206": {
                "ans1": "x^2+c",
                "ans2": "x+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{x^2}2+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac x2+c",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0y = log_e e^{1/2}, then\u00a0\\int y dx\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac x2+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36992": {
                "ans1": " (0, 6)",
                "ans2": " [0, 6]",
                "ans3": "R - (0, 6)",
                "ans4": "R - [0, 6]",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function f(x)=\\sqrt{6x-x^2}\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": " [0, 6]",
                "explanation": "f(x)=\\sqrt{9-(x-3)^2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39636": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The number of functions from {3,4,5} to {a,b} is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "[n(B)]^{[n(A)]}= 2^3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31722": {
                "ans1": "16/9",
                "ans2": "9/16",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "3/4",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\;\\;\\frac{1-\\cos\\;4x}{1-\\cos\\;3x}=",
                "correct_ans": "16/9",
                "explanation": "use L-Hospital",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31097": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "For specifying a st. line, how many geometrical parameters should be known?",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "y=mx+c, hence two parameters",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30364": {
                "ans1": "x^2+\\ln x+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{x^2}2+\\ln x+c",
                "ans3": "2x^2+\\ln x+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac x2+\\ln x+c",
                "question_text": "If f'(x)=x+\\frac{1}{x}\u200b\u00a0then f(x) is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x^2}2+\\ln x+c",
                "explanation": "f'(x)=x+\\frac{1}{x}; df(x)=(x+\\frac{1}{x})dx, integrating, f(x)=\\frac{x^2}{2}+lnx+c",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37960": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{1+x^2}",
                "ans2": "-\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\u00a0y= sec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}}) + cosec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}})\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "y=pi/2so derivatiive is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32431": {
                "ans1": "100",
                "ans2": "160",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "120",
                "question_text": "If n(U) = 300, n(A) = 160 and n(B) = 240 then what is the minimum value of n(A \u2229 B)?",
                "correct_ans": "100",
                "explanation": "For minimum n(A \u2229 B), n(A \u222a B) should be maximum.The maximum n (A \u222a B) is n(\u222a) = 300n(A \u2229 B) = n(A) + n(B) - n(A\u222aB ) = 160+240-300 = 100",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39108": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "A line makes an angle\u00a0\\dfrac{\\pi}{4} , \\dfrac{3\\pi}{4}\u200b\u00a0with x- axis an y- axis respectively . Then",
                "correct_ans": "both",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32893": {
                "ans1": "16/9",
                "ans2": "9/4",
                "ans3": "4/9",
                "ans4": "81/16",
                "question_text": "A.M between two numbers is\u00a016\u00a0and G.M is\u00a09, then H.M is ,",
                "correct_ans": "81/16",
                "explanation": "AM\u00d7HM=GM^2\n\n16 \\times HM = 9^2\n\nHM = \\dfrac{81}{16}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36658": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The area between the curve\u00a0y = x^3\u00a0 and the ordinates\u00a0x=-2 and\u00a0x=2 is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "\\displaystyle{\\int_{0}^{2} x^3 dx} = 2 \\times \\dfrac{2^4}{4} = 8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35984": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "i",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0(\\dfrac{-1+\\sqrt{3}i}{2})^{99}",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "=(\u03c9)^{99}=(\u03c93)^{33}=1^{33}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39444": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c9",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\u03c9\u00a0is cube root of unity. Then the value of\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix} 1 & \\omega & \\omega^2\\\\ \\omega & \\omega^2 & 1 \\\\ \\omega^2 & 1 & \\omega \\end{vmatrix}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31040": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}{\\sqrt{x\\ }}}",
                "correct_ans": "doesn't exist",
                "explanation": "Left hand limit is not defined.LHL \\neq RHL",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39900": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "3\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0(\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{i})\\overrightarrow{i} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{j})\\overrightarrow{j} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{k})\\overrightarrow{a} =",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "explanation": "(a.i)i+(a.j\u200b)j\u200b+(a.k)a=ax\u200bi+ay\u200bj\u200b+az\u200bk=a",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32708": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "i",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0i^2= -1, then\u00a0i^2+i^4+i^6+i^8+...+ to\u00a0(2n+1) term equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35803": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert dx",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30371": {
                "ans1": "2\u03c0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\displaystyle \\int^{1 / 2}_{-1/2} \\cos x \\log \\left(\\cfrac{1+x}{1-x}\\right) d x=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Being odd function.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33817": {
                "ans1": "e=0",
                "ans2": "e=1",
                "ans3": "e>1",
                "ans4": "e<1",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the circle is",
                "correct_ans": "e=0",
                "explanation": "The eccentricity of the circle is\u00a00.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39906": {
                "ans1": "50",
                "ans2": "85",
                "ans3": "75",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "If the polygon has 3915 diagonals, then the number of its sides are,",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34180": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1/e",
                "ans3": "R",
                "ans4": "R-1",
                "question_text": "For\u00a0y =\\ log_a\\ x to be valid; a=",
                "correct_ans": "R-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30839": {
                "ans1": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "ans2": "k/\u03b1 and k/\u03b2",
                "ans3": "1/\u03b1 and 1/\u03b2",
                "ans4": "\u03b1 and \u03b2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\u03b1\u00a0and \u03b2\u00a0are the roots of\u00a0f(x) = 0 then roots of\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0are",
                "correct_ans": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "explanation": "\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31105": {
                "ans1": "Unique solution",
                "ans2": "Infinite Solution",
                "ans3": "finite solution",
                "ans4": "No solution",
                "question_text": "General values give",
                "correct_ans": "Infinite Solution",
                "explanation": "Since n is infinite.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32996": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{e^x}x",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "question_text": "\\int e^x\\left(\\frac1{x^2}-\\frac1x\\right)dx",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37428": {
                "ans1": "9",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\u221a2",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the conic section\u00a0xy=9\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2",
                "explanation": "Solution:\\sqrt{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36966": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "-2",
                "ans3": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "ans4": "\u22122 if n is even and 2 if it is odd",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0cosx+secx=\u22122\u00a0, then for a positive integer n, \\cos^n x+\\sec^n xdx is",
                "correct_ans": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30183": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "\u221a74",
                "ans3": "\u221a54",
                "ans4": "\u221a53",
                "question_text": "The distance of point (2, 5, 7) from the x-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a74",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33715": {
                "ans1": "-1/\u221a3",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "For what value of\u00a0p, is\u00a0(\\vec{i}+\\vec{j}\u2212\\vec{k})p a unit vector?",
                "correct_ans": "both",
                "explanation": "\u2223(i+j\u200b\u2212k)p\u2223=1p^2+p^2 +p^2 = 1^23p^2 = 1p = \\pm \\dfrac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39085": {
                "ans1": "straight line",
                "ans2": "parabola",
                "ans3": "ellipse",
                "ans4": "circle",
                "question_text": "If z is a complex number |z| =1 represents",
                "correct_ans": "circle",
                "explanation": "\u2223z\u2223=1|x + iy| =1\\sqrt{x^2 + y^2} =1x^2 + y^2 =1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37395": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If the planes x + 2y + kz = 0 and 2x + y - 2z = 0 are at right angles then the value of k is:",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34947": {
                "ans1": "7",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "The total number of subsets of a finite set A has 56 more elements than the total number of subsets of another finite set B. find m+n.",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "2^n\u22122^m=562^m=56+2^nis satisfied by\u00a0m=6, n=3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33255": {
                "ans1": "m\u00d7n",
                "ans2": "n\u00d7p",
                "ans3": "p\u00d7n",
                "ans4": "n\u00d7m",
                "question_text": "If the order of matrix A is\u00a0 m\u00d7p\u00a0. And the order of B is p\u00d7n\u00a0. Then the order of matrix AB is",
                "correct_ans": "m\u00d7n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38890": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "Area bounded by the curve y = sin x and the x-axis between x = 0 and x = 2/\u03c0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "From the symmetry;A = 2 \\times \\int_{0}^{\\pi} dx\n\nA = 2 \\times cos x|_0^{\\pi}A =4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33592": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "1/5",
                "ans3": "1/3",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "In triangle ABC, if\u00a0tanA+tanB+tanC=5 then\u00a0cotA.cotB.cotC=",
                "correct_ans": "1/5",
                "explanation": "If A+B+C=\u03c0then\u00a0tanA+tanB+tanC=tan(A)tan(B)tan(C)cotA cotB cotC=\\dfrac{1}{5}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31471": {
                "ans1": "cotx\u2013x+C",
                "ans2": "\u2212cotx\u2013x+C",
                "ans3": "cotx+x+C",
                "ans4": "\u2212cotx+x+C",
                "question_text": "\u222bcot\u00b2x\u00a0dx equals to",
                "correct_ans": "\u2212cotx\u2013x+C",
                "explanation": "\\int cot\u00b2x dx\\int (cosec\u00b2x -1) dx-cot x \u2013 x + C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30424": {
                "ans1": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "ans2": "symmetric matrix",
                "ans3": "orthogonal",
                "ans4": "idempotent",
                "question_text": "If A is square matrix, then\u00a0A - A^T is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32622": {
                "ans1": "60\u00b0",
                "ans2": "30\u00b0",
                "ans3": "90\u00b0",
                "ans4": "45\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The angle between the pair of lines with direction ratios\u00a0(1, 1, 2) and\u00a0(\\sqrt{3} -1, -\\sqrt{3}- 1, 4) is:",
                "correct_ans": "60\u00b0",
                "explanation": "\u00a0cos\u03b8=l1\u200bl2\u200b+m1\u200bm2\u200b+n1\u200bn2\u200b\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32311": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "The distance of point (2, 5, 7) from the xy-plane is",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36134": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "32",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "12",
                "question_text": "Let A and B have 4 and 8 elements respectively. What can be the maximum number of elements in AUB?",
                "correct_ans": "12",
                "explanation": "n(AUB) = n(A) + n(B) - n(AnB)n(AUB) is maximum when n(AnB) = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35860": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "2/x",
                "ans3": "1/(2\\sqrt{(1-x^2)})",
                "ans4": "(1-x^2)",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\\cos^{-1} (2x^2 - 1)\u00a0w.r.t\u00a0cos^{-1}x\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39147": {
                "ans1": "1/3",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "\u221a5/3",
                "ans4": "1/\u221a5",
                "question_text": "sin(arccos(2/3\u200b))=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a5/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33815": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-e",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0y =\u00a01+x+x^2+ \u2026 + \\infty and\u00a0\u2223x\u2223<1\u00a0then\u00a0\\dfrac{dy}{dx} at x=0 is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "y=1/(1-x)dy/dx = 1/(1-x)^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35559": {
                "ans1": "x=0",
                "ans2": "y=0",
                "ans3": "x+y=0",
                "ans4": "x-y=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the normal to the curve y = sin x at (0, 0) is",
                "correct_ans": "x+y=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30420": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The degree of the differential equation\u00a0(1+\\dfrac{dy}{dx})^3 = (\\dfrac{dy}{dx})^2",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30997": {
                "ans1": "\\lambda\\neq-2",
                "ans2": "\\lambda\\neq2",
                "ans3": "\u03bb=2",
                "ans4": "\u03bb=-2",
                "question_text": "If the inverse of the \u00a0\\begin{bmatrix} 2 & \\lambda & -4 \\\\ -1 & 3 & 4 \\\\ 1 & -2 & -3 \\end{bmatrix}\u00a0 exists then",
                "correct_ans": "\\lambda\\neq-2",
                "explanation": "|A|\\neq0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35604": {
                "ans1": "e<1",
                "ans2": "e>1",
                "ans3": "e=1",
                "ans4": "e=\u221e",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity e of hyperbola is",
                "correct_ans": "e>1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34855": {
                "ans1": "2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "3 sq. units   ",
                "ans3": "6 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "12 sq. units   ",
                "question_text": "The area between the region (0+0i), (0+3i) and (4+0i) is",
                "correct_ans": "6 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}It\\;is\\;right\\;angle\\;triangle.\\\\\\;\\;area=\\frac12\\times\\;base\\;\\times\\;height\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=2\\times4\\;\\times\\;3\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=6\\;sq.\\;units\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38272": {
                "ans1": "m/n",
                "ans2": "n/m",
                "ans3": "2mn",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}=",
                "correct_ans": "m/n",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}\\\\Applying\\;L'Hospital's\\;rule\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\cos mx\\times m}{sec^2nx\\times n}\\\\=\\frac{\\cos0\\times m}{sec^20\\times n}=\\frac mn\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30007": {
                "ans1": "15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans2": "-15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans3": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "ans4": "-15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of bisectors of 3x^2-15xy+2y^2=0 are",
                "correct_ans": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30946": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}x+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac1{(x+1)}",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2+2x+2}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32037": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x\\\\Applying\\;L'\\;Hospitals'\\;rule,\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}\\times\\cos x-0}1\\\\=\\frac{e^0\\times1-0}1=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35652": {
                "ans1": "(-\ua699,\ua699)",
                "ans2": "[-a,a]    ",
                "ans3": "[0, \ua699)    ",
                "ans4": "(-a,a)",
                "question_text": "The domain of function \\log_e\\left(a^2-x^2\\right) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-a,a)",
                "explanation": "For\\;\\log\\;(a\u00b2-x\u00b2)\\;to\\;be\\;valid\\;a\u00b2-x\u00b2>0\\;This\\;only\\;valids\\;for\\;x\\;\\in\\;(-a,\\;a)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38321": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The non-empty proper subsets of a set are 30. The cardinality of set is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Number\\;of\\;non-empty\\;proper\\;subsets=\\;30\\;\\\\or,\\;2^n-2=30\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;2^n=32\\;\\;\\\\i.e.\\;n\\;=\\;5\\;\\\\Hence\\;cardinality\\;of\\;set\\;is\\;5.\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34262": {
                "ans1": "720",
                "ans2": "360",
                "ans3": "180",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The number of ways on which the word \u2018PEOPLE\u2019 can be arranged are",
                "correct_ans": "180",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}As\\;there\\;are\\;two\\;P's\\;and\\;two\\;E's,\\;the\\;number\\;of\\;ways\\;of\\;arrangement\\;=\\;\\frac{6!}{2!2!}\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;180\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37430": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}\\\\Applying\\;L'Hospital's\\;rule\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac4{2\\times{\\displaystyle\\frac1{2\\sqrt x}}}\\\\=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}4\\sqrt x\\\\=4\\sqrt{\\frac14}=2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31778": {
                "ans1": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "ans2": " -\\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans3": " \\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "If y= \\frac\\pi2-\\cos^{-1}x+\\sin^{-1}x , \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39434": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3",
                "ans3": "\u00bd ",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4sec^2x\\;dx\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\vert(\\tan x)\\vert_0^{\\textstyle\\frac\\pi4}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\tan\\frac\\pi4-\\tan0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33097": {
                "ans1": "x^2+2",
                "ans2": "x^2-1",
                "ans3": "x^2+3",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If f(x-1)=x+2 then f(x^2) equals",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36443": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "a-b",
                "ans4": "a+b",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x=",
                "correct_ans": "a-b",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Here,\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x\\\\Applying\\;L'\\;Hospitals'\\;rule,\\\\=\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}\\times a-e^{bx}\\times b}1\\\\=\\frac{e^0\\times a-e^0\\times b}1\\\\=a-b\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39427": {
                "ans1": "3Im(z)   ",
                "ans2": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "ans3": "2 Re(z)   ",
                "ans4": "2i Re(z)",
                "question_text": "If z be any complex number then z-\\overline z =",
                "correct_ans": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Here,\\;z\\;=\\;a\\;+ib\\;\\&\\;z=a-ib\\;\\\\Hence\\;z\\;-z\\;=\\;(a\\;+\\;ib)\\;-\\;(a-ib)\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2i\\;b\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2i\\;Im\\;(z)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34402": {
                "ans1": "diagonal matrix",
                "ans2": "scalar matrix",
                "ans3": "symmetric matrix",
                "ans4": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "question_text": "The inverse of diagonal matrix is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "diagonal matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38794": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "question_text": "If x^y=a then \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31464": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "-4",
                "question_text": "The Y-coordinates of a point on line joining (1,3,-5) and (9,1,7) is 5. The Z-coordinate of point is",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Let\\;point\\;divides\\;line\\;in\\;k:1\\;internally\\\\Y-coordinates\\;=\\frac{k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\\\\\;\\;5\\;=\\frac{\\;k\\times11+1\\times3}{k+1}\\;\\;\\Rightarrow k=1:3\\;\\\\Now,\\;Z-coordinates=\\;\\frac{1\\times7+3\\times\\;(-5)}{1+3}=-2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31956": {
                "ans1": "\\log\\left(\\cos x\\right)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{c\\mathrm{os}x}\\right)+c",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(secx\\right)+c",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin x\\;\\cos x\\;dx}{2\\cos^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36585": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "2\u221a3    ",
                "ans4": "3\u221a2    ",
                "question_text": "If a=b=3 and \\angle B= 45^0in \u0394ABC then c=",
                "correct_ans": "3\u221a2    ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}As\\;a=\\;b\\Rightarrow\\;\\angle A=\\angle B=45^\\circ\\;\\\\i.e.\\;\\angle C\\;=\\;90^\\circ\\\\\\;for\\;right\\;angle\\;at\\;\\angle C,\\;c=\\sqrt{a^2+b^2}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\sqrt{3^2+3^3}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=3\\sqrt2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36084": {
                "ans1": "90^0",
                "ans2": "60^0",
                "ans3": "45^0",
                "ans4": "30^0",
                "question_text": "The smallest angle of a \u0394ABC whose sides are a=7, b=4\\sqrt3\u00a0and c=\\sqrt3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "30^0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;angle\\;corresponding\\;to\\;smallest\\;side\\;is\\;smallest\\;one\\;in\\;a\\;triangle\\;\\\\i.e.\\;\\angle C\\;is\\;smallest\\;\\\\\\;Hence,\\;\\cos\\;C=\\frac{a^2+b^2-c^2}{2ab}\\;\\\\or,\\;\\cos\\;C=\\frac{7\u00b2+\\;(4\\surd3)\u00b2-(\\surd3)\u00b2}{2\\times\\;7\\;\\times\\;4\\surd3\\;}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;\\cos\\;C\\;=\\surd3\\\\\\;C=30^\\circ\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31111": {
                "ans1": "e<1",
                "ans2": "e>1",
                "ans3": "e=1",
                "ans4": "e=\u221e",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity e of hyperbola is",
                "correct_ans": "e>1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37396": {
                "ans1": "\\frac12\\vert\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b\\times\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c\\times\\overrightarrow a\\vert",
                "ans2": "\\vert\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b\\times\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c\\times\\overrightarrow a\\vert",
                "ans3": "2\\vert\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b\\times\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c\\times\\overrightarrow a\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\frac14\\vert\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b\\times\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c\\times\\overrightarrow a\\vert",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}, \\overrightarrow{b}, \\overrightarrow{c} be the position vectors of three vertices of the triangle. Then the area of the triangle is given by",
                "correct_ans": "\\vert\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b\\times\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c\\times\\overrightarrow a\\vert",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33214": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "The number of unit vectors perpendicular to both\u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0are :",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36982": {
                "ans1": "\\log_e3",
                "ans2": "\\-log_e3",
                "ans3": "\\-log_3e",
                "ans4": "\\log_3e",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\log_e(1+x)}{3^x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log_3e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37153": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "e^{-1}",
                "ans3": "1+e",
                "ans4": "\\frac{1-e}e",
                "question_text": "\\frac2{1!}+\\frac4{3!}+\\frac6{5!}+.....+\\infty\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38266": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "3GA",
                "ans3": "3GB",
                "ans4": "3OG",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0GG\u00a0is the centroid of a triangle , then\u00a0\\overrightarrow{GA}+\\overrightarrow{GB}+\\overrightarrow{GC} =",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31066": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "3/2",
                "question_text": "The ratio in which the line\u00a03 x - y + 5=0 divides the line segment joining the points (2,5) and ( - 2,2) is:",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38948": {
                "ans1": "polar",
                "ans2": "a concentric circle",
                "ans3": "a diameter",
                "ans4": "chord of contact",
                "question_text": "The locus of the middle points of parallel chords of a circle is",
                "correct_ans": "a diameter",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38767": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The sum of fourth roots of unity is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "The four roots of unity are:\u00a01, i, -1, -i1 + i + -1 + -i=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30174": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt3",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{\\frac13}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac73}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac{11}4}",
                "question_text": "1+\\frac12+\\frac{1.3}{3.6}+\\frac{1.3.5}{3.6.9}+.......\\;is\\;equal\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31783": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "e^{-1}",
                "ans3": "3e/2",
                "ans4": "e/2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0t_n\\mathrm{=}\\dfrac{\\mathrm{\\Sigma }n}{n\\mathrm{!}}, then the sum of the infinite series\u00a0\\mathrm{\\Sigma }{\\mathrm{t}}_n\u200b\u00a0is equal to:",
                "correct_ans": "3e/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32597": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "1+x+y+z",
                "ans3": "xyz",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix} 1+x & y & z \\\\ x & 1+y & z \\\\ x & y & 1+z \\end{vmatrix} =",
                "correct_ans": "1+x+y+z",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36319": {
                "ans1": "144",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "64",
                "question_text": "Set A has 3 elements and the set B has 4 elements. Then the number of injective functions that can be defined from set A to set B is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "4P3\u200b=24",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34218": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If the planes x + 2y + kz = 0 and 2x + y - 2z = 0 are at right angles then the value of k is:",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38322": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "The x- coordinate of a point on the line joining the points\u00a0P( 2,2,1) and\u00a0Q ( 5, 1 , -2) is\u00a04\u00a0. Find its z \u2013 coordinate",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33676": {
                "ans1": "B^2\u20134AC<0",
                "ans2": "B^2\u20134AC=0",
                "ans3": "B^2\u20134AC>0",
                "ans4": "B^2\u20134AC=1",
                "question_text": "The general equation of a conic section is given by the following equation :\u00a0Ax^2 + Bxy +Cy^2 +Dx+Ey+F = 0 . A curve maybe identified as an ellipse by which of the following conditions?",
                "correct_ans": "B^2\u20134AC=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37774": {
                "ans1": "mn",
                "ans2": "m^2+n^2",
                "ans3": "m+n",
                "ans4": "\\frac{m+n}2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0(p+q)^{th}  and\u00a0(p-q)^{th} term of an A.P are respectively\u00a0m and n, then the\u00a0p^{th} term is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{m+n}2",
                "explanation": "(p+q)th\u00a0term =\u00a0a+ (p+q-1)d = m(p\u2212q)th\u00a0term =\u00a0a+ (p-q-1)d = nSum =\u00a02a + (2p-2)d = m+n\u2192a+(p\u22121)d=2m+n\u200b\u2192tp\u200b=a+(p\u22121)d",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36162": {
                "ans1": "15C7\\;.\\;x^7",
                "ans2": "15C8\\;.\\;x^8\\;and\\;15C9\\;.x^9",
                "ans3": "15C7\\;.\\;x^7\\;and\\;15C8\\;.x^8",
                "ans4": "15C8\\;.\\;x^8",
                "question_text": "A middle term in the expansion of\u00a0(1 + x)^{15} is",
                "correct_ans": "15C7\\;.\\;x^7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32640": {
                "ans1": "x=\\sqrt e",
                "ans2": "x=1/e",
                "ans3": "x=e",
                "ans4": "x=1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The stationary point of\u00a0x^x is",
                "correct_ans": "x=1/e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39460": {
                "ans1": "bc=de",
                "ans2": "be = cd",
                "ans3": "bd = ce",
                "ans4": "b^2e\\;=\\;a^2c",
                "question_text": "The conditions that root of the equation\u00a0x^2-bx+c = 0 and\u00a0x^2+dx+e=0 common is",
                "correct_ans": "be = cd",
                "explanation": "both roots are same so , them must be equal\u00a0b/d = c/e\u00a0or, be=cd",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34892": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": " \u221e",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": " \\lim_{x \\to \\infty} \u200b x tan(1/x) is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "lim x\u2192\u221e \u200b xtan(1/x)= \\lim_{1/x \\to 0}lim 1/x\u21920 \u200b tan(1/x)/(1/x)=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32389": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "\\int_{-7}^7(\\sin\\;x)^7dx",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Since it is odd, hence the integration is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33726": {
                "ans1": "7x + y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans2": "7x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans3": "7x + y - 5z + 75 = 0",
                "ans4": "7x + y + 5z - 75 = 0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Let P(-7, 1, -5) be a point on a plane and let O be origin. If OP is normal to the plane, then it's equation is",
                "correct_ans": "7x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "explanation": "Solution:Eqn of plane-7(x + 7) + 1(y - 1) - 5(z + 5) = 07x - y + 5z + 75 = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35450": {
                "ans1": "\u221e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "lim\\;\\;x\\rightarrow\\infty\\;\u200b\\;\\;(\\;\\sqrt{\\;x^{\\;\\;2}\\;+2x+1}-x)",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30144": {
                "ans1": "1/|x|",
                "ans2": "1/x",
                "ans3": "|x|",
                "ans4": "e ",
                "question_text": "\\frac{\\displaystyle d}{dx}\\;\\log\\mid x\\mid",
                "correct_ans": "1/x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35341": {
                "ans1": "z",
                "ans2": "x",
                "ans3": "y",
                "ans4": "x and y",
                "question_text": "For unit (x, y, z) moves parallel to XY-plane which of the three variable x, y, z remains fixed?",
                "correct_ans": "z",
                "explanation": "When a point (x, y, z) moves parallel xy-plane, only z-coordinate remains fixed.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35187": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{i+1}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-1}{i-1}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{1}{i-1}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If conjugate of a complex number is\u00a0\u00a0\\dfrac{1}{i - 1}\u00a0then the complex number is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-1}{i+1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37658": {
                "ans1": "\\frac25tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{10}\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans3": "\\frac45\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "ans4": "\\frac15\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "question_text": "\\int\\;\\frac1{\\;\\;(4x^{\\;\\;2\\;}\\;+25)}\\;dx\\;\u200b\\;\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{10}\\tan^{-1}\\frac{2x}5",
                "explanation": "Use standard formula.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36762": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "The number of functions from {a,b,c} into {1,2} is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "No. of functions =n(B)^{n(A)}\n =2^{3}\n =8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34505": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0/3",
                "question_text": "The acute angle between the lines x-\u221a3 = 0 and x = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}x=0\\;means\\;Y-axis\\;\\;\\\\Slope\\;=\\;\\tan\\;\\theta\\;=\\;-1/-\\surd3\\;\\rightarrow\\;\\theta\\;=\\;30^\\circ\\;with\\;x-axis\\\\\\;\\;i.e\\;with\\;Y-axis,\\;\\theta\\;=\\;60^\\circ\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39598": {
                "ans1": "A^{-2}",
                "ans2": "A+I",
                "ans3": "I\u2212A",
                "ans4": "A\u2212I",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0A^2 - A + I = 0, then inverse of the matrix A is",
                "correct_ans": "I\u2212A",
                "explanation": "A(I\u2212A)=IA^{-1} =I\u2212A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36113": {
                "ans1": "2n\\pi+\\pi",
                "ans2": "2n\\pi+\\frac{7\\pi}6",
                "ans3": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}4",
                "ans4": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}3",
                "question_text": "The general values of x satisfying the equation cosec x = -\u00a0\\sqrt{2}\u200b\u00a0, and cot x = 1 both is",
                "correct_ans": "2n\\pi+\\frac{5\\pi}4",
                "explanation": "cotx=1x = \\dfrac{\\pi}{4}Cosine of an angle is negative and contingent of same angle is positive. It lies in the 3rd quadrant.\u00a0\\pi + \\dfrac{\\pi}{4}\u00a0=\u00a0\\dfrac{5\\pi}{4}and the general value =\u00a02n \\pi + \\dfrac{5\\pi}{4}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39577": {
                "ans1": " (1,-3)",
                "ans2": "(-1,3)",
                "ans3": " (1,3)",
                "ans4": " (-1.-3)",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The centre of circle x=-1+2cos(\u03b8) and y=3+2sin(\u03b8) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-1,3)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35586": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "ans2": "\u03b2x-\u03b1y=0",
                "ans3": " x+y=0",
                "ans4": "\u03b2x+\u03b1y=0",
                "question_text": "If a circle has center at (\u03b1,\u03b2), and passes through origin , then equation of the tangent at origin is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Slopeofradius=\\beta/\\alpha;Eqnoftangentatorigin,\\\\y-0=-\\frac\\alpha\\beta\\times(x-0\\;so\\;\\alpha x+\\beta y=0\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37034": {
                "ans1": "(4, 5]",
                "ans2": " (4, 5)",
                "ans3": " [4, 5)",
                "ans4": " [4, 5]",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}LetA=\\{x:x\\;\\epsilon\\;R,x\\geq4\\}\\;and\\\\\\;B=\\{x\\;\\epsilon\\;R:x<5\\}\\;Then\\ A\\cap B\\;\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": " [4, 5)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33317": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/2",
                "ans4": "\u03c0 \u200b/6",
                "question_text": "Ify=sin^{-1}x+cos^{-1}x,\\frac{dy}{dx}\u200bis",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}y=sin^{-1}x+cos^{-1}x\\\\y=\\frac\\pi2\\\\\u200b\\frac{dy}{dx}=0\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35590": {
                "ans1": "are only additive inverse of each other",
                "ans2": " are only multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans3": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans4": "have same argument",
                "question_text": "Two complex numbers -i and i",
                "correct_ans": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "explanation": "i-i = 0 and \u2013i*i=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36403": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2\u2212\u03b1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0+\u03b1",
                "ans4": " \\pi/2+\\alpha\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "question_text": "The inclination of the line x cos\u03b1+ y sin\u03b1=p with positive x-axis is",
                "correct_ans": " \\pi/2+\\alpha\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}slope=-cos\\alpha/sin\\alpha=-cot\\alpha=tan(\\pi/2+\\alpha)\\\\henceangle=\\pi/2+\\alpha\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39697": {
                "ans1": "R",
                "ans2": "\u03d5",
                "ans3": "{0}",
                "ans4": "{x : x \u2265 0}",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function\u00a0f(x) = \\dfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x - |x|}} is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03d5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32096": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "-2",
                "ans3": "-6",
                "ans4": "3.5",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the inverse doesn't exist for given matrix\u00a0\\begin{bmatrix} 6&a-2\\\\3&a \\end{bmatrix}\u00a0then value of a is",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "determinant is zero, so , its value is -2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39366": {
                "ans1": " a and b are equal in magnitude but opposite in sign",
                "ans2": " a and b are equal",
                "ans3": "a and b are opposite in sign",
                "ans4": "a and b are reciprocal to each other.",
                "question_text": "ax^2\u00a0+ 2hxy + by^2\u00a0= 0 represents a pair of perpendicular lines if",
                "correct_ans": " a and b are equal in magnitude but opposite in sign",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36419": {
                "ans1": "are only additive inverse of each other",
                "ans2": "are only multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans3": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "ans4": "have same argument",
                "question_text": "Two complex numbers -i and i",
                "correct_ans": "are both additive and multiplicative inverse of each other",
                "explanation": "i-i = 0 and \u2013i*i=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30509": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2\u2212\u03b1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0+\u03b1",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "question_text": "The inclination of the line x cos\u03b1+ y sin\u03b1=p with positive x-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "explanation": "slope=-cos\u03b1/sin\u03b1=-cot\u03b1=tan(\u03c0/2+\u03b1)hence angle= \u03c0/2+\u03b1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39331": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac xy",
                "ans2": "-\\frac{x^n}{y^n}",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{x^{n-1}}{y^{n-1}}",
                "ans4": "\\frac yx",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0x^n + y^n =c^n then the value of\u00a0dy/dx\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{x^{n-1}}{y^{n-1}}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31078": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "ans2": "\u03b2x-\u03b1y=0",
                "ans3": "x+y=0",
                "ans4": "\u03b2x+\u03b1y=0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a circle has center at (\u03b1,\u03b2), and passes through origin , then equation of the tangent at origin is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "explanation": "y-0=-\\dfrac{\u03b1}{\u03b2}\\times (x-0)so ,\u00a0\u00a0\u03b1x+\u03b2y=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33710": {
                "ans1": "n+1",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "2n-1",
                "ans4": "2n+1",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of\u00a0(\\frac{x^2 + 2 + 1}{x^2})^n\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2n+1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38409": {
                "ans1": "-4",
                "ans2": "\u2264  \u221a13 \u200b",
                "ans3": "\u2264 5",
                "ans4": "|5|",
                "question_text": "The equation 2cos\u00a0\u03b8\u00a0- 3sin\u00a0\u03b8\u00a0= k has real solution in \u03b8\u00a0then k =",
                "correct_ans": "\u2264  \u221a13 \u200b",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34769": {
                "ans1": "m=3",
                "ans2": "m=-\\frac12",
                "ans3": "m=2",
                "ans4": "m= -4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0For what value of m two vector\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a} =\u00a0\\overrightarrow{i}-2\\overrightarrow{j}+4\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0= 2\\overrightarrow{i}-7\\overrightarrow{j}+m\\overrightarrow{k} are orthogonal?",
                "correct_ans": "m= -4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37006": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{3e}{4!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{4e^2}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of\u00a0x^3 in the expansion of\u00a0e^{2x+3} is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{8e^3}{3!}\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\u00a0e^{2x+3}=e^3.e^{2x}\u00a0\\frac{8e^3}{3!}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39254": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}2",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}5",
                "ans3": "\\frac{21}{25}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sqrt{29}}2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of\u00a025x^{2}\u00a0+ 4y^{2}\u00a0= 100 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\sqrt{21}}5",
                "explanation": "e=\\sqrt{1-\\frac4{25}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34153": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\;\\frac{\\left(1+x\\right)^6-1}{(1+x)^2-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36630": {
                "ans1": "31",
                "ans2": "60",
                "ans3": "61",
                "ans4": "81",
                "question_text": "Number of distinct terms in the expansion of\u00a0(1+ 2x + x^2 )^{30}\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "61",
                "explanation": "(1+2x+x^2)^{30}= (1+x)^{60}= number of terms= 61",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32549": {
                "ans1": "2:1",
                "ans2": "3:2",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "5:2",
                "question_text": "The ratio in which yz plane divided the join of (4, 6, 7) and (-1, 2, 5) is",
                "correct_ans": "4:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31670": {
                "ans1": "ceentroid",
                "ans2": "orthocentre",
                "ans3": "in-centre",
                "ans4": "circumcentre",
                "question_text": "If (0,0),(3,0) and (0,3) are vertices of triangle then origin is",
                "correct_ans": "orthocentre",
                "explanation": "(0,0),(3,0), (0,3) are vertices of a rt. angled triangle, so origin is orthocentre",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32692": {
                "ans1": "|x|",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\vert x\\vert^2}2",
                "ans3": "\\frac{x\\vert x\\vert}2",
                "ans4": "\\frac{x^2}2",
                "question_text": "\\int\\vert x\\vert\\;dx\\;is\\;equal\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x\\vert x\\vert}2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39022": {
                "ans1": "30",
                "ans2": "60",
                "ans3": "45",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The angle between the pair of lines\u00a0x^2 - y^2 - 2y + 1 = 0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "Coeff. of\u00a0x^2+ Coeff. of\u00a0y^2\n\n= 1 - 1\n\n= 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35475": {
                "ans1": "cd",
                "ans2": "-cd",
                "ans3": "c",
                "ans4": "-c",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\Delta_1\u200b\u00a0=det(\\begin{bmatrix}0 & 1\\\\c & d\\end{bmatrix}) then the value of \u00a0\\Delta_1=",
                "correct_ans": "-c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33013": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{a-b}{b-c}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2c}{a+b}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{a-b}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0x = 1\u00a0is a root of the equation\u00a0(b\u2212c)x \n^2\n +(c\u2212a)x+(a\u2212b)=0 then the other root is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{a-b}{b-c}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33648": {
                "ans1": "x",
                "ans2": "x^2",
                "ans3": "2x",
                "ans4": "3x+7",
                "question_text": "A function f : R\u00a0\u2192\u00a0R is defined by\u00a0f(x)=(7x\u22123)\u00a0then\u00a0\u00a0ff^{-1} (x)",
                "correct_ans": "x",
                "explanation": "ff^{\u22121}(x)=x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38035": {
                "ans1": "e=0",
                "ans2": "e=1",
                "ans3": "e>1",
                "ans4": "e<1",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the circle is",
                "correct_ans": "e=0",
                "explanation": "The eccentricity of the circle is\u00a00.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33721": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "i",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0i^2= -1, then\u00a0i^2+i^4+i^6+i^8+...+ to\u00a0(2n+1) term equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38779": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert dx",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33792": {
                "ans1": "Unique solution",
                "ans2": "Infinite Solution",
                "ans3": "finite solution",
                "ans4": "No solution",
                "question_text": "General values give",
                "correct_ans": "Infinite Solution",
                "explanation": "Since n is infinite.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34315": {
                "ans1": "50",
                "ans2": "85",
                "ans3": "75",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "If the polygon has 3915 diagonals, then the number of its sides are,",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37963": {
                "ans1": "16/9",
                "ans2": "9/4",
                "ans3": "4/9",
                "ans4": "81/16",
                "question_text": "A.M between two numbers is\u00a016\u00a0and G.M is\u00a09, then H.M is ,",
                "correct_ans": "81/16",
                "explanation": "AM\u00d7HM=GM^2\n\n16 \\times HM = 9^2\n\nHM = \\dfrac{81}{16}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38815": {
                "ans1": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "ans2": "k/\u03b1 and k/\u03b2",
                "ans3": "1/\u03b1 and 1/\u03b2",
                "ans4": "\u03b1 and \u03b2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\u03b1\u00a0and \u03b2\u00a0are the roots of\u00a0f(x) = 0 then roots of\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0are",
                "correct_ans": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "explanation": "\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38919": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}{\\sqrt{x\\ }}}",
                "correct_ans": "doesn't exist",
                "explanation": "Left hand limit is not defined.LHL \\neq RHL",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30876": {
                "ans1": "100",
                "ans2": "160",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "120",
                "question_text": "If n(U) = 300, n(A) = 160 and n(B) = 240 then what is the minimum value of n(A \u2229 B)?",
                "correct_ans": "100",
                "explanation": "For minimum n(A \u2229 B), n(A \u222a B) should be maximum.The maximum n (A \u222a B) is n(\u222a) = 300n(A \u2229 B) = n(A) + n(B) - n(A\u222aB ) = 160+240-300 = 100",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31133": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "-2",
                "ans3": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "ans4": "\u22122 if n is even and 2 if it is odd",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0cosx+secx=\u22122\u00a0, then for a positive integer n, \\cos^n x+\\sec^n xdx is",
                "correct_ans": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34720": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{e^x}x",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "question_text": "\\int e^x\\left(\\frac1{x^2}-\\frac1x\\right)dx",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35332": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The area between the curve\u00a0y = x^3\u00a0 and the ordinates\u00a0x=-2 and\u00a0x=2 is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "\\displaystyle{\\int_{0}^{2} x^3 dx} = 2 \\times \\dfrac{2^4}{4} = 8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37144": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "i",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0(\\dfrac{-1+\\sqrt{3}i}{2})^{99}",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "=(\u03c9)^{99}=(\u03c93)^{33}=1^{33}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36828": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "A line makes an angle\u00a0\\dfrac{\\pi}{4} , \\dfrac{3\\pi}{4}\u200b\u00a0with x- axis an y- axis respectively . Then",
                "correct_ans": "both",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35901": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{1+x^2}",
                "ans2": "-\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\u00a0y= sec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}}) + cosec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}})\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "y=pi/2so derivatiive is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37118": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c9",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\u03c9\u00a0is cube root of unity. Then the value of\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix} 1 & \\omega & \\omega^2\\\\ \\omega & \\omega^2 & 1 \\\\ \\omega^2 & 1 & \\omega \\end{vmatrix}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31427": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "3\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0(\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{i})\\overrightarrow{i} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{j})\\overrightarrow{j} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{k})\\overrightarrow{a} =",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "explanation": "(a.i)i+(a.j\u200b)j\u200b+(a.k)a=ax\u200bi+ay\u200bj\u200b+az\u200bk=a",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39375": {
                "ans1": "9",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\u221a2",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the conic section\u00a0xy=9\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2",
                "explanation": "Solution:\\sqrt{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32685": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1/e",
                "ans3": "R",
                "ans4": "R-1",
                "question_text": "For\u00a0y =\\ log_a\\ x to be valid; a=",
                "correct_ans": "R-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34601": {
                "ans1": "2\u03c0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\displaystyle \\int^{1 / 2}_{-1/2} \\cos x \\log \\left(\\cfrac{1+x}{1-x}\\right) d x=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Being odd function.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35657": {
                "ans1": "15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans2": "-15x^2+2xy+15y^2=0",
                "ans3": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "ans4": "-15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of bisectors of 3x^2-15xy+2y^2=0 are",
                "correct_ans": "15x^2+2xy-15y^2=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31784": {
                "ans1": "2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "3 sq. units  ",
                "ans3": "6 sq.units  ",
                "ans4": "12 sq. units",
                "question_text": "The area between the region (0+0i), (0+3i) and (4+0i) is",
                "correct_ans": "6 sq.units  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37269": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "a-b   ",
                "ans4": "a+b",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}x=",
                "correct_ans": "a-b   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37537": {
                "ans1": "\\log\\left(\\cos x\\right)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{c\\mathrm{os}x}\\right)+c",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(secx\\right)+c",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin x\\;\\cos x\\;dx}{2\\cos^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{secx}\\right)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32057": {
                "ans1": "m/n    ",
                "ans2": "n/m   ",
                "ans3": "2mn",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin mx}{\\tan nx}=",
                "correct_ans": "m/n    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38398": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}x+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac1{(x+1)}",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2+2x+2}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}(x+1)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35835": {
                "ans1": "(-\ua699,\ua699)",
                "ans2": "[-a,a]    ",
                "ans3": "[0, \ua699)    ",
                "ans4": "(-a,a)",
                "question_text": "The domain of function \\log_e\\left(a^2-x^2\\right) is",
                "correct_ans": "(-a,a)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30145": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "2\u221a3",
                "ans4": "3\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If a=b=3 and \u2220B=45^0 in \u0394ABC then c=",
                "correct_ans": "3\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34961": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{e^{\\sin x}-1}x=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33135": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3   ",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3    ",
                "ans3": "\u00bd",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\tan^2x\\;dx}{\\sin^2x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31805": {
                "ans1": "90^0",
                "ans2": "60^0",
                "ans3": "45^0",
                "ans4": "30^0",
                "question_text": "The smallest angle of a \u0394ABC whose sides are a=7, b=4\\sqrt3\u00a0and c=\\sqrt3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "30^0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32590": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The non-empty proper subsets of a set are 30. The cardinality of set is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39842": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": " 4   ",
                "ans3": "-2  ",
                "ans4": "-4",
                "question_text": "The Y-coordinates of a point on line joining (1,3,-5) and (9,1,7) is 5. The Z-coordinate of point is",
                "correct_ans": "-2  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39746": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)}",
                "question_text": "If x^y=a then \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\log a}{x(\\log x)^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34255": {
                "ans1": "720",
                "ans2": "360",
                "ans3": "180",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "The number of ways on which the word \u2018PEOPLE\u2019 can be arranged are",
                "correct_ans": "180",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36552": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow{\\textstyle\\frac14}}\\frac{4x-1}{2\\sqrt x-1}=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36674": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\sin(\\frac1x)=",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39749": {
                "ans1": "x^2+2",
                "ans2": "x^2-1",
                "ans3": "x^2+3",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If f(x-1)=x+2 then f(x^2) equals",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33714": {
                "ans1": "3Im(z)   ",
                "ans2": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "ans3": "2 Re(z)   ",
                "ans4": "2i Re(z)",
                "question_text": "If z be any complex number then z-\\overline z =",
                "correct_ans": "2i Im(z)   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33391": {
                "ans1": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "ans2": " -\\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans3": " \\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "If y= \\frac\\pi2-\\cos^{-1}x+\\sin^{-1}x , \\frac{\\operatorname dy}{\\operatorname dx}=",
                "correct_ans": " \\frac2{\\sqrt{1-x^2}} ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33270": {
                "ans1": "\\log(e^x-e^{-x})+c",
                "ans2": "\\log(e^x+e^{-x})+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(e^x\\right)+C",
                "ans4": "cot^{-1}\\left(e^x\\right)+C",
                "question_text": "The integral\u00a0\\int \\frac{\\mathrm dx}{e^x + e^{-x}}dx\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}\\left(e^x\\right)+C",
                "explanation": "\\int \\frac{\\mathrm dx}{e^x + e^{-x}}\\int\\frac{e^xdx}{{(e^x)}^2+1}\\\\Put\\;e^x\\;=\\;y\\\\\\int\\frac{dy}{y^2+1}=\\tan^{-1}\\left(y\\right)+C\\;=\\tan^{-1}\\left(e^x\\right)\\;+\\;C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36956": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "The sum of 1st n natural no. is\u00a0\\frac{1}{5}\u00a0times the sum of their squares then n =\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "\\frac{n(n+1)}{2} = \\frac{1}{5}\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}{6}n = 7",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39998": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0f(x) = |x-1| \u00a0then value of f'(1) is",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "At x=1,f(1)=\\left|1-1\\right|=0\\\\f'(x)\\lbrack\\frac{d\\left|x\\right|}{dx}=\\frac{\\left|x\\right|}x=\\frac x{\\left|x\\right|},x\\neq0\\rbrack",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30441": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans3": "\u2212\u03c0/6",
                "ans4": "\u2212\u03c0/4",
                "question_text": "The principal value of arguments of complex number 1 - i is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\u2212\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "In the argand diagram 1-i lies on the fourth quardant so the principal argument",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34580": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "3\u03c0/4",
                "ans4": "2\u03c0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\tan^{-1}(3) \u00a0and\u00a0tan^{-1}( 2) \u00a0are two angles of a triangle then other angle is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "\\pi3^{rd}\\;angle\\;\\;=\\;\\pi-\\tan^{-1}\\left(2\\right)-\\tan^{-1}\\left(3\\right)\\\\=\\frac\\pi4(Using calculator in radian mode)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31126": {
                "ans1": "\\sin^{-1}\\left(\\frac1{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\sin^{-1}\\left(\\frac2{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\sin^{-1}\\left(\\frac3{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac3{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "question_text": "The angle between the plane x + 2y + 3z + 4 = 0 and positive z-axis is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\sin^{-1}\\left(\\frac3{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "explanation": "\\frac{1}{\\sqrt14}Dc's z-axis 0,0,1sin\\theta = l_1l_2 + m_1m_2 +n_1n_2 = \\frac{3}{\\sqrt14}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32002": {
                "ans1": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac1{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac2{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac3{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If vector\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a} = \\overrightarrow{i} + 2\\overrightarrow{j} +3\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0then the angle between vector\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and positive x-axis is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac1{\\sqrt{14}}\\right)",
                "explanation": "DR's of positive x-axis: 1,0,0DR's of given vector A: 1,2,3\\cos\\theta\\;=\\;\\frac{a_1a_2+b_1b_2+c_1c_2}{\\sqrt{a_1^2+b_1^2+c_1^2}\\sqrt{a_2^2+b_2^2+c_2^2}}\\\\=\\;\\frac1{\\sqrt{14}}\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34727": {
                "ans1": "-1\\leq x\\leq1",
                "ans2": "-1\\leq x\\leq2",
                "ans3": "-2\\leq x\\leq2",
                "ans4": "0\\leq x\\leq1",
                "question_text": "The inverse function f(x) =\u00a0\\sin^{-1} (1-2x) \u00a0 is defined for ( Where x is real number )",
                "correct_ans": "0\\leq x\\leq1",
                "explanation": "\\leq\\leq\\leq",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32272": {
                "ans1": "\\frac s\\Delta",
                "ans2": "\\frac\\Delta s",
                "ans3": "r + 4R",
                "ans4": " 4R",
                "question_text": "In\u00a0\\triangle ABC\u00a0,\u00a0\\frac{1}{r_1} + \\frac{1}{r_2} + \\frac{1}{r_3}\u00a0is equal to\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac s\\Delta",
                "explanation": "Formula:\\frac{1}{r_1} + \\frac{1}{r_2} + \\frac{1}{r_3}Note:You can also apply dimensional\u00a0method.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35349": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "\u03c9",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0(\\frac{-1+\\sqrt{-3}}{2})^5 + (\\frac{-1-\\sqrt{-3}}{2})^5 =",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "\u03c9^5 + (\u03c9^2)^5 = \u03c9^5 + \u03c9^{10}\\omega^3.\\omega^2+{(\\omega^3)}^3.\\omega=\\omega^2+\\omega\\;\\;\\lbrack\\omega^3=1\\rbrack\\\\=-1\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\lbrack1+\\omega+\\omega^2=0\\rbrack",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35540": {
                "ans1": "2^n",
                "ans2": "n^n",
                "ans3": "n!",
                "ans4": "n^2",
                "question_text": "let P be a set containing n distinct elements\u00a0then the number of function that can be defined from P\u00a0to\u00a0P\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "n^n",
                "explanation": "\\left(n(B)\\right)^{n(A)}\\left(n(P)\\right)^{n(P)}=n^n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32727": {
                "ans1": "7!",
                "ans2": "8!",
                "ans3": "9!",
                "ans4": "10!",
                "question_text": "In how many ways can a 7\u00a0boy\u00a0and 2 girls can be seated in a circular table\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "8!",
                "explanation": "Total number 7+2 = 9no of circular arrangement = (n-1)!(9-1)!8!",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34245": {
                "ans1": "4h^2 = 9ab",
                "ans2": "9h^2 = 12ab",
                "ans3": "48h^2 = 49ab",
                "ans4": "49h^2 = 48ab",
                "question_text": "The condition for which the ratio\u00a0of the slopes of two st. lines of\u00a0\u00a0ax^2 + 2hxy + by^2 = 0 \u00a0is 3:4 is",
                "correct_ans": "48h^2 = 49ab",
                "explanation": "(mn).{(2h)}^2\\;=\\;{(m+n)}^2.ab\\\\ (3.4).{(2h)}^2\\;\\;=\\;{(3+4)}^2.ab\\;48h^2 = 49ab",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31573": {
                "ans1": "l=0",
                "ans2": "n=0",
                "ans3": "m=0",
                "ans4": "l=m",
                "question_text": "The condition for st. line lx+my+n =0 to be normal to\u00a0x^2 + y^2 -a^2 = 0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "n=0",
                "explanation": "x^2 + y^2 =a^2 ,n=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38084": {
                "ans1": "\\left(0,\\pm\\sqrt7\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\left(0,\\pm\\sqrt6\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\left(\\pm\\sqrt7,0\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\left(\\pm\\sqrt6,0\\right)",
                "question_text": "The foci of ellipse\u00a0\\frac{x^2}{9} + \\frac{y^2}{16} =1\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(0,\\pm\\sqrt7\\right)",
                "explanation": "a=3 , b=4b>a\\sqrt(1-\\frac{9}{16}) = \\frac{\\sqrt7}{4}\\pm\\pm\\pm\u200b\u200b\u200b\u200b\\sqrt7\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38435": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "720",
                "ans3": "60",
                "ans4": "240",
                "question_text": "The maximum number of triangles that can be formed by joining the vertices of decagon polgyon having ten sides is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "120",
                "explanation": "No. of triangles that can be\u00a0 formed from 10 non- collinear points. (Decagon points)={}^{10}C_{3\\;\\;}=\\;120",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36370": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{2\\tan x.secx}{{(1-\\tan x)}^2}",
                "ans2": "sec^2(\\frac\\pi4+x)",
                "ans3": "-sec^2(x).\\tan x",
                "ans4": "-sec^2(\\frac\\pi4-x)",
                "question_text": "If y =\u00a0(\\frac{1+\\tan x}{1-tanx})\u00a0then\u00a0\\frac{\\mathrm dy}{\\mathrm d x} =",
                "correct_ans": "sec^2(\\frac\\pi4+x)",
                "explanation": "y=\\frac{tan\\frac{\\pi}{4}+tanx}{1-tan\\frac{\\pi}{4}tanx}\\tan({\\frac{\\pi}{4}+x})\\frac{\\mathrm dy}{\\mathrm d x} = \\sec^2(\\frac{\\pi}{4}+x)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38232": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "\\frac{e-e^{-1}}2-1",
                "ans4": "\\frac{e-e^{-1}}2",
                "question_text": "The sum of the infinite series\u00a0\\frac{1}{3!} + \\frac{1}{5!} + \\frac{1}{7!}+\\frac{1}{9!}+ ..... \u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{e-e^{-1}}2-1",
                "explanation": "e=1+\\frac{1}{1!} + \\frac{1}{2!} + \\frac{1}{3!}+\\frac{1}{4!}+ ..... e^{-1}=1-\\frac{1}{1!} + \\frac{1}{2!} -\\frac{1}{3!}+\\frac{1}{4!}- ..... \\frac{e-e^{-1}}2=\\frac{1}{1!}  + \\frac{1}{3!}+\\frac{1}{5!}+ ..... \\frac{e-e^{-1}}2-1= \\frac{1}{3!}+\\frac{1}{5!}+ \\frac{1}{7!}+..... \u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30537": {
                "ans1": "\u221a5+3",
                "ans2": "\u2212\u221a5-3",
                "ans3": "1/(\u221a5\u22123)",
                "ans4": "1/(\u221a5+3)",
                "question_text": "For a quadratic equation having rational coefficients whose one root is\u00a0\\sqrt5 - 3\u00a0then other root is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\u2212\u221a5-3",
                "explanation": "For rational coefficients. roots are conjugate.\\alpha= \\sqrt5 -3\\beta= - \\sqrt5 -3\\sqrt{}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33256": {
                "ans1": "{(x+1)}^3",
                "ans2": "x^3+1",
                "ans3": "x^3+x+1",
                "ans4": "x^3+x",
                "question_text": "Let f:R\\rightarrow R \u00a0and g:R\\rightarrow R\u00a0be two functions defined by\u00a0f(x) = x + 1,      g(x) = x^3 \u00a0then the composite function (gof) is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "{(x+1)}^3",
                "explanation": "\u200d\u200d\u200d=(x+1)^3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38150": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "1/3",
                "ans3": "1/4",
                "ans4": "2/3",
                "question_text": "Area bounded by\u00a0y = x^2 \u00a0, x-axis and x=1 is",
                "correct_ans": "1/3",
                "explanation": "Area = \\int_0^1 x^2 dx=[\\frac{x^3}{3}]_0^1\\frac{1}{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35110": {
                "ans1": "\\left(\\frac g2,\\frac f2\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\left(-\\frac g2,-\\frac f2\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\left(-\\frac g2,\\frac f2\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\left(-g,-f\\right)",
                "question_text": "The center of the circle\u00a0x^2+y^2+gx+fy+c=0\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(-\\frac g2,-\\frac f2\\right)",
                "explanation": "centre = (\\frac{-g}{2},\\frac{-f}{2})",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34715": {
                "ans1": "30",
                "ans2": "40",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "28",
                "question_text": "The next term of the sequence 2,6,12,20........is",
                "correct_ans": "30",
                "explanation": "sequence = 1*2,2*3,3*4,4*5,...next term = 5*6=30",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31058": {
                "ans1": "m/n",
                "ans2": "n/m",
                "ans3": "m",
                "ans4": "n",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x \\to 0} \\frac{sinmx}{tannx}?",
                "correct_ans": "m/n",
                "explanation": "Using L-Hospital Rule:\\lim_{x \\to 0} \\frac{cosmx }{sec^2nx}\\frac{m}{n}\\frac{m}{n}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33220": {
                "ans1": "Symmetric",
                "ans2": "skew-symmetric",
                "ans3": "square",
                "ans4": "triangle",
                "question_text": "For any square matrix if\u00a0a_{ij} =- a_{ji}\u00a0 then the matrix is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "skew-symmetric",
                "explanation": "here,a_{ij} = -a_{ji}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30127": {
                "ans1": "A.P",
                "ans2": "G.P.",
                "ans3": "H.P.",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If x,y,z are in G.P., then logx, logy, logz are in",
                "correct_ans": "A.P",
                "explanation": "x,y,z are in G.P^2Taking log on both sides we get2logy = logx + logzi.e logx, logy, logz are in A.P.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33065": {
                "ans1": "(0,0)",
                "ans2": "(1,2)",
                "ans3": "(1,3)",
                "ans4": "(2,3)",
                "question_text": "If two ends of latus rectum of a parabola are (-3,6) and (5,0) then its focus is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "(1,3)",
                "explanation": "(\\frac{-3+5}{2},\\frac{6+0}{2}) = (1,3)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30551": {
                "ans1": "11",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "13",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "Numbers of non -empty subsets of set A={1,2,3,4} ?",
                "correct_ans": "15",
                "explanation": "No.\u00a0of elements(n)=42^4-1=15",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30076": {
                "ans1": "21",
                "ans2": "31",
                "ans3": "41",
                "ans4": "51",
                "question_text": "The numbers of mutually unlike terms in the expansion of\u00a0(1-x^3-3x+3x^2)^{10}\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "31",
                "explanation": "(1-x^3-3x+3x^2)^{10}(1-x)^{3*10}No.\u00a0of terms = 30+1 = 31",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35587": {
                "ans1": "They are coplanar",
                "ans2": "They are collinear",
                "ans3": "They are linearly dependent",
                "ans4": "They are represented by the side of triangle",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a} +\\overrightarrow{b}+\\overrightarrow{c} = 0\u00a0 which of the following is not true .\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a},\\overrightarrow{b}and\\overrightarrow{c}?",
                "correct_ans": "They are collinear",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow{a}+\\overrightarrow{b}+\\overrightarrow{c} = 0 ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33227": {
                "ans1": "\\omega",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "\\omega^2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\omega\u00a0is a cube root of unity then\u00a0\\omega ^{25}\u00a0= ?",
                "correct_ans": "\\omega",
                "explanation": "\\omega ^ {25}(\\omega^{3})^8 \\omega1*\\omega = \\omega",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35723": {
                "ans1": "\\triangle",
                "ans2": "\\triangle",
                "ans3": "\\triangle",
                "ans4": "\\triangle",
                "question_text": "In\u00a0\\triangle ABC , bc SinA=\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "\\triangle",
                "explanation": "\\triangle =\\frac{1}{2}bcsinAbcSinA=2\\triangle",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31242": {
                "ans1": "n^2",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "n-1",
                "ans4": "n",
                "question_text": "Difference between sum of 'n' even numbers and sum of odd numbers is :",
                "correct_ans": "n",
                "explanation": "sum of n even numbers= n(n+1)n^2n(n+1)-n^2=n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34328": {
                "ans1": "2/3",
                "ans2": "3/2",
                "ans3": "3/4",
                "ans4": "4/5",
                "question_text": "Length of latus rectum of\u00a02y^2 + 3x+4 = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "3/2",
                "explanation": "2y^2 = -(3x+4)y^2 = -\\frac{3}{2}(x+4/3)length of latus rectum = 3/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37488": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0,1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0^nP_r =^nC_r\u00a0then r",
                "correct_ans": "0,1",
                "explanation": "\\frac{n!}{(n-r)!}=\\frac{n!}{(n-r)!\\;r!}r! = 1r=0\\;or\\;1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36348": {
                "ans1": "6/7,2/7,3/7",
                "ans2": "6/7,2/7,-3/7",
                "ans3": "6/7,-2/7,3/7",
                "ans4": "-6/7,2/7,3/7",
                "question_text": "The projection of line on the axes are 6,2,3 then the dc's of the line is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "6/7,2/7,3/7",
                "explanation": "x_2-x_1 = 6y_2-y_1=2z_2-z_1=3\\sqrt{(x_2-x1)^2+(y_2-y_1)^2+(z_2-z_1)^2}7so6/7,2/7,3/7\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31662": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt{2}",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{3}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac{k}{2}}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{\\frac{k}{3}}",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the conic\u00a0x^2 - y^2 = k^2 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{2}",
                "explanation": "\\sqrt{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31761": {
                "ans1": "bc=de",
                "ans2": "bd=ce",
                "ans3": "be=cd",
                "ans4": "b^2d=c^2e",
                "question_text": "If both the roots of the equations\u00a0x^2+bx+c=0\\;and\\;x^2+dx+e=0\u00a0are common then\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "be=cd",
                "explanation": "For both root common,coefficients are proportional,\\frac11=\\frac bd=\\frac cebe=cd",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35165": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{}1-x^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-1}{\\sqrt{}1-x^2}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{x^2 - 1}",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0cos(cos^{-1}x)\u00a0wrt x is?",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "cos(cos^{-1}x)Required derivative = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34082": {
                "ans1": "e^x secx+c",
                "ans2": "e^x secx.tanx+c",
                "ans3": "e^x tanx+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{e^x}{tanx}+c",
                "question_text": "\\int e^x (sec^2x+tanx) \\mathrm{d}x\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "e^x tanx+c",
                "explanation": "\\int e^x [f(x) + f'(x)]dx = e^xf(x) +c\\int e^x (sec^2x + tanx)dx = e^xtanx + c",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31344": {
                "ans1": "e=0",
                "ans2": "e=1",
                "ans3": "e>1",
                "ans4": "e<1",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the circle is",
                "correct_ans": "e=0",
                "explanation": "The eccentricity of the circle is\u00a00.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31929": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "i",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0i^2= -1, then\u00a0i^2+i^4+i^6+i^8+...+ to\u00a0(2n+1) term equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31590": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert dx",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39224": {
                "ans1": "Unique solution",
                "ans2": "Infinite Solution",
                "ans3": "finite solution",
                "ans4": "No solution",
                "question_text": "General values give",
                "correct_ans": "Infinite Solution",
                "explanation": "Since n is infinite.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33743": {
                "ans1": "50",
                "ans2": "85",
                "ans3": "75",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "If the polygon has 3915 diagonals, then the number of its sides are,",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38488": {
                "ans1": "16/9",
                "ans2": "9/4",
                "ans3": "4/9",
                "ans4": "81/16",
                "question_text": "A.M between two numbers is\u00a016\u00a0and G.M is\u00a09, then H.M is ,",
                "correct_ans": "81/16",
                "explanation": "AM\u00d7HM=GM^2\n\n16 \\times HM = 9^2\n\nHM = \\dfrac{81}{16}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38176": {
                "ans1": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "ans2": "k/\u03b1 and k/\u03b2",
                "ans3": "1/\u03b1 and 1/\u03b2",
                "ans4": "\u03b1 and \u03b2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\u03b1\u00a0and \u03b2\u00a0are the roots of\u00a0f(x) = 0 then roots of\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0are",
                "correct_ans": "k\u03b1 and k\u03b2",
                "explanation": "\u00a0f(\\dfrac{x}{k}) = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34074": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "doesn't exist",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}{\\sqrt{x\\ }}}",
                "correct_ans": "doesn't exist",
                "explanation": "Left hand limit is not defined.LHL \\neq RHL",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36866": {
                "ans1": "100",
                "ans2": "160",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "120",
                "question_text": "If n(U) = 300, n(A) = 160 and n(B) = 240 then what is the minimum value of n(A \u2229 B)?",
                "correct_ans": "100",
                "explanation": "For minimum n(A \u2229 B), n(A \u222a B) should be maximum.The maximum n (A \u222a B) is n(\u222a) = 300n(A \u2229 B) = n(A) + n(B) - n(A\u222aB ) = 160+240-300 = 100",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37794": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "-2",
                "ans3": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "ans4": "\u22122 if n is even and 2 if it is odd",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0cosx+secx=\u22122\u00a0, then for a positive integer n, \\cos^n x+\\sec^n xdx is",
                "correct_ans": "\u22122 if n is odd and 2 if it is even",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36967": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{e^x}x",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{e^x}{x^2}",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "question_text": "\\int e^x\\left(\\frac1{x^2}-\\frac1x\\right)dx",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{e^x}x",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32723": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The area between the curve\u00a0y = x^3\u00a0 and the ordinates\u00a0x=-2 and\u00a0x=2 is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "\\displaystyle{\\int_{0}^{2} x^3 dx} = 2 \\times \\dfrac{2^4}{4} = 8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33348": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "i",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0(\\dfrac{-1+\\sqrt{3}i}{2})^{99}",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "=(\u03c9)^{99}=(\u03c93)^{33}=1^{33}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34798": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "A line makes an angle\u00a0\\dfrac{\\pi}{4} , \\dfrac{3\\pi}{4}\u200b\u00a0with x- axis an y- axis respectively . Then",
                "correct_ans": "both",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30576": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{1+x^2}",
                "ans2": "-\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac2{1+x^2}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\u00a0y= sec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}}) + cosec^{-1} ({\\dfrac{1-x^2}{1+x^2}})\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "y=pi/2so derivatiive is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34618": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c9",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\u03c9\u00a0is cube root of unity. Then the value of\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix} 1 & \\omega & \\omega^2\\\\ \\omega & \\omega^2 & 1 \\\\ \\omega^2 & 1 & \\omega \\end{vmatrix}\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39494": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "3\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0(\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{i})\\overrightarrow{i} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{j})\\overrightarrow{j} + (\\overrightarrow{a}.\\overrightarrow{k})\\overrightarrow{a} =",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a",
                "explanation": "(a.i)i+(a.j\u200b)j\u200b+(a.k)a=ax\u200bi+ay\u200bj\u200b+az\u200bk=a",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37408": {
                "ans1": "9",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\u221a2",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the conic section\u00a0xy=9\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2",
                "explanation": "Solution:\\sqrt{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38768": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1/e",
                "ans3": "R",
                "ans4": "R-1",
                "question_text": "For\u00a0y =\\ log_a\\ x to be valid; a=",
                "correct_ans": "R-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35731": {
                "ans1": "2\u03c0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\u03c0",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\displaystyle \\int^{1 / 2}_{-1/2} \\cos x \\log \\left(\\cfrac{1+x}{1-x}\\right) d x=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Being odd function.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34735": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "ans3": "-1/2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\cos^{-1}x-\\sin^{-1}x\\;=\\;\\frac\\pi6,\\\\\\;then\\;x\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac\\pi2-2\\;\\sin^{-1}x=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle6}\\\\x=\\sin^{-1}\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle6}=\\frac12\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30725": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;is\\;parallel\\;to\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;is\\;perpendicular\\;to\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;or\\;\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;is\\;a\\;null\\;vector\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "such relation doesn't hold",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\overrightarrow aand\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;are\\;two\\;vectors\\\\such\\;that\\;\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow a.\\overset\\rightharpoonup b=0\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b=0\\;,\\\\then\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;or\\;\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;is\\;a\\;null\\;vector\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33784": {
                "ans1": "diagonal matrix",
                "ans2": "scalar matrix",
                "ans3": "symmetric matrix",
                "ans4": "skew symmetric matrix",
                "question_text": "The inverse of diagonal matrix is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "diagonal matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35470": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "17",
                "question_text": "The smallest value of\u00a05\\cos\\theta+12 is",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32556": {
                "ans1": "vertices of equilateral triangle",
                "ans2": "concylic",
                "ans3": "vertices of rt. angled triangle",
                "ans4": "collinear",
                "question_text": "The points (a,b+c) , (b,c+a) and (c,a+b) are",
                "correct_ans": "collinear",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32323": {
                "ans1": "an even function",
                "ans2": "an odd function",
                "ans3": "neither even nor odd ",
                "ans4": "a costant function",
                "question_text": "The function f(x) =\u00a0(x^2+\\cos x+1)\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "an even function",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33258": {
                "ans1": "\\cos\\theta=A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2",
                "ans2": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{(A_1+B_1+C_1)(A_2+B_2+C_2)}",
                "ans3": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}",
                "ans4": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{\\sqrt{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;angle\\;between\\;two\\;planes\\;\\\\A_1x\\;+B_1y+C_1z+D_1=0\\;and\\\\\\;\\;A_2x\\;+B_2y+C_2z+D_2=0\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{A_1A_2+B_1B_2+C_1C_2}{\\sqrt{(A_1^2+B_1^2+C_1^2)(A_2^2+B_2^2+{C^2}_2)}}",
                "explanation": "Fundamental formula",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33164": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac23",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}3",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac13",
                "ans4": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac32",
                "question_text": "Angle between x=2 and x-3y=6 is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37648": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\pi",
                "ans3": "\\frac\\pi{180}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{180}\\pi",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\sin x^o}xis",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac\\pi{180}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37188": {
                "ans1": "-1/3 , 2/3 , -2/3",
                "ans2": "1/3 , 2/3 ,2/3",
                "ans3": "-1/3 , -2/3, -2/3",
                "ans4": "1/3, -2/3, -2/3",
                "question_text": "The direction cosines of the line passing through the point (-1,2,5) and (-2,4,3) are",
                "correct_ans": "-1/3 , 2/3 , -2/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Direction\\;ratios\\;of\\;line\\;joining\\;(-1,2,5)\\;and\\;(-2,4,3)\\;are\\\\-2-(-1),4-2,3-5\\rightarrow-1,2,-2\\\\dcs\\;are\\;-\\frac13,\\frac23.-\\frac23\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32202": {
                "ans1": "36",
                "ans2": "144",
                "ans3": "574",
                "ans4": "754",
                "question_text": "The number of words that can be formed out of the word ARTICLE so that the vowels occupy only even places is",
                "correct_ans": "144",
                "explanation": "By using basic principle of counting,4*3*3*2*5*1=144",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31031": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "ans4": "-\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\overrightarrow a=k\\widehat a,\\;then\\;k\\;equals\\;",
                "correct_ans": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39161": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The length of latus rectum of the parabola\u00a04x^2-4x-2y+3=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32097": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "10",
                "question_text": "If A=\u00a0 \u00a0\\begin{bmatrix}0&2&3\\\\4&5&6\\\\7&8&9\\end{bmatrix} \u00a0 is a 3 X 3 matrix , then trace of A is",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "Trace means sum of elements of main diagonal.So, 0+9+5=14",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38294": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "does not exist",
                "question_text": "value\\;of\\;\\lim_{x\\rightarrow o}\\frac{\\left|x\\right|}x=",
                "correct_ans": "does not exist",
                "explanation": "In LHL its value is -1 and in RHL its value is 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38637": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25a^2c^2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}6ca=25b^2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25ac\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}6c^2=25ab\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;condition\\;that\\;the\\;roots\\\\\\;of\\;ax^2+bx+c=0\\;are\\\\\\;in\\;the\\;ratio\\;2:3\\;is\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}6b^2=25ac\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Let\\;roots\\;are\\;2K\\;and\\;3K\\;\\\\sum\\;of\\;roots\\;=2K\\;+3K\\;=\\;-\\frac ba\\rightarrow K=-\\frac b{5a}\\\\Product\\;of\\;roots\\;=\\;2K.3K\\;=\\frac ca\\rightarrow K^2=\\frac c{6a}\\\\or,\\left(-\\frac b{5a}\\right)^2=\\frac c{6a}\\rightarrow6b^2=25ac\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39599": {
                "ans1": "point",
                "ans2": "pair of lines",
                "ans3": "sphere",
                "ans4": "a pair of planes",
                "question_text": "In a three dimensional xyz space , the equation\u00a0x^2-5x+6=0 represents",
                "correct_ans": "a pair of planes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37214": {
                "ans1": "\\log_e(1+x^2)+c",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac12\\log_e\\left(1+x^2\\right)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac x{1+x^4}dx\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac12\\tan^{-1}x^2\\;+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30131": {
                "ans1": "\\left[-\\frac13,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans2": "\\left[0,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans3": "\\left[-1,1\\right]",
                "ans4": "\\left[-1,\\frac13\\right]",
                "question_text": "The range of the function f(x)=\\cos\\;\\frac x3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\left[-1,1\\right]",
                "explanation": "obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37535": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\omega\\;is\\;a\\;non\\;real\\;cube\\;root\\\\\\;of\\;unity\\;,\\;then\\;\\vert1-\\omega\\vert\\;is\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt3",
                "explanation": "\\left|1-\\frac{-1+\\sqrt3i}2\\right|=\\sqrt{\\frac94+\\frac34}=\\sqrt3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30064": {
                "ans1": "R=\\frac{abc}{4\\triangle}",
                "ans2": "R=\\frac{abc}\\triangle",
                "ans3": "R=\\frac{a+b+c}{4\\triangle}",
                "ans4": "R=\\frac{a+b+c}\\triangle",
                "question_text": "If R is the radius of circum-circle of\u00a0\u00a0\\\\\\triangle ABC,\\;and\\;\\triangle\\;is\\;its\\;area,\\;then",
                "correct_ans": "R=\\frac{abc}{4\\triangle}",
                "explanation": "Obvious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36886": {
                "ans1": "c>0",
                "ans2": "c=1",
                "ans3": "c=\\pm\\sqrt3",
                "ans4": "c=2",
                "question_text": "If direction cosines of the line are\u00a0\\\\\\\\\\frac1c,\\frac1c,\\frac1c,\\;then",
                "correct_ans": "c=\\pm\\sqrt3",
                "explanation": "l^2+m^2+n^2=1\\rightarrow\\frac1{c^2}+\\frac1{c^2}+\\frac1{c^2}=1\\rightarrow c=\\pm\\sqrt3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35468": {
                "ans1": "\\frac23\\\\",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "\\frac32\\\\",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The\\;inverse\\;of\\;matrix\\;A=\\begin{bmatrix}1&2\\\\k&3\\end{bmatrix}does\\;not\\;exist,\\;then\\;K=\\\\",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac32\\\\",
                "explanation": "\\left|A\\right|=0\\;or\\;3-2k=0\\\\k=\\frac32\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33393": {
                "ans1": "2x^2+3x+18=0",
                "ans2": "x^2+6x-9=0",
                "ans3": "x^2+6x+9=0",
                "ans4": "x^2-6x+9=0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\alpha,\\beta\\;are\\;roots\\;of\\;the\\;equation\\;9x^2+6x+1=0\\;then\\\\\\;\\;the\\;equation\\;with\\;roots\\frac1\\alpha,\\frac1\\beta is",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+6x+9=0",
                "explanation": "Replace\\;x\\;by\\;\\frac1x.\\;The\\;new\\;equation\\;will\\;be,\\\\9\\left(\\frac1x\\right)^2+6\\left(\\frac1x\\right)+1=0\\\\i.e\\;x^2+6x+9=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33311": {
                "ans1": "Vertex\\;\\left(0,0\\right)",
                "ans2": "length\\;of\\;latus\\;rectum=4\\left|a\\right|",
                "ans3": "e=2",
                "ans4": "focus\\left(a,0\\right)",
                "question_text": "which of the following is not true for parabola\u00a0y^2=4ax",
                "correct_ans": "e=2",
                "explanation": "e=2\\;is\\;not\\;true \\;since,e=1\\; for\\;parabola",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30213": {
                "ans1": "48",
                "ans2": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|^2",
                "ans3": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\\;\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|=4,\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|=2\\;and\\;angle\\;between\\;\\overrightarrow a\\;\\&\\;\\overrightarrow{b\\;}is\\\\\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}6,\\;then\\;\\left(\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b\\right)^2is\\;equal\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|^2",
                "explanation": "\\\\\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b\\right|=a^2b^2\\sin^2\\theta=16\\times4\\times\\left(\\sin\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}6\\right)^2\\\\=16\\times4\\times\\frac14=\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34654": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "undefined",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "The Value of\u00a0\\log_{10}0\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "Note that logarithm of 0 in any phase is undefined.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35714": {
                "ans1": "1/e",
                "ans2": "e^x",
                "ans3": "2e^x",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "The value of Cosh x+sinh x is",
                "correct_ans": "e^x",
                "explanation": "\\cos hx=\\frac{e^x+e^{-x}}2and\\;sinhx=\\frac{e^x-e^{-x}}2\\\\so,\\cos hx+\\sin hx=e^x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37501": {
                "ans1": "7",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "The length of complex number Z=3+4i from origin is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "Length\\;of\\;z\\;from\\;origin=\\left|z\\right|=\\left|3+4i\\right|=\\sqrt{9+16}=5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33478": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1/4",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "If\\;x+2y+z+3=0\\;and\\;2x+4y+kz+5=0\\;are\\;parallel\\;\\\\plane,\\;then\\;k=",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "\\frac12=\\frac24=\\frac1k\\\\k=2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35804": {
                "ans1": "2n\\mathrm\\pi+\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "ans2": "n\\mathrm\\pi+\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "ans3": "2n\\mathrm\\pi\\pm\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "ans4": "n\\mathrm\\pi\\pm\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "question_text": "The most general value of\u00a0\\\\\\theta\\;which\\;satisfies\\\\\\sin\\theta=\\frac1{-2}and\\;\\tan\\theta=\\frac1{\\sqrt3}",
                "correct_ans": "2n\\mathrm\\pi+\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "explanation": "\\theta\\;lies\\;in\\;III\\;quadrants\\;so\\;PV=\\mathrm\\pi+\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}6=\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\\\mathrm{general}\\;\\mathrm{value}=2\\mathrm{n\u03c0}+\\frac{7\\mathrm\\pi}6\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34330": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "n^2",
                "ans4": "2^n",
                "question_text": "The order of the power set of a set of order n is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "2^n",
                "explanation": "2^n\\;if\\;there\\;are\\;n\\;element\\;in\\;set\\;A.\\;So\\;N\\left(P(A)\\right)=2^n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32198": {
                "ans1": "\\frac\\pi2",
                "ans2": "\\pi",
                "ans3": "2\\pi",
                "ans4": "3\\pi",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\int_{-1}^{3}\\left[\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\frac{x}{1+x^{2}}\\right)+\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\frac{1+x^{2}}{x}\\right)\\right] dx  is",
                "correct_ans": "2\\pi",
                "explanation": "\u00a0\u00a0\\int_{-1}^3\\left[\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac x{1+x^2}\\right)+cot^{-1}\\left(\\frac x{1+x^2}\\right)\\right]dx\\;=\\int_{-1}^3\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2dx\\\\=\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2{\\left[x\\right]^3}_{-1}=2\\mathrm\\pi\u00a0\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32624": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}3",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}4",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2\\mathrm\\pi}3",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2",
                "question_text": "The angle between the pair of straight line\u00a0y^2\\sin^2\\theta-xy\\sin\\theta+x^2\\left(\\cos^2\\theta-1\\right)=0\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2",
                "explanation": "Compare\\;with\\;ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0\\\\and\\;here\\;a+b=0\\\\i.e\\;\\theta=\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37661": {
                "ans1": "\\left[0,\\infty\\right]",
                "ans2": "\\left(-\\infty,\\infty\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\left[1,e\\right]",
                "ans4": "\\left(0,\\infty\\right)",
                "question_text": "The\\;range\\;of\\;the\\;function\\;f\\left(x\\right)=e^x",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(0,\\infty\\right)",
                "explanation": "Range\\;of\\;function\\;f\\left(x\\right)=e^xis\\;\\left(0,\\infty\\right)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34508": {
                "ans1": "Symmetric matrix",
                "ans2": "Skew -symetric matrix",
                "ans3": "Diagonal matrix",
                "ans4": "Scalar matrix",
                "question_text": "A+A^T=0\\;then\\;matrix\\;A\\;is\\;called",
                "correct_ans": "Skew -symetric matrix",
                "explanation": "A=-A^T\\\\A^T=-A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32327": {
                "ans1": "2e",
                "ans2": "3e",
                "ans3": "2e-1",
                "ans4": "3e",
                "question_text": "The sum of the series:\u00a01+\\frac{2^2}{2!}+\\frac{3^2}{3!}+\\frac{4^2}{4!}\\dots is\\\\",
                "correct_ans": "2e",
                "explanation": "\\sum_{n=1}^\\infty\\frac{n^2}{n!}=\\sum_{n=1}^\\infty\\frac n{\\left(n-1\\right)!}\\\\=\\sum_{n=1}^\\infty\\frac1{\\left(n-2\\right)!}+\\sum_{n=1}^\\infty\\frac1{\\left(n-1\\right)!}=2e\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31877": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\log a}{\\log b}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\log b}{\\log a}",
                "ans3": "\\frac ab",
                "ans4": "\\frac ba",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{a^{\\sin x}-1}{b^{\\sin x}-1}\\;is\\;equal\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\log a}{\\log b}",
                "explanation": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{a^{\\sin x}\\cos x\\left(\\log a\\right)}{b^{\\sin x}\\cos x\\left(\\log b\\right)}\\left[L-Hospital's\\;rule\\right]\\\\=\\frac{\\log a}{\\log b}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32357": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\tan2x}8",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan8x}8",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan4x}{18}+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan4x}8+c",
                "question_text": "\\\\\\int\\frac1{1+\\cos8x}dx",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\tan4x}8+c",
                "explanation": "I=\\int\\frac1{2\\cos^24x}dx=\\frac12\\int sec^24xdx\\\\=\\frac12\\left(\\frac{\\tan4x}4\\right)+c",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31172": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1x",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{2x}",
                "ans3": "\\frac12",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\\log_{x^2.}x.\\;with\\;respect\\;to\\;x\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "y=\\frac{\\log x}{\\log x^2}=\\frac12\\\\\\frac{dy}{dx}=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35867": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "1/3",
                "ans3": "1/6",
                "ans4": "1/5",
                "question_text": "The distance between the parallel planes 2x - 2y + z + 1 = 0 and 4x - 4y + 2x + 3 = 0 is:",
                "correct_ans": "1/6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39216": {
                "ans1": "b = c",
                "ans2": "a\\, \\bot \\, (b-c)",
                "ans3": "b=c \\quad \\textrm{or} \\quad  a\\, \\bot \\, (b-c)",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "If a, b, c are non-zero vectors such that\u00a0\u00a0 a\\, \\, .\\, \\, b=a\\, \\, .\\, \\, c,\u00a0then which statement is true",
                "correct_ans": "b=c \\quad \\textrm{or} \\quad  a\\, \\bot \\, (b-c)",
                "explanation": "a.b=a.c\\Rightarrow a.b-a.c=0\\Rightarrow a.(b-c)=0 \nb-c=0\\, \\, {\\rm or}\\, \\, a \\bot (b-c) \\Rightarrow b=c",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31155": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1 ",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinite",
                "question_text": "The number of solutions of the equations x + 4y - z= 0, 3x - 4y - z = 0,x - 3y + z = 0 equals:",
                "correct_ans": "1 ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38465": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{1}{4}",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{7}{2}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{3}{4}",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{4}{3}",
                "question_text": "The area enclosed by the axis of x and the curve\u00a0y = x^{2} - 10x + 24\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{4}{3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36801": {
                "ans1": "even powers of x\u22122",
                "ans2": "odd powers of x\u22122",
                "ans3": "even powers of x",
                "ans4": "odd powers of x",
                "question_text": "The polynomial symmetric about the line\u00a0x=2 is a sum of multiples of :",
                "correct_ans": "even powers of x\u22122",
                "explanation": "x=2, f(x-2) = f(-(x-2))(x-2)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31586": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "e",
                "ans3": "1/e",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "\\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { e ^ { \\sin x } - 1 } { x } =",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{align} lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { e ^ { \\sin x } - 1 } { x } & = \\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { e ^ { \\sin x } - 1 } { \\sin x } \\times \\cfrac { \\sin x } { x } \\\\ & = \\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { e ^ { \\sin x } - 1 } { \\sin x } \\times \\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { \\sin x } { x } = 1 \\times 1 = 1 \\end{align}ORUsing L-Hopital Rule:\\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { e ^ { \\sin x } - 1 } { x } = \\lim _ { x \\rightarrow 0 } \\cfrac { \\cos x e ^ { \\sin x } } { 1 } = 1 . e ^ { 0 } = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39690": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The number of tangents to the parabola\u00a0y^2\u00a0= 4x through (9, 6) is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39722": {
                "ans1": "\\mathbb {R}",
                "ans2": "\\{-1, 1\\}",
                "ans3": "[-1,1 ] ",
                "ans4": " [ -\\cfrac{\\pi}{2}, \\cfrac{\\pi}{2} ] ",
                "question_text": "The domain of\u00a0\\sin^{-1} x\u00a0is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "[-1,1 ] ",
                "explanation": "\\sin^{-1} x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32803": {
                "ans1": "ax^2-2hxy+by^2=0",
                "ans2": "bx^2-2hxy+ay^2=0",
                "ans3": "ax^2+2hxy-by^2=0",
                "ans4": "bx^2+2hxy-ay^2=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the lines through the origin and perpendicular to the lines represented by the equation\u00a0ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "bx^2-2hxy+ay^2=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31771": {
                "ans1": "2^9",
                "ans2": "9^2",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "12",
                "question_text": "Let A = {1, 2, 3}. Then, the total number of distinct relations that can be defined over A is:",
                "correct_ans": "2^9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38246": {
                "ans1": "3A",
                "ans2": "\u22123A",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{1}{3}A",
                "ans4": "A",
                "question_text": "A matrix\u00a0A\u00a0is defined as\u00a0A = \\left[ a_{ij} \\right]\u00a0such that\u00a0a_{ij} = (-1)^{i+j}\u00a0for all\u00a0i,j \\in {1,2,3}\u00a0. Then,\u00a0 A^2\u00a0=\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3A",
                "explanation": "A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & -1 & 1 \\\\ -1 & 1 & -1 \\\\ 1 & -1 & 1 \\end{pmatrix}A^2 = \\begin{pmatrix}1 & -1 & 1 \\\\ -1 & 1 & -1 \\\\ 1 & -1 & 1 \\end{pmatrix} \\times \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & -1 & 1 \\\\ -1 & 1 & -1 \\\\ 1 & -1 & 1 \\end{pmatrix}A^2 = \\begin{pmatrix} 3 & -3 & 3 \\\\ -3 & 3 & -3 \\\\ 3 & -3 & 3 \\end{pmatrix} = 3A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37543": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\left(\\cfrac{1 + i}{1 - i}\\right)^{m}\u00a0= 1 then m =\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33336": {
                "ans1": "x^{a+1} + \\cfrac{a^{x}}{log_{e}a}+ c",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{x^{a+1}}{a+1}+ a^{x} log_{e}a + c",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{x^{a+1}}{a+1} + \\cfrac{a^{x}}{log_{e}a} + c",
                "ans4": "x^{a+1} + a^{x+1} + c",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\int\\left(e^{a \\log_e x}+e^{x \\log_ea}\\right) d x=",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{x^{a+1}}{a+1} + \\cfrac{a^{x}}{log_{e}a} + c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39716": {
                "ans1": "5x+y+12z-23=0",
                "ans2": "5x+6y+2z-23=0",
                "ans3": "x+6y+2z-23=0",
                "ans4": "x+y+z-13=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the plane through the points (1, 2, 3), (-1, 4, 2) and (3, 1, 1) is",
                "correct_ans": "5x+6y+2z-23=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34912": {
                "ans1": "\u22122i",
                "ans2": "2i",
                "ans3": "\u22122i,\u22122i",
                "ans4": "2i,2i",
                "question_text": "The roots of the equation\u00a0ix^{2} -4x-4i=0\u00a0are\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\u22122i,\u22122i",
                "explanation": "We have;\u00a0ix^{2} -4x-4i=0 \\\\ \\Rightarrow x^{2} +4ix-4=0 \\quad \\left[ \\text{multiplying both sides by } -i \\right] \\\\ \\Rightarrow x^{2} +2ix+2ix-4=0 \\\\ \\Rightarrow (x+2i)(x+2i)=0 \\\\ \\Rightarrow x=-2i,\\, \\, -2i.\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38817": {
                "ans1": "log_{e} 2 ",
                "ans2": "log_{e} 3 ",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{1}{2} log_{e} 2",
                "ans4": "log_{e} 3 - 1",
                "question_text": "\\cfrac{1}{3} + \\cfrac{1}{3.3^{2}} + \\cfrac{1}{5.3^{5}} + \\cfrac{1}{7.3^{7}} + \u2026\u2026\u2026. + to \\infty",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{1}{2} log_{e} 2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33074": {
                "ans1": "{(0,\\infty)} - \\{2,4\\}",
                "ans2": "{(-\\infty,\\infty)} - \\{2,4\\}",
                "ans3": "{(0,\\infty)} - [2,4]",
                "ans4": "{[0,\\infty)} - \\ (2,4\\ )",
                "question_text": "The domain of\u00a0\u00a0f(x) = \\cfrac {x^2 - 6x + 5}{x^2 -6x + 8}\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "{(-\\infty,\\infty)} - \\{2,4\\}",
                "explanation": "f(x) = \\cfrac {x^2 - 6x + 5}{x^2 -6x + 8}f(x) = \\cfrac {x^2 - 6x + 5}{(x-2)(x-4)}{(-\\infty,\\infty)} - \\{2,4\\}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38487": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt{158}",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{160}",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{161}",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt{162}",
                "question_text": "If the position vectors of P and Q are\u00a0(i+3j-7k)\u00a0and\u00a0(5i-2j+4k),\u00a0then\u00a0|\\overrightarrow{PQ} |\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt{162}",
                "explanation": "\\overline{PQ}=(5-1)i+(-2-3)j+(4+7)k=4i-5j+11k|\\overline{PQ}|=\\sqrt{16+25+121} =\\sqrt{162} \\, .",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37470": {
                "ans1": "\\pm 6 ",
                "ans2": "\\pm 3",
                "ans3": "\\pm 8 ",
                "ans4": "\\pm 9 ",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\alpha\u00a0and\u00a0\\beta\u00a0are the roots of the equation\u00a0x^{2}\u00a0\u2013px +36 =0 then\u00a0\\alpha ^{2}\u00a0\u00a0+\u00a0\\beta ^{2}\u00a0=9, then p=\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\pm 9 ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36481": {
                "ans1": "4, \\pi/2",
                "ans2": "1, \\pi/3",
                "ans3": "2, 7\\pi/6",
                "ans4": "2, \\pi/6",
                "question_text": "The polar co-ordinates of the point \\left(\\sqrt{3}, 1\\right)\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "2, \\pi/6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39734": {
                "ans1": "Ellipse",
                "ans2": "Parabola",
                "ans3": "Hyperbola",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "The locus of a variable point whose distance from\u00a0( -2, 0) is\u00a0\\cfrac{2}{3}\u00a0\u00a0times its distance from the line x = -\\cfrac{9}{2}\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "Ellipse",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38458": {
                "ans1": "3100",
                "ans2": "3300",
                "ans3": "2900",
                "ans4": "1400",
                "question_text": "In a town of 10,000 families it was found that 40% family buy newspaper\u00a0A, 20% buy newspaper\u00a0B\u00a0\u00a0and 10% families buy newspaper\u00a0C, 5% families buy\u00a0A\u00a0\u00a0and\u00a0B, 3% buy\u00a0B\u00a0and\u00a0C\u00a0\u00a0and 4% buy\u00a0A\u00a0Aand\u00a0C. If 2% families buy all the three newspapers, then number of families which buy\u00a0A\u00a0\u00a0only is",
                "correct_ans": "3300",
                "explanation": "n(A) = 0.4 \\times 10,000 = 4000 \\\\ n(B) = 0.2 \\times 10,000 = 2000 \\\\ n(C) = 0.1 \\times 10,000 = 1000 \\\\ n( A \\cap B ) = 0.05 \\times 10,000 = 500 \\\\ n(B \\cap C) = 0.03 \\times 10,000 = 300 \\\\ n(A \\cap C) = 0.04 \\times 10,000 = 400 \\\\ n(A \\cap B \\cap C) = 0.02 \\times 10,000 = 200Also, the number of people who buy only A isn(A_o) = n(A) - n(A \\cap B) - n(A \\cap C) + n(A \\cap B \\cap C)n(A_o) = 4000 - 500 - 400 + 200 = 3300\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37758": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "The number of spheres of a given radius R and touching the co-ordinate planes is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36352": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "3 or 5",
                "ans3": "5 or 7",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "If 8cr\u00a0- 7c3 = 7c2 , then r =",
                "correct_ans": "3 or 5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34098": {
                "ans1": "A\u2212B",
                "ans2": "A+B",
                "ans3": "2A",
                "ans4": "2B",
                "question_text": "If the sum of\u00a0n\u00a0terms of an A.P. is\u00a0nA+n^{2} B\u00a0where\u00a0A,B are constants, then its common difference will be",
                "correct_ans": "2B",
                "explanation": "Given:S_n = An + Bn^2 \\\\ \\Rightarrow S_{n-1} = A(n-1) + B(n-1)^2S_n - S_{n-1} = t_n = A(n - n + 1) + B( n^2 - (n-1)^2)\\Rightarrow t_n = A + B(2n-1) \\\\ \\Rightarrow t_n = (A+B) + (n-1)(2B)a = A+B\\, , \\, d = 2B",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33697": {
                "ans1": "2e",
                "ans2": "3e",
                "ans3": "3e\u22121",
                "ans4": "e",
                "question_text": "\\cfrac{1\\, .\\, 2}{1\\, !} +\\cfrac{2\\, .\\, 3}{2\\, !} +\\cfrac{3\\, .\\, 4}{3\\, !} +\\cfrac{4\\, .\\, 5}{4\\, !} +.....\\infty =",
                "correct_ans": "3e",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{1\\, .\\, 2}{1\\, !} +\\cfrac{2\\, .\\, 3}{2\\, !} +\\cfrac{3\\, .\\, 4}{3\\, !} +\\cfrac{4\\, .\\, 5}{4\\, !} +.....\\infty =T_{n} =\\cfrac{n(n+1)}{n\\; !} =\\cfrac{n+1}{(n-1)\\; !} =\\cfrac{(n-1)+2}{(n-1)\\; !}=\\cfrac{1}{(n-2)\\; !} +\\cfrac{2}{(n-1)\\; !}=e+2e=3e.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33202": {
                "ans1": "\\theta =2n\\pi",
                "ans2": "\\theta =\\cfrac{2n\\pi }{p\\pm q}",
                "ans3": "\\theta =\\cfrac{n\\pi }{p+q}",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\cos p\\theta =\\cos q\\theta ,p\\ne q\u00a0then\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\theta =\\cfrac{2n\\pi }{p\\pm q}",
                "explanation": "\\cos p\\theta =\\cos q\\theta \\Rightarrow p\\theta =2n\\pi \\pm q\\theta \\Rightarrow \\theta =\\cfrac{2n\\pi }{p\\pm q}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38263": {
                "ans1": "n \\pi \\pm \\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans2": "2 n \\pi \\pm \\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans3": "n \\pi+(-1)^{n} \\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans4": "n \\pi+\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "question_text": "If tan\\theta  + tan(\\pi /2 -\\theta)\u00a0= 2, then general values of\u00a0\\theta\u00a0=\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "n \\pi+\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33494": {
                "ans1": "(2, 4)",
                "ans2": "(1, 5)",
                "ans3": "(6, 2)",
                "ans4": "(-1, 3)",
                "question_text": "If the Ortho-centre and centroid of a triangle are (-3, 5) and (3, 3) respectively, then its circum-centre is:",
                "correct_ans": "(6, 2)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30636": {
                "ans1": "x = -y",
                "ans2": "x = y",
                "ans3": "x >y"
            },
            "31308": {
                "ans1": "equilateral",
                "ans2": "isosceles",
                "ans3": "rt. angled isosceles",
                "ans4": "scalene",
                "question_text": "If the position vectors of vertices A, B, C of\u00a0\\Delta ABC\u00a0\u00a0are\u00a0( 7\u200b\u200b\u200b\u200b \\overset{{\\rightarrow }}{j} +10 \\overset{{\\rightarrow }}{k} )\u00a0and\u00a0\\overset{{\\rightarrow }}{i}\u00a0+\u00a06\\overset{{\\rightarrow }}{j}\u00a0+\u00a06\\overset{{\\rightarrow }}{k}\u00a0, then the triangle is",
                "correct_ans": "rt. angled isosceles",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39143": {
                "ans1": "y\\left[\\cfrac{6 x+10}{2 x+3}+3 \\log (2 x+3)\\right]",
                "ans2": "y[(3 x+5) \\cdot(2 x+1)+\\log (3 x+5)]",
                "ans3": "y\\left(\\cfrac{3 x+2}{4 x+5}+\\cfrac{\\log (2 x+3)}{2}\\right)",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "The derivative of\u00a0\u00a0y=(2 x+3)^{3 x+5}\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "y\\left[\\cfrac{6 x+10}{2 x+3}+3 \\log (2 x+3)\\right]",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34208": {
                "ans1": "a parabola",
                "ans2": "an ellipse",
                "ans3": "a pour line",
                "ans4": "a circle",
                "question_text": "Whatever may be the value of\u00a0\\alpha, the locus of point of intersection of the lines\u00a0x \\cos \\alpha+y \\sin \\alpha=a\u00a0and\u00a0x \\sin \\alpha-\u00a0ycos\\alpha=b\u00a0\u00a0is a:",
                "correct_ans": "a circle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38554": {
                "ans1": "45",
                "ans2": "75",
                "ans3": "90",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "In how many ways can 10 balls be divided between two boys, one receiving two and the other eight balls?",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "\\cfrac{10\\; !}{2\\; !\\; 8\\; !} =45\\cfrac{10\\; !}{8\\; !\\; 2\\; !} =45\\therefore",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37600": {
                "ans1": "5 and 4",
                "ans2": "5 and -4",
                "ans3": "-5 and 4",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0x\u00a0is real, then value of the expression\u00a0\\cfrac { x ^ { 2 } + 14 x + 9 } { x ^ { 2 } + 2 x + 3 }\u00a0lies between",
                "correct_ans": "-5 and 4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array} { l } { \\cfrac { x ^ { 2 } + 14 x + 9 } { x ^ { 2 } + 2 x + 3 } = y \\Rightarrow x ^ { 2 } + 14 x + 9 = x ^ { 2 } y + 2 x y + 3 y } \\\\ { \\Rightarrow x ^ { 2 } ( y - 1 ) + 2 x ( y - 7 ) + ( 3 y - 9 ) = 0 } \\\\ { \\text { since } x \\text { is real, } \\therefore 4 ( y - 7 ) ^ { 2 } - 4 ( 3 y - 9 ) ( y - 1 ) > 0 } \\\\ { \\Rightarrow 4 \\left( y ^ { 2 } + 49 - 14 y \\right) - 4 \\left( 3 y ^ { 2 } + 9 - 12 y \\right) > 0 } \\\\ { \\Rightarrow 4 y ^ { 2 } + 196 - 56 y - 12 y ^ { 2 } - 36 + 48 y > 0 } \\\\ { \\Rightarrow 8 y ^ { 2 } + 8 y - 160 < 0 \\Rightarrow y ^ { 2 } + y - 20 < 0 } \\\\ { \\Rightarrow ( y + 5 ) ( y - 4 ) < 0 } \\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38816": {
                "ans1": "0^0",
                "ans2": "45^0",
                "ans3": "90^0",
                "ans4": "180^0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow a=-7\\overrightarrow b\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow c=8\\overrightarrow b\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow b\u00a0is non zero vector then angle between\u00a0\\overrightarrow a\u00a0and\u00a0\u00a0\\overrightarrow c\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "180^0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39970": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(\\frac23\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\frac32\\right)",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{3^x-2^x}x=",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\frac32\\right)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33123": {
                "ans1": " \\frac1{1-x^2}",
                "ans2": "-\\frac1{1-x^2}",
                "ans3": " \\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": " -\\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "question_text": "Derivative of \\cos^{-1}x with respect to x is",
                "correct_ans": " -\\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32164": {
                "ans1": "4:5",
                "ans2": "5:4",
                "ans3": "4:3",
                "ans4": "3:4",
                "question_text": "Two numbers a and b having ratio of HM to GM 4:5. The value of\u00a0\\frac{a+b}{2\\sqrt{ab}} is",
                "correct_ans": "5:4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30052": {
                "ans1": "secx tanx + c  ",
                "ans2": "tanx + secx = c   ",
                "ans3": "tanx \u2013 secx +c   ",
                "ans4": "sinx + cosx + c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{(1-\\sin x)}=",
                "correct_ans": "tanx + secx = c   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35624": {
                "ans1": "\\overrightarrow{AD}=\\frac{\\overrightarrow{AB}+\\overrightarrow{AC}}2",
                "ans2": "\\overrightarrow{AD}=\\frac{\\overrightarrow{AB}-\\overrightarrow{AC}}2",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow{AD}=\\overrightarrow{AB}+\\overrightarrow{AC}",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow{AD}=\\overrightarrow{AB}-\\overrightarrow{AC}",
                "question_text": "If D is the midpoint of BC in \u0394ABC then which of the following is true?",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow{AD}=\\frac{\\overrightarrow{AB}+\\overrightarrow{AC}}2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39452": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1/e",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "e/e-1",
                "question_text": "x\\xrightarrow{lim}0^{(1-x)^\\frac1x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1/e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38910": {
                "ans1": "(0,\u00b13)     ",
                "ans2": "(\u00b13  ,0)   ",
                "ans3": "(0, \u00b12\u221a3  )    ",
                "ans4": "(\u00b12\u221a3,0)",
                "question_text": "The vertices of conic described by 3x^2-4y^2=36\\; is",
                "correct_ans": "(\u00b12\u221a3,0)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34577": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "infinite",
                "question_text": "The number of solutions of equation sinx + cosx = 2 are",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39714": {
                "ans1": "(3, \u221e)   ",
                "ans2": "(-3, \u221e)   ",
                "ans3": "[-3, \u221e)   ",
                "ans4": "[3, \u221e)",
                "question_text": "The range of the function f(x)=x^2-4x+7\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "[3, \u221e)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35175": {
                "ans1": "A",
                "ans2": "B",
                "ans3": "A \ua4f5 B   ",
                "ans4": "\u0278",
                "question_text": "B U (A \ua4f5 B) =",
                "correct_ans": "B",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33015": {
                "ans1": "a^2-9a+10=0\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "a^2+9a+18=0\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "a^2+9a-18=0\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "a^2-9a-10=0\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "In \u0394ABC, \u2220B= 30^0\\;\n , b=3 and c=3\\sqrt3\u00a0then which of the following is correct?",
                "correct_ans": "a^2-9a+10=0\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32507": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4i",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "2\u221a5",
                "question_text": "\\sqrt{(5+12i)}+\\sqrt{(5-12i)}=",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35330": {
                "ans1": "  1/2sin3x + c   ",
                "ans2": "\u221a2/3sin3x + c    ",
                "ans3": "2/\u221a3 sin3x+c    ",
                "ans4": "\u221a( 2/3)sin3x + c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\sqrt{1+\\cos6x}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2/3sin3x + c    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32798": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "If f\u2019\u2019(x)= \\frac{x^2}5 then degree of f(x) is",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35926": {
                "ans1": "\u2220A  ",
                "ans2": "\u2220C",
                "ans3": "45^0",
                "ans4": "90^0",
                "question_text": "In \u0394ABC, bcosC = ccosB, then \u2220B=",
                "correct_ans": "\u2220C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38361": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3    ",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\u221a3/2     ",
                "ans4": "1/\u221a3",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow a,\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;\\&\\;\\overrightarrow c\u00a0are perpendicular unit vector then \\vert\\overrightarrow a+\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;+\\;\\overrightarrow c\\vert=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34535": {
                "ans1": "4x^3-3x\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "3x^3-4x\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "12x^2-3\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "12x^2-3x\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "Derivative of cos\u00a03(\\cos^{-1}x) with respect to x is",
                "correct_ans": "12x^2-3\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31933": {
                "ans1": "(6,-3, 3)   ",
                "ans2": "(7,4,8)  ",
                "ans3": "(6,-12, 12)  ",
                "ans4": "(-6,-12,12)",
                "question_text": "The distance of point \u2018P\u2019 from origin is 6 and direction cosines of line OP are 1, -2 and 2. The coordinates of point \u2018P\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "(6,-12, 12)  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34071": {
                "ans1": "row matrix   ",
                "ans2": "column matrix   ",
                "ans3": "symmetric matrix  ",
                "ans4": "square matrix",
                "question_text": "In a matrix, i=j then it is",
                "correct_ans": "square matrix",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31566": {
                "ans1": "A \u2229 B",
                "ans2": "A U B",
                "ans3": "A",
                "ans4": "complimet of B",
                "question_text": "For any two sets A and B , (A-B)U(B-A)U(A\u00a0\u2229B) is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "A U B",
                "explanation": "Draw from vendiagram",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33371": {
                "ans1": "Family of concentric circles ",
                "ans2": "family of parabola with same vertex",
                "ans3": "family of parallel lines with slope 1",
                "ans4": "an empty locus",
                "question_text": "If the absissa and a ordinate of a oint increase at the same rate , then the locus of the point represents\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "family of parallel lines with slope 1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{dy}{dt}=\\frac{dx}{dt}\\rightarrow dy=dx\\;integrate,\\\\\\int dy\\;=\\int dx\\;\\rightarrow y=x\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32162": {
                "ans1": "\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b=0",
                "ans2": "\\overrightarrow a\\times\\overrightarrow b=0",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a\\;and\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;are\\;collinear",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow a\\;=\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\overrightarrow aand\\overrightarrow bare\\;unit\\;vectors,\\;then\\;which\\;one\\;of\\;the\\;following\\;is\\;true?\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a\\;=\\;\\overrightarrow b\\;",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\vert\\;\\overrightarrow a\\vert=\\vert\\;\\overrightarrow b\\vert\\;=1\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31961": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\pi x^2}2-x+c\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac\\pi2x-\\frac{x^2}2+c\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "cosec x + c",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac1{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}+c\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int\\sin^{-1}(\\cos\\;x)dx\\;equals\\;to\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac\\pi2x-\\frac{x^2}2+c\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int\\sin^{-1}(\\sin\\;\\left(\\frac\\pi2-x\\right))dx\\;=\\int\\left(\\frac\\pi2-x\\right)dx\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac\\pi2x-\\frac{x^2}2+c\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34988": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\left|x\\right|\\leqslant3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\left|x\\right|<3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\left|x\\right|\\geq3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\left|x\\right|>3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lbrack3,\\infty)U(-\\infty,-3\\rbrack\\;is\\;the\\;slution\\;set\\;for\\;the\\;inequality\\;:\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\left|x\\right|\\geq3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lbrack3,\\infty)U(-\\infty,-3\\rbrack\\Rightarrow\\left|x\\right|\\geq3\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39010": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans2": "n\\pi+\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans3": "n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans4": "2n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi3",
                "question_text": "The\\;general\\;solution\\;of\\;3\\cos ec^2x-4=0\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}3\\;\\cos ec^2x=4\\rightarrow\\sin^2x=\\frac34=\\sin^2\\frac\\pi3\\\\therefore,\\;x=n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi3\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36439": {
                "ans1": "\\cos^{-1}\\frac12",
                "ans2": "\\cos^{-1}\\frac13",
                "ans3": "\\cos^{-1}\\frac1{\\sqrt3}",
                "ans4": "\\pi/3",
                "question_text": "The angle between diagonal of the cube is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\cos^{-1}\\frac13",
                "explanation": "\\cos^{-1}\\left(\\frac13\\right)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39781": {
                "ans1": "A/G",
                "ans2": "G/A",
                "ans3": "G^2/A",
                "ans4": "A^2/G",
                "question_text": "If the arthemetic and geometric mean of the two distinct positive numbers are A and G repectively then their harmonic mean is",
                "correct_ans": "G^2/A",
                "explanation": "G^2 =AH",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35932": {
                "ans1": "2:-3",
                "ans2": "3:2",
                "ans3": "4:1",
                "ans4": "3:1",
                "question_text": "The ratio in\u00a0which the\u00a0 line joining the point (1,-2,3) and (4,2,-1) is divided by xy plane is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3:1",
                "explanation": "Let the ratio be K:1\u00a0In xy plane , z=0k=3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35893": {
                "ans1": "\\left[-\\frac13,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans2": "\\left[0,\\frac13\\right]",
                "ans3": "[-1,1]",
                "ans4": "\\left[-1,\\frac13\\right]",
                "question_text": "The\\;range\\;of\\;the\\;function\\;f(x)=\\cos\\frac x3is",
                "correct_ans": "[-1,1]",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39665": {
                "ans1": "|x|=x",
                "ans2": "|x|=max{x,-x}",
                "ans3": "|x|=-x",
                "ans4": "|x|=min{x,-x}",
                "question_text": "For any real x ,",
                "correct_ans": "|x|=max{x,-x}",
                "explanation": "Obious",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36759": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "ans3": "\\frac12",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\cos^{-1}x-\\sin^{-1}x=\\frac\\pi6,\\;then\\;x\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\cos^{-1}x-\\sin^{-1}x=\\frac\\pi6\\\\or,\\frac\\pi2-2\\sin^{-1}x=\\frac\\pi6\\\\or,Sin^{-1}x=\\frac\\pi6\\\\or,x=1/2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35177": {
                "ans1": "{(-\\infty,\\infty) - \\{1,4\\}}",
                "ans2": "{(1,4)}",
                "ans3": "{(-\\infty,1] \\cup [4,\\infty)}",
                "ans4": "{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "question_text": "The domain of\u00a0f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {x^2-5x+4}}\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "explanation": "f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {x^2-5x+4}}f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {(x-1)(x-4)}}For denominator to be non-zero and square root to have positive content,\u00a0{(x-1)(x-4)} > 0From the table,\u00a0{(x-1)(x-4)} > 0\u00a0is satisfied for\u00a0x<1\u00a0and\u00a0x>4.{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35496": {
                "ans1": "doesn't exist",
                "ans2": "equals to 1",
                "ans3": "equals to -1",
                "ans4": "equals to 0",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0^-}\\frac{\\sin\\vert x\\vert}x=\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "equals to -1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0^-}\\frac{\\sin\\vert x\\vert}x=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0^-}\\frac{\\displaystyle\\sin(-x)}{\\displaystyle x}=-1\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35241": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/6",
                "question_text": "The angle between the planes 2x-y+z=6 and x+y+2z=7 is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/3",
                "explanation": "\\cos\\theta=\\frac{1(2)+1(-1)+2(1)}{\\sqrt{4+1+1}{\\displaystyle\\sqrt{1+1+4}}}=1/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31106": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{3+\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{3-\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac3{14}+\\frac{\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac3{14}-\\frac{\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\frac{1\\;}{3+\\sqrt5}\\;is\\;a\\;root\\;of\\;a\\;quadratic\\;equation\\;,\\;then\\;the\\;other\\;root\\;is\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{3-\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\frac{1\\;}{3+\\sqrt5}\\;=\\frac{3-\\sqrt5}{9-5}=\\frac34-\\frac{\\sqrt5}4\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37116": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "If the line 2x-3y+4+k(-x+y+5)=0 is horizontal ,then the value of k is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}slope\\;=-\\frac{2-k}{k-3}\\\\For\\;horizontal\\;line\\;,\\;slope=0\\\\so,\\;k=2\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31448": {
                "ans1": "only one solution",
                "ans2": "two solution ",
                "ans3": "infinitely many solution",
                "ans4": "no solution",
                "question_text": "The\\;equation\\;\\sqrt3\\sin\\;x\\;+\\;\\cos\\;x\\;=4\\;has",
                "correct_ans": "no solution",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}a=\\sqrt{3\\;,\\;b=1\\;,\\;c=4\\;}\\\\\\sqrt{a^2+b^2}=2\\\\\\vert c\\vert>\\sqrt{a^2+b^2}\\\\the\\;given\\;equation\\;has\\;no\\;solution\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32203": {
                "ans1": "point",
                "ans2": "pair of lines",
                "ans3": "sphere",
                "ans4": "a pair of planes",
                "question_text": "In a three dimensional xyz space the equation\u00a0x^2-5x+6=0\u00a0represents",
                "correct_ans": "a pair of planes",
                "explanation": "(x-2)(x-3)=0 represents a pair of parallel planes bith parallel to yz plane",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39312": {
                "ans1": "A^2\\;and\\;A^3\\;always\\;commute\\;for\\;multiplication",
                "ans2": "A\\;and\\;adj(A)\\;always\\;commute\\;for\\;multiplication",
                "ans3": "A\\;adj(A)\\;=\\vert A\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\left(A^T\\right)^{-1}=\\left(A^{-1}\\right)^T",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following is NOT true for a singular square matrix A?",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(A^T\\right)^{-1}=\\left(A^{-1}\\right)^T",
                "explanation": "For non singular , (d) is not true",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "37647": {
                "ans1": "a pair of perpendicular lines",
                "ans2": "a pair of parallel lines",
                "ans3": "a pair of coincident lines",
                "ans4": "a parabola",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}x^2-6xy+9y^2+4x-12y+4=0\\;represents\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "a pair of parallel lines",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}x^2-6xy+9y^2+4x-12y+4=0\\\\comparing\\;with\\;ax^2+2hxy+by^2+2yx+2fy+c=0\\\\then\\;a=1\\;b=9\\;h=-3\\\\h^2=ab\\\\represents\\;a\\;pair\\;of\\;parallel\\;lines\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38313": {
                "ans1": "64",
                "ans2": "124",
                "ans3": "258",
                "ans4": "512",
                "question_text": "The sum of the coefficients of even power of\u00a0x\u00a0in the expansion of\u00a0\\left( 1 + x + x ^ { 2 } + x ^ { 3 } \\right) ^ { 5 }\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "512",
                "explanation": "To find sum of coefiicients, put\u00a0x=1. And since the sum of odd and even coefficeints are equal, the required answer is:\\cfrac{4^5}{2} = 512OR1 + x + x^2 + x^3 = (1+x)(1+x^2)\\left( 1 + x + x ^ { 2 } + x ^ { 3 } \\right) ^ { 5 } = (1+x)^5 (1+x^2)^5\u00a0(1+5x + 10x^2 + 10x^3 + 5x^4 + x^5)(1 + 5 x ^ { 2 } + 10 x ^ { 4 } + 10 x ^ { 6 } + 5 x ^ { 8 } + x ^ { 10 } )2^5 = 3210 \\times 32 + 5 \\times 32 = 512",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "34157": {
                "ans1": "6sq. units",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{1}{6}",
                "ans3": "3 sq. units",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{1}{3}",
                "question_text": "Let y be the function which passes through (1, 2) and having slope (2x +1). The area bounded between the curve and X-axis is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{1}{6}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39405": {
                "ans1": "( - \\infty , \\infty )",
                "ans2": "[ - 2 , \\infty )",
                "ans3": "( - 2,3 )",
                "ans4": "( - \\infty , - 2 )",
                "question_text": "If the domain of function\u00a0f ( x ) = x ^ { 2 } - 6 x + 7\u00a0is\u00a0( - \\infty , \\infty ), then the range of function is",
                "correct_ans": "[ - 2 , \\infty )",
                "explanation": "x ^ { 2 } - 6 x + 7 = ( x - 3 ) ^ { 2 } - 2\\infty \\infty ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30822": {
                "ans1": "2n\\pi + \\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "ans2": "n \\pi+\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans3": "2n\\pi + \\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans4": "(2n+1) \\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "question_text": "The general solution of the trigonometric equation\u00a0sin\\pi = cos\\theta = \\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}is:",
                "correct_ans": "2n\\pi + \\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38503": {
                "ans1": "8 \\pi i",
                "ans2": "4 \\pi i",
                "ans3": "{ {\\pi i} \\over 2}",
                "ans4": "{ {\\pi i} \\over 4}",
                "question_text": "The period of\u00a0\\cosh ({\\theta \\over 4})\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "8 \\pi i",
                "explanation": "Note this:\\cosh x = \\cos (ix)\\sinh x = \\cfrac {\\sin (ix)} { i}\\cos (ax)8 \\pi iNOTE that, the period is always positive!",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35463": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "-2",
                "question_text": "If the system of equations x + 2y - 3z = 1, (k + 2) z = 4, (2k +1)y + z= 2 is inconsistent then P =",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38201": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "240",
                "ans3": "360",
                "ans4": "480",
                "question_text": "How many number plates of vehicles consisting of 4 different digits can be made out of integers 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6?",
                "correct_ans": "360",
                "explanation": "P(6,4)\u00a0= 6.5.4.3=360",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35200": {
                "ans1": "{(-\\infty,\\infty) - \\{1,4\\}}",
                "ans2": "{(1,4)}",
                "ans3": "{(-\\infty,1] \\cup [4,\\infty)}",
                "ans4": "{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "question_text": "The domain of\u00a0f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {x^2-5x+4}}\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "explanation": "f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {x^2-5x+4}}f(x) = \\cfrac {1}{\\sqrt {(x-1)(x-4)}}For denominator to be non-zero and square root to have positive content,\u00a0{(x-1)(x-4)} > 0From the table,\u00a0{(x-1)(x-4)} > 0\u00a0is satisfied for\u00a0x<1\u00a0and\u00a0x>4.{(-\\infty,1) \\cup (4,\\infty)}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32721": {
                "ans1": "45\\mathrm{{}^\\circ}",
                "ans2": "90\\mathrm{{}^\\circ}",
                "ans3": "15\\mathrm{{}^\\circ}",
                "ans4": "30\\mathrm{{}^\\circ}",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\u00a0 \\sin ^{-1} \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{3} }{2} \\right)-\\sin ^{-1} \\left(\\cfrac{1}{2} \\right)\u00a0is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "30\\mathrm{{}^\\circ}",
                "explanation": "\\sin ^{-1} \\left[\\cfrac{\\sqrt{3} }{2} \\right]-\\sin ^{-1} \\left[\\cfrac{1}{2} \\right]=60^{o} -30^{o} =30^{o}.\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36485": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "2n + 1",
                "ans4": "2n - 1",
                "question_text": "The number of terms whose value depends on x in the expansion of\u00a0 \\left(x^{2}-2+\\cfrac{1}{x^{2}}\\right)^{n}\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "2n",
                "explanation": "\\left(x^{2}-2+\\cfrac{1}{x^{2}}\\right)^{n}\n=\\left[\\left(x-\\cfrac{1}{x}\\right)^{2}\\right]^{n}Total no. of terms = (2n +1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31922": {
                "ans1": "e\\hat{}4",
                "ans2": "e\\hat{}5",
                "ans3": "e",
                "ans4": "e\\hat{}3",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\lim _{x \\rightarrow 0}\\left(\\cfrac{1+x}{1-3 x}\\right)^{\\cfrac{1}{x}}=",
                "correct_ans": "e\\hat{}4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{align} \\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\to 0} \\left(\\cfrac{1+x}{1-3x}\\right)^{1/x}} &= \\left( \\cfrac {\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\to 0}(1+x)^{1/x}}} {\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\to 0}(1-3x)^{1/x}}} \\right) \\\\&=\\cfrac{e^1}{e^{-3}}\\quad\\left(\\because\\,\\,\\displaystyle{\\lim_{x\\to 0} (1+ax)^{1/x}=e^a}\\right)\\\\ &=e^4 \\end{align}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38405": {
                "ans1": "11/2",
                "ans2": "9/2",
                "ans3": "7/2",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0P = \\left[ \\begin{array} { c c } { 1 } & { 3/2 } \\\\ { 1 } & {a - 3 } \\end{array} \\right] , Q = \\left[ \\begin{array} { c c } { 2 } & { 4 } \\\\ { 1 } & { - 1 } \\end{array} \\right]\u00a0and\u00a0|PQ| = |Q|\u00a0then\u00a0a =",
                "correct_ans": "11/2",
                "explanation": "Note that\u00a0|PQ| = |P||Q|\u00a0So,\u00a0|PQ| = |Q| \\Rightarrow |P| = 1\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix} 1 & 3/2 \\\\ 1 & (a-3) \\end{vmatrix} = 0 \\\\ \\Rightarrow a = 11/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38607": {
                "ans1": "(3, -7)",
                "ans2": "(4, 2) ",
                "ans3": "(2, -7)",
                "ans4": "(2, -5)",
                "question_text": "Two vertices of a triangle are (5, 9) and (-4, 1). Then, the 3rd vertex if the medians meet at (1, 1) is:",
                "correct_ans": "(2, -7)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "35009": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "1-1/e",
                "ans4": "1+1/e",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the curve\u00a0y=\\ln x, the x-axis and the straight line\u00a0x=e\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\ln x = 0 \\Rightarrow x = 1\\displaystyle \\therefore \\text{ Area }(A) = \\int_{1}^e ydx = \\int_1^e \\ln x dx \\\\ = [x \\ln x - x]_1^e \\\\ = (e \\ln e - e) - (0-1) \\\\ = e.1 - e+1 = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "38050": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "1/3",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "3/4",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\lim _{x \\rightarrow 0} \\cfrac{\\tan 2 x-x}{3 x-\\sin x}=",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30402": {
                "ans1": "e^2 + log2",
                "ans2": "e",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "Let f be the exponential function\u00a0e^x\u00a0and g be the logarithmic function log_{e}x\u00a0, then the value of (f + g) (1) =",
                "correct_ans": "e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36034": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac { 1 } { 3 }",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac { 3 } { 4 }",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac { 4 } { 3 }",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If the ratio of gradients of the lines represented by\u00a0a x ^ { 2 } + 2 h x y + b y ^ { 2 } = 0\u00a0is 1 : 3, then the value of the ratio\u00a0h ^ { 2 } : a b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac { 4 } { 3 }",
                "explanation": "m_1Then,m_1 + m_2-\\cfrac{2h}{b} = 4mSquaring the first equation and dividind by second,\\cfrac{4h^2}{ab}\\cfrac{h^2}{ab} = \\cfrac{4}{3}4h^2 \\lambda = ab (1 + \\lambda)^2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33484": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{3}",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\theta\u00a0is the angle between the planes represented by the equation\u00a0\\text{2x\\({}^{2}\\)}+\\text{y\\({}^{2}\\)}-\\text{3z\\({}^{2}\\)}+3xy-2yz-zx=0, then\u00a0\\theta\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "39896": {
                "ans1": "1: 2: 3",
                "ans2": "2: 3: 4",
                "ans3": "3: 4: 5",
                "ans4": "4: 5: 6",
                "question_text": "If the sides of a right angled traingle are in A.P., then the sides are proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "3: 4: 5",
                "explanation": "a-d,\\; a,\\; a+d(a+d)^{2} =a^{2} +(a-d)^{2}\\Rightarrow a^{2} +d^{2} +2ad=a^{2} +a^{2} -2ad+d^{2}\\Rightarrow a=4ds=a-d:a:a+d=(4d-d)\\; :\\; 4d:(4d+d)=3:4:5.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31367": {
                "ans1": "2e",
                "ans2": "3e",
                "ans3": "4e",
                "ans4": "e - 1",
                "question_text": "\\cfrac{1.2}{1!} + \\cfrac{2.3}{2!} + \\cfrac{3.4}{3!} + \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 + \\infty\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36819": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{1}{3} \\tan^{-1} \\left( \\cfrac{x^3+1}{2} \\right)+c",
                "ans2": "\\log_e \\left[ (x^3+1)-\\sqrt{x^6+2x^3+3} \\right] + c",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{1}{3} \\log_e \\left[ (x^3+1) + \\sqrt{x^6+2x^3+5} \\right]+c",
                "ans4": "\\sin^{-1} \\left( \\cfrac{x^3+1}{2} \\right)",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\int \\cfrac{x^2}{\\sqrt{x^6+2x^3+5}}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{1}{3} \\log_e \\left[ (x^3+1) + \\sqrt{x^6+2x^3+5} \\right]+c",
                "explanation": "x^3=t3x^2 dx=dtNow,\\begin{align} I & = \\cfrac{1}{3} \\int \\cfrac{dt}{\\sqrt{t^2+2t+5}} \\\\ & = \\cfrac{1}{3} \\int \\cfrac{dt}{\\sqrt{(t+1)^2+2^2}} \\\\ & = \\cfrac{1}{3} \\log \\left[ (t+1) + \\sqrt{(t+1)^2+2^2} \\right] \\\\ & = \\cfrac{1}{3} \\log \\left[ (x^3+1) + \\sqrt{x^6+2x^3+5} \\right] \\end{align}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33537": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac { - \\pi } { 2 } \\text { and } 1",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac { \\pi } { 2 } \\text { and } \\sqrt { 2 }",
                "ans3": "0 \\text { and } \\sqrt { 2 }",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac { \\pi } { 2 } \\text { and } 1",
                "question_text": "Argument and modulus of\u00a0\u00a0\\cfrac { 1 + i } { 1 - i }\u00a0are respectively",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac { \\pi } { 2 } \\text { and } 1",
                "explanation": "{ \\pi \\over 2}\u00a0 ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "30571": {
                "ans1": "4\\pi",
                "ans2": "\\pi",
                "ans3": "\\pi /2",
                "ans4": "2\\pi",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the curve y\u00a0 = \\sqrt{4 -x^{2}}\u00a0and the upper part of x-axis is:",
                "correct_ans": "2\\pi",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36940": {
                "ans1": "3 : 4 : 5",
                "ans2": "4 : 3 : 5",
                "ans3": "5 : 4 : 3",
                "ans4": "5 : 3 : 4",
                "question_text": "In\u00a0 \\Delta ABC, \\sin A = 4/5 \\space and \\space \\sin B = 3/5.\u00a0\u00a0Then, the sides of the triangle are proportional to",
                "correct_ans": "4 : 3 : 5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36236": {
                "ans1": "x",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{|x|}{x}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{1}{x}",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "\\cfrac{d}{d x}(\\log |x|)=\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{1}{x}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31916": {
                "ans1": "\\pi \\quad",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{3}",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}",
                "question_text": "The period of |sinx| + |cosx| is",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36710": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{\\left(sin^{-1}x\\right)^{2}}{2}+ c",
                "ans2": "- \\cfrac{2}{ \\sqrt{1- x^{2}}}+ c",
                "ans3": "- cot (sin^{-1}x) + c",
                "ans4": "cosec(sin^{-1}x) + c",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\int _{}^{ }{}\\cfrac{cosec^{2} \\left(sin^{-1}x\\right)}{\\sqrt{1- x^{2}}}dx=\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "- cot (sin^{-1}x) + c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31181": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{3}+\\theta",
                "ans2": "\\cfrac{\\pi}{4}+\\theta",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{7\\pi}{12}+\\theta",
                "ans4": "\\cfrac{3\\pi}{4}+\\theta",
                "question_text": "The argument of the complex number\u00a0z=(1+\\sqrt{3} i)(1+i)(\\cos \\theta+i \\sin \\theta)\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{7\\pi}{12}+\\theta",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33302": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The maximum number of normal that can be drawn from a point to a parabola is:",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "y = mx - am^3 - 2am",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36571": {
                "ans1": "e^{a-bx}",
                "ans2": "e^{a-bx} -1",
                "ans3": "1+a\\log _{e} (a-bx)",
                "ans4": "e^{-bx}",
                "question_text": "1+\\cfrac{a-bx}{1\\, !} +\\cfrac{(a-bx)^{2} }{2\\, !} +\\cfrac{(a-bx)^{3} }{3\\, !} +....\\infty =",
                "correct_ans": "e^{a-bx}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "36051": {
                "ans1": "x + y +z = xyz",
                "ans2": "xy + yz + zx = 1",
                "ans3": "x^{2} +y^{2} +z^{2} + 2xyz = 1",
                "ans4": "x^{2} +y^{2} + 2xy = 1",
                "question_text": "If sin^{-1}x + sin^{-1}y + sin^{-1}z= \\pi /2, then",
                "correct_ans": "x^{2} +y^{2} +z^{2} + 2xyz = 1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31095": {
                "ans1": "A.P.",
                "ans2": "G.P",
                "ans3": "H.P",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If a, b, c form one G.P. and\u00a0\\alpha, \\beta, \\gamma\u00a0another G.P., then\u00a0 \\cfrac{a}{\\alpha}, \\cfrac{b}{\\beta}, \\cfrac{c}{\\gamma}\u00a0form:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "G.P",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "31236": {
                "ans1": "\\cfrac{1}{8} (x^2-1) + c",
                "ans2": "2\\tan^{-1} \\sqrt{1+x}+c",
                "ans3": "\\cfrac{1}{4}(2x^2-1)+c",
                "ans4": "2\\sqrt{x} + 4 + c",
                "question_text": "\\displaystyle \\int \\cos \\left \\{ 2\\tan^{-1} \\sqrt{\\cfrac{1-x}{1+x}} \\right \\}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\cfrac{1}{4}(2x^2-1)+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "32523": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The differential coefficient of\u00a0\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{1+x^{2}}-1}{x}\\right)\u00a0with respect to\u00a0\u00a0\\tan ^{-1} x\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "y=\\tan^{-1} \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}-1}{x}\\right)x=\\tan \\thetay=\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{1+\\tan ^{2} \\theta}-1}{\\tan \\theta}\\right)=\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{\\sec \\theta-1}{\\tan \\theta}\\right)=\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{1-\\cos \\theta}{\\sin \\theta}\\right)=\\tan ^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{2 \\sin ^{2} \\theta / 2}{2 \\sin \\theta / 2 \\cos \\theta / 2}\\right)=\\tan ^{-1}(\\tan \\theta / 2)=\\theta / 2=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\tan ^{-1} xNow,\\cfrac{d \\tan ^{-1}(\\sqrt{1+x^{2}}-1)}{d \\tan ^{-1} x}=\\cfrac{1}{2} \\cfrac{d \\tan ^{-1} x}{d \\tan ^{-1} x}=\\cfrac{1}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "33940": {
                "ans1": "positive",
                "ans2": "negative",
                "ans3": "zero",
                "ans4": "infinity",
                "question_text": "Two lines\u00a0 \\text{L\\(_{1}\\)} \u00a0\u00a0and\u00a0\u00a0 \\text{L\\(_{2}\\)}\u00a0intersect. Then, the shortest distance between them is",
                "correct_ans": "zero",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        },
        "2": {
            "41267": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "-6",
                "question_text": "If the sum of n terms of an AP is\u00a03n^2+5n then its common difference is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44902": {
                "ans1": "3/5",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt5}",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "4/5",
                "question_text": "In an ellipse , the distance between the foci is 6 and its minor axis is 8. Then, the eccentricity is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3/5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43138": {
                "ans1": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac38",
                "ans2": "\\left|x\\right|<1",
                "ans3": "\\left|x\\right|>\\frac38",
                "ans4": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac43",
                "question_text": "The expansion of\u00a0 \\left(4-3x\\right)^{-\\frac35}\u00a0 \u00a0in terms od ascending powers of x is valid only if\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac43",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42972": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "16",
                "question_text": "If A is a matrix of order 3 X 3 and |A| =2 , then |adj. A| is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42493": {
                "ans1": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans2": "1/2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans3": "2n cos n\u03b8",
                "ans4": "n cos 2\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x}=2\\cos\\theta\\;then\\\\\\;x^n+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x^n}\\;is\\end{array}\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac1x=2\\cos\\theta\\;\\rightarrow\\left(x+\\frac1x\\right)^2=\\;4\\cos^2\\theta\\rightarrow x^2+\\frac1{x^2}=2(2\\cos^2\\theta-1)=2\\cos2\\theta\\\\x^n+\\frac1{x^n}=2\\cos n\\theta\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49766": {
                "ans1": "-3/2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "3/2",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\overrightarrow a,\\overrightarrow b,\\overrightarrow c\\;are\\;unit\\;vectors\\;\\\\such\\;that\\;\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow c=0\\;,\\\\\\;then\\;\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b.\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c.\\overrightarrow a\\end{array}\\\\\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "-3/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47396": {
                "ans1": "\\sin^{-1}x-\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans2": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans3": "\\sin^{-1}x-\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans4": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "question_text": "Value of\u00a0\\int\\sqrt{\\frac{1-x}{1+x}}dx is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40659": {
                "ans1": "x+y+z=0",
                "ans2": "17x+14y+11z=0",
                "ans3": "7x+4y+z=0",
                "ans4": "17x+14y+z=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the plane through the intersection of the planes x+2y+3z-4=0 and 4x+3y+2z+1=0 and passing through origin is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "17x+14y+11z=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45648": {
                "ans1": "15 sq. units",
                "ans2": "75 sq. units",
                "ans3": "8 sq. units",
                "ans4": "4\\sqrt2\\;square\\;units",
                "question_text": "The tangents are drawn from the point (5,4) to the circle\u00a0 x^2+y^2-4x-2y-11=0\u00a0. The area of quadletrial formed by these tangents and the radii at the point of contact is",
                "correct_ans": "4\\sqrt2\\;square\\;units",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49035": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The number of solutions of\u00a0\\log_4(x+1)=\\log_2(x-3)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44185": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "16",
                "question_text": "If the slope of one of the lines represented by\u00a0ax^2+10xy+y^2=0 is four times the slope of other , then a is",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42135": {
                "ans1": "3/2",
                "ans2": "3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "The area bound by the x axis and the curve\u00a0y=4x-x^2-3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "4/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43965": {
                "ans1": "abc",
                "ans2": "2abc",
                "ans3": "3abc",
                "ans4": "4abc",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}In\\;\\triangle ABC,\\;a(b^2+c^2)\\cos A\\;+\\\\\\;b(c^2+a^2)\\cos B\\;+\\\\\\;c(a^2+b^2)\\cos C\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "3abc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45653": {
                "ans1": "x=1 is a point of maximum",
                "ans2": "x=-1 is a point of minimum",
                "ans3": "maximum value > minimum value",
                "ans4": "maximum value< minimum value",
                "question_text": "For the function\u00a0y=x+\\frac1x",
                "correct_ans": "maximum value< minimum value",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44243": {
                "ans1": "5240",
                "ans2": "1440",
                "ans3": "2880",
                "ans4": "720",
                "question_text": "In how many ways 5 boys and 5 girls can be arranged alternately in a round table?",
                "correct_ans": "2880",
                "explanation": "otal ways = (5-1)! X 5! =2880",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41538": {
                "ans1": "729",
                "ans2": "512",
                "ans3": "256",
                "ans4": "128",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\left(2+5\\omega+2\\omega^2\\right)^6\u00a0equals",
                "correct_ans": "729",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41334": {
                "ans1": "4.6",
                "ans2": "2\\sqrt2,3\\sqrt2",
                "ans3": "2\\sqrt2,3\\sqrt5",
                "ans4": "2\\sqrt2,4\\sqrt3",
                "question_text": "The length of the intercept made by the circle\u00a0x^2 + y^2 +2x -4y-1 =0\u00a0represents mutually perpendicular straight lines is",
                "correct_ans": "2\\sqrt2,3\\sqrt5",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}length\\;of\\;intersept\\;on\\;the\\;x\\;axis\\;=2\\sqrt{g^2-c}\\\\and\\;on\\;y\\;axis\\;=2\\sqrt{f^2-c}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43562": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "Let f(x+y) = f(x) f(y) for all x,y; suppose f(5)=2,f'(0)=3 then f'(5) equals",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47535": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "x",
                "question_text": "If x = 2017! then the value of\u00a0\\frac1{\\log_2x}+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle\\log_3x}+......+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle\\log_{2017}x}",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac1{\\log_2x}+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle\\log_3x}+......+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle\\log_{2017}x}\\\\=\\log_x1.2.3.....2017\\\\=\\log_xx=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44606": {
                "ans1": "lm=an",
                "ans2": "lm^2=an",
                "ans3": "l^2n=am",
                "ans4": "\\ln=am^2",
                "question_text": "If the line lx+my+n=0 touches the parabola\u00a0y^2=4ax if",
                "correct_ans": "\\ln=am^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47151": {
                "ans1": "1/3",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-1/2",
                "question_text": "If the lines 2x+3ay-1=0 and 3x+4y+1=0 are mutually perpendicular then the value of a is",
                "correct_ans": "-1/2",
                "explanation": "product of slopes = -1so, a=-1/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42377": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/2",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/4",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;value\\;of\\\\\\;\\int_0^\\frac\\pi2\\frac{\\sqrt{cotx}}{\\sqrt{\\tan x}+\\sqrt{cotx}}\\operatorname dx\\;is\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44872": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "2n",
                "ans3": "2n+1",
                "ans4": "2n-1",
                "question_text": "The number of terms whose value depend on x in the expansion ofx^2-2+\\frac1{x^2}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "2n",
                "explanation": "Total no. of terms = 2n+1no. of independent of x =1no. of ters depend on x=2n+1-1=2n",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47408": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "80",
                "ans3": "60",
                "ans4": "45",
                "question_text": "The function\u00a0x^4-62x^2+ax+9\u00a0attains maximum value at x=1 then the value of a is",
                "correct_ans": "120",
                "explanation": "x^4-62x^2+ax+94x^3-124x+a12x^2-124xAs maximum value in f'(x) =0\u00a0 \u00a0at x =1\u00a0so, 4-124+a=0a=120",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46890": {
                "ans1": "\\tan^{-1}5x",
                "ans2": "\\tan^{-1}5x-\\tan^{-1}x",
                "ans3": "\\tan^{-1}2x",
                "ans4": "2\\tan^{-1}2x",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;y=\\tan^{-1}\\frac{4x}{1+5x^2}\\;\\\\then\\;y\\;equals\\end{array}\n",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan^{-1}5x-\\tan^{-1}x",
                "explanation": "\\tan^{-1}\\frac{5x-x}{1+5x.x}=\\tan^{-1}5x-\\tan^{-1}x",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41273": {
                "ans1": "16/3",
                "ans2": "32/3",
                "ans3": "64/3",
                "ans4": "128/3",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the parabola\u00a0y^2=x, the line y=4 and y axis is",
                "correct_ans": "64/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41742": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The value of a for which\u00a0ax^2 + 3xy -2y^2+6x+13y+c=0represents mutually perpendicular straight lines is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "coeff. of x^2 + coeff. of y^2 =0 i.e a-2=0 a=2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46553": {
                "ans1": "p^2=q^2+r^2",
                "ans2": "q^2=pr",
                "ans3": "r^2=p+q",
                "ans4": "p^2=r+q",
                "question_text": "The fourth,seventh and tenth terms of GP are p,g,r respectively then\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "q^2=pr",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48121": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43442": {
                "ans1": "\\frac12f'(x_o)",
                "ans2": "f'(x_o)",
                "ans3": "2f'(x_o)",
                "ans4": "f'(x_o)^2",
                "question_text": "If\\;f'(x_0)\\;exists,\\\\\\;then\\;\\lim_{\\triangle X\\rightarrow0}\\\\\\;\\;\\frac{f(x_0+\\triangle x)-f(x_0\\;-\\triangle x)}{2\\triangle x}\\;\\\\is\\;equal\\;to:",
                "correct_ans": "f'(x_o)",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\lim_{\\triangle X\\rightarrow0}\\;\\;\\frac{f(x_0+\\triangle x)-f(x_0\\;-\\triangle x)}{2\\triangle x}\\;\\\\=\\frac12\\left[\\;\\lim_{\\triangle X\\rightarrow0}\\;\\;\\frac{f(x_0+\\triangle x)-f(x_0)}{2\\triangle x}\\;+\\;\\lim_{\\triangle X\\rightarrow0}\\;\\;\\frac{f(x_0+\\triangle x)-f(x_0)}{-2\\triangle x}\\;\\right]\\\\=\\frac12\\lbrack f'(x_0)+f'(x_0)\\rbrack\\\\=f'(x_0)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40356": {
                "ans1": "g=c^2",
                "ans2": "f=c^2",
                "ans3": "f^2=c",
                "ans4": "g^2=c",
                "question_text": "The\\;circle\\\\\\;x^2+y^2+2gx\\;+\\;2fy+c=0\\;\\\\touches\\;x\\;axis\\;if:",
                "correct_ans": "g^2=c",
                "explanation": "x^2+y^2+2gx + 2fy+c=0......(i)2\\sqrt{g^2-c}Now, circle (i) touches x axis, if Length of intercept=0g^2=c\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40057": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\sqrt3}2",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{\\sqrt2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{\\sqrt3}",
                "question_text": "In the ellipse \\frac{x^2}{a^2}+\\frac{y^2}{b^2}=1\u00a0the angle between the lines joining the foci with the positive end\u00a0of minor axis is a right angle. Then the eccentricity of the ellipse is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{\\sqrt2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44490": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "If the radius of in circle of a triangle with its sides 5k, 6k and 5k is 6, then k is equal to:",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2s=\\;5k\\;+\\;6k+\\;5k=16k\\Rightarrow\\;s\\;=\\;8k\\;\\\\\\;Now,\\;r=\\;\\frac\\triangle s\\\\6=\\frac{\\sqrt{s(s-a)\\;(s-b)\\;(s-c)}}s\\;\\;\\\\5=\\frac{\\sqrt{8k.3k.2k.3k}}{8k}\\;\\Rightarrow k=4\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49114": {
                "ans1": "\\vert KA\\vert=K^n\\vert A\\vert",
                "ans2": "\\vert KA\\vert=K^{n-1}\\vert A\\vert",
                "ans3": "\\vert KA\\vert=nK\\vert A\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\vert KA\\vert=n^K\\vert A\\vert",
                "question_text": "If A is a square matrix of order n, then for scalar k",
                "correct_ans": "\\vert KA\\vert=K^n\\vert A\\vert",
                "explanation": "If we multiply a matrix A by a scalar k, then each element is k times the original. While finding determinant value of kA i.e. |kA|, we will take k common from every row of n different rows (or columns).kA=k.k.k....kAk\" |A|",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48042": {
                "ans1": "(-\\infty,\\infty)",
                "ans2": "(-1,1)U(1,\\infty)",
                "ans3": "(-\\infty,1)U(1,\\infty)",
                "ans4": "(-\\infty,1)U(-1,\\infty)",
                "question_text": "If\\;f(x)=\\frac x{1-x},x\u22601\\;then\\\\\\;the\\;range\\;of\\;f\\;is:",
                "correct_ans": "(-\\infty,1)U(-1,\\infty)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40631": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "5/3",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "1/3",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\triangle ABC,\\;\\angle C\\;is\\;right\\;angle.\\\\\\;The\\;maximum\\;\\;value\\;of\\\\\\;\\cos A.\\cos B\\;is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46465": {
                "ans1": "-\\sqrt{\\frac{x-1}{x+1}}+c",
                "ans2": "\\sqrt{\\frac{x-1}{x+1}}+c",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt{\\frac{x+1}{x-1}}+c",
                "ans4": "-\\sqrt{\\frac{x+1}{x-1}}+c",
                "question_text": "Value\\;of\\\\\\;\\int\\frac{dx}{(x-1)\\sqrt{x^2-1}}\\;equals:",
                "correct_ans": "-\\sqrt{\\frac{x+1}{x-1}}+c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}I=\\int\\frac{dx}{(x-1)\\sqrt{x^2-1}}\\\\=\\int\\frac{dx}{(x-1)^2\\sqrt{\\displaystyle\\frac{x+1}{x-1}}}\\\\Let\\;u=\\frac{x+1}{x-1}\\\\du=\\frac{(x-1).1-(x+1).1}{(x-1)^2}dx\\\\=\\frac{-2dx}{(x-1)^2}\\\\I=-\\frac12\\int\\frac{du}{\\sqrt u}=-\\sqrt u+c\\\\=\\sqrt{\\frac{x+1}{x-1}}+c\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42086": {
                "ans1": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt3",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "If P = (0, 1, 0) and Q = (0, 0, 1) be the given points, then the projection of PQ on the plane x+y+z=3 is:",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42647": {
                "ans1": "x^{-2}+y^{-2}=4p^{-2}",
                "ans2": "x^{-2}+y^{-2}=p^{-2}",
                "ans3": "x^2+y^2=4p^{-2}",
                "ans4": "x^2+y^2=p^2",
                "question_text": "The locus of the mid-point of the intercept of the line xcos\u03b1\u00a0+ ysin\u03b1\u00a0= p between the coordinates axes is:",
                "correct_ans": "x^{-2}+y^{-2}=4p^{-2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47174": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c=0",
                "ans2": "abc=1",
                "ans3": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "ans4": "a+b+c=1",
                "question_text": "If\\\\\\;a\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow{k,}\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow i+b\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k\\;and\\\\\\overrightarrow{\\;i}+\\overrightarrow j+c\\overrightarrow k\\;\\\\are\\;coplanar\\;then:",
                "correct_ans": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;the\\;given\\;vectors\\;are\\;coplanar,\\;then\\;\\;\\\\\\begin{vmatrix}a&1&1\\\\1&b&1\\\\1&1&c\\end{vmatrix}\\;\\;=0\\\\a(bc-1)\\times-1(c-1)+(1-b)=0\\;\\\\abc-a-c+1+1-b=0\\;\\\\\\Rightarrow a+b+c=abc\\;+2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45494": {
                "ans1": "180",
                "ans2": "90",
                "ans3": "48",
                "ans4": "24",
                "question_text": "The number of ways in which a mixed double tennis game be organized between 10 players consisting of 6 men and 4 women is:",
                "correct_ans": "180",
                "explanation": "If\\;2\\;men\\;and\\;2\\;women\\;are\\;selected\\;at\\;a\\;time,\\;2\\;mixed\\;double\\;game\\;can\\;be\\;organized.\\;So\\;total\\;number\\;of\\;ways\\;=\\;2\\times C(6,\\;2)\\;\\times C\\;(4,\\;2)\\;=180",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41611": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}6",
                "ans2": "\\frac{n(n+1)}3",
                "ans3": "\\frac{n(n^2+1)}4",
                "ans4": "\\frac{n(n^2+3)}2",
                "question_text": "The\\;n^{th}\\;term\\;of\\;the\\;series\\\\\\;1^2+\\;(1^2+2^2)+(1^2+\\;2^2+3^2)+\\\\....\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}6",
                "explanation": "(1^2+\\;2^2+3^2)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43423": {
                "ans1": "4/3",
                "ans2": "5/3",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "1/3",
                "question_text": "Area\\;bounded\\;by\\;parabola\\;\\\\y^2=x\\;and\\;straight\\;line\\\\\\;2y=x\\;in\\;square\\;unit\\;is:",
                "correct_ans": "4/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}y^2=x\\;\\&\\;2y\\;=\\;x\\;we\\;get\\;\\;\\\\y^2\\;=\\;2y\\;\\;\\\\y(y-2)=0\\;\\\\y\\;=\\;0,\\;y\\;=\\;2\\;\\;\\\\Curves\\;intersect\\;at\\;(0,\\;0)\\;and\\;(4,\\;2)\\\\A=\\int_0^4\\left(\\sqrt x-x/2\\right)dx=\\left[\\frac23x^\\frac32-\\frac{x^2}4\\right]_0^4\\\\=\\left(\\frac{16}3-4\\right)=4/3\\;sq.\\;unit\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49924": {
                "ans1": "r=13",
                "ans2": "r=14",
                "ans3": "r=15",
                "ans4": "r=16",
                "question_text": "In\\;the\\;expansion\\;of\\\\\\;(1+x)^{43},\\;the\\;coefficients\\\\\\;of\\;(2r\\;+\\;1)^{th}\\;and\\;\\\\(r\\;+\\;2)^{th}\\;terms\\;are\\;equal\\\\.\\;Then:",
                "correct_ans": "r=14",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48480": {
                "ans1": "(0.1]",
                "ans2": "[0,1]",
                "ans3": "(-\u221e,0]",
                "ans4": "(-\u221e,1)",
                "question_text": "The domain of definition if the function given by\u00a02^x+2^y=2 is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "(-\u221e,1)",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2^y=2-2^x\\\\2-2^x>0\\\\2^x<2\\\\x<1\\\\x=(-\\infty,1)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42539": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{x^2}2-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "ans3": "x^2+\\ln(x^2+1)+c",
                "ans4": "x^2-\\ln(x^2+1)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{(x^4+1)}{\\;(x^{\\;2}+1)}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46114": {
                "ans1": "1:2",
                "ans2": "2:1",
                "ans3": "\u221a2:1",
                "ans4": "1:\u221a2",
                "question_text": "The distance between the foci and distance between directrices of the hyperbola\u00a0\\frac{x^{2}}{a^{2}} - \\frac{y^{2}}{b^{2}} =1\u00a0 are in the ratio 3:2, then a:b is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47444": {
                "ans1": "0<\\alpha<\\beta",
                "ans2": "\\alpha<\\beta<0",
                "ans3": "0<\\alpha<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\alpha<0<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\alpha\\;and\\;\\beta\\;(\\alpha<\\beta)\\;are\\;the\\\\\\;roots\\;of\\;the\\;equation\\\\\\;x^2+bx+c=0\\;\\\\where\\;c<0<b\\;then",
                "correct_ans": "\\alpha<0<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "explanation": "put method:put: b=1 , c= -2 [c<0<b]then find the roots of the equation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42986": {
                "ans1": " 15",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "31",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In an examination, a candidate has to pass in each of the 5 subjects. In how many ways can he fail?",
                "correct_ans": "31",
                "explanation": "Total no. of ways by which he fails will be C(5,1)+C(5,2)+C(5,3)+C(5,4)+C(5,5)=31",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46285": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "A line makes angle \u03b1, \u03b2, \u03b3 with x-axis, y-axis and z-axis respectively then cos 2\u03b1 + cos 2\u03b2 + cos 2\u03b3 is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46684": {
                "ans1": "4\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "3\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "2\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "ABCD is a parallelogram with AC and BD as diagonals then\u00a0\\vec{AC}-\\vec{BD}\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "2\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49530": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c=0",
                "ans2": "abc=1",
                "ans3": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "ans4": "a+b+c=1",
                "question_text": "If\\\\\\;a\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow{k,}\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow i+b\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k\\;and\\\\\\overrightarrow{\\;i}+\\overrightarrow j+c\\overrightarrow k\\;\\\\are\\;coplanar\\;then:",
                "correct_ans": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;the\\;given\\;vectors\\;are\\;coplanar,\\;then\\;\\;\\\\\\begin{vmatrix}a&1&1\\\\1&b&1\\\\1&1&c\\end{vmatrix}\\;\\;=0\\\\a(bc-1)\\times-1(c-1)+(1-b)=0\\;\\\\abc-a-c+1+1-b=0\\;\\\\\\Rightarrow a+b+c=abc\\;+2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45717": {
                "ans1": " 1/2",
                "ans2": "\u221a3/2",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "\u221a2/3",
                "question_text": "If the latus rectum of an ellipse be equal to half of its minor axis, then its eccentricity is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44756": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "1/(xy)",
                "ans3": "1/(2y-x)",
                "ans4": "1/(2y-1)",
                "question_text": ".If\u00a0y=\\sqrt{(x+\\sqrt{(x+\\sqrt{(x+.....)))}}} \\; then\u00a0dy/dx=",
                "correct_ans": "1/(2y-1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47577": {
                "ans1": "(1,\u221e)",
                "ans2": "(0,\u221e)",
                "ans3": " (0,1]",
                "ans4": "(0.5,1)",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function\u00a0\\sqrt{(\\log_{0.5}(x))} is",
                "correct_ans": " (0,1]",
                "explanation": "log0.5\u200b(x)\u22650andx>0thenx\u22641andx>0;sodomain=(0,1]",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44377": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "n(n+1)/2",
                "ans3": "\\left(\\frac{n(n+1)}2\\right)^2",
                "ans4": "n(n+1)(2n+1)/6",
                "question_text": "Sum of the series 1 + (3 + 5) + (7 + 9 + 11) + ..... to n terms is",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(\\frac{n(n+1)}2\\right)^2",
                "explanation": "Sn\u200b=1+(3+5)+(7+9+11)+....\u00a0to n1^{3}+2^{3}+....",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49381": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "-23",
                "question_text": "If the line 2x+y+k=0 is normal to parabola\u00a0y^{2}=-8x\u00a0 then value of k is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41056": {
                "ans1": "sin(2\u03b1)",
                "ans2": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "ans3": "cos(2\u03b1)",
                "ans4": "cot(2\u03b1)",
                "question_text": "If \u00a0tan(\u03b1)=\\sqrt{a}\u200b\u00a0where a is a positive rational number and is not a perfect square then which of the following is a rational number?",
                "correct_ans": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46574": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "-3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If the normal to the curve y=f(x) at the point (3,4) makes an angle 3\u03c0/4 with +ve x-axis then f'(3)=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}slope\\;of\\;normal=-\\frac1{f'(x)}=\\tan\\frac{3\\pi}4=-1\\\\f'(x)=1\\\\f'(3)=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43832": {
                "ans1": "st. line",
                "ans2": "parabola",
                "ans3": "circle",
                "ans4": "ellipse",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0z = x + iy = (k+3) + i \\sqrt{(5-k^2)}\u200b, then the locus of z is",
                "correct_ans": "circle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45719": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "-2",
                "question_text": "The sum of the slopes of the lines x^2 + kxy -3y^2 = 0 \u00a0is twice the product of the slopes, then k =",
                "correct_ans": "-2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46828": {
                "ans1": "\u221a2 -1",
                "ans2": "2\u221a2-1",
                "ans3": "2(\u221a2-1)",
                "ans4": "2(\u221a2+1)",
                "question_text": "Area of the region bounded by\u00a0y = sin x, y = cos x, x =0 and x=\u03c0/2\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "2(\u221a2-1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45767": {
                "ans1": "\u221a3",
                "ans2": "2\u221a3",
                "ans3": "\u221a2",
                "ans4": "6\u221a3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The projection of a line segment joining two end points (1,2,3) and (3,4,5) on a line with dc's 1/\u221a3, 1/\u221a3, 1/\u221a3 is",
                "correct_ans": "2\u221a3",
                "explanation": " (x_2-x_1)l + (y_2-y_1)m + (z_2-z_1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45626": {
                "ans1": "a^3\\left(1-\\frac2a\\right)",
                "ans2": "a^3\\left(1+\\frac3a\\right)",
                "ans3": "a^3\\left(1-\\frac3a\\right)",
                "ans4": "a^3\\left(1+\\frac2a\\right)",
                "question_text": "The value of the determinant\u00a0\\begin{vmatrix}1+a&1&1\\\\1&1+a&1\\\\1&1&1+a\\end{vmatrix}",
                "correct_ans": "a^3\\left(1+\\frac3a\\right)",
                "explanation": "Perform matrix operations.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45320": {
                "ans1": "R-{3,3}",
                "ans2": " {-3,3}",
                "ans3": " (-3,3)",
                "ans4": "{-3,3}",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function f : R\\rightarrowR by\u00a0h(x)=1/\\sqrt{9-x^2}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": " (-3,3)",
                "explanation": "Here, function f is defined; when\u00a09-x^2>0so\u00a0-3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42917": {
                "ans1": "sin(2\u03b1)",
                "ans2": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "ans3": "cos(2\u03b1)",
                "ans4": "cot(2\u03b1)",
                "question_text": "If \u00a0tan(\u03b1)=\\sqrt{a}\u200b\u00a0where a is a positive rational number and is not a perfect square then which of the following is a rational number?",
                "correct_ans": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43885": {
                "ans1": "672/x^{\\;\\;3}",
                "ans2": "673/x^{\\;\\;3}",
                "ans3": "672/x^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans4": "673/x^{\\;\\;2}",
                "question_text": "The fourth term from the end in the expansion of\u00a0 (x^3/2-2/x^2)^9 is",
                "correct_ans": "672/x^{\\;\\;3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41646": {
                "ans1": "x<3",
                "ans2": "x>1/3",
                "ans3": " x<1/3",
                "ans4": "x>3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the sum of the series\u00a01 + \\dfrac{3}{x} + \\dfrac{9}{x^2} + \\dfrac{27}{x^3} + \u2026\u2026\u2026, ,x>0\u00a0is a finite number, then",
                "correct_ans": "x>3",
                "explanation": "Sum will be finite when |r|<1 i.e, 3/x <1 \\implies x>3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40301": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "If a,b and c are in A.P. then\u00a0\\frac{(a-c)^2}{(b^2-ac)}=",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41819": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "If roots of a quadratic equation\u00a0x^2 - bx + c = 0\u00a0are two consecutive integers then\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0b^2 -4c=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43801": {
                "ans1": "\\frac xa+\\frac yb-\\frac zc=0",
                "ans2": "\\frac xa-\\frac yb+\\frac zc=0",
                "ans3": "\\frac xa+\\frac yb+\\frac zc=0",
                "ans4": "\\frac xa-\\frac yb-\\frac zc=0",
                "question_text": "If from the point P(a,b,c) perpendicular PL, PM be drawn to YOZ and ZOX planes, then the equation of the plane OLM is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac xa+\\frac yb-\\frac zc=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46220": {
                "ans1": " (1, 0)",
                "ans2": "(0, 1)",
                "ans3": "(-1, 0)",
                "ans4": "(0,-1)",
                "question_text": "The point of intersection of tangents at the end points of the latus-rectum of the parabola\u00a0 y^2 = 4x is equal to:",
                "correct_ans": "(-1, 0)",
                "explanation": "Equation of tangent is\u00a0yy_1 = 2a(x+x_1)\u00a0and a = 1Coordinates of end points of the latus rectum are: A(1,2) and B(1,-2)So, Equation of tangent at A(1,2) is: 2y = 2(x+1)Equation of tangent at B(1,-2) is: -2y = 2(x+1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44348": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "3/2",
                "ans3": "-3/2",
                "ans4": "-3",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\;\\overrightarrow a,\\overrightarrow b\\;and\\overrightarrow{\\;c\\;} are unit vectors such that\u00a0\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow c=0 then the value of\u00a0\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b\\;+\\;\\overrightarrow b.\\overrightarrow c\\;+\\overrightarrow c.\\overrightarrow a equals :",
                "correct_ans": "-3/2",
                "explanation": "Here,\u00a0(a + b + c). (a + b + c) = 0a^2 + b^2 + c^2 + 2( a. b + b. c + c. a) =03 + 2(a.b + b.c + c.a) = 0a.b + b.c + c.a = -3/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43783": {
                "ans1": "2\u03c0/3",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0+2",
                "ans4": "\u03c0-2",
                "question_text": "The perimeter of certain sector of a circle equal to the length of the arc of semi-circle. Then angle at the centre of sector in radians are",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0-2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Asgiven,2r+l=\\frac12(2\\pi r)\\\\Hence\\frac lr=\\pi-2\\\\Since\\frac lr=\\theta;hence\\theta=\\pi-2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48152": {
                "ans1": "-2",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a,b,c are in AP then the sum of coefficient of\u00a0\u00a0(1+( ax^2 -2bx + c))^{10}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "a,b,c are in AP\u00a0=> 2b = a + c => a-2b+c=0putting\u00a0x=1 ,\u00a0 required sum\u00a0= ( 1+a-2b+c)^{10} = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46842": {
                "ans1": "-1/\u221a3",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "\u221e",
                "question_text": "For the curve\u00a0\u00a0x = t^2 - 1, y = t^2 - t\u00a0,\u00a0the tangent line is perpendicular to x-axis where\u00a0t =",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40967": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "1-1/e",
                "ans4": "1+1/e",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the curve y=ln(x), the x-axis and straight line\u00a0x=e is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45349": {
                "ans1": "(\u2212\u221e,0)",
                "ans2": "(\u2212\u221e,0]",
                "ans3": "(\u2212\u221e,-1)",
                "ans4": "(\u2212\u221e,\u221e)",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function\u00a0\u00a0y= \\dfrac{1}{\\sqrt{|x|-x}}\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "(\u2212\u221e,0)",
                "explanation": "For it must be \u2223x\u2223\u2212x>0=>\u2223x\u2223>xBut\u00a0|x|=x for x positive and \u2223x\u2223>x\u00a0for x negativehence, Domain =\u00a0(-\u221e,0)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40041": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "a",
                "ans3": "b",
                "ans4": "a+b",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If H.M. between a and b be H, then\u00a0\u00a0\\dfrac{(H+a)}{(H-a)} + \\dfrac{(H+b)}{(H-b)} =",
                "correct_ans": "a",
                "explanation": "Take\u00a0a = 2, b=8 then\u00a0H=3.2 Now put the values.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44496": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "16",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "If a function\u00a0f(x)=x^2 + \\dfrac{a}{x}\u200b\u00a0has a local minimum at\u00a0x=2 , then a=",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41889": {
                "ans1": "n2^{n-1}",
                "ans2": "n2^n",
                "ans3": "(n+1)2^{n-1}",
                "ans4": "(n-1)2^{n-1}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0(1+x)^n = C_0 + C_1x + C_2x^2 + \u2026. + C_nx^n then\u00a0C_1+2C_2+3C_3+\u2026+nC_n =",
                "correct_ans": "n2^{n-1}",
                "explanation": "Differentiate and put x=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45961": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "\u221a3",
                "ans4": "\u221a2",
                "question_text": "In \u2206 ABC if\u00a03a = b+c then\u00a0cot \\dfrac{B}{2} cot \\dfrac{C}{2} =",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "Use formula.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49941": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0 \u200b/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "ans4": "\u03c0 \u200b/6",
                "question_text": "The eccentric angle of point on the ellipse\u00a0x^2 + 3y^2 = 6\u00a0which is at a distance 2 from its centre is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42830": {
                "ans1": " g^2=c",
                "ans2": " f^2=c",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "xy",
                "question_text": "If the circle\u00a0x^2 + y^2 + 2gx + 2fy + c = 0 touches x-axis, then",
                "correct_ans": " g^2=c",
                "explanation": "Radius =\u2223y\u00a0co-ordinate\u00a0of\u00a0centre\u2223\\sqrt{(g^2+f^2-c)}g^2 =c\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43033": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "If a,b, and c are unit vectors, then\u00a0\u00a0|(a-b)|^2+|(b-c)|^2+|(c-a)|^2\u00a0 do not exceed",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41738": {
                "ans1": "20",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "40",
                "ans4": "60",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If 5 parallel straight lines are intersected by 4 parallel straight lines, then the number of parallelograms, thus formed is",
                "correct_ans": "60",
                "explanation": "No. of parallelograms=C(5,2)\u00d7C(4,2)=60",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45751": {
                "ans1": "(0,10)",
                "ans2": "(-5,5)",
                "ans3": "(-10,10)",
                "ans4": " (-20,20)",
                "question_text": "If the line 3x+4y+k=0\u00a0cuts the circle\u00a0x^2+y^2=4\u00a0at two distinct points, then k lies in",
                "correct_ans": "(-10,10)",
                "explanation": "\u22235k\u200b\u2223<2\u2223k\u2223<10-10<k<10k\u03f5(\u221210,10)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47628": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "-2",
                "question_text": "A line makes angles\u00a0\\dfrac{\u03b1}{2},\\dfrac{\u03b2}{2},\\dfrac{\u03b3}{2}\u200b\u00a0with the positive direction of coordinate axes, then\u00a0cos\u03b1+cos\u03b2+cos\u03b3\u00a0 is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49883": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0/3",
                "ans4": "\u03c0/2",
                "question_text": "Value of\u00a0\u00a0\\int_{0}^{\\pi/2} \\dfrac{\\sin x}{(\\sin x+\\cos x)} dx\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41920": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}",
                "ans2": "(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "ans3": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "ans4": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}+\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "question_text": "The general solution of \u221a3cosx + sinx = \u221a2is",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\sqrt3\\cos x+\\sin x}{\\sqrt{\\left(\\sqrt3\\right)^2+1^2}}\\times\\sqrt{\\left(\\sqrt3\\right)^2+1^2}=\\sqrt2\\\\or,\\;\\frac{\\sqrt3}2\\cos x+\\frac12\\sin x=\\frac1{\\sqrt2}\\\\or,\\;\\sin\\left(x+\\frac\\pi3\\right)=\\sin\\frac\\pi4\\\\or,\\;\\left(x+\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\right)=n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}\\\\x=n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41530": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "13",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of (2x+y+8z)^4 are",
                "correct_ans": "15",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}No.\\;of\\;terms={}^{m+n+1}C_{m-1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;={}^{3+4+1}C_{3-1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;={}^6C_2\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{6!}{(6-4)!2!}=15\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41592": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45727": {
                "ans1": "e^{a^2}+e^{b^2}",
                "ans2": "e^a+e^b",
                "ans3": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "ans4": "e^a-e^b",
                "question_text": "(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{a^4-b^4}{2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{a^6-b^6}{3!}\\right)+..........=",
                "correct_ans": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^4-b^4}{\\displaystyle2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^6-b^6}{\\displaystyle3!}\\right)+..........\\\\=\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^2}{\\displaystyle1!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle a^4}{\\displaystyle2!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle a^6}{\\displaystyle3!}+......\\right)-\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle b^2}{\\displaystyle1!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle b^4}{\\displaystyle2!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle b^6}{\\displaystyle3!}+......\\right)\\\\=(e^{a^2}-1)-(e^{b^2}-1)\\\\=e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45481": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{\\sin^4x}4+\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "question_text": "\\int(\\sin x\\cos x)^3dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46633": {
                "ans1": "3/2",
                "ans2": "3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "The area bound by the x axis and the curve\u00a0y=4x-x^2-3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "4/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49399": {
                "ans1": "\u221a2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "2 sq. units  ",
                "ans3": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "\u221a3/2 units",
                "question_text": "If a=2 and \\frac a{\\cos A}=\\frac b{\\cos{\\displaystyle B}}=\\frac c{\\cos{\\displaystyle C}} then area of \u0394ABC is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac a{\\cos A}\\;=\\frac b{\\cos B}=\\frac c{\\cos C}.........(1)\\\\Also\\;in\\;\\triangle ABC,\\frac a{\\sin A}\\;=\\frac b{sinB}=\\frac c{\\sin C}.........(2)\\;\\\\dividing\\;(1)\\;by\\;(2)\\\\\\tan\\;A\\;=\\;\\tan\\;B\\;=\\;\\tan\\;C\\;\\Rightarrow\\;A=\\;B\\;=\\;C\\;(equilateral\\;triangle)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43558": {
                "ans1": "c/b",
                "ans2": "b/c",
                "ans3": "a/b",
                "ans4": "b/a",
                "question_text": "\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=",
                "correct_ans": "b/c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=\\frac{c-a\\times{\\displaystyle\\frac{a^2+c^2-b^2}{2ac}}}{b-a\\times\\frac{a^2+b^2-c^2}{2ab}}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{\\frac{2c^2-a^2-c^2+b^2}c}{\\frac{2b^2-a^2-b^2+c^2}b}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{c^2+b^2-a^2}c\\times\\frac b{c^2+b^2-a^2}=\\frac bc\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46927": {
                "ans1": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans2": "1/2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans3": "2n cos n\u03b8",
                "ans4": "n cos 2\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x}=2\\cos\\theta\\;then\\\\\\;x^n+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x^n}\\;is\\end{array}\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac1x=2\\cos\\theta\\;\\rightarrow\\left(x+\\frac1x\\right)^2=\\;4\\cos^2\\theta\\rightarrow x^2+\\frac1{x^2}=2(2\\cos^2\\theta-1)=2\\cos2\\theta\\\\x^n+\\frac1{x^n}=2\\cos n\\theta\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48501": {
                "ans1": "4 sq. units ",
                "ans2": "10 sq. units ",
                "ans3": "25/2 sq. units ",
                "ans4": "25/4 sq. units ",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by curve y=2x-4, y=1 and y-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "25/4 sq. units ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40734": {
                "ans1": "9/4",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "1/4",
                "ans4": "1/8",
                "question_text": "The sum of all terms of geometric sequence is equals to 5/4 times the sum of all odd terms of the following series. The common ratio of series is",
                "correct_ans": "1/4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;series\\;is:\\;a,\\;ar,\\;ar^2,\\;ar^3,\\;ar^4,\\;ar^5.....\\;\\\\sum\\;of\\;series=\\frac54\\times(sum\\;ofa,ar^2,ar^4....)\\;\\\\or,\\;\\frac a{1-r}=\\frac54\\times\\frac a{1-r^2}\\\\or,\\;4r\u00b2-5r\\;+\\;1\\;=\\;0\\;\\\\or,\\;(4r-1)\\;(r-1)=0\\;\\\\either,\\;4r-1=0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;r\\;=\\;\\frac14\\;\\\\or,\\;r-1=0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;r=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48509": {
                "ans1": "5h^2=ab",
                "ans2": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "ans3": "9h^2=5ab    ",
                "ans4": "h^2=ab",
                "question_text": "If slope of one line represented by ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is five times the slope of another line then",
                "correct_ans": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}m_1\\;=\\;5m_2\\;\\;\\\\Now,\\;sum\\;of\\;slopes=\\frac{2h}{\\boldsymbol\\;b}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;m_1+\\;m_2\\;=-\\frac{2h}{\\;b}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;5m\u2082\\;+\\;m\u2082\\;=\\;-\\frac{2h}b\\;\\Rightarrow m\u2082\\;=\\;-\\frac h{3b}\\\\also,\\;product\\;of\\;roots=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;m_1m_2=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;5m_2^2=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;5\\times\\left(-\\frac5{3b}\\right)^2=\\frac ab\\\\i.e.\\;5h^2=9ab\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40031": {
                "ans1": "-330m^2",
                "ans2": "-330m^5",
                "ans3": "330m^7",
                "ans4": "-330m^7",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of\u00a0x^{-3}  in the expansion of \\left(x-\\frac mx\\right)^{11} is",
                "correct_ans": "-330m^7",
                "explanation": "For\\;coeff.\\;of\\;x^{-3}\\;in\\;the\\;expansion\\;of\\;\\left(x^1-\\frac m{x^1}\\right)^{11}:\\\\r=\\frac{n\\alpha-m}{\\alpha+\\beta}=\\frac{11\\ast1-(-3)}{1+1}=7\\\\Now,\\;term=\\;t_{7+1}={}^{11}C_7\\;x^{11-7}\\;\\left(-\\frac mx\\right)^7\\\\So,\\;coeff.\\;of\\;x^{-3}=-330m^7",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48796": {
                "ans1": "20 cm^2/2",
                "ans2": "40 cm^2/2",
                "ans3": "60 cm^2/s",
                "ans4": "80 cm^2/s",
                "question_text": "The length of a square is increasing at 6 cm/s. The rate of increase of area when the length of square is 5 cm/s",
                "correct_ans": "60 cm^2/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}A=l^2\\\\\\frac{dA}{dt}=\\frac{dl^2}{dt}=2l\\frac{dl}{dt}\\;\\;\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2\\times5\\times6\\;=60\\;cm\u00b2/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46602": {
                "ans1": "scalene",
                "ans2": "isosceles ",
                "ans3": "equilateral",
                "ans4": "right angle",
                "question_text": "If semi perimeter is equal to ex-radius\u00a0 of a triangle is",
                "correct_ans": "right angle",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}semi\\;perimeter=ex-radius\\;\\\\or,\\;s=r_1\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;s=\\frac\\triangle{s-a}\\;\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;s(s-a)=\\sqrt{s(s-a)\\;(s-b)\\;(s-c)}\\;\\\\or,\\;\\;\\sqrt{\\frac{(s-b)\\;(s-c)\\;}{s\\;(s-a)}}=1\\;\\\\or,\\;\\;\\;\\tan\\left(\\frac A2\\right)=\\tan\\left(\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}4\\right)\\;\\;\\\\ie.\\;A\\;=\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2\\;i.e.\\;right\\;angle\\;triangle\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48118": {
                "ans1": "2\u0394",
                "ans2": "\u0394",
                "ans3": "4\u0394",
                "ans4": "\u0394/2",
                "question_text": "If the area of \u0394ABC\u00a0is\u00a0\u0394\u00a0then,\u00a0a^2\\sin{(2B)} + b^2\\sin{(2A)} =",
                "correct_ans": "4\u0394",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45056": {
                "ans1": " [-3, 3)",
                "ans2": "(\u22123,3)",
                "ans3": " (-3, 3]",
                "ans4": "[\u22123,3]",
                "question_text": "The domain of\u00a0f(x) =\\sqrt{9-x^2}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "[\u22123,3]",
                "explanation": "9\u2212x^2\u22650\u27f6 \u22123\u2264x\u22643",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48565": {
                "ans1": "(n+2)\\times2^{n-1}",
                "ans2": "(n+1)\\times2^n",
                "ans3": "(n+1)\\times2^{n-1}",
                "ans4": "(n+2)\\times2^n",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(1 + x)^n = C_0 + C_1x + C_2x^2 + .... + C_nx^n, then the value of\u00a0C_0+2C_1+3C_2 + .... + (n+1)C_n\u200b\u00a0will be:",
                "correct_ans": "(n+1)\\times2^n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41806": {
                "ans1": "(5,5)",
                "ans2": "(5,10)",
                "ans3": "(10,10)",
                "ans4": " (10,5)",
                "question_text": "The pole of the straight line\u00a0x+2y=1 with respect to circle\u00a0x^2+y^2=5\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "(5,10)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40222": {
                "ans1": "\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "ans2": "3\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/6",
                "ans4": "\u03c0 \u200b/3",
                "question_text": "The two angles of a triangle are\u00a0\\cot^{-1}2\u00a0and\u00a0\\cot^{-1}3 then the third angle is",
                "correct_ans": "3\u03c0 \u200b/4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40137": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "\u221a3",
                "ans4": "1/\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If\u00a04\\sin^{-1}x+\\cos^{-1}x=\\pi\u00a0, then\u00a0x\u00a0equals",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "4sin\u22121x+cos\u22121x=\u03c0;or, 4\\sin^{-1}x+ \\dfrac{\\pi}{2} - \\sin^{-1}x=\\piHence, \\sin^{-1}x=\\dfrac{\\pi}{6}so, x=\\dfrac{1}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40130": {
                "ans1": "ab+gh=0",
                "ans2": "h^2-ab=0",
                "ans3": "ah+bg=0",
                "ans4": "ag+bh=0",
                "question_text": "If the pair of straight lines represented by\u00a0ax^2+ 2hxy-ay^2 = 0 and\u00a0bx^2 + 2gxy - by^2 = 0 be such that each bisects the angles between the other then",
                "correct_ans": "ab+gh=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45103": {
                "ans1": "10/3",
                "ans2": "20/3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The area of the triangle formed by the lines\u00a04x^2 \u2013 9xy \u2013 9y^2 = 0 and\u00a0x = 2\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "10/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41551": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "1/4",
                "ans3": "3/4",
                "ans4": "5/4",
                "question_text": "Let\u00a0x\u00a0be a number which exceeds its square by a greatest possible quantity. Then\u00a0x\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45749": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "36",
                "ans4": "49",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the y-axis, the curve\u00a0x^2=4(y-2) and the line\u00a0y = 11 is",
                "correct_ans": "36",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42823": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "If a line segment subtends angles\u00a0a, b, c with three dimensional coordinate axes respectively then\u00a0\\cos {2a} + \\cos {2b} + \\cos{2c} =",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "cos2\u03b1+cos2\u03b2+cos2\u03b3= 2 \\cos^2 \\alpha - 1 + 2 \\cos^2 \\beta - 1 + 2 \\cos^2 \\gamma - 1= 2 (\\cos^2 \\alpha + \\cos^2 \\beta + \\cos^2 \\gamma) - 3= - 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43614": {
                "ans1": "x^2-x+6=0",
                "ans2": "x^2-6x-6=0",
                "ans3": "x^2-x-13=0",
                "ans4": "x^2-x-6=0",
                "question_text": "The sum of roots of quadratic equation is\u00a01\u00a0and sum of their squares is\u00a013. Then the equation is",
                "correct_ans": "x^2-x-6=0",
                "explanation": "x1\u200b+x2\u200b=1;x1^2\u200b+x2^2\u200b=13so(x1\u200b+x2\u200b)^2\u22122x1\u200b\u2217x2\u200b=13x1\u200b\u2217x2\u200b=\u22126",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48392": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "2e",
                "ans3": "e/3",
                "ans4": "e/2",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\infty}\\left(\\frac{x+3}{x+4}\\right)^x",
                "correct_ans": "e",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44386": {
                "ans1": "x^2+y^2+2x+4y=10",
                "ans2": "x^2+y^2-2x+4y=10",
                "ans3": "x^2+y^2+2x-4y=10",
                "ans4": "x^2+y^2-2x-4y=10",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0a,b,c are in\u00a0A.P. then, the line\u00a0ax+by+c = 0\u00a0\u00a0is normal to the circle",
                "correct_ans": "x^2+y^2-2x+4y=10",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44743": {
                "ans1": "-1/2",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0y = \\tan^{-1}\\sqrt{\\dfrac{1+\\cos x}{1-\\cos x}} then,\u00a0\\dfrac{\\mathrm{d}y }{\\mathrm{d} x}\u200b=",
                "correct_ans": "-1/2",
                "explanation": "\u00a0\\dfrac{1+\\cos x}{1-\\cos x}=\\cot {\\dfrac{x}{2}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47330": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\cos\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2y-1}{\\cos\\;x}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2y-1}{\\sin\\;x}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sin\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "question_text": "If y =\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+........}}}then dy/dx =",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\cos\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47914": {
                "ans1": "(\u2212\u221e,e)",
                "ans2": "(0,e)",
                "ans3": "(0,2e)",
                "ans4": "(1/e,2e)",
                "question_text": "The function f(x)=lnx/x is increasing in the interval",
                "correct_ans": "(0,e)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43101": {
                "ans1": " (4, 9)",
                "ans2": "(9, 4)",
                "ans3": "(1,2\\sqrt3)",
                "ans4": "(3,4)",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is the point of intersection of perpendicular tangents to the ellipse 9x^2\u00a0+ 4y^2\u00a0= 36?",
                "correct_ans": "(1,2\\sqrt3)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47076": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "50",
                "ans3": "5\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If projection of any line on coordinate axes are 3,4, and 5 then its length is",
                "correct_ans": "5\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41362": {
                "ans1": "(5,5)",
                "ans2": "(5,10)",
                "ans3": "(10,10)",
                "ans4": " (10,5)",
                "question_text": "The pole of the straight line\u00a0x+2y=1 with respect to circle\u00a0x^2+y^2=5\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "(5,10)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46878": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "36",
                "ans4": "49",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the y-axis, the curve\u00a0x^2=4(y-2) and the line\u00a0y = 11 is",
                "correct_ans": "36",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45145": {
                "ans1": " also unit vectors",
                "ans2": "of equal magnitude",
                "ans3": "collinear",
                "ans4": "perpendicular",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0are unit vectors then \u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0+\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0\u2013\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "perpendicular",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46776": {
                "ans1": "1/3 sq. unit",
                "ans2": "1/6 sq. unit",
                "ans3": "2/3 sq. unit",
                "ans4": "1 sq. unit",
                "question_text": "The area of the region bounded by\u00a0y^2= x, y= |x|\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "1/6 sq. unit",
                "explanation": "Area\u00a0=\\int_{0}^{1}{\\sqrt{x}-x}\\text{ d}x= \\dfrac{1}{6} \\text{ sq. unit}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41483": {
                "ans1": " ln |sin3x| + ln |sin2x| + ln |sinx| + c",
                "ans2": " ln |sec3x|. ln |sec2x| .ln |secx| + c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec\\;3x\\vert)}3-\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec2x\\vert)}2-\\log\\vert secx\\vert+c",
                "ans4": "both a and c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\tan\\;x.\\tan\\;2x.\\tan\\;3x\\;dx\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\;",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec\\;3x\\vert)}3-\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec2x\\vert)}2-\\log\\vert secx\\vert+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49285": {
                "ans1": "2\u0394",
                "ans2": "\u0394",
                "ans3": "4\u0394",
                "ans4": "\u0394/2",
                "question_text": "If the area of \u0394ABC\u00a0is\u00a0\u0394\u00a0then,\u00a0a^2\\sin{(2B)} + b^2\\sin{(2A)} =",
                "correct_ans": "4\u0394",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46361": {
                "ans1": "(-1,-1)",
                "ans2": "(0,-1)",
                "ans3": "(1,1)",
                "ans4": "(-1,0)",
                "question_text": "The circumcentre of a triangle formed by the lines xy + 2x + 2y + 4 = 0 and x + y + 2 = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "(-1,-1)",
                "explanation": "xy + 2x + 2y + 4 = 0 .......(i)\nx+y+ 2 = 0...............(ii)\nFrom (i) & (ii),\nxy=0 = x=0, y = 0In rt. angeled triangle circumcentre is the midpoint of the hypotenuse, hence circumcentre=(-1,-1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47207": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "60\u00b0",
                "ans3": "90\u00b0",
                "ans4": "45\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In a\u00a0\u0394\u00a0ABC, a = 2b and A = 3B, then the angle A is:",
                "correct_ans": "90\u00b0",
                "explanation": "Here,\u00a0a = 2bsinA = 2sinB2sinB = sin(3B)2sinB - 3sinB + 4sin^3B = 0sinB(1 - 4sin^2B) = 0sinB = \\dfrac{1}{2}B = 30\u00b0A = 3 \\times 30\u00b0= 90",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49838": {
                "ans1": "tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans2": "1/2 tan(x/2) - log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans3": "-tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans4": "sin x + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "question_text": "\\frac d{dx}x\\log(1+\\cos x)=",
                "correct_ans": "-tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47665": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1/4",
                "ans3": "1/3",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\log\\;2\\;-\\frac{\\log^22}{2!}+\\frac{\\log^32}{3!}-.....\\infty=",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49731": {
                "ans1": "\\tan\\frac x2+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}4+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}2+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}8+c",
                "question_text": "\u222b(1\u2212cosx+cos^2x\u2212cos^3x+..........)dx, for \u00a0|cos x| \\neq 1, is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan\\frac x2+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48760": {
                "ans1": "c/b   ",
                "ans2": "b/c   ",
                "ans3": "a/b   ",
                "ans4": "b/a",
                "question_text": "\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=",
                "correct_ans": "b/c   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47777": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi2",
                "ans2": "(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4+\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans3": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4-\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans4": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4+\\frac\\pi3",
                "question_text": "The general solution of \\sqrt3cosx + sinx =\\sqrt2 is",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4-\\frac\\pi3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47029": {
                "ans1": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans2": "\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans3": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}-e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans4": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}-e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{e^x-1}{e^x+1}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40457": {
                "ans1": "\u221a2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "2 sq. units     ",
                "ans3": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "\u221a3/2 units",
                "question_text": "If a=2 and \\frac a{\\cos A}=\\frac b{\\cos{\\displaystyle B}}=\\frac c{\\cos{\\displaystyle C}} then area of \u0394ABC is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40378": {
                "ans1": "e^{a^2}+e^{b^2}",
                "ans2": "e^a+e^b",
                "ans3": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "ans4": "e^a-e^b",
                "question_text": "(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{a^4-b^4}{2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{a^6-b^6}{3!}\\right)+..........=",
                "correct_ans": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48235": {
                "ans1": "4 sq. units    ",
                "ans2": "10 sq. units    ",
                "ans3": "25/2 sq. units    ",
                "ans4": "25/4 sq. units",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by curve y=2x-4, y=1 and y-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "25/4 sq. units",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47590": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "13",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of (2x+y+8z)^4 are",
                "correct_ans": "15",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47352": {
                "ans1": "5h^2=ab",
                "ans2": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "ans3": "9h^2=5ab    ",
                "ans4": "h^2=ab",
                "question_text": "If slope of one line represented by ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is five times the slope of another line then",
                "correct_ans": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45814": {
                "ans1": "20 cm^2/2",
                "ans2": "40 cm^2/2",
                "ans3": "60 cm^2/s",
                "ans4": "80 cm^2/s",
                "question_text": "The length of a square is increasing at 6 cm/s. The rate of increase of area when the length of square is 5 cm/s",
                "correct_ans": "60 cm^2/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43041": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "ans2": " -\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{1+x^2}x+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x}}x+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2\\sqrt{1+x^2}}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40825": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41445": {
                "ans1": "300m^2",
                "ans2": "-300 m^5",
                "ans3": "330m^7",
                "ans4": "-330m^7",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of x^{-3} in the expansion of \\left(x-\\frac mx\\right)^{11} is",
                "correct_ans": "-330m^7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44760": {
                "ans1": "scalene",
                "ans2": "isosceles",
                "ans3": " equilateral   ",
                "ans4": "right angle",
                "question_text": "If semi perimeter is equal to ex-radius\u00a0 of a triangle is",
                "correct_ans": "right angle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44101": {
                "ans1": "9/4  ",
                "ans2": "\u00bd",
                "ans3": "\u00bc",
                "ans4": "1/8",
                "question_text": "The sum of all terms of geometric sequence is equals to 5/4 times the sum of all odd terms of the following series. The common ratio of series is",
                "correct_ans": "\u00bc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45373": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{bmatrix}1&0\\\\0&0\\end{bmatrix}\\;and\\;\\begin{bmatrix}0&0\\\\0&1\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{bmatrix}2&1\\\\0&0\\end{bmatrix}\\;and\\;\\begin{bmatrix}-1&2\\\\5&6\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{bmatrix}1&-1\\\\0&5\\end{bmatrix}\\;and\\;\\begin{bmatrix}3&2\\\\0&0\\end{bmatrix}",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Two matrices which are not invertible but their sum is invertible is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{bmatrix}1&0\\\\0&0\\end{bmatrix}\\;and\\;\\begin{bmatrix}0&0\\\\0&1\\end{bmatrix}",
                "explanation": "|A|= 0 & |B| = 0. Hence they are not invertible. But A + B is invertable",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41554": {
                "ans1": " 4x-3y+8=0",
                "ans2": "3x-3y+6=0",
                "ans3": "y=x",
                "ans4": "4x-3y=0",
                "question_text": "A line makes zero intercepts on the co-ordinate axes. If It is perpendicular to the line 3x + 4y + 6 = 0, then its equation is",
                "correct_ans": "4x-3y=0",
                "explanation": "For zero intercepts on the axes, line must pass through origin. Thus, equation of line through origin & perpendicular to 3x + 4y + 6 = 0 is 4x \u2013 3y = 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48778": {
                "ans1": "5h^2=ab",
                "ans2": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "ans3": "9h^2=5ab    ",
                "ans4": "h^2=ab",
                "question_text": "If slope of one line represented by ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is five times the slope of another line then",
                "correct_ans": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44396": {
                "ans1": "straight line",
                "ans2": "circle",
                "ans3": "ellipse",
                "ans4": "parabola",
                "question_text": "The locus of centre of a circle\u00a0x^2+y^2-6x\\cos\u03b8-8y\\sin\u03b8-10=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "ellipse",
                "explanation": "Centre is (3 cos\u03b8, 4 sin\u03b8)\\\\x = 3 cos\u03b8, y = 4 sin\u03b8\u00a0x^{2/9}+y^{2/16}=1\\\\x2/9+y2/16=1i.e. Ellipse",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42628": {
                "ans1": "168",
                "ans2": "336",
                "ans3": "280",
                "ans4": "1680",
                "question_text": "A person has got 12 acquaintances of whom 8 are relatives. In how many ways can he invite 7 guests so that 5 of them may be relatives.",
                "correct_ans": "336",
                "explanation": "^8C_5 \\times\n\u00a0^4C_2\u200b\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40867": {
                "ans1": "are equal",
                "ans2": "are in AP",
                "ans3": "are in GP",
                "ans4": "are in HP",
                "question_text": "In \u2206ABC,\u00a02c\\cos^2{\\frac{A}{2}}+2a\\cos^2{\\frac{C}{2}}=3b\u00a0then a,b,c",
                "correct_ans": "are in AP",
                "explanation": "2cos ^\n2\n  \n2\nA\n\u200b\n +2acos ^\n2\n  \n2\nC\n\u200b\n \n=c(1+cosA)+a(1+cosC)\\\\\n=a+c+ccosA+acosC\\\\\nOr, 3b = a+b+c\\\\\nOr, 2b = a+c\\\\\nSo, b = (a+c)/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44484": {
                "ans1": "2x+2y=5",
                "ans2": "2x-2y=5",
                "ans3": "x+y=1",
                "ans4": "x-y=1",
                "question_text": "If one end of the diameter is (1, 1) and the other end lies on the line x + y = 3 then the locus of centre of circle is",
                "correct_ans": "2x+2y=5",
                "explanation": "a =\u00a0\\frac{1+t}{2} \\;and \\;b=\\frac{4-t}{2} ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49366": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "ln 3",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a01-ln2+{\\frac{(ln2)^2}{2!}}-{\\frac{(ln2)^3}{3!}}+\u2026....... is",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\u00a0e^{\u2212ln2}=e^{ln(1/2\u200b)}=1/2\u200b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41695": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44948": {
                "ans1": "even function",
                "ans2": "odd function",
                "ans3": "zero",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If h(x)=f(x)+f(-x) then h(x) has got an extreme value at the point where f'(x) is",
                "correct_ans": "even function",
                "explanation": "h'(x)=f'(x)-f'(-x); for maxima h'(x)=0; hence f'(x)=f'(-x) i,e, even",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48838": {
                "ans1": "m+n",
                "ans2": "m-n",
                "ans3": "m+5n",
                "ans4": "m+8n",
                "question_text": "What is the 11th term of the sequence: m-2n,m-n,m,...?",
                "correct_ans": "m+8n",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47349": {
                "ans1": "(-1, 1)",
                "ans2": "R -(-1, 1)",
                "ans3": "R-[-1, 1]",
                "ans4": "(-\u221e, \u221e)",
                "question_text": "Domain of a function f(x) =\u00a0\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{x^2-1}}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "R-[-1, 1]",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45188": {
                "ans1": " \u03c0/2",
                "ans2": "\u03c0/6",
                "ans3": " arctan(1/2)",
                "ans4": " \u03c0/4",
                "question_text": "The angle between the tangents to the parabola\u00a0y^2=4a(x-a) drawn from its origin is",
                "correct_ans": " \u03c0/2",
                "explanation": "Combined equation of tangents to the parabola from origin is given by\\\\SS_1=T^2\\Rightarrow\\>(y^2-4ax+4a^2).4a^2=(-2ax+4a^4)^2 \\Rightarrow\\>x^2-y^2=0\\\\Angle between tangents = \u03c0/2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43993": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\frac{1+i}{1-i}^n=1 then the least integral value of n is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40339": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "e",
                "ans3": "1/e",
                "ans4": "e-1",
                "question_text": "Area bounded by y = lnx, x-axis and the line x =1 and x = e is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45763": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "A line makes angle \u03b1,\u03b2,\u03b3\u00a0with x- axis and z- axis respectively then cos2\u03b1+cos2\u03b2+cos2\u03b3\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41670": {
                "ans1": "m+n",
                "ans2": "(m+n)/2",
                "ans3": "mn",
                "ans4": "m-n",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(p+q)^{th} and\u00a0(p-q)^{th}\u00a0term of an AP are respectively\u00a0m\u00a0and\u00a0n, then the\u00a0p^{th}\u00a0term is",
                "correct_ans": "(m+n)/2",
                "explanation": "(p+q)th=a+(p+q\u22121)d=m(p-q)^{th} = a + (p-q-1)d = nsum:2a + (2p-2)d = m + n2(a + (p-1)d) = m +np^{th} term = \\dfrac{m+n}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42511": {
                "ans1": "H^2",
                "ans2": "4H^2",
                "ans3": "2H^2",
                "ans4": "16H^2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the pair of straight line Ax^2 + 2Hxy + By^2 forms the equilateral triangle with line ax+by + c=0 then the value of (A+3B)(B+3A) is",
                "correct_ans": "4H^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49344": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{2c^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac2{c^2}",
                "question_text": "The circle\u00a0x^2+y^2+2ax+c^2 =0 and\u00a0x^2+y^2+2by+c^2=0\u00a0touches if",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43760": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "3/4",
                "ans4": "19/9",
                "question_text": "The projection of the vector\u00a0\\vec{i} - 2\\overrightarrow{j} + \\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0on the vector\u00a04\\overrightarrow{i} - 4 \\overrightarrow{j} + 7\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "19/9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45248": {
                "ans1": "cos\u03b8+isin\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos9\u03b8+isin9\u03b8",
                "ans3": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "ans4": "cos4\u03b8-isin4\u03b8",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\dfrac{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^4}{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^5} is",
                "correct_ans": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40179": {
                "ans1": "(a+b+c)",
                "ans2": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans3": "2abc(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans4": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{vmatrix}a-b-c&2a&2a\\\\2b&b-c-a&2b\\\\2c&2c&c-a-b\\end{vmatrix} =",
                "correct_ans": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40422": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\u00a0\\log \\tan1^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 2^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 3^{\\circ}+\\cdots+\\log \\tan 89^{\\circ}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47978": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\tan^4x}4+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan^2x}5+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan^{-1}x}5+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin^4x}{\\cos^6x}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46993": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "96",
                "ans3": "216",
                "ans4": "240",
                "question_text": "In how many ways number divisible by 3 can be formed from the integers 0,1,2,3,4,5 if each number so formed consists of different digits.",
                "correct_ans": "240",
                "explanation": "Taking 5 digits combination sum;The sum of (1+2+3+4+5) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 so 5!The sum of (0+1+2+3+4) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 is, 4\u00d74\u00d73\u00d72\u00d71=96Total =\u00a0216216",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47678": {
                "ans1": "4,5",
                "ans2": "-4,7",
                "ans3": "-4,3",
                "ans4": "13,7",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0(2+i\\sqrt{3})\u00a0is a root of the equation\u00a0x^2+px+ q =0\u00a0then the value of\u00a0p\u00a0and\u00a0q\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "-4,7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41212": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "9",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the coefficient of\u00a0x^7 in the expansion of\u00a0(1 + x) (1 + x^2 ) (1 + x^3) . . . . . . (1 + x^{100})",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "(0,7),(1.6),(2,5),(3,4)=4\u00a0ways(1,2,4) =1(1,2,4)=1\u00a0waysTotal =\u00a055\u00a0ways",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46710": {
                "ans1": "-2",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a,b,c are in AP then the sum of coefficient of\u00a0\u00a0(1+( ax^2 -2bx + c))^{10}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "a,b,c are in AP\u00a0=> 2b = a + c => a-2b+c=0putting\u00a0x=1 ,\u00a0 required sum\u00a0= ( 1+a-2b+c)^{10} = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42650": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "16",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "If a function\u00a0f(x)=x^2 + \\dfrac{a}{x}\u200b\u00a0has a local minimum at\u00a0x=2 , then a=",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45390": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The sum of coefficients of\u00a0(x^2 \u2013 x \u2013 1)^{99}\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "(1^2-1-1)^{99}=-1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45689": {
                "ans1": "4,2",
                "ans2": "4,3",
                "ans3": "4,1",
                "ans4": "3,1",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0f(x) = |sin4x + 3| then, the maximum and minimum value of\u00a0f(x)\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "4,2",
                "explanation": "We have\u00a0|sin4x| \u2264 1i.e.\u00a0-1 \u2264 sin4x \u2264 1i.e.\u00a02 \u2264 sin4x+3 \u2264 4So, Max = 4 and Min =2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49271": {
                "ans1": "(1,1)",
                "ans2": "(1,0)",
                "ans3": "(1,-1)",
                "ans4": "(0,0)",
                "question_text": "On the parabola\u00a0y=x^2, the point least distance from straight line\u00a0y=2x-4 is",
                "correct_ans": "(1,1)",
                "explanation": "Parabola\u00a0y=x^2St.line\u00a0y=2x-4hence the eqn will be\u00a0x^2-2x+4=0Let\u00a0f(x)=x^2-2x+4; f'(x)=2x-2for least distance\u00a0f'(x)=0 hence\u00a0x=1; thus\u00a0y=1^2; the point is\u00a0(1,1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49711": {
                "ans1": "2x\u2212y=0,y\u22123z=0",
                "ans2": "2x+3z=0,y=0",
                "ans3": "2x\u2212y=0,z=0",
                "ans4": "2x\u2212y=0,2x+3z=0",
                "question_text": "Plane 2x\u2212(1+\u03bb)y+3\u03bbz=0, where \u03bb\u00a0is an arbitrary constant, passes through the intersection of planes",
                "correct_ans": "2x\u2212y=0,y\u22123z=0",
                "explanation": "2x\u2212(1+\u03bb)y+3\u03bbz=0(2x\u2212y)+\u03bb(3z\u2212y)=0hence required planes\u00a02x-y=0 and\u00a03z-y=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40919": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3/2",
                "ans4": "2/3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0|\\dfrac{(z-1)}{(z-2)}|=1 then Re(z)=",
                "correct_ans": "3/2",
                "explanation": "Let\u00a0z=x+iyso\u00a0|x+iy-1|=|x+iy-2|(x-1)^2+y^2=(x-2)^2+y^2solving,\u00a0x=\\dfrac{3}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49051": {
                "ans1": "1/\u221a2",
                "ans2": "1/\u221a3",
                "ans3": "\u221a3",
                "ans4": "-\u221a3",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(tan^{-1} x)^2 -(cot^{-1}x)^2 = (\\dfrac{\\pi}{2\\sqrt{3}})^2, then x=",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45167": {
                "ans1": "2\u03c0 \u200b/5",
                "ans2": "\u03c0 \u200b/5",
                "ans3": "\u03c0 \u200b/15",
                "ans4": "\u03c0 \u200b/10",
                "question_text": "The amplitude of\u00a0sin(\\dfrac{\\pi}{5}) + i ( 1 - cos(\\dfrac{\\pi}{5})) is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03c0 \u200b/10",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42235": {
                "ans1": "3x+2y+z=1",
                "ans2": "3x+2y+z=0",
                "ans3": "2x+3y+z=0",
                "ans4": "3x+2y\u2212z=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane through intersection of planes\u00a0x+2y+3z+4=0 and\u00a04x+3y+2z+1 =0 and the origin is",
                "correct_ans": "3x+2y+z=0",
                "explanation": "The equation of plane is\u00a0x+2y+3z+4(k(4x+3y+2z+1))=0since it passes through\u00a0(0,0)so\u00a04+k=0\u00a0hence\u00a0k=-4, substituting gives\u00a03x+2y+z=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46214": {
                "ans1": "2x+4y+3z+16=0",
                "ans2": " 2x - 4y -3z + 8 = 0",
                "ans3": "2x\u22124y+3z\u22128=0",
                "ans4": "2x+4y\u22123z\u221216=0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Equation of plane passing through\u00a0(1, -3, -2) and perpendicular to the planes\u00a0x + 2y + 2z = 5 and\u00a03x + 3y + 2z = 8 is:",
                "correct_ans": "2x\u22124y+3z\u22128=0",
                "explanation": "Equation of plane through\u00a0(1,-3, -2)\u00a0is:a(x - 1) + b(y+ 3) + c(z+ 2) =0using perpendicular conditiona + 2b + 2c =03a + 3b + 2c = 0So, equation of plane isExpanding:\u00a02x - 4y + 3z - 8 =0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48699": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+\\frac\\pi4",
                "ans2": "2n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi4",
                "ans3": "n\\pi\\pm\\frac\\pi4",
                "ans4": "n\\pi-\\frac\\pi4",
                "question_text": "The general solution of\u00a0|sinx|=cosx\u00a0\u00a0is given by",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi+\\frac\\pi4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43441": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{-q}{(p+q)}",
                "ans2": "\\frac q{(p+1)}",
                "ans3": "\\frac p{(q+1)}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{- p}{(q+1)}",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the lines\u00a0p(x^2)- qxy - y^2 = 0 make the area\u00a0\u03b1\u00a0and \u03b2\u00a0with x-axis, then the value of tan(\u03b1+\u03b2)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-q}{(p+q)}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42082": {
                "ans1": "5/3",
                "ans2": "4/3",
                "ans3": "3/5",
                "ans4": "5/9",
                "question_text": "(3sec(\u03d5),4tan(\u03d5))\u00a0is any point on a conic then eccentricity is",
                "correct_ans": "5/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45927": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "\u221e",
                "question_text": "derivative of\u00a0log_e e^x\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "Here,\\\\y=\\log_ee^x=x\\;\\\\(\\sin ce\\;\\log_e\\;and\\;e\\;are\\;inverse\\;of\\;each,\\;they\\;cancel\\;out.)\\\\So,\\;derivative\\;is\\;given\\;by:\\\\\\frac{\\operatorname d\\log_ee^x}{\\operatorname dx}=\\frac{\\operatorname dx}{\\operatorname dx}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40816": {
                "ans1": "1/n",
                "ans2": "2/n",
                "ans3": "-1/n",
                "ans4": "-2/n",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If n is not a multiple of 3, then the coeffiecient of xn in the expansion of\u00a0log_e(1+x+x^2) is",
                "correct_ans": "1/n",
                "explanation": "Log expansion",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42169": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}",
                "ans2": "(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "ans3": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "ans4": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}+\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "question_text": "The general solution of \u221a3cosx + sinx = \u221a2is",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\sqrt3\\cos x+\\sin x}{\\sqrt{\\left(\\sqrt3\\right)^2+1^2}}\\times\\sqrt{\\left(\\sqrt3\\right)^2+1^2}=\\sqrt2\\\\or,\\;\\frac{\\sqrt3}2\\cos x+\\frac12\\sin x=\\frac1{\\sqrt2}\\\\or,\\;\\sin\\left(x+\\frac\\pi3\\right)=\\sin\\frac\\pi4\\\\or,\\;\\left(x+\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\right)=n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}\\\\x=n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle4}-\\frac{\\displaystyle\\pi}{\\displaystyle3}\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49668": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "13",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of (2x+y+8z)^4 are",
                "correct_ans": "15",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}No.\\;of\\;terms={}^{m+n+1}C_{m-1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;={}^{3+4+1}C_{3-1}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;={}^6C_2\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{6!}{(6-4)!2!}=15\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49157": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47843": {
                "ans1": "e^{a^2}+e^{b^2}",
                "ans2": "e^a+e^b",
                "ans3": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "ans4": "e^a-e^b",
                "question_text": "(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{a^4-b^4}{2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{a^6-b^6}{3!}\\right)+..........=",
                "correct_ans": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^4-b^4}{\\displaystyle2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^6-b^6}{\\displaystyle3!}\\right)+..........\\\\=\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle a^2}{\\displaystyle1!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle a^4}{\\displaystyle2!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle a^6}{\\displaystyle3!}+......\\right)-\\left(\\frac{\\displaystyle b^2}{\\displaystyle1!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle b^4}{\\displaystyle2!}+\\frac{\\displaystyle b^6}{\\displaystyle3!}+......\\right)\\\\=(e^{a^2}-1)-(e^{b^2}-1)\\\\=e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40868": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{\\sin^4x}4+\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "question_text": "\\int(\\sin x\\cos x)^3dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\sin^4x}4-\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\sin^6}{\\displaystyle x}}6+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49686": {
                "ans1": "3/2",
                "ans2": "3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "The area bound by the x axis and the curve\u00a0y=4x-x^2-3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "4/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47974": {
                "ans1": "\u221a2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "2 sq. units  ",
                "ans3": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "\u221a3/2 units",
                "question_text": "If a=2 and \\frac a{\\cos A}=\\frac b{\\cos{\\displaystyle B}}=\\frac c{\\cos{\\displaystyle C}} then area of \u0394ABC is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac a{\\cos A}\\;=\\frac b{\\cos B}=\\frac c{\\cos C}.........(1)\\\\Also\\;in\\;\\triangle ABC,\\frac a{\\sin A}\\;=\\frac b{sinB}=\\frac c{\\sin C}.........(2)\\;\\\\dividing\\;(1)\\;by\\;(2)\\\\\\tan\\;A\\;=\\;\\tan\\;B\\;=\\;\\tan\\;C\\;\\Rightarrow\\;A=\\;B\\;=\\;C\\;(equilateral\\;triangle)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43074": {
                "ans1": "c/b",
                "ans2": "b/c",
                "ans3": "a/b",
                "ans4": "b/a",
                "question_text": "\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=",
                "correct_ans": "b/c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=\\frac{c-a\\times{\\displaystyle\\frac{a^2+c^2-b^2}{2ac}}}{b-a\\times\\frac{a^2+b^2-c^2}{2ab}}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{\\frac{2c^2-a^2-c^2+b^2}c}{\\frac{2b^2-a^2-b^2+c^2}b}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\frac{c^2+b^2-a^2}c\\times\\frac b{c^2+b^2-a^2}=\\frac bc\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46303": {
                "ans1": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans2": "1/2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans3": "2n cos n\u03b8",
                "ans4": "n cos 2\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x}=2\\cos\\theta\\;then\\\\\\;x^n+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x^n}\\;is\\end{array}\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac1x=2\\cos\\theta\\;\\rightarrow\\left(x+\\frac1x\\right)^2=\\;4\\cos^2\\theta\\rightarrow x^2+\\frac1{x^2}=2(2\\cos^2\\theta-1)=2\\cos2\\theta\\\\x^n+\\frac1{x^n}=2\\cos n\\theta\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47494": {
                "ans1": "4 sq. units ",
                "ans2": "10 sq. units ",
                "ans3": "25/2 sq. units ",
                "ans4": "25/4 sq. units ",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by curve y=2x-4, y=1 and y-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "25/4 sq. units ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47962": {
                "ans1": "9/4",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "1/4",
                "ans4": "1/8",
                "question_text": "The sum of all terms of geometric sequence is equals to 5/4 times the sum of all odd terms of the following series. The common ratio of series is",
                "correct_ans": "1/4",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;series\\;is:\\;a,\\;ar,\\;ar^2,\\;ar^3,\\;ar^4,\\;ar^5.....\\;\\\\sum\\;of\\;series=\\frac54\\times(sum\\;ofa,ar^2,ar^4....)\\;\\\\or,\\;\\frac a{1-r}=\\frac54\\times\\frac a{1-r^2}\\\\or,\\;4r\u00b2-5r\\;+\\;1\\;=\\;0\\;\\\\or,\\;(4r-1)\\;(r-1)=0\\;\\\\either,\\;4r-1=0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;r\\;=\\;\\frac14\\;\\\\or,\\;r-1=0\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;r=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48350": {
                "ans1": "5h^2=ab",
                "ans2": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "ans3": "9h^2=5ab    ",
                "ans4": "h^2=ab",
                "question_text": "If slope of one line represented by ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is five times the slope of another line then",
                "correct_ans": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}m_1\\;=\\;5m_2\\;\\;\\\\Now,\\;sum\\;of\\;slopes=\\frac{2h}{\\boldsymbol\\;b}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;m_1+\\;m_2\\;=-\\frac{2h}{\\;b}\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;5m\u2082\\;+\\;m\u2082\\;=\\;-\\frac{2h}b\\;\\Rightarrow m\u2082\\;=\\;-\\frac h{3b}\\\\also,\\;product\\;of\\;roots=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;m_1m_2=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;5m_2^2=\\frac ab\\\\or,\\;5\\times\\left(-\\frac5{3b}\\right)^2=\\frac ab\\\\i.e.\\;5h^2=9ab\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48629": {
                "ans1": "-330m^2",
                "ans2": "-330m^5",
                "ans3": "330m^7",
                "ans4": "-330m^7",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of\u00a0x^{-3}  in the expansion of \\left(x-\\frac mx\\right)^{11} is",
                "correct_ans": "-330m^7",
                "explanation": "For\\;coeff.\\;of\\;x^{-3}\\;in\\;the\\;expansion\\;of\\;\\left(x^1-\\frac m{x^1}\\right)^{11}:\\\\r=\\frac{n\\alpha-m}{\\alpha+\\beta}=\\frac{11\\ast1-(-3)}{1+1}=7\\\\Now,\\;term=\\;t_{7+1}={}^{11}C_7\\;x^{11-7}\\;\\left(-\\frac mx\\right)^7\\\\So,\\;coeff.\\;of\\;x^{-3}=-330m^7",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49664": {
                "ans1": "20 cm^2/2",
                "ans2": "40 cm^2/2",
                "ans3": "60 cm^2/s",
                "ans4": "80 cm^2/s",
                "question_text": "The length of a square is increasing at 6 cm/s. The rate of increase of area when the length of square is 5 cm/s",
                "correct_ans": "60 cm^2/s",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}A=l^2\\\\\\frac{dA}{dt}=\\frac{dl^2}{dt}=2l\\frac{dl}{dt}\\;\\;\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;2\\times5\\times6\\;=60\\;cm\u00b2/s\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49504": {
                "ans1": "scalene",
                "ans2": "isosceles ",
                "ans3": "equilateral",
                "ans4": "right angle",
                "question_text": "If semi perimeter is equal to ex-radius\u00a0 of a triangle is",
                "correct_ans": "right angle",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}semi\\;perimeter=ex-radius\\;\\\\or,\\;s=r_1\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;s=\\frac\\triangle{s-a}\\;\\;\\;\\\\or,\\;s(s-a)=\\sqrt{s(s-a)\\;(s-b)\\;(s-c)}\\;\\\\or,\\;\\;\\sqrt{\\frac{(s-b)\\;(s-c)\\;}{s\\;(s-a)}}=1\\;\\\\or,\\;\\;\\;\\tan\\left(\\frac A2\\right)=\\tan\\left(\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}4\\right)\\;\\;\\\\ie.\\;A\\;=\\frac{\\mathrm\\pi}2\\;i.e.\\;right\\;angle\\;triangle\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46462": {
                "ans1": "3,12",
                "ans2": "4,9",
                "ans3": "2,18",
                "ans4": "7,6",
                "question_text": "The G.M. of two numbers is 6 and the A.M. is 6.5 then the numbers are:",
                "correct_ans": "4,9",
                "explanation": "\u00a0For\u00a0option\u00a0bG M= \\sqrt{4 \\times 9}=6A M= \\dfrac{4+9}{2}=6.5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40271": {
                "ans1": "x-y-1=0",
                "ans2": "x+y-1=0",
                "ans3": "x-y+1=0",
                "ans4": "x+y+1=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the straight line equally inclined to the axes and equidistant from the points (1, - 2) and (3,4) is:",
                "correct_ans": "x-y-1=0",
                "explanation": "The line which is equally inclined to the axes (i.e. both X-axis & Y-axis) makes an angle of 45 degrees with +ve X-axis.so, the slope of the line is given by,m=tan45=1now. let the equation of line be,y=mx+cy=1.x+cy=x+cx-y+c=0Now, the line is equidistant from the given two points A(1, - 2) and B(3,4).so, equating perpendicular distances from these points:\\pm\\frac{1\\ast1-1(-2)+c}{\\sqrt{1^2+{(-1)}^2}}=\\pm\\frac{1\\ast3-1\\ast4+c}{\\sqrt{1^2+{(-1)}^2}}\\\\\\Rightarrow Taking\\;+ve\\;on\\;both\\;sides,\\\\\\Rightarrow1+2+c=3-4+c\\Rightarrow3=1\\;(not\\;ok)\\\\\\\\\\Rightarrow Taking\\;-ve\\;on\\;left\\;side,\\\\\\Rightarrow-(1+2+c)=3-4+c\\Rightarrow-3-c=-1+c\\\\\\Rightarrow-2=2c\\Rightarrow c=-1\\\\\\\\So, the equation of the line is:x-y-1=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48185": {
                "ans1": "(2,\u221216),(\u22122,16)",
                "ans2": "(0,2),(2,16)",
                "ans3": "(0,\u22122),(2,\u221216)",
                "ans4": "(2,16),(\u22122,\u221216)",
                "question_text": "The points of the curve\u00a0y = 12x-x^3 at which the gradient is zero are",
                "correct_ans": "(2,16),(\u22122,\u221216)",
                "explanation": "Gradient means the slope of the tangent.The slope of the tangent is given by,\\frac{\\mathrm dy}{\\mathrm d x} =12-3x^2 = 0x= \\pm 2 at\\;x=2,\\\\y=12\\ast2-2^3=16\\\\at\\;x=-2,\\\\y=12\\ast(-2)-{(-2)}^3=-16\\\\so, the points are (2, 16) and (-2, -16).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43304": {
                "ans1": "A",
                "ans2": "B",
                "ans3": "\u03d5",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If A&B\u00a0are two disjoint sets , then the intersection of\u00a0A\u00a0and\u00a0B\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03d5",
                "explanation": "Two set are disjoint means,\u00a0A\u00a0and\u00a0B\u00a0doesn't have any common elements.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45156": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans3": "\\frac{cosx}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans4": "\\frac{sinx}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "question_text": "What is the derivative of\u00a0\\sqrt{\\sin x}\u200b\u00a0with respect to\u00a0x?",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "explanation": "\\frac{d\\sqrt{\\sin x}}{dx} = \\frac{d\\sqrt{\\sin x}}{d\\sin x}.\\frac{d{\\sin x}}{dx}  \\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47638": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "4abc",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "The value of the determinant\u00a0\\left| \\begin{array}{ccc}a & a + b & a + c \\\\ 2 a & 2 a + 3 b & 2 a + 3 c \\\\ 3 a & 3 a + 4 b & 3 a + 4 c \\end{array} \\right|=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Solving by Put Method:Put a = b= c =1\\left| \\begin{array}{ccc}1 & 2 &2 \\\\2 & 5 & 5 \\\\ 3& 7 & 7 \\end{array} \\right|=0C_2Now calculate value of options:a) 1+1+1=3b) 0c) 4*1*1*1=4d) 1So, the answer is 0= option(b).-Watch this lecture to find determinants by shortcuts, ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48383": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "\u221e",
                "question_text": "derivative of\u00a0log_e e^x\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "Here,\\\\y=\\log_ee^x=x\\;\\\\(\\sin ce\\;\\log_e\\;and\\;e\\;are\\;inverse\\;of\\;each,\\;they\\;cancel\\;out.)\\\\So,\\;derivative\\;is\\;given\\;by:\\\\\\frac{\\operatorname d\\log_ee^x}{\\operatorname dx}=\\frac{\\operatorname dx}{\\operatorname dx}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48039": {
                "ans1": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow b}{\\overrightarrow a}",
                "ans2": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow a}{\\overrightarrow b}",
                "ans3": "x=y=0",
                "ans4": "x+y=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are non zero and non collinear and\u00a0x \\overrightarrow{a} + y \\overrightarrow{b} = 0\u00a0 where\u00a0x\u00a0and\u00a0y\u00a0are scalars then,",
                "correct_ans": "x=y=0",
                "explanation": "Since the vectors are linearly independent.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43337": {
                "ans1": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|=\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans2": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|<\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are two vectors then\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}-\\overrightarrow{b}= \\overrightarrow{b}-\\overrightarrow{a} if",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b=\\overrightarrow b-\\overrightarrow a\\\\\\Rightarrow2\\overrightarrow a=2\\overrightarrow b\\Rightarrow\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45778": {
                "ans1": "18/25",
                "ans2": "50/9",
                "ans3": "18/5",
                "ans4": "9/25",
                "question_text": "The length of the latus rectum of the ellipse\u00a0\\dfrac{x^{2}}{25} + \\dfrac{y^{2}}{9}=125 is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "18/5",
                "explanation": "a^2 = 25b^2 = 9a>b\\frac{2b^2}{a}\\frac{2*9}{5} = \\frac{18}{5}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44013": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert\\;dx\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\;Since,\\;\\int\\left|x\\right|dx=\\frac{x\\left|x\\right|}2+c\\\\\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert\\;dx\\;=\\left(\\frac{(x-2)\\left|x-2\\right|}2\\right)_0^4\\\\=\\left\\{\\frac{(4-2)\\left|4-2\\right|}2\\right\\}-\\left\\{\\frac{(0-2)\\left|0-2\\right|}2\\right\\}\\\\=\\frac{2\\ast2}2-\\frac{(-2)\\ast2}2=2+2=4Note: You can use the calculator to get the value directly.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42658": {
                "ans1": "n^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans2": "{(n+1)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans3": "{(2n)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\\\{(n-1)}^{th}\\;term",
                "question_text": "The term free from\u00a0x\u00a0in the expansion of\u00a0\\left(x + \\cfrac{1}{x} \\right)^{2 n} is:",
                "correct_ans": "{(n+1)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "explanation": "The\\;term\\;containing\\;x^m\\;in\\;the\\;expansion\\;of\\;{(ax^\\alpha+\\frac b{x^\\beta})}^n\\;is\\;given\\;by:\\;\\\\{(r+1)}^{th}\\;term.r = \\frac{n\\alpha - m}{\\alpha+\\beta}x^0r=\\frac{1.2n-0}{1+1}r=n(n+1{)^{th}\\;}term",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43525": {
                "ans1": "3\ud835\udc65\u22122\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67\u22127=0",
                "ans2": "2\ud835\udc65+3\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67\u221219=0",
                "ans3": "\u22123\ud835\udc65+2\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc65\u221249=0",
                "ans4": "3\ud835\udc65\u22122\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67+7=0",
                "question_text": "If the length of the perpendicular drawn from the origin on a plane is 7 units and its direction ratios are -3, 2, 6 then the plane is",
                "correct_ans": "\u22123\ud835\udc65+2\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc65\u221249=0",
                "explanation": "Direction ratios of normal = -3, 2, 6l=\\frac a{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac{-3}{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac{-3}7\\\\m=\\frac b{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac2{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac27\\\\n=\\frac c{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac6{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac67Equation of plane in normal form: \\frac{-3}7x+\\frac27y+\\frac67z=7\\\\-3x+2y+6z=49\\\\-3x+2y+6z-49=0\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46690": {
                "ans1": "cos\u03b8\u2212\u03b8cos\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos\u03b8\u2212\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "ans3": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8cos\u03b8",
                "ans4": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{x\\cos\\theta-\\theta\\cos x}{x-\\theta}=",
                "correct_ans": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "explanation": "Using the L-Hospital rule,\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac{\\operatorname d\\left(x\\cos\\theta-\\theta\\cos x\\right)}{\\operatorname dx}}{\\displaystyle\\frac{\\operatorname d\\left(x-\\theta\\right)}{\\operatorname dx}}=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{1.\\cos\\theta-\\theta.\\left(-\\sin x\\right)}{1-0}\\\\=\\cos\\theta+\\theta\\sin\\theta\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40000": {
                "ans1": "2 n\u03c0",
                "ans2": "n\u03c0",
                "ans3": "n\u03c0 + n/2",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "\\frac{3+2i\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}\u200b\u00a0will be real if \u03b8=",
                "correct_ans": "n\u03c0",
                "explanation": "\\frac{3+2i\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}=\\frac3{1-2\\sin\\theta}+\\frac{2\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}i\\\\The\\;given\\;complex\\;number\\;will\\;be\\;real\\;if,\\\\imaginary\\;part=0\\\\\\frac{2\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}=0\\\\sin\\theta=0\\\\\\Rightarrow sin\\theta=\\sin0\\\\\\Rightarrow\\theta=n\\pi+{(-1)}^n.0\\;\\;\\lbrack Genral\\;solution\\rbrack\\theta = n\\pi",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48322": {
                "ans1": "sin(2\u03b1)",
                "ans2": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "ans3": "cos(2\u03b1)",
                "ans4": "cot(2\u03b1)",
                "question_text": "If \u00a0tan(\u03b1)=\\sqrt{a}\u200b\u00a0where a is a positive rational number and is not a perfect square then which of the following is a rational number?",
                "correct_ans": "tan(2\u03b1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41451": {
                "ans1": "1:2",
                "ans2": "2:1",
                "ans3": "\u221a2:1",
                "ans4": "1:\u221a2",
                "question_text": "The distance between the foci and distance between directrices of the hyperbola\u00a0\\frac{x^{2}}{a^{2}} - \\frac{y^{2}}{b^{2}} =1\u00a0 are in the ratio 3:2, then a:b is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a2:1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41786": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "1/(xy)",
                "ans3": "1/(2y-x)",
                "ans4": "1/(2y-1)",
                "question_text": ".If\u00a0y=\\sqrt{(x+\\sqrt{(x+\\sqrt{(x+.....)))}}} \\; then\u00a0dy/dx=",
                "correct_ans": "1/(2y-1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40684": {
                "ans1": " 15",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "31",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In an examination, a candidate has to pass in each of the 5 subjects. In how many ways can he fail?",
                "correct_ans": "31",
                "explanation": "Total no. of ways by which he fails will be C(5,1)+C(5,2)+C(5,3)+C(5,4)+C(5,5)=31",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41820": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "-23",
                "question_text": "If the line 2x+y+k=0 is normal to parabola\u00a0y^{2}=-8x\u00a0 then value of k is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48089": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "-3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "If the normal to the curve y=f(x) at the point (3,4) makes an angle 3\u03c0/4 with +ve x-axis then f'(3)=",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}slope\\;of\\;normal=-\\frac1{f'(x)}=\\tan\\frac{3\\pi}4=-1\\\\f'(x)=1\\\\f'(3)=1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43709": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{x^2}2-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "ans3": "x^2+\\ln(x^2+1)+c",
                "ans4": "x^2-\\ln(x^2+1)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{(x^4+1)}{\\;(x^{\\;2}+1)}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\times arctanx+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49713": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "n(n+1)/2",
                "ans3": "\\left(\\frac{n(n+1)}2\\right)^2",
                "ans4": "n(n+1)(2n+1)/6",
                "question_text": "Sum of the series 1 + (3 + 5) + (7 + 9 + 11) + ..... to n terms is",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(\\frac{n(n+1)}2\\right)^2",
                "explanation": "Sn\u200b=1+(3+5)+(7+9+11)+....\u00a0to n1^{3}+2^{3}+....",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44142": {
                "ans1": "0<\\alpha<\\beta",
                "ans2": "\\alpha<\\beta<0",
                "ans3": "0<\\alpha<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "ans4": "\\alpha<0<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\alpha\\;and\\;\\beta\\;(\\alpha<\\beta)\\;are\\;the\\\\\\;roots\\;of\\;the\\;equation\\\\\\;x^2+bx+c=0\\;\\\\where\\;c<0<b\\;then",
                "correct_ans": "\\alpha<0<\\beta<\\vert\\alpha\\vert",
                "explanation": "put method:put: b=1 , c= -2 [c<0<b]then find the roots of the equation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47660": {
                "ans1": " 1/2",
                "ans2": "\u221a3/2",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "\u221a2/3",
                "question_text": "If the latus rectum of an ellipse be equal to half of its minor axis, then its eccentricity is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46845": {
                "ans1": "(1,\u221e)",
                "ans2": "(0,\u221e)",
                "ans3": " (0,1]",
                "ans4": "(0.5,1)",
                "question_text": "The domain of the function\u00a0\\sqrt{(\\log_{0.5}(x))} is",
                "correct_ans": " (0,1]",
                "explanation": "log0.5\u200b(x)\u22650andx>0thenx\u22641andx>0;sodomain=(0,1]",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41603": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c=0",
                "ans2": "abc=1",
                "ans3": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "ans4": "a+b+c=1",
                "question_text": "If\\\\\\;a\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow{k,}\\\\\\;\\overrightarrow i+b\\overrightarrow j+\\overrightarrow k\\;and\\\\\\overrightarrow{\\;i}+\\overrightarrow j+c\\overrightarrow k\\;\\\\are\\;coplanar\\;then:",
                "correct_ans": "a+b+c=abc+2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;the\\;given\\;vectors\\;are\\;coplanar,\\;then\\;\\;\\\\\\begin{vmatrix}a&1&1\\\\1&b&1\\\\1&1&c\\end{vmatrix}\\;\\;=0\\\\a(bc-1)\\times-1(c-1)+(1-b)=0\\;\\\\abc-a-c+1+1-b=0\\;\\\\\\Rightarrow a+b+c=abc\\;+2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45043": {
                "ans1": "4\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "3\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "2\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "ABCD is a parallelogram with AC and BD as diagonals then\u00a0\\vec{AC}-\\vec{BD}\u00a0=",
                "correct_ans": "2\\overrightarrow{AB}\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46544": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-2",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "A line makes angle \u03b1, \u03b2, \u03b3 with x-axis, y-axis and z-axis respectively then cos 2\u03b1 + cos 2\u03b2 + cos 2\u03b3 is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48742": {
                "ans1": "(0.1]",
                "ans2": "[0,1]",
                "ans3": "(-\u221e,0]",
                "ans4": "(-\u221e,1)",
                "question_text": "The domain of definition if the function given by\u00a02^x+2^y=2 is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "(-\u221e,1)",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2^y=2-2^x\\\\2-2^x>0\\\\2^x<2\\\\x<1\\\\x=(-\\infty,1)\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43855": {
                "ans1": " (4, 9)",
                "ans2": "(9, 4)",
                "ans3": "(1,2\\sqrt3)",
                "ans4": "(3,4)",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is the point of intersection of perpendicular tangents to the ellipse 9x^2\u00a0+ 4y^2\u00a0= 36?",
                "correct_ans": "(1,2\\sqrt3)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46658": {
                "ans1": "2\u0394",
                "ans2": "\u0394",
                "ans3": "4\u0394",
                "ans4": "\u0394/2",
                "question_text": "If the area of \u0394ABC\u00a0is\u00a0\u0394\u00a0then,\u00a0a^2\\sin{(2B)} + b^2\\sin{(2A)} =",
                "correct_ans": "4\u0394",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40847": {
                "ans1": "1/3 sq. unit",
                "ans2": "1/6 sq. unit",
                "ans3": "2/3 sq. unit",
                "ans4": "1 sq. unit",
                "question_text": "The area of the region bounded by\u00a0y^2= x, y= |x|\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "1/6 sq. unit",
                "explanation": "Area\u00a0=\\int_{0}^{1}{\\sqrt{x}-x}\\text{ d}x= \\dfrac{1}{6} \\text{ sq. unit}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47556": {
                "ans1": " also unit vectors",
                "ans2": "of equal magnitude",
                "ans3": "collinear",
                "ans4": "perpendicular",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0are unit vectors then \u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0+\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0and\u00a0\\vec{a}\u00a0\u2013\u00a0\\vec{b}\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "perpendicular",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46653": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "50",
                "ans3": "5\u221a2",
                "ans4": "\u221a2",
                "question_text": "If projection of any line on coordinate axes are 3,4, and 5 then its length is",
                "correct_ans": "5\u221a2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42399": {
                "ans1": "(\u2212\u221e,e)",
                "ans2": "(0,e)",
                "ans3": "(0,2e)",
                "ans4": "(1/e,2e)",
                "question_text": "The function f(x)=lnx/x is increasing in the interval",
                "correct_ans": "(0,e)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44159": {
                "ans1": "(-1,-1)",
                "ans2": "(0,-1)",
                "ans3": "(1,1)",
                "ans4": "(-1,0)",
                "question_text": "The circumcentre of a triangle formed by the lines xy + 2x + 2y + 4 = 0 and x + y + 2 = 0 is",
                "correct_ans": "(-1,-1)",
                "explanation": "xy + 2x + 2y + 4 = 0 .......(i)\nx+y+ 2 = 0...............(ii)\nFrom (i) & (ii),\nxy=0 = x=0, y = 0In rt. angeled triangle circumcentre is the midpoint of the hypotenuse, hence circumcentre=(-1,-1)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49300": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1/4",
                "ans3": "1/3",
                "ans4": "1/2",
                "question_text": "\\log\\;2\\;-\\frac{\\log^22}{2!}+\\frac{\\log^32}{3!}-.....\\infty=",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46138": {
                "ans1": "tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans2": "1/2 tan(x/2) - log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans3": "-tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "ans4": "sin x + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "question_text": "\\frac d{dx}x\\log(1+\\cos x)=",
                "correct_ans": "-tan(x/2) + log (1 + cos x) + c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42032": {
                "ans1": "30\u00b0",
                "ans2": "60\u00b0",
                "ans3": "90\u00b0",
                "ans4": "45\u00b0",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In a\u00a0\u0394\u00a0ABC, a = 2b and A = 3B, then the angle A is:",
                "correct_ans": "90\u00b0",
                "explanation": "Here,\u00a0a = 2bsinA = 2sinB2sinB = sin(3B)2sinB - 3sinB + 4sin^3B = 0sinB(1 - 4sin^2B) = 0sinB = \\dfrac{1}{2}B = 30\u00b0A = 3 \\times 30\u00b0= 90",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45306": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "36",
                "ans4": "49",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the y-axis, the curve\u00a0x^2=4(y-2) and the line\u00a0y = 11 is",
                "correct_ans": "36",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45225": {
                "ans1": "\\tan\\frac x2+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}4+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}2+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan{\\displaystyle\\frac x2}}8+c",
                "question_text": "\u222b(1\u2212cosx+cos^2x\u2212cos^3x+..........)dx, for \u00a0|cos x| \\neq 1, is",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan\\frac x2+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40714": {
                "ans1": " ln |sin3x| + ln |sin2x| + ln |sinx| + c",
                "ans2": " ln |sec3x|. ln |sec2x| .ln |secx| + c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec\\;3x\\vert)}3-\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec2x\\vert)}2-\\log\\vert secx\\vert+c",
                "ans4": "both a and c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\tan\\;x.\\tan\\;2x.\\tan\\;3x\\;dx\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\;",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec\\;3x\\vert)}3-\\frac{(\\log\\vert sec2x\\vert)}2-\\log\\vert secx\\vert+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41981": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\cos\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2y-1}{\\cos\\;x}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2y-1}{\\sin\\;x}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sin\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "question_text": "If y =\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+\\sqrt{\\sin\\;x\\;+........}}}then dy/dx =",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\cos\\;x}{2y-1}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44806": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\tan^4x}4+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan^2x}5+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan^{-1}x}5+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin^4x}{\\cos^6x}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44202": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "3/4",
                "ans4": "19/9",
                "question_text": "The projection of the vector\u00a0\\vec{i} - 2\\overrightarrow{j} + \\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0on the vector\u00a04\\overrightarrow{i} - 4 \\overrightarrow{j} + 7\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "19/9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45627": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "9",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the coefficient of\u00a0x^7 in the expansion of\u00a0(1 + x) (1 + x^2 ) (1 + x^3) . . . . . . (1 + x^{100})",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "(0,7),(1.6),(2,5),(3,4)=4\u00a0ways(1,2,4) =1(1,2,4)=1\u00a0waysTotal =\u00a055\u00a0ways",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48203": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\u00a0\\log \\tan1^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 2^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 3^{\\circ}+\\cdots+\\log \\tan 89^{\\circ}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49869": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "16",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "If a function\u00a0f(x)=x^2 + \\dfrac{a}{x}\u200b\u00a0has a local minimum at\u00a0x=2 , then a=",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44734": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "A line makes angle \u03b1,\u03b2,\u03b3\u00a0with x- axis and z- axis respectively then cos2\u03b1+cos2\u03b2+cos2\u03b3\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49639": {
                "ans1": "-2",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a,b,c are in AP then the sum of coefficient of\u00a0\u00a0(1+( ax^2 -2bx + c))^{10}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "a,b,c are in AP\u00a0=> 2b = a + c => a-2b+c=0putting\u00a0x=1 ,\u00a0 required sum\u00a0= ( 1+a-2b+c)^{10} = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47154": {
                "ans1": "4,5",
                "ans2": "-4,7",
                "ans3": "-4,3",
                "ans4": "13,7",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0(2+i\\sqrt{3})\u00a0is a root of the equation\u00a0x^2+px+ q =0\u00a0then the value of\u00a0p\u00a0and\u00a0q\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "-4,7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44888": {
                "ans1": "H^2",
                "ans2": "4H^2",
                "ans3": "2H^2",
                "ans4": "16H^2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the pair of straight line Ax^2 + 2Hxy + By^2 forms the equilateral triangle with line ax+by + c=0 then the value of (A+3B)(B+3A) is",
                "correct_ans": "4H^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41955": {
                "ans1": "(a+b+c)",
                "ans2": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans3": "2abc(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans4": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{vmatrix}a-b-c&2a&2a\\\\2b&b-c-a&2b\\\\2c&2c&c-a-b\\end{vmatrix} =",
                "correct_ans": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46468": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "96",
                "ans3": "216",
                "ans4": "240",
                "question_text": "In how many ways number divisible by 3 can be formed from the integers 0,1,2,3,4,5 if each number so formed consists of different digits.",
                "correct_ans": "240",
                "explanation": "Taking 5 digits combination sum;The sum of (1+2+3+4+5) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 so 5!The sum of (0+1+2+3+4) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 is, 4\u00d74\u00d73\u00d72\u00d71=96Total =\u00a0216216",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42075": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{2c^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac2{c^2}",
                "question_text": "The circle\u00a0x^2+y^2+2ax+c^2 =0 and\u00a0x^2+y^2+2by+c^2=0\u00a0touches if",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47514": {
                "ans1": "cos\u03b8+isin\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos9\u03b8+isin9\u03b8",
                "ans3": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "ans4": "cos4\u03b8-isin4\u03b8",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\dfrac{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^4}{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^5} is",
                "correct_ans": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48783": {
                "ans1": "m+n",
                "ans2": "(m+n)/2",
                "ans3": "mn",
                "ans4": "m-n",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(p+q)^{th} and\u00a0(p-q)^{th}\u00a0term of an AP are respectively\u00a0m\u00a0and\u00a0n, then the\u00a0p^{th}\u00a0term is",
                "correct_ans": "(m+n)/2",
                "explanation": "(p+q)th=a+(p+q\u22121)d=m(p-q)^{th} = a + (p-q-1)d = nsum:2a + (2p-2)d = m + n2(a + (p-1)d) = m +np^{th} term = \\dfrac{m+n}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47395": {
                "ans1": "20 cm^2/2",
                "ans2": "40 cm^2/2",
                "ans3": "60 cm^2/s",
                "ans4": "80 cm^2/s",
                "question_text": "The length of a square is increasing at 6 cm/s. The rate of increase of area when the length of square is 5 cm/s",
                "correct_ans": "60 cm^2/s",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47586": {
                "ans1": "5h^2=ab",
                "ans2": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "ans3": "9h^2=5ab    ",
                "ans4": "h^2=ab",
                "question_text": "If slope of one line represented by ax^2+2hxy+by^2=0 is five times the slope of another line then",
                "correct_ans": "5h^2=9ab  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46982": {
                "ans1": "300m^2",
                "ans2": "-300 m^5",
                "ans3": "330m^7",
                "ans4": "-330m^7",
                "question_text": "The coefficient of x^{-3} in the expansion of \\left(x-\\frac mx\\right)^{11} is",
                "correct_ans": "-330m^7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46765": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "13",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "15",
                "question_text": "The number of terms in the expansion of (2x+y+8z)^4 are",
                "correct_ans": "15",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47702": {
                "ans1": "4 sq. units    ",
                "ans2": "10 sq. units    ",
                "ans3": "25/2 sq. units    ",
                "ans4": "25/4 sq. units",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by curve y=2x-4, y=1 and y-axis is",
                "correct_ans": "25/4 sq. units",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42149": {
                "ans1": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans2": "\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans3": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}-e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "ans4": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}-e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{e^x-1}{e^x+1}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "2\\log(e^{\\textstyle\\frac x2}+e^{\\textstyle\\frac{-x}2})+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43459": {
                "ans1": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi2",
                "ans2": "(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4+\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans3": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4-\\frac\\pi3",
                "ans4": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4+\\frac\\pi3",
                "question_text": "The general solution of \\sqrt3cosx + sinx =\\sqrt2 is",
                "correct_ans": "n\\pi+(-1)^n\\frac\\pi4-\\frac\\pi3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43445": {
                "ans1": "9/4  ",
                "ans2": "\u00bd",
                "ans3": "\u00bc",
                "ans4": "1/8",
                "question_text": "The sum of all terms of geometric sequence is equals to 5/4 times the sum of all odd terms of the following series. The common ratio of series is",
                "correct_ans": "\u00bc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41127": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "ans2": " -\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "ans3": "-\\frac{1+x^2}x+c",
                "ans4": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x}}x+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{dx}{x^2\\sqrt{1+x^2}}=",
                "correct_ans": "-\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x^2}}x+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48518": {
                "ans1": "\u221a2 sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "2 sq. units     ",
                "ans3": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "ans4": "\u221a3/2 units",
                "question_text": "If a=2 and \\frac a{\\cos A}=\\frac b{\\cos{\\displaystyle B}}=\\frac c{\\cos{\\displaystyle C}} then area of \u0394ABC is",
                "correct_ans": "\u221a3 sq. units   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43314": {
                "ans1": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans2": "x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "ans3": "x+5y-3z=7  ",
                "ans4": "x-5y+3z=7",
                "question_text": "The equation of plane passing through (1,1,1) and (2,0,3) & perpendicular to plane x+2y-3z=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "-x+5y+3z=7   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44616": {
                "ans1": "scalene",
                "ans2": "isosceles",
                "ans3": " equilateral   ",
                "ans4": "right angle",
                "question_text": "If semi perimeter is equal to ex-radius\u00a0 of a triangle is",
                "correct_ans": "right angle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46931": {
                "ans1": "c/b   ",
                "ans2": "b/c   ",
                "ans3": "a/b   ",
                "ans4": "b/a",
                "question_text": "\\frac{c-a\\cos B}{b-a\\cos C}=",
                "correct_ans": "b/c   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46036": {
                "ans1": "e^{a^2}+e^{b^2}",
                "ans2": "e^a+e^b",
                "ans3": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "ans4": "e^a-e^b",
                "question_text": "(a^2-b^2)+\\left(\\frac{a^4-b^4}{2!}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{a^6-b^6}{3!}\\right)+..........=",
                "correct_ans": "e^{a^2}-e^{b^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41121": {
                "ans1": "(2,\u221216),(\u22122,16)",
                "ans2": "(0,2),(2,16)",
                "ans3": "(0,\u22122),(2,\u221216)",
                "ans4": "(2,16),(\u22122,\u221216)",
                "question_text": "The points of the curve\u00a0y = 12x-x^3 at which the gradient is zero are",
                "correct_ans": "(2,16),(\u22122,\u221216)",
                "explanation": "Gradient means the slope of the tangent.The slope of the tangent is given by,\\frac{\\mathrm dy}{\\mathrm d x} =12-3x^2 = 0x= \\pm 2 at\\;x=2,\\\\y=12\\ast2-2^3=16\\\\at\\;x=-2,\\\\y=12\\ast(-2)-{(-2)}^3=-16\\\\so, the points are (2, 16) and (-2, -16).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43366": {
                "ans1": "3,12",
                "ans2": "4,9",
                "ans3": "2,18",
                "ans4": "7,6",
                "question_text": "The G.M. of two numbers is 6 and the A.M. is 6.5 then the numbers are:",
                "correct_ans": "4,9",
                "explanation": "\u00a0For\u00a0option\u00a0bG M= \\sqrt{4 \\times 9}=6A M= \\dfrac{4+9}{2}=6.5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44864": {
                "ans1": "cos\u03b8\u2212\u03b8cos\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos\u03b8\u2212\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "ans3": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8cos\u03b8",
                "ans4": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{x\\cos\\theta-\\theta\\cos x}{x-\\theta}=",
                "correct_ans": "cos\u03b8+\u03b8sin\u03b8",
                "explanation": "Using the L-Hospital rule,\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{\\displaystyle\\frac{\\operatorname d\\left(x\\cos\\theta-\\theta\\cos x\\right)}{\\operatorname dx}}{\\displaystyle\\frac{\\operatorname d\\left(x-\\theta\\right)}{\\operatorname dx}}=\\lim_{x\\rightarrow\\theta}\\frac{1.\\cos\\theta-\\theta.\\left(-\\sin x\\right)}{1-0}\\\\=\\cos\\theta+\\theta\\sin\\theta\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46704": {
                "ans1": "3\ud835\udc65\u22122\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67\u22127=0",
                "ans2": "2\ud835\udc65+3\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67\u221219=0",
                "ans3": "\u22123\ud835\udc65+2\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc65\u221249=0",
                "ans4": "3\ud835\udc65\u22122\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc67+7=0",
                "question_text": "If the length of the perpendicular drawn from the origin on a plane is 7 units and its direction ratios are -3, 2, 6 then the plane is",
                "correct_ans": "\u22123\ud835\udc65+2\ud835\udc66+6\ud835\udc65\u221249=0",
                "explanation": "Direction ratios of normal = -3, 2, 6l=\\frac a{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac{-3}{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac{-3}7\\\\m=\\frac b{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac2{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac27\\\\n=\\frac c{\\sqrt{a^2+b^2+c^2}}=\\frac6{\\sqrt{{(-3)}^2+2^2+6^2}}=\\frac67Equation of plane in normal form: \\frac{-3}7x+\\frac27y+\\frac67z=7\\\\-3x+2y+6z=49\\\\-3x+2y+6z-49=0\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48814": {
                "ans1": "a+b+c",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "4abc",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "The value of the determinant\u00a0\\left| \\begin{array}{ccc}a & a + b & a + c \\\\ 2 a & 2 a + 3 b & 2 a + 3 c \\\\ 3 a & 3 a + 4 b & 3 a + 4 c \\end{array} \\right|=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "Solving by Put Method:Put a = b= c =1\\left| \\begin{array}{ccc}1 & 2 &2 \\\\2 & 5 & 5 \\\\ 3& 7 & 7 \\end{array} \\right|=0C_2Now calculate value of options:a) 1+1+1=3b) 0c) 4*1*1*1=4d) 1So, the answer is 0= option(b).-Watch this lecture to find determinants by shortcuts, ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43070": {
                "ans1": "2 n\u03c0",
                "ans2": "n\u03c0",
                "ans3": "n\u03c0 + n/2",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "\\frac{3+2i\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}\u200b\u00a0will be real if \u03b8=",
                "correct_ans": "n\u03c0",
                "explanation": "\\frac{3+2i\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}=\\frac3{1-2\\sin\\theta}+\\frac{2\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}i\\\\The\\;given\\;complex\\;number\\;will\\;be\\;real\\;if,\\\\imaginary\\;part=0\\\\\\frac{2\\sin\\theta}{1-2\\sin\\theta}=0\\\\sin\\theta=0\\\\\\Rightarrow sin\\theta=\\sin0\\\\\\Rightarrow\\theta=n\\pi+{(-1)}^n.0\\;\\;\\lbrack Genral\\;solution\\rbrack\\theta = n\\pi",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42065": {
                "ans1": "x-y-1=0",
                "ans2": "x+y-1=0",
                "ans3": "x-y+1=0",
                "ans4": "x+y+1=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the straight line equally inclined to the axes and equidistant from the points (1, - 2) and (3,4) is:",
                "correct_ans": "x-y-1=0",
                "explanation": "The line which is equally inclined to the axes (i.e. both X-axis & Y-axis) makes an angle of 45 degrees with +ve X-axis.so, the slope of the line is given by,m=tan45=1now. let the equation of line be,y=mx+cy=1.x+cy=x+cx-y+c=0Now, the line is equidistant from the given two points A(1, - 2) and B(3,4).so, equating perpendicular distances from these points:\\pm\\frac{1\\ast1-1(-2)+c}{\\sqrt{1^2+{(-1)}^2}}=\\pm\\frac{1\\ast3-1\\ast4+c}{\\sqrt{1^2+{(-1)}^2}}\\\\\\Rightarrow Taking\\;+ve\\;on\\;both\\;sides,\\\\\\Rightarrow1+2+c=3-4+c\\Rightarrow3=1\\;(not\\;ok)\\\\\\\\\\Rightarrow Taking\\;-ve\\;on\\;left\\;side,\\\\\\Rightarrow-(1+2+c)=3-4+c\\Rightarrow-3-c=-1+c\\\\\\Rightarrow-2=2c\\Rightarrow c=-1\\\\\\\\So, the equation of the line is:x-y-1=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48100": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "\u221e",
                "question_text": "derivative of\u00a0log_e e^x\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "Here,\\\\y=\\log_ee^x=x\\;\\\\(\\sin ce\\;\\log_e\\;and\\;e\\;are\\;inverse\\;of\\;each,\\;they\\;cancel\\;out.)\\\\So,\\;derivative\\;is\\;given\\;by:\\\\\\frac{\\operatorname d\\log_ee^x}{\\operatorname dx}=\\frac{\\operatorname dx}{\\operatorname dx}=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44528": {
                "ans1": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|=\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans2": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|<\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are two vectors then\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}-\\overrightarrow{b}= \\overrightarrow{b}-\\overrightarrow{a} if",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b=\\overrightarrow b-\\overrightarrow a\\\\\\Rightarrow2\\overrightarrow a=2\\overrightarrow b\\Rightarrow\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49376": {
                "ans1": "A",
                "ans2": "B",
                "ans3": "\u03d5",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "If A&B\u00a0are two disjoint sets , then the intersection of\u00a0A\u00a0and\u00a0B\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\u03d5",
                "explanation": "Two set are disjoint means,\u00a0A\u00a0and\u00a0B\u00a0doesn't have any common elements.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48656": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert\\;dx\\;=",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\;Since,\\;\\int\\left|x\\right|dx=\\frac{x\\left|x\\right|}2+c\\\\\\int_0^4\\vert x-2\\vert\\;dx\\;=\\left(\\frac{(x-2)\\left|x-2\\right|}2\\right)_0^4\\\\=\\left\\{\\frac{(4-2)\\left|4-2\\right|}2\\right\\}-\\left\\{\\frac{(0-2)\\left|0-2\\right|}2\\right\\}\\\\=\\frac{2\\ast2}2-\\frac{(-2)\\ast2}2=2+2=4Note: You can use the calculator to get the value directly.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46816": {
                "ans1": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow b}{\\overrightarrow a}",
                "ans2": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow a}{\\overrightarrow b}",
                "ans3": "x=y=0",
                "ans4": "x+y=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are non zero and non collinear and\u00a0x \\overrightarrow{a} + y \\overrightarrow{b} = 0\u00a0 where\u00a0x\u00a0and\u00a0y\u00a0are scalars then,",
                "correct_ans": "x=y=0",
                "explanation": "Since the vectors are linearly independent.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40735": {
                "ans1": "-\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans2": "\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans3": "\\frac{cosx}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "ans4": "\\frac{sinx}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "question_text": "What is the derivative of\u00a0\\sqrt{\\sin x}\u200b\u00a0with respect to\u00a0x?",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "explanation": "\\frac{d\\sqrt{\\sin x}}{dx} = \\frac{d\\sqrt{\\sin x}}{d\\sin x}.\\frac{d{\\sin x}}{dx}  \\frac{1}{2\\sqrt{sinx}}.cosx  ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46670": {
                "ans1": "18/25",
                "ans2": "50/9",
                "ans3": "18/5",
                "ans4": "9/25",
                "question_text": "The length of the latus rectum of the ellipse\u00a0\\dfrac{x^{2}}{25} + \\dfrac{y^{2}}{9}=125 is:\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "18/5",
                "explanation": "a^2 = 25b^2 = 9a>b\\frac{2b^2}{a}\\frac{2*9}{5} = \\frac{18}{5}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47416": {
                "ans1": "n^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans2": "{(n+1)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans3": "{(2n)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\\\{(n-1)}^{th}\\;term",
                "question_text": "The term free from\u00a0x\u00a0in the expansion of\u00a0\\left(x + \\cfrac{1}{x} \\right)^{2 n} is:",
                "correct_ans": "{(n+1)}^{th}\\;term\\\\",
                "explanation": "The\\;term\\;containing\\;x^m\\;in\\;the\\;expansion\\;of\\;{(ax^\\alpha+\\frac b{x^\\beta})}^n\\;is\\;given\\;by:\\;\\\\{(r+1)}^{th}\\;term.r = \\frac{n\\alpha - m}{\\alpha+\\beta}x^0r=\\frac{1.2n-0}{1+1}r=n(n+1{)^{th}\\;}term",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48639": {
                "ans1": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow b}{\\overrightarrow a}",
                "ans2": "x\\;=\\;-\\frac{y\\overrightarrow a}{\\overrightarrow b}",
                "ans3": "x=y=0",
                "ans4": "x+y=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are non zero and non collinear and\u00a0x \\overrightarrow{a} + y \\overrightarrow{b} = 0\u00a0 where\u00a0x\u00a0and\u00a0y\u00a0are scalars then,",
                "correct_ans": "x=y=0",
                "explanation": "Since the vectors are linearly independent.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42069": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{3}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{-3}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{-2}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0y=cos^{-1}(4x^3-3x), then \\frac{dy}{dx}=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{-3}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "explanation": "cos\\thetay=cos^{-1}(4cos^3\\theta - 3cos\\theta)cos^{-1}(cos3\\theta)=3\\theta =3cos^{-1}x: \\frac{dy}{dx}=\\frac{-3}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45696": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1 ",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "both b and c",
                "question_text": "The solution of the equation\u00a0log_2(3-x)+log_2(1-x)=3 is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "-1 ",
                "explanation": "\\log_2\\left(\\left(3-x\\right)\\left(1-x\\right)\\right)\\log_2\\left(3-3x-x+x^2\\right)=3x^2 - 4x + 3 = 2^3x^2-4x-5=0(x+1)(x-5)=0=> -1,5At x=5 LHS is not definedx=-1 is the only solution",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45646": {
                "ans1": "\\sin(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "ans2": "\\cos(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "ans3": "\\tan(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "ans4": "\\cot(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "question_text": "\\int \\frac{xe^x}{cos^2(xe^x-e^x)}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\tan(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "explanation": "put xe^x-e^x=t(xe^t+e^t-e^x)dx = dtxe^xdx = dtI= \\int\\frac{dt}{cos^2t}=\\int sec^2t dt=tant+ctan(xe^x-e^x)+c",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46978": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "cot(cot^{-1}x+cot^{-1}y+cot^{-1}z )",
                "ans4": "\\pi",
                "question_text": "tan(tan^{-1}x+tan^{-1}y+tan^{-1}z )= ",
                "correct_ans": "cot(cot^{-1}x+cot^{-1}y+cot^{-1}z )",
                "explanation": "put x=2 , y=3,z=4tan(tan^{-1}x+tan^{-1}y+tan^{-1}z = 0.6cot(cot^{-1}2+cot^{-1}3+cot^{-1}4 )= 0.6option (C) is correct",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48165": {
                "ans1": "8/3",
                "ans2": "16/3",
                "ans3": "32/3",
                "ans4": "64/3",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the curve\u00a0y^2 = 8x , \u00a0the x-axis and its latus rectum is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "16/3",
                "explanation": "\\int_0 ^2 \\sqrt{8x} dx = \\frac{16}{3}sq. units",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44769": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{vmatrix}k&2k\\\\2k&4k\\end{vmatrix}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{vmatrix}1&2k\\\\3&4k\\end{vmatrix}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{vmatrix}1&2k\\\\3k&4k\\end{vmatrix}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{vmatrix}k&2k\\\\3k&4\\end{vmatrix}",
                "question_text": "If A=\u00a0\\begin{bmatrix} 1 & 2 \\\\[0.3em] 3 & 4 \\\\[0.3em] \\end{bmatrix}, then k |A|",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{vmatrix}1&2k\\\\3&4k\\end{vmatrix}",
                "explanation": "|A|\u00a0= 4-2*3 = -2k|A| = -2kOn expanding , only option (b) gives the value -2k.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47661": {
                "ans1": "7^\\frac{n+1}{2}",
                "ans2": "7^\\frac{n}{2}",
                "ans3": "7^\\frac{n-1}{2}",
                "ans4": "7^\\frac{n}{4}",
                "question_text": "Geometric mean of 7,7^2,7^3.....7^n is",
                "correct_ans": "7^\\frac{n+1}{2}",
                "explanation": "GM=(7*7^2*7^3*.........*7^n)^{\\frac{1}{n}}7^{\\frac{n(n+1)}{2n}} = 7^\\frac{n+1}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43082": {
                "ans1": "-2x^2+2x+1",
                "ans2": "-x^2+x+1",
                "ans3": "-3x^2+3x+1",
                "ans4": "2x^2-3x+1",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0f(x) = ax^2+bx+c , f(0) = 1 \u00a0and\u00a0f'(0) = 2 , then f(x) = ",
                "correct_ans": "-2x^2+2x+1",
                "explanation": "f(0) = 1=> a*0+b*0+c = 1 => c=1f(1) = 1 => a+b+c =1 => a+b+1 = 1=> a=-bf'(x)=2ax+bGiven , f'(0)=2=> 2=2a*(0) +b => b=2a=-2f(x) = -2x^2+2x+1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44732": {
                "ans1": "(6,-12,12)",
                "ans2": "(6,12,-12)",
                "ans3": "(-6,12,12)",
                "ans4": "(1,-2,2)",
                "question_text": "Distance of P from origin is 6. The dc's of OP are 1,-2,2 . Then the coordinates of P are(IOE 2074)",
                "correct_ans": "(6,-12,12)",
                "explanation": "\\frac{x_1-0}{OP},\\frac{y_1-0}{OP},\\frac{z_1-0}{OP}\\frac{x_1-0}{OP} = 1 => \\frac{x_1}{6}=>x_1=6\\frac{y_1-0}{OP} = -2 =>y_1=-12\\frac{z_1-0}{OP} = 2 => z_1=12coordinates of P are (6,-12,12)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41886": {
                "ans1": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|=\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans2": "\\left|\\overrightarrow a\\right|<\\left|\\overrightarrow b\\right|",
                "ans3": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "ans4": "\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b=0",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}\u00a0and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0are two vectors then\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}-\\overrightarrow{b}= \\overrightarrow{b}-\\overrightarrow{a} if",
                "correct_ans": "\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b=\\overrightarrow b-\\overrightarrow a\\\\\\Rightarrow2\\overrightarrow a=2\\overrightarrow b\\Rightarrow\\overrightarrow a=\\overrightarrow b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47440": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\pi}{3}",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\pi}{4}",
                "ans3": "\\frac{2\\pi}{3}",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\pi}{6}",
                "question_text": "\\overrightarrow{a},\\overrightarrow{b},\\overrightarrow{c} \u00a0are unit vectors and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a} + \\overrightarrow{b} +\\overrightarrow{c}=0 \u00a0then angle between\u00a0\\overrightarrow{a}and\u00a0\\overrightarrow{b}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{2\\pi}{3}",
                "explanation": "\\overrightarrow{a}+\\overrightarrow{b}+\\overrightarrow{c}=0\\overrightarrow{a} + \\overrightarrow{b} = -\\overrightarrow{c}(\\overrightarrow{a}+\\overrightarrow{b})^2=(-\\overrightarrow{c})^2a^2+b^2+2abcos\\theta = c^21+1+2*1*1cos\\theta =1cos\\theta = -\\frac{1}{2}\\theta = \\frac{2\\pi}{3}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41366": {
                "ans1": "-1",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "e^a-e^b",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x \\to 0} \\frac{e^{ax}-e^{bx}}{e^x}=",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "use formula\u00a0\\frac{1-1}{1}=0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41954": {
                "ans1": "\\log\\left(\\frac e2\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{\\frac e2}\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{\\frac2e}\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\log\\left(\\frac e3\\right)",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^{\\frac{\\pi}{4}} sin^3x.sec^3x dx=\u00a0?",
                "correct_ans": "\\log\\left(\\sqrt{\\frac e2}\\right)",
                "explanation": "I=\\int_0^{\\frac{\\pi}{4}} \\frac{sin^3x}{cos^3x}dx\\int_0^\\frac{\\pi}{4}tan^3xdx\\int_0^\\frac{\\pi}{4} (sec^2x -1).tanx dx[\\frac{tan^2x}{2}-logsecx]_0^\\frac{\\pi}{4}(\\frac{1}{2}-0)-(log \\sqrt{2} -0)=\\frac{1}{2} - \\frac{1}{2}log2\\frac{1}{2}(loge-log2)=log\\sqrt{\\frac{e}{2}}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46011": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt3",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{\\sqrt3}",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0tan^{-1}x + 4cot^{-1}x=\\pi\u00a0, then x=",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt3",
                "explanation": "tan^{-1}x + cot^{-1}x + 3cot^{-1}x=\\pi=> \\frac{\\pi}{2} + 3cot^{-1}x = \\pix=cot{\\frac{\\pi}{6}}=\\sqrt{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47425": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{\\tan^4x}4+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\tan^2x}5+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\tan^{-1}x}5+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\sin^4x}{\\cos^6x}dx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\tan^5x}5+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43427": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "3/4",
                "ans4": "19/9",
                "question_text": "The projection of the vector\u00a0\\vec{i} - 2\\overrightarrow{j} + \\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0on the vector\u00a04\\overrightarrow{i} - 4 \\overrightarrow{j} + 7\\overrightarrow{k}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "19/9",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44924": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "9",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the coefficient of\u00a0x^7 in the expansion of\u00a0(1 + x) (1 + x^2 ) (1 + x^3) . . . . . . (1 + x^{100})",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "(0,7),(1.6),(2,5),(3,4)=4\u00a0ways(1,2,4) =1(1,2,4)=1\u00a0waysTotal =\u00a055\u00a0ways",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40744": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "can't be determined",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\u00a0\\log \\tan1^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 2^{\\circ}+\\log \\tan 3^{\\circ}+\\cdots+\\log \\tan 89^{\\circ}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47699": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "16",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "If a function\u00a0f(x)=x^2 + \\dfrac{a}{x}\u200b\u00a0has a local minimum at\u00a0x=2 , then a=",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47763": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "A line makes angle \u03b1,\u03b2,\u03b3\u00a0with x- axis and z- axis respectively then cos2\u03b1+cos2\u03b2+cos2\u03b3\u00a0is equal to",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48379": {
                "ans1": "-2",
                "ans2": "-1",
                "ans3": "0",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If a,b,c are in AP then the sum of coefficient of\u00a0\u00a0(1+( ax^2 -2bx + c))^{10}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "a,b,c are in AP\u00a0=> 2b = a + c => a-2b+c=0putting\u00a0x=1 ,\u00a0 required sum\u00a0= ( 1+a-2b+c)^{10} = 1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46073": {
                "ans1": "4,5",
                "ans2": "-4,7",
                "ans3": "-4,3",
                "ans4": "13,7",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If\u00a0(2+i\\sqrt{3})\u00a0is a root of the equation\u00a0x^2+px+ q =0\u00a0then the value of\u00a0p\u00a0and\u00a0q\u00a0are",
                "correct_ans": "-4,7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44441": {
                "ans1": "H^2",
                "ans2": "4H^2",
                "ans3": "2H^2",
                "ans4": "16H^2",
                "question_text": "\u00a0If the pair of straight line Ax^2 + 2Hxy + By^2 forms the equilateral triangle with line ax+by + c=0 then the value of (A+3B)(B+3A) is",
                "correct_ans": "4H^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47107": {
                "ans1": "(a+b+c)",
                "ans2": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans3": "2abc(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans4": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{vmatrix}a-b-c&2a&2a\\\\2b&b-c-a&2b\\\\2c&2c&c-a-b\\end{vmatrix} =",
                "correct_ans": "(a+b+c)^{\\;\\;3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44942": {
                "ans1": "120",
                "ans2": "96",
                "ans3": "216",
                "ans4": "240",
                "question_text": "In how many ways number divisible by 3 can be formed from the integers 0,1,2,3,4,5 if each number so formed consists of different digits.",
                "correct_ans": "240",
                "explanation": "Taking 5 digits combination sum;The sum of (1+2+3+4+5) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 so 5!The sum of (0+1+2+3+4) =15 is exactly divisible by 3 is, 4\u00d74\u00d73\u00d72\u00d71=96Total =\u00a0216216",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47196": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{a^2}+\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{2c^2}",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac2{c^2}",
                "question_text": "The circle\u00a0x^2+y^2+2ax+c^2 =0 and\u00a0x^2+y^2+2by+c^2=0\u00a0touches if",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{a^2}-\\frac1{b^2}=\\frac1{c^2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43046": {
                "ans1": "cos\u03b8+isin\u03b8",
                "ans2": "cos9\u03b8+isin9\u03b8",
                "ans3": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "ans4": "cos4\u03b8-isin4\u03b8",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0\\dfrac{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^4}{(\\cos\\theta+i \\sin\\theta)^5} is",
                "correct_ans": "cos\u03b8-isin\u03b8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41032": {
                "ans1": "m+n",
                "ans2": "(m+n)/2",
                "ans3": "mn",
                "ans4": "m-n",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0(p+q)^{th} and\u00a0(p-q)^{th}\u00a0term of an AP are respectively\u00a0m\u00a0and\u00a0n, then the\u00a0p^{th}\u00a0term is",
                "correct_ans": "(m+n)/2",
                "explanation": "(p+q)th=a+(p+q\u22121)d=m(p-q)^{th} = a + (p-q-1)d = nsum:2a + (2p-2)d = m + n2(a + (p-1)d) = m +np^{th} term = \\dfrac{m+n}{2}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44524": {
                "ans1": "x=1 is a point of maximum",
                "ans2": "x=-1 is a point of minimum",
                "ans3": "maximum value > minimum value",
                "ans4": "maximum value< minimum value",
                "question_text": "For the function\u00a0y=x+\\frac1x",
                "correct_ans": "maximum value< minimum value",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41696": {
                "ans1": "3/2",
                "ans2": "3/4",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "7",
                "question_text": "The area bound by the x axis and the curve\u00a0y=4x-x^2-3\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "4/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44272": {
                "ans1": "-3/2",
                "ans2": "1/2",
                "ans3": "2/3",
                "ans4": "3/2",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\overrightarrow a,\\overrightarrow b,\\overrightarrow c\\;are\\;unit\\;vectors\\;\\\\such\\;that\\;\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow c=0\\;,\\\\\\;then\\;\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b.\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c.\\overrightarrow a\\end{array}\\\\\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "-3/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48821": {
                "ans1": "abc",
                "ans2": "2abc",
                "ans3": "3abc",
                "ans4": "4abc",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}In\\;\\triangle ABC,\\;a(b^2+c^2)\\cos A\\;+\\\\\\;b(c^2+a^2)\\cos B\\;+\\\\\\;c(a^2+b^2)\\cos C\\;is\\;equal\\;to\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "3abc",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47955": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "16",
                "question_text": "If the slope of one of the lines represented by\u00a0ax^2+10xy+y^2=0 is four times the slope of other , then a is",
                "correct_ans": "16",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42221": {
                "ans1": "3/5",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{\\sqrt5}",
                "ans3": "1/2",
                "ans4": "4/5",
                "question_text": "In an ellipse , the distance between the foci is 6 and its minor axis is 8. Then, the eccentricity is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "3/5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42469": {
                "ans1": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans2": "1/2 cos n\u03b8",
                "ans3": "2n cos n\u03b8",
                "ans4": "n cos 2\u03b8",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x}=2\\cos\\theta\\;then\\\\\\;x^n+\\frac{\\displaystyle1}{\\displaystyle x^n}\\;is\\end{array}\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "2 cos n\u03b8",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;x+\\frac1x=2\\cos\\theta\\;\\rightarrow\\left(x+\\frac1x\\right)^2=\\;4\\cos^2\\theta\\rightarrow x^2+\\frac1{x^2}=2(2\\cos^2\\theta-1)=2\\cos2\\theta\\\\x^n+\\frac1{x^n}=2\\cos n\\theta\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47502": {
                "ans1": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac38",
                "ans2": "\\left|x\\right|<1",
                "ans3": "\\left|x\\right|>\\frac38",
                "ans4": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac43",
                "question_text": "The expansion of\u00a0 \\left(4-3x\\right)^{-\\frac35}\u00a0 \u00a0in terms od ascending powers of x is valid only if\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\left|x\\right|<\\frac43",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44990": {
                "ans1": "15 sq. units",
                "ans2": "75 sq. units",
                "ans3": "8 sq. units",
                "ans4": "4\\sqrt2\\;square\\;units",
                "question_text": "The tangents are drawn from the point (5,4) to the circle\u00a0 x^2+y^2-4x-2y-11=0\u00a0. The area of quadletrial formed by these tangents and the radii at the point of contact is",
                "correct_ans": "4\\sqrt2\\;square\\;units",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46350": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "-6",
                "question_text": "If the sum of n terms of an AP is\u00a03n^2+5n then its common difference is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42677": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "16",
                "question_text": "If A is a matrix of order 3 X 3 and |A| =2 , then |adj. A| is",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40373": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "The number of solutions of\u00a0\\log_4(x+1)=\\log_2(x-3)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45644": {
                "ans1": "x+y+z=0",
                "ans2": "17x+14y+11z=0",
                "ans3": "7x+4y+z=0",
                "ans4": "17x+14y+z=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of the plane through the intersection of the planes x+2y+3z-4=0 and 4x+3y+2z+1=0 and passing through origin is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "17x+14y+11z=0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46719": {
                "ans1": "\\sin^{-1}x-\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans2": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans3": "\\sin^{-1}x-\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "ans4": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "question_text": "Value of\u00a0\\int\\sqrt{\\frac{1-x}{1+x}}dx is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sin^{-1}x+\\frac12\\sqrt{1-x^2}+c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48874": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{xy}\\\\",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{2y-x}\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{2y-1}\\\\",
                "question_text": "If y=\u00a0\\sqrt{x+\\sqrt{x+\\sqrt{x+\\cdots}}}\\;then\\frac{dy}{dx}=\\\\",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{2y-1}\\\\",
                "explanation": "y=\\sqrt{x+y}\\\\y^2=x+y\\\\2y\\frac{dy}{dx}=1+\\frac{dy}{dx}\\Rightarrow\\frac{dy}{dx}=\\frac1{2y-1}\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44416": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{x^2}2-x+2\\;\\tan^{-1}x+c\\\\",
                "ans2": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\;\\tan^{-1}x+c\\\\",
                "ans3": "x^2+\\log\\left(x^2+1\\right)+c\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\left(x^2-1\\right)^2}2+2log\\left(x^2+1\\right)+c\\\\",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{x^4+1}{x^2+1}dx\\\\",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\;\\tan^{-1}x+c\\\\",
                "explanation": "\\int\\frac{x^4+1}{x^2+1}dx=\\int\\frac{\\left(x^4-1\\right)+2}{x^2+1}dx\\\\=\\int\\left(x^2-1+\\frac2{x^2+1}\\right)dx\\\\\\frac{x^3}3-x+2\\;\\tan^{-1}x+c\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42063": {
                "ans1": "\\frac14",
                "ans2": "\\frac12",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}4",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "question_text": "The eccentricity of the conic section\u00a0x^2+4y^2-4x+24y+24=0\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "explanation": "e=\\sqrt{1-\\frac14}=\\frac{\\sqrt3}2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40733": {
                "ans1": "\\left(-\\infty,e\\right)",
                "ans2": "\\left(0,e\\right)",
                "ans3": "\\left(0,2e\\right)",
                "ans4": "\\left(\\frac1e,2e\\right)",
                "question_text": "The function f(x) =\u00a0\\frac{\\log_ex}x\u00a0is increasing in the interval",
                "correct_ans": "\\left(0,e\\right)",
                "explanation": "F'\\left(x\\right)=\\frac1{x^2}-\\frac{\\log_ex}{x^2}=\\frac{1-\\log_ex}{x^2}\\\\For\\;1-\\log_ex>0\\Rightarrow1>\\log_ex\\Rightarrow e>x\\\\f\\mathit{\\left(x\\right)}is\\mathit\\;increasing\\mathit\\;in\\mathit{\\left({0,e}\\right)}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45801": {
                "ans1": "e",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "1-\\frac1e",
                "ans4": "1+\\frac1e",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the curve Y=Inx, then x- axis and the straight line\u00a0 x=e is",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "In X-axis, put y=0\\Rightarrow x=1\\\\Area=\\int_1^elnx\\;dx=\\left[x\\;lnx-x\\right]_1^e\\\\=\\left(e\\;lne-e\\right)-\\left(0-1\\right)=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42713": {
                "ans1": "(5,5)",
                "ans2": "(5 , 10)",
                "ans3": "( 10, 5)",
                "ans4": "(10, 10)",
                "question_text": "The pole of the straight line x+2y=1 with respect to the circle\u00a0x^2+y^2=5\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "(5 , 10)",
                "explanation": "Let\\;\\left(x_1,y_1\\right)be\\;the\\;pole.\\;Then\\;the\\;equation\\;of\\;polar\\;is\\\\xx_1+yy_1=5\\dots\\left(1\\right)\\\\Since\\;equation\\;\\left(1\\right)\\&\\;x+2y=1\\;represent\\;the\\;same\\;\\\\straight\\;line,so\\\\\\frac{x_1}1=\\frac{y^1}2=\\frac51\\\\x_1=5,y_1=10\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;pole=\\left(5,10\\right)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48602": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "If\u00a0\\left(\\frac{1+i}{1-i}\\right)^n=1\u00a0 then the least integral value of n is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\left(\\frac{1+i}{1-i}\\right)^n=\\left(\\frac{1+i}{1-i}\\times\\frac{1+i}{1+i}\\right)^n=i^n\\\\\\therefore i^n=1\\;so\\;,\\;least\\;value\\;of\\;n=4\\;\\;\\\\\\left(\\because i^4=1\\right)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45028": {
                "ans1": "15",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "31",
                "ans4": "32",
                "question_text": "In\u00a0 an examiation,a candidate has to pass in each of the 5 subject . In how many way can he fail?",
                "correct_ans": "31",
                "explanation": "={}^5C_1+{}^5C_2+{}^5C_3+",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47484": {
                "ans1": "6/17",
                "ans2": "3/17",
                "ans3": "4/17",
                "ans4": "5/17",
                "question_text": "The value of\u00a0cot\\;\\left(\\cos ec^{-1}\\frac53+\\tan^{-1}\\frac23\\right)\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "6/17",
                "explanation": "cot\\left(\\tan^{-1}\\frac34+\\tan^{-1}\\frac23\\right)=cot\\;\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{{\\displaystyle\\frac34}+{\\displaystyle\\frac23}}{1-{\\displaystyle\\frac34}{\\displaystyle\\frac23}}\\right)\\\\=cot\\;\\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{17}6\\right)=\\frac6{17}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47070": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "If a,b,c are in A.P. then\u00a0\u00a0\\frac{\\left(a-c\\right)^2}{b^2-ac}=",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "\\Rightarrow b=\\frac{a+c}2\\\\\\frac{\\left(a-c\\right)^2}{\\left({\\displaystyle\\frac{a+c}2}\\right)^2-ac}=\\frac{4\\left(a-c\\right)^2}{\\left(a-c\\right)^2}=4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43662": {
                "ans1": "400",
                "ans2": "600",
                "ans3": "300",
                "ans4": "200",
                "question_text": "Let n (U)=700, n (A)=200, n(B)=300 and\u00a0n\\left(A\\cap B\\right)=100\\;then\\;n\\left(A'\\cap B'\\right)=",
                "correct_ans": "300",
                "explanation": "n\\left(A^c\\cap B^c\\right)=n\\left(A\\cap B\\right)^c=n(U)-n(A\\cup B)\\\\=n(U)-n(A)-n(B)+n(A\\cap B)\\\\=700-200-300+100\\\\=300\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44956": {
                "ans1": "12",
                "ans2": "50",
                "ans3": "5\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "\\sqrt2",
                "question_text": "If the projection of any line on coordinate axes are 3,4, and 5 then its length is",
                "correct_ans": "5\\sqrt2",
                "explanation": "Let 'd' be the lenghtdl=3,\\;dm=4,\\;dn=5\\\\d^2\\left(l^2+m^2+n^2\\right)=50\\\\d^2\\left(1\\right)=50\\\\d=5\\sqrt2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41776": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "8",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "If\\;\\overrightarrow a,\\overrightarrow{b\\;}and\\;\\overrightarrow care\\;unit\\;vector,then\\;\\\\\\left|\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b\\right|^2\\;+\\left|\\overrightarrow b-\\overrightarrow c\\right|^2+\\left|\\overrightarrow c-\\overrightarrow a\\right|^2does\\;not\\;exceed",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "\\\\\\left|\\overrightarrow a-\\overrightarrow b\\right|^2\\;+\\left|\\overrightarrow b-\\overrightarrow c\\right|^2+\\left|\\overrightarrow c-\\overrightarrow a\\right|^2\\;\\\\=2\\left(a^2+b^2+c^2\\right)-2\\left(\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b.\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c.\\overrightarrow a\\right)\\\\=2\\times3-2\\left(\\overrightarrow a.\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow b.\\overrightarrow c+\\overrightarrow c.\\overrightarrow a\\right)\\\\=6-\\left\\{\\left(\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow c\\right)^2-a^2-b^2-c^2\\right\\}\\\\=9-\\left|\\overrightarrow a+\\overrightarrow b+\\overrightarrow c\\right|^2\\leq9",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48738": {
                "ans1": "( 1,1)",
                "ans2": "(1,0)",
                "ans3": "(1,-1)",
                "ans4": "(0,0)",
                "question_text": "On the parabola\u00a0y=x^2,\\;the\\;point\\;least\\;dis\\tan ce\\;from\\;the\\;straight\\;line\\;\\\\y=2x-4\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "( 1,1)",
                "explanation": "Parabola\\;y=x^2\\dots\\left(1\\right)\\\\Straight\\;line\\;y=2x-4\\dots\\left(2\\right)\\\\From\\left(1\\right)\\&\\left(2\\right)x^2-2x\\;+4=0\\\\Let\\;f\\left(x\\right)=x^2-2x+4\\\\f'\\left(x\\right)=2x-2\\\\for\\;least\\;dis\\tan ce,\\;f'\\left(x\\right)=0\\\\2x-2=0\\Rightarrow x=1\\;from\\;\\left(1\\right)\\\\y=1^2=1\\\\Point=\\left(1,1\\right)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "48400": {
                "ans1": "\\frac{672}{x^3}\\\\",
                "ans2": "672x^3\\\\",
                "ans3": "\\frac98x^{17}\\\\",
                "ans4": "\\frac89x^{17}\\\\",
                "question_text": "The Fourth term from the end in the expansion of\\left(\\frac{x^3}2-\\frac2{x^2}\\right)^9\\\\is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{672}{x^3}\\\\",
                "explanation": "4^{th}term\\;from\\;end\\;=7^{th}term\\;from\\;beginning\\\\t_7=t_{6+1}=\\left(-1\\right)^6\\;{}^9C_6\\left(\\frac{x^3}2\\right)^{9-6}.\\left(\\frac2{x^2}\\right)^6=\\frac{672}{x^3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40500": {
                "ans1": "n\u03c0\u00b1\u03c0/3",
                "ans2": "2n\u03c0\u00b1\u03c0/3     ",
                "ans3": "2n\u03c0\u00b1\u03c0/4   ",
                "ans4": "n\u03c0\u00b1\u03c0/6",
                "question_text": "The general solution of 2cosA cos3A + 1=0 is",
                "correct_ans": "n\u03c0\u00b1\u03c0/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42663": {
                "ans1": "5",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "The number\u00a0 of terms in the expansion of \\{{(a+4b)^2(a-4b)^2\\}}^3 are",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46573": {
                "ans1": " -\\frac1{2x^2}\\left(\\log_ex+\\frac12\\right)\\;+\\;c",
                "ans2": " \\frac1{2x^2}\\left(\\log_ex+\\frac12\\right)\\;+\\;c",
                "ans3": " -\\frac1{2x^2}\\left(\\log_ex-\\frac12\\right)\\;+\\;c",
                "ans4": " \\frac1{2x^2}\\left(\\log_ex-\\frac12\\right)\\;+\\;c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{\\log_ex}{x^3}dx=",
                "correct_ans": " -\\frac1{2x^2}\\left(\\log_ex+\\frac12\\right)\\;+\\;c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46467": {
                "ans1": "2^{10}-11\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "2^{10}-10\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "2^{10}-9\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "2^{10}-8\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": ". A student can solve 10 questions. In how many ways can he solve two or more questions?",
                "correct_ans": "2^{10}-11\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42757": {
                "ans1": "\\frac1{(1-x)^2}",
                "ans2": "\\frac1{(1-x)}",
                "ans3": "\\frac1{(1+x)^2}",
                "ans4": "\\frac1{(1-x)^3}",
                "question_text": "The\u00a0 sum of the given series is : 1\\;+\\;3x\\;+\\;6x^2\\;+\\;10x^3\\;+\\;\\dots\\dots\\dots.\\infty",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac1{(1-x)^3}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46967": {
                "ans1": "-n(2n+1)   ",
                "ans2": "-2n(4n+1)    ",
                "ans3": "\u2013(2n+1)(4n+3)    ",
                "ans4": "\u2013(2n-1)(4n-1)",
                "question_text": "The sum of nth term of series for odd value of n is\u00a0(1^2-2^2)+\\;(3^2-4^2)+\\;(5^2-6^2)+\\;(7^2-8^2)+\\;\\dots\\dots\\dots\\dots.",
                "correct_ans": "\u2013(2n-1)(4n-1)",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43530": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "-1/2",
                "ans3": "1",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "\\lim_{x\\rightarrow0}\\frac{\\left(\\log_e\\left(\\cos x\\right)\\right)}{x^2}=",
                "correct_ans": "-1/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49535": {
                "ans1": "2880",
                "ans2": "1400",
                "ans3": "1200",
                "ans4": "3212",
                "question_text": "The number of ways in which 5 boys and 5 girls can be sit in a circular table alternatively is",
                "correct_ans": "2880",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41381": {
                "ans1": "a=c",
                "ans2": "b=c",
                "ans3": "\\angle A=90^0\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "\\angle B=90^0\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "In \u0394ABC, 2cosBsinC=sinA then",
                "correct_ans": "b=c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45526": {
                "ans1": "16",
                "ans2": "8",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "If a, b and c are in AP and abc=64, the minimum value of \u2018b\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46029": {
                "ans1": "1/99",
                "ans2": "1/100",
                "ans3": "1/101",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\frac\\pi4\\frac{\\sin^{99}x}{\\cos^{101}x}\\operatorname dx=",
                "correct_ans": "1/100",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40982": {
                "ans1": "9y-17=0    ",
                "ans2": "9y+17=0   ",
                "ans3": "8y-17=0   ",
                "ans4": "8y+17=0",
                "question_text": "The equation of directrix of\u00a02x^2+8x+8y-1=0\\; is",
                "correct_ans": "8y-17=0   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42420": {
                "ans1": "a",
                "ans2": "0",
                "ans3": "-1",
                "ans4": "2tanA",
                "question_text": "In \u0394ABC, \u2220A=\\frac\\pi2\u00a0then tanA+tanB-tanAtanB=",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49633": {
                "ans1": "1/3sq. units   ",
                "ans2": "2/3sq. units",
                "ans3": " 4/3sq. units",
                "ans4": "8/3sq. units",
                "question_text": "The area bounded by the region\u00a0y^2=4(x+1)\\;\\;\u00a0 and coordinate axis is",
                "correct_ans": " 4/3sq. units",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45313": {
                "ans1": "25q=6p^{2\\;}\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans2": "25p=6q^{2\\;}\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans3": "6q=25q^{2\\;}\\;\\;\\;",
                "ans4": "6p=25q^{2\\;}\\;\\;\\;",
                "question_text": "If the roots of\u00a0 equation x^2-px+q=0 are in ratio 2:3 then",
                "correct_ans": "25q=6p^{2\\;}\\;\\;\\;",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41593": {
                "ans1": "R",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}Z^+\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "{0}",
                "ans4": "{0,2}",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;f(x)=x^2\\;and\\;g(x)\\;=2^x,\\;the\\;solution\\;set\\;of\\;fog(x)=gof(x)\\;is\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "{0,2}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}For\\;f(x)=x^2\\;and\\;g(x)\\;=2^x,\\;and\\;fog(x)=gof(x)\\;\\rightarrow f(2^x)=g(x^2)\\\\or,(2^x)^2=2^{x^2}\\\\or,2^{2x}=2^{x^2}\\\\or,x^2-2x=0\\\\or,x=0,2\\\\therefore,Solution\\;set=\\{0.2\\}\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "43189": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "\\sqrt2",
                "ans4": "undefined",
                "question_text": "The\\;eccentricity\\;of\\;a\\;conic\\;in\\;polar\\;form\\;r^2=32\\;\\cos ec2\\theta\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "\\sqrt2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}r^2=32\\;\\cos ec2\\theta\\;\\\\(r\\sin\\theta)(r\\cos\\theta)=16\\\\xy=16\\\\which\\;is\\;rec\\tan gular\\;hyperbola\\\\e=\\sqrt2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "40812": {
                "ans1": "-4",
                "ans2": "-9",
                "ans3": "-6",
                "ans4": "36",
                "question_text": "The\\;product\\;of\\;all\\;the\\;roots\\;of\\;an\\;eqn\\;x^2-\\vert x\\vert-6=0\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "-9",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;x2-\\vert x\\vert-6=0\\;\\\\\\vert x\\vert^2-\\vert x\\vert-6=0\\\\(\\vert x\\vert-3)(\\vert x\\vert+2)=0\\\\now,\\;-2\\;is\\;not\\;possible\\;\\\\so,x=3,-3\\\\and\\;product\\;=-9\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46497": {
                "ans1": "\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^4+c",
                "ans2": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^4}{4x}+c",
                "ans3": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^4}4+c",
                "ans4": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^4}{x}+c",
                "question_text": "\\int\\frac{(x+1)(x+\\log\\;x)^3}xdx=",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{\\displaystyle\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^4}4+c",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\int\\frac{(x+1)(x+\\log\\;x)^3}xdx=\\int\\left(1+\\frac1x\\right)\\left(x+\\log x\\right)^3dx\\\\let,\\;x+\\log x=y\\\\or,\\left(1+\\frac1x\\right)dx=dy\\\\\\int y^3dy\\;=\\frac{y^4}4+c=\\frac{\\displaystyle\\left(\\;x+\\log x\\right)^3}4+c\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44615": {
                "ans1": "1/3",
                "ans2": "2/3",
                "ans3": "4/3",
                "ans4": "8/3",
                "question_text": "Area\\;bound\\;by\\;y^2=x\\;and\\;x=2y\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "1/3",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Area=\\int_0^2\\left(y_2-y_1\\right)dx\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\int_0^2\\left(\\sqrt x-\\frac x2\\right)dx={\\left[\\frac{2x^{\\displaystyle\\frac32}}3-\\frac{x^2}4\\right]^2}_0=1/3\\;sq.\\;units\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41454": {
                "ans1": "c is arithmetic mean of a and b",
                "ans2": "c is geometric mean of a and b",
                "ans3": "c is harmonic mean of a and b",
                "ans4": "b is harmonic mean of a and b",
                "question_text": "Let a,b,c be three distinct non negative numbers . If the vectors\u00a0\\begin{array}{l}a\\overrightarrow i+a\\overrightarrow j+c\\overrightarrow k\\;,\\overrightarrow i+\\overrightarrow k\\;and\\;c\\;\\overrightarrow i+c\\overrightarrow j+b\\overrightarrow k\\end{array} lie on a plane , then",
                "correct_ans": "c is geometric mean of a and b",
                "explanation": "The given vectors are coplanarSo, c is geometric\u00a0mean of a and b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46724": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "11",
                "question_text": "The projection of a line on a coordinate axes are 2,3,6 then length of the line is",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Le\\;L\\;be\\;the\\;length\\\\Ll=2.Lm=3,Ln=6\\\\Therefore,L^2(l^2+m^2+n^2)=2^2+3^2+6^2\\\\L=7\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "41764": {
                "ans1": "1/2",
                "ans2": "1/x",
                "ans3": "x/2",
                "ans4": "x^2",
                "question_text": "If\\;y=\\tan^{-1}\\sqrt{\\frac{1-\\cos x}{1+\\cos x}},then\\;dy/dx=",
                "correct_ans": "1/2",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;y=\\tan^{-1}\\sqrt{\\frac{1-\\cos x}{1+\\cos x}}=\\tan^{-1}\\sqrt{\\frac{2\\sin^2x/2}{2\\cos^2x/2}}=\\tan^{-1}\\tan\\frac x2=\\frac x2\\\\dy/dx=1/2\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "49805": {
                "ans1": "a is one of the cube roots of unity",
                "ans2": "b is one of the cube roots of unity",
                "ans3": "a/b is one of the cube roots of unity",
                "ans4": "a/b is one of the cube roots of -1",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;\\begin{vmatrix}a&b&0\\\\0&a&b\\\\b&0&a\\end{vmatrix}=0\\;then\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "a/b is one of the cube roots of -1",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;\\begin{vmatrix}a&b&0\\\\0&a&b\\\\b&0&a\\end{vmatrix}=a(a^2-0)-b(-b^2)=a^3+b^3=0\\\\\\left(\\frac ab\\right)^3=-1\\\\\\frac ab=\\pm i\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "45442": {
                "ans1": "C(50,9)",
                "ans2": "C(50.10)",
                "ans3": "C(50,29)",
                "ans4": "C(50,30)",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;coefficient\\;of\\;x^{30}in\\;the\\;expression\\;of\\;(1+x)^{50}(1-x+x^2)^{50}\\;is\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "C(50,30)",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\;(1+x)^{50}(1-x+x^2)^{50}\\;\\;=\\lbrack(1-x)^3\\rbrack^{50^{}}=(1-x)^{150}\\\\E_{r+1}=^{150}C_r(-x)^{150-r}\\\\For\\;the\\;coefficient\\;of\\;x^{50},150-r=30\\rightarrow r=120\\\\Coeff\\;of\\;x^{30}=^{150}C_{120}\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "42913": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": " \u03c0/4",
                "ans3": " \u03c0/2",
                "ans4": " \u03c0",
                "question_text": "\\int_0^\\pi\\frac{\\sin\\;x\\;+\\;\\cos\\;x}{\\sqrt{1+\\sin2x}}dx\\;=",
                "correct_ans": " \u03c0/2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "46951": {
                "ans1": "7560",
                "ans2": "4845",
                "ans3": "240",
                "ans4": "60",
                "question_text": "The number of ways in which letters of word \"ACCOUNTANT\" can be arranged so that vowels come together is",
                "correct_ans": "7560",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{7!\\;x\\;4!}{2x2x2x2}=7560\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "47657": {
                "ans1": "straight line",
                "ans2": "parabola",
                "ans3": "circle",
                "ans4": "ellipse",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}If\\;z=x+iy\\;=(k+3)+i\\sqrt{5+k^2},then\\;locus\\;of\\;z\\;is\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array} ",
                "correct_ans": "circle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "44465": {
                "ans1": "Acute angled triangle",
                "ans2": "right angled triangle",
                "ans3": "obtuse angle triangle",
                "ans4": "right angled isosceles triangle",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;angle\\;of\\;a\\;\\triangle ABC\\;are\\;in\\;AP\\;such\\;that\\;b:c=\\sqrt3:\\sqrt2,then\\;\\triangle ABC\\;is\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "Acute angled triangle",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2B=A+C\\;and\\;b:c\\;=\\sqrt3:\\sqrt2\\\\or,\\;b=\\sqrt3k\\;,\\;c=\\sqrt2k\\\\sides\\;are\\;also\\;in\\;AP\\;so\\;2b=a+c\\\\a=2b-c=2\\sqrt3k-\\sqrt2k\\\\\\cos A=\\frac{b2+c2-a2}{2bc}=80.63^\\circ<90^\\circ\\\\so\\;acute\\;angle\\;triangle\\\\\\\\\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        }
    },
    "chemistry": {
        "1": {
            "55587": {
                "ans1": "Na and Ca",
                "ans2": "Mg and Al",
                "ans3": "Na and Be",
                "ans4": "Be and Al",
                "question_text": "Which of this pair shows diagonal relation?",
                "correct_ans": "Be and Al",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53716": {
                "ans1": "Carboniumion",
                "ans2": "Carbanion",
                "ans3": "Free-radical",
                "ans4": "carbocation",
                "question_text": "The intermediate formed during addition of HBr to propene in presence of peroxide is",
                "correct_ans": "Carboniumion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54456": {
                "ans1": "Fractional distillation",
                "ans2": "Sublimation",
                "ans3": "Steam distillation",
                "ans4": "crystallization ",
                "question_text": "Aniline can be purified by",
                "correct_ans": "Steam distillation",
                "explanation": "Because aniline is steam volatile",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51688": {
                "ans1": "NH_4^+",
                "ans2": "H_2O",
                "ans3": "CN^-",
                "ans4": "HCl",
                "question_text": "Which of this is Bronsted acid but Lewis base?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2O",
                "explanation": "water is both bronsted acid and base",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51722": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "n+1",
                "ans4": "n-1",
                "question_text": "The atomic orbitals are filled up in the order of",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "The energy of the atomic orbitals increase with increase on (n+l) value",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52477": {
                "ans1": "Dutch metal",
                "ans2": "Invar",
                "ans3": "Constantan",
                "ans4": "German silver",
                "question_text": "Which of this is not an alloy of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Invar",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54277": {
                "ans1": "\\;CH_4\\;",
                "ans2": "\\;CH_3Cl",
                "ans3": "\\;CH_3NO_2",
                "ans4": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest boiling point?",
                "correct_ans": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "explanation": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50323": {
                "ans1": "98",
                "ans2": "49",
                "ans3": "32.66",
                "ans4": "24.5",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;equivalent\\;weight\\;of\\;\\\\H_3PO_4,\\;in\\;the\\;reaction\\end{array}\\begin{array}{l}Ca(OH)_{2\\;}+\\;H_3PO_4\\;\\\\\\rightarrow CaHPO_4\\;+H_2O\\;\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "98",
                "explanation": "Basicity is 1 so, eq wt. is equal to molecular wt.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57100": {
                "ans1": "K_4Fe(CN)_6",
                "ans2": "FeO",
                "ans3": "Fe(CO)_5",
                "ans4": "Fe_3O_4",
                "question_text": "The oxidation number of Fe is least in",
                "correct_ans": "Fe(CO)_5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56307": {
                "ans1": "F^-",
                "ans2": "Cl^-",
                "ans3": "Br^-",
                "ans4": "I^-",
                "question_text": "Which of these is most reducing?",
                "correct_ans": "F^-",
                "explanation": "Fluorine is most reducing agent",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55181": {
                "ans1": "0.1 mole of glucose",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}11.2\\;molecules\\;of\\;CO_2\\\\gas\\;at\\;STP\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "N_A\\;CH_4\\;molecule",
                "ans4": "20g\\;of\\;H_2O",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest mass?",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}11.2\\;molecules\\;of\\;CO_2\\\\gas\\;at\\;STP\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}0.1\\;mole\\;C_4H_{12}O_6\\;=18g\\\\11.2\\;l\\;CO_{2\\;}\\;at\\;STP\\;=22g\\\\N_A\\;CH_4\\;molecules\\;=16g\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57882": {
                "ans1": "N_2O_5",
                "ans2": "NO_2",
                "ans3": "N_2O_3",
                "ans4": "N_2O",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following oxides of nitrogen is paramagnetic?",
                "correct_ans": "NO_2",
                "explanation": "The number of electron in nitrogen dioxide is 7+16=23",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55059": {
                "ans1": "Lavigation",
                "ans2": "Forth Floatation",
                "ans3": "electromagnetic seperation",
                "ans4": "leaching",
                "question_text": "Concentration of Bacixite ore by",
                "correct_ans": "Forth Floatation",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55184": {
                "ans1": "Ethyl iodide",
                "ans2": "ethyl alcohol",
                "ans3": "Ethanal",
                "ans4": "Iodoform",
                "question_text": "Diethyl ether with conc. HI gives 2 moles of",
                "correct_ans": "Ethyl iodide",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53385": {
                "ans1": "CH_4",
                "ans2": "C_2H",
                "ans3": "C_3H_4",
                "ans4": "C_2H_6",
                "question_text": "Hydrolysis of aluminium carbine produces",
                "correct_ans": "CH_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50713": {
                "ans1": "Its molecular weight",
                "ans2": "1/2 the molecular weight",
                "ans3": "1/4 the molecular weight",
                "ans4": "1/8 of the molecular weight",
                "question_text": "The equivalent mass of iodine in the following reaction is?\\begin{array}{l}I_2\\;+\\;2S_2SO_3^{2-}\\\\\\;\\rightarrow2I^-\\;+\\;S_4O_6^{2-}\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "1/2 the molecular weight",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56282": {
                "ans1": "Benzene",
                "ans2": "benzoic acid",
                "ans3": "nitro benzene",
                "ans4": "toluene",
                "question_text": "The compound that is most reactive towards electrophilic nitration is",
                "correct_ans": "Benzene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52469": {
                "ans1": "Na_2CO_3",
                "ans2": "CuSO_4",
                "ans3": "CH_3COOK",
                "ans4": "KCl",
                "question_text": "Which of the following salts cationic hydrolysis?",
                "correct_ans": "CuSO_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56861": {
                "ans1": "18 gm",
                "ans2": "54gm",
                "ans3": "36 gm",
                "ans4": "72 gm ",
                "question_text": "Which of these have the same number of hydrogen atoms as 32 grams of methane?",
                "correct_ans": "72 gm ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59164": {
                "ans1": "Aufball's principle",
                "ans2": "Bohr's model",
                "ans3": "Hund's rule",
                "ans4": "Pauli's exclusion principle",
                "question_text": "Silicon atom in its\u00a0ground state has two unpaired electrons in the outer most orbital. This is the result?",
                "correct_ans": "Hund's rule",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54050": {
                "ans1": "BF_3",
                "ans2": "AlCl_3",
                "ans3": "H_2O",
                "ans4": "CO_2",
                "question_text": "Which molecule is linear molecule?",
                "correct_ans": "CO_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50655": {
                "ans1": "copper",
                "ans2": "iron",
                "ans3": "magnesium",
                "ans4": "cobalt",
                "question_text": "Chlorophyll contains the metal",
                "correct_ans": "magnesium",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56021": {
                "ans1": "8",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "2",
                "question_text": "The number of electrons in sulphur atom having n+l=3 are",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Configuration\\;of\\;sulphur\\;is\\;1s^2\\;2s^2\\;sp^6\\;3s^2\\;3p^4\\;\\\\So,\\;electrons\\;with\\;(n\\;+\\;l)\\;value\\;3\\;are\\;that\\;of\\;2p\\;and\\;3s\\;i.e.\\;8\\;electrons\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55972": {
                "ans1": "CaCl_2",
                "ans2": "HCl",
                "ans3": "NaOH",
                "ans4": "NaCl",
                "question_text": "Exhausted permutit is recharged using",
                "correct_ans": "NaCl",
                "explanation": "Used exhausted permutit is recharged by passing NaCl solution.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54665": {
                "ans1": "iron",
                "ans2": "mercury",
                "ans3": "graphite",
                "ans4": "platinum",
                "question_text": "In the electrolysis r\u00e9action Cathode used during manufacture of NaOH by Castner Kellener's process is",
                "correct_ans": "mercury",
                "explanation": "In Castner Kellener's process NaCl solution is electrolysed using Hg as cathode to give sodium amalgam which gives NaOH on hydrolysis.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58104": {
                "ans1": "air",
                "ans2": "Fe_2O_3",
                "ans3": "CaCO_3",
                "ans4": "SiO_2",
                "question_text": "In open hearth process, impurities are removed using",
                "correct_ans": "Fe_2O_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58857": {
                "ans1": "SnCl_2",
                "ans2": "SnCl_4",
                "ans3": "Cl^-",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "In\\;the\\;reaction\\\\\\;SnCl_2\\;+\\;2Cl^-\\rightarrow\\;\\\\SnCl_4,\\;Lewis\\;acid\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "Cl^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59476": {
                "ans1": "H_2",
                "ans2": "CH_4",
                "ans3": "ethane",
                "ans4": "butane",
                "question_text": "The product formed on heating sodium formate with soda-lime is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56678": {
                "ans1": "Fe{\\left(CO\\right)}_5",
                "ans2": "FeO",
                "ans3": "Fe_3O_4",
                "ans4": "FeO_3",
                "question_text": "O.N.\u00a0of iron is minimum in",
                "correct_ans": "Fe{\\left(CO\\right)}_5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51141": {
                "ans1": "vacuum distillation",
                "ans2": "simple distillation",
                "ans3": "steam distillation",
                "ans4": "sublimation",
                "question_text": "The method of purification of glycerin is",
                "correct_ans": "vacuum distillation",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52748": {
                "ans1": "F",
                "ans2": "He",
                "ans3": "O",
                "ans4": "Ne",
                "question_text": "Element with highest first ionization potential is",
                "correct_ans": "He",
                "explanation": "He has highest ionization potential.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55900": {
                "ans1": "Mg(NO_3)_2",
                "ans2": "Pb(NO_3)_2",
                "ans3": "Al(NO_3)_3",
                "ans4": "Bi(NO_3)_3",
                "question_text": "Which of these is insoluble in water?",
                "correct_ans": "Bi(NO_3)_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54666": {
                "ans1": "CO_2",
                "ans2": "CaCl_2",
                "ans3": "I_2",
                "ans4": "SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest melting point?",
                "correct_ans": "CaCl_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54372": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_{4\\;\u200b}",
                "ans2": "Na_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "NH_4Cl",
                "question_text": "Which of these have all three types of bonds?",
                "correct_ans": "NH_4Cl",
                "explanation": "NH4\u200bCl\u00a0has all three types of bonds.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53618": {
                "ans1": "Halide",
                "ans2": "Oxide",
                "ans3": "Sulphide",
                "ans4": "Hydroxide",
                "question_text": "The principle ore of Zinc is",
                "correct_ans": "Sulphide",
                "explanation": "The principle ore of zinc is zinc blend which is a sulphide ore.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58177": {
                "ans1": "NH _4 \u200b",
                "ans2": "BF_3",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "HSO_4\\;^-\\;\u200b",
                "question_text": "Which of these is lewis acid but not Bronsted acid?",
                "correct_ans": "BF_3",
                "explanation": "BF3\u200b; has incomplete octet on Boron so it is electron acceptor (lewis acid) but it can't donate proton (Bronsted acid).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59633": {
                "ans1": "7",
                "ans2": "8",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "The number of s-electrons in Cr-atom is:",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53283": {
                "ans1": "35 gm",
                "ans2": " 36gm",
                "ans3": " 27gm",
                "ans4": "30gm",
                "question_text": "Mass of water formed by heating 3gm of\u00a0H_{2}\u200b\u00a0with 32gm of oxygen is",
                "correct_ans": " 27gm",
                "explanation": "H_{2} ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55921": {
                "ans1": "But-2-enal",
                "ans2": "propenal",
                "ans3": "propynal",
                "ans4": " But-2-ynal",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of acraldehyde is",
                "correct_ans": "propenal",
                "explanation": "CH_{2} = CH\u2212CHO\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59991": {
                "ans1": "Pyramidal",
                "ans2": "Tetrahedral",
                "ans3": " Coplannar",
                "ans4": " Trigonal",
                "question_text": "Structure of ammonia is",
                "correct_ans": "Pyramidal",
                "explanation": "Due to repulsive force of lone pair of electron.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54243": {
                "ans1": "ClF",
                "ans2": "PCl _3 \u200b",
                "ans3": "SiF _4 \u200b",
                "ans4": "CHCl _3 \u200b",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following has zero dipole moment?",
                "correct_ans": "SiF _4 \u200b",
                "explanation": "SiF4\u200b\u00a0is symmetrical molecule hence its dipole moment is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50988": {
                "ans1": "96500C",
                "ans2": " 1 mole of electron",
                "ans3": "6.022\\times10^{23}\\;\\times1.6\\times10\\;^{\\;-19\\;}\\;C",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "One Faraday is",
                "correct_ans": "all",
                "explanation": "1 Faraday is charge of 1 mole of electron so, 1F=1 mole\u00a0e^{-}e\u2212=96500C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52674": {
                "ans1": "equal to meatal",
                "ans2": "greater than metal",
                "ans3": "less than metal",
                "ans4": "depends upon formation of slag",
                "question_text": "The density of slag is always",
                "correct_ans": "less than metal",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57914": {
                "ans1": "ethane = ethane = ethyne",
                "ans2": "ethane > ethene > ethyne",
                "ans3": " ethyne >ethene > ethane",
                "ans4": "ethane > ethyne > ethane",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Electronegativity order of carbon in hydrocarbon is",
                "correct_ans": " ethyne >ethene > ethane",
                "explanation": "Increasing in 's' character increases electronegativity",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55387": {
                "ans1": "N_A",
                "ans2": "2N_A",
                "ans3": "3N_A",
                "ans4": "4N_A",
                "question_text": "The number of atoms present in 1 mol\u00a0 H_2O at 25^oC is",
                "correct_ans": "3N_A",
                "explanation": "1mole of H_2O = 1N_AH \n2\n\u200b\n O=1N \nA\n\u200b\n  H_2OH \n2\n\u200b\n O molecules = 3N_A3N \nA\n\u200b\n  atoms",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50897": {
                "ans1": "Fe",
                "ans2": "Mn",
                "ans3": "Al",
                "ans4": "Zn",
                "question_text": "Pyrolusite is an ore of",
                "correct_ans": "Mn",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51256": {
                "ans1": "NO",
                "ans2": "N_2O",
                "ans3": "NO_2",
                "ans4": "N_2O_5",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In lightning the gas formed is?",
                "correct_ans": "NO",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52053": {
                "ans1": "Ionic",
                "ans2": "Covalent",
                "ans3": "Coordinate",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "Which bond is possible in between salt of lewis acid lewis base?",
                "correct_ans": "Coordinate",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56153": {
                "ans1": " Te and I",
                "ans2": "Zn and Ga",
                "ans3": "Fe and Co",
                "ans4": "K and Ca",
                "question_text": "Which of these pairs represents anamolous pair in Mendeleev's periodic table?",
                "correct_ans": " Te and I",
                "explanation": "Te(at.wt. =127.6) and I(at.wt.=127)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56209": {
                "ans1": " graphite",
                "ans2": "mercury",
                "ans3": " iron",
                "ans4": "palladium",
                "question_text": "In Kellener-Solvay process, the cathode used for electrolysis of brine is",
                "correct_ans": "mercury",
                "explanation": "In Kellener solvay process, brine solution is electrolyzed using Hg as cathode to get Na-Hg which on hydrolysis gives NaOH.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56077": {
                "ans1": "NaCl",
                "ans2": "NaOH",
                "ans3": " CaCl_2",
                "ans4": "KOH",
                "question_text": "Exhausted permutit can be recharged using",
                "correct_ans": "NaCl",
                "explanation": "The used permutit is recharged by using NaCl solution.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55258": {
                "ans1": "3g\\;of\\;H_2",
                "ans2": "34g\\;of\\;NH_3",
                "ans3": "44g\\;of\\;CO_2",
                "ans4": "80g\\;of\\;SO_2",
                "question_text": "Which of these contains most number of molecules?",
                "correct_ans": "34g\\;of\\;NH_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52496": {
                "ans1": "Aziridine",
                "ans2": "Phenetole",
                "ans3": "THF",
                "ans4": "Dioxane",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is aromatic compound ?",
                "correct_ans": "Phenetole",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59520": {
                "ans1": "5 cc of 1N HCl",
                "ans2": "10 cc of 1N HCl",
                "ans3": "5 cc of 1N Ammonium Hydroxide",
                "ans4": "10 cc of 1N ammonia solution",
                "question_text": "Two solutions 100cc of 0.2N HCl and 50 cc of 0.5M ammonia solution mixed to each other the un-reacted agent is",
                "correct_ans": "10 cc of 1N HCl",
                "explanation": "100 cc of 0.2 N\u00a0HCI= 20cc of 1N\u00a0HCINH_3\u200b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54603": {
                "ans1": " N^{---}",
                "ans2": "O ^{--}",
                "ans3": "F^-",
                "ans4": "equal in all",
                "question_text": "The size of ion is greater in",
                "correct_ans": " N^{---}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53402": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "The number of isomers of\u00a0C_5H_{12}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50012": {
                "ans1": "B",
                "ans2": "O",
                "ans3": "C",
                "ans4": "N",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest first ionization potenial?",
                "correct_ans": "N",
                "explanation": "In a period O.N. increase from left to right however\u00a0NN\u00a0due to more stable half-filled 2p-orbitals have higher I.P. than\u00a0OO",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59765": {
                "ans1": "NO",
                "ans2": "NO_2",
                "ans3": "N_2O",
                "ans4": "HNO_3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The fixation product of nitrogen during lightening is",
                "correct_ans": "NO",
                "explanation": "N_2 and\u00a0O_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56873": {
                "ans1": "PbSO _4 \u200b",
                "ans2": "BaSO_4",
                "ans3": "PbCl_2",
                "ans4": "Pb(NO_3)_2",
                "question_text": "Which of these is soluble in water",
                "correct_ans": "Pb(NO_3)_2",
                "explanation": "All metal nitrates are soluble in water.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53446": {
                "ans1": "CaO",
                "ans2": "MgO",
                "ans3": "CaCO _3",
                "ans4": "MgCO_3",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The flux used during extraction of iron from haematite is",
                "correct_ans": "CaCO _3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55292": {
                "ans1": "Aniline",
                "ans2": "Nitrobenzene",
                "ans3": "Cyclohexane",
                "ans4": "chlorobenzene",
                "question_text": "Nitration of benzene gives",
                "correct_ans": "Nitrobenzene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57743": {
                "ans1": "Cu",
                "ans2": "Mg",
                "ans3": "Cr",
                "ans4": "Ni",
                "question_text": "Which metal can't be obtained by the electrolysis of its aqueous solution ?",
                "correct_ans": "Mg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54166": {
                "ans1": "He",
                "ans2": "O",
                "ans3": "F",
                "ans4": "Ne",
                "question_text": ".Elements with highest 1st ionization potential is",
                "correct_ans": "He",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50523": {
                "ans1": "289500 C     ",
                "ans2": "96500 C     ",
                "ans3": "86850 C    ",
                "ans4": "28950 C",
                "question_text": "The amount of electricity required to liberate 0.3 mole of Al^{3+} is",
                "correct_ans": "86850 C    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56205": {
                "ans1": "Rhombic",
                "ans2": "Colloidal",
                "ans3": "Monoclinic  ",
                "ans4": "Milk of Sulphur",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is most stable allotrope of Sulphur?",
                "correct_ans": "Rhombic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52295": {
                "ans1": "Cu=\\lbrackAr\\rbrack4s^23d^{10}",
                "ans2": "Cu=\\lbrackAr\\rbrack4s^23d^{10}",
                "ans3": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^03d^5",
                "ans4": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^23d^5",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
                "correct_ans": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^23d^5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52164": {
                "ans1": "chlorine gas   ",
                "ans2": "nitric acid    ",
                "ans3": "bromine water    ",
                "ans4": "sulphuric acid",
                "question_text": "Benzene does not reacts with",
                "correct_ans": "bromine water    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53236": {
                "ans1": "Hg",
                "ans2": "Au",
                "ans3": "Cd",
                "ans4": "Ca",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element lies in group\u00a0 of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Au",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55732": {
                "ans1": "Melting of ice into water.    ",
                "ans2": "Expansion of metal on heating.",
                "ans3": "Dissolving of sugar into water.    ",
                "ans4": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element is methylating agent?",
                "correct_ans": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57659": {
                "ans1": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans2": "positive & reduction centre ",
                "ans3": "negative & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans4": "negative & reduction centre ",
                "question_text": "Anode in electrolytic cell is",
                "correct_ans": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58363": {
                "ans1": "KMnO_4",
                "ans2": "Mn_2O_4",
                "ans3": "Mn_2O_3",
                "ans4": "MnO_2",
                "question_text": "Lowest oxidation state of manganese is found in",
                "correct_ans": "Mn_2O_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50779": {
                "ans1": "PO_3^{--}",
                "ans2": "H_2PO_3^{--}",
                "ans3": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "ans4": " H_2PO_3^{--} ",
                "question_text": "Conjugate acid of\u00a0HPO^{3--}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55550": {
                "ans1": "Fractional distillation",
                "ans2": "Sublimation",
                "ans3": "Steam distillation",
                "ans4": "crystallization ",
                "question_text": "Aniline can be purified by",
                "correct_ans": "Steam distillation",
                "explanation": "Because aniline is steam volatile",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56429": {
                "ans1": "Group I    ",
                "ans2": "Group II    ",
                "ans3": "Group III   ",
                "ans4": "Group zero ",
                "question_text": "The chloride of which group elements of periodic table form neutral solution in water?",
                "correct_ans": "Group I    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59709": {
                "ans1": "NO_2^+",
                "ans2": "C_2H_2",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "All",
                "question_text": "Which of these has sp hybridization?",
                "correct_ans": "All",
                "explanation": "This is obvious.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50865": {
                "ans1": "precipitant",
                "ans2": "oxidant",
                "ans3": "ion-exchanger",
                "ans4": "complexant",
                "question_text": "Calgon is a/an",
                "correct_ans": "complexant",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50858": {
                "ans1": "H_2O",
                "ans2": "NH_3",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of these is a non-polar molecule with polar bond?",
                "correct_ans": "SO_3",
                "explanation": "SO3 has polar bond but due to symmetric geometry have zero net dipole moment and molecule is non-polar.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59406": {
                "ans1": "Mg^{++}",
                "ans2": "Na^+",
                "ans3": "F^-",
                "ans4": "O^{--}",
                "question_text": "Which of these species have largest size?",
                "correct_ans": "O^{--}",
                "explanation": "The species are iso-electronic with 10 electrons each so, size increases with increase in no. of protons so,\u00a0O^l{--} with least number of protons has largest size",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56942": {
                "ans1": "n=3,l=0,m=0",
                "ans2": "n=2,l=1,m=0",
                "ans3": "n=1,l=1,m=\u22121",
                "ans4": "n=4,l=0,m=0",
                "question_text": "Which of these sets of quantum number represents least number of energy?",
                "correct_ans": "n=2,l=1,m=0",
                "explanation": "Orbital with lower\u00a0(n+l)\u00a0value has less energy and if\u00a0(n+l) is same then orbital with lower\u00a0n\u00a0has less energy.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57456": {
                "ans1": "B",
                "ans2": "C",
                "ans3": "N",
                "ans4": "O",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest first ionization potential value?",
                "correct_ans": "N",
                "explanation": "The ionization potential increases along the period however from\u00a0N\u00a0to\u00a0O\u00a0it decreases as nitrogen has more stable half filled\u00a02p\u00a0orbital. So , the order is\u00a0B<C<O<N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59513": {
                "ans1": "ionic",
                "ans2": "covalent",
                "ans3": "coordinate",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "Which bond is possible in between salt of lewis acid lewis base?",
                "correct_ans": "coordinate",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56217": {
                "ans1": "Cl_2",
                "ans2": "Br_2",
                "ans3": "F_2",
                "ans4": "I_2",
                "question_text": "Carnalite is used for the extraction of",
                "correct_ans": "Br_2",
                "explanation": "Carnalite is used to extract bromine.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57746": {
                "ans1": "BeCl_2",
                "ans2": "AlCl_3",
                "ans3": "BF_3",
                "ans4": "BCl_3",
                "question_text": "Which is not lewis acid?",
                "correct_ans": "BeCl_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52050": {
                "ans1": "electrophilic",
                "ans2": "nucleophilic",
                "ans3": "free radical",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The mechanism of addition of HCl\u00a0to ethylene is",
                "correct_ans": "electrophilic",
                "explanation": "Addition of\u00a0HCl\u00a0to ethylene starts with adding H+\u00a0to give a carbocation. So, it is electrophilic addition",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50327": {
                "ans1": "tempering",
                "ans2": "annealing",
                "ans3": "quenching",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "Which of the heat treatment process of steel gives hard and brittle type of steel?",
                "correct_ans": "quenching",
                "explanation": "Quenching is process of heating steel to redness followedby sudden cooling which give hard & brittle steel.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55046": {
                "ans1": "+1",
                "ans2": "+2",
                "ans3": "+3",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "O.N. of 'Fe' in sod. nitroprusside\u00a0Na_{2}[ Fe(CN)_5NO ] is",
                "correct_ans": "+2",
                "explanation": "+2+x\u22125+1=0;so,x=+2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54530": {
                "ans1": "alcohol",
                "ans2": "water",
                "ans3": "ammonia",
                "ans4": "benzene",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The metal formed by electrolysis of molten rock salt can be stored in:",
                "correct_ans": "benzene",
                "explanation": "The metal formed by electrolysis of rock salt(NaCl) is Na and is stored in benzene as alcohol, water and ammonia reacts with sodium metal.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58483": {
                "ans1": "NaNO_3",
                "ans2": "LiNO_3",
                "ans3": "Pb(NO_3)_2",
                "ans4": "Cu(NO_3)_2",
                "question_text": "Nitrogen dioxide cannot be obtained by heating",
                "correct_ans": "NaNO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52720": {
                "ans1": "Na",
                "ans2": "Cl_2",
                "ans3": "Na\\;and\\;Cl_2",
                "ans4": "O_2",
                "question_text": "The products of Down's process",
                "correct_ans": "Na\\;and\\;Cl_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53320": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "10",
                "ans4": "N_A",
                "question_text": "Total no. of electrons present in 3.2 gm of\u00a0CH_4\u200b\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "10",
                "explanation": "CH_4\u200b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55903": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The magnetic quantum number is -3 then what is the possible principle quantum number?",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "To have magnetic quantum number -3, the value of l should be 3 and principle quantum number should be 4.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58155": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "Along the period ionization potential\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "increases",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55574": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The no. of unpaired electrons in Cr atom is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "From electronic configuration.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52772": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "+3,-3",
                "ans3": "+3,-5",
                "ans4": "+5,-3",
                "question_text": "Oxidation number of nitrogen in\u00a0NH_4\u200bNO_3",
                "correct_ans": "+5,-3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58465": {
                "ans1": "Carbocation",
                "ans2": "Alkyl free radical",
                "ans3": "Carbanion",
                "ans4": "Carbene",
                "question_text": "Intermediate formed in Kharash effect is,",
                "correct_ans": "Alkyl free radical",
                "explanation": "Free radical mechanism",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54482": {
                "ans1": "BeCl_2",
                "ans2": "AlCl_3",
                "ans3": "BF_3",
                "ans4": "BCl_3",
                "question_text": "Which is not lewis acid?",
                "correct_ans": "BeCl_2",
                "explanation": "It needs two lone pair of electrons for make octet.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50664": {
                "ans1": "PO_3^{--}",
                "ans2": "H_2PO_3^{--}",
                "ans3": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "ans4": " H_2PO_3^{--} ",
                "question_text": "Conjugate acid of HPO_3^{--} is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57109": {
                "ans1": "Hg",
                "ans2": "Au",
                "ans3": "Cd",
                "ans4": "Ca",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element lies in group\u00a0 of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Au",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50911": {
                "ans1": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans2": "positive & reduction centre ",
                "ans3": "negative & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans4": "negative & reduction centre ",
                "question_text": "Anode in electrolytic cell is",
                "correct_ans": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54286": {
                "ans1": "chlorine gas   ",
                "ans2": "nitric acid    ",
                "ans3": "bromine water    ",
                "ans4": "sulphuric acid",
                "question_text": "Benzene does not reacts with",
                "correct_ans": "bromine water    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55018": {
                "ans1": "C_2H_5Br",
                "ans2": "C_2H_5Cl",
                "ans3": "CH_3I",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element is methylating agent?",
                "correct_ans": "C_2H_5Cl",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57532": {
                "ans1": "KMnO_4",
                "ans2": "Mn_2O_4",
                "ans3": "Mn_2O_3",
                "ans4": "MnO_2",
                "question_text": "Lowest oxidation state of manganese is found in",
                "correct_ans": "Mn_2O_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57471": {
                "ans1": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^10",
                "ans2": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^9",
                "ans3": "Cu=[Ar]4s^03d^5",
                "ans4": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^5",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
                "correct_ans": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57791": {
                "ans1": "Group I    ",
                "ans2": "Group II    ",
                "ans3": "Group III   ",
                "ans4": "Group zero ",
                "question_text": "The chloride of which group elements of periodic table form neutral solution in water?",
                "correct_ans": "Group I    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52986": {
                "ans1": "Melting of ice into water.    ",
                "ans2": "Expansion of metal on heating.",
                "ans3": "Dissolving of sugar into water.    ",
                "ans4": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is chemical reaction?",
                "correct_ans": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54924": {
                "ans1": "289500 C     ",
                "ans2": "96500 C     ",
                "ans3": "86850 C    ",
                "ans4": "28950 C",
                "question_text": "The amount of electricity required to liberate 0.3 mole of Al3+ is",
                "correct_ans": "86850 C    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53856": {
                "ans1": "Rhombic",
                "ans2": "Colloidal",
                "ans3": " Monoclinic    ",
                "ans4": "Milk of Sulphur",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is most stable allotrope of Sulphur?",
                "correct_ans": "Rhombic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58295": {
                "ans1": "2n^2",
                "ans2": "n^2",
                "ans3": "I^2",
                "ans4": "4n^2",
                "question_text": "The total no. of orbitals present in a shell is given by",
                "correct_ans": "n^2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54090": {
                "ans1": "C",
                "ans2": "CO",
                "ans3": "H_2",
                "ans4": "Cu_2O",
                "question_text": "The reducing agent in the Bessemer converter during extraction of copper from copper pyrite is",
                "correct_ans": "Cu_2O",
                "explanation": "Extraction of copper involves self reduction of Cu2S by Cu2\u200bO.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52254": {
                "ans1": "carbocation",
                "ans2": "carbanion",
                "ans3": "free radical",
                "ans4": "carbene",
                "question_text": "The reaction intermediate formed by homolytic fission is",
                "correct_ans": "free radical",
                "explanation": "During homolytic fission the fragment gets one electron each to form free radical",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57325": {
                "ans1": "NO",
                "ans2": "N_2O_3",
                "ans3": "N_2O_4",
                "ans4": "N_2O_5",
                "question_text": "Which nitrogen oxide is more acidic?",
                "correct_ans": "N_2O_5",
                "explanation": "Higher the oxidation state higher the acidic strength",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58663": {
                "ans1": "22.4 lit",
                "ans2": "11.2 lit",
                "ans3": "44.8 lit",
                "ans4": "33.6 lit",
                "question_text": "The volume of\u00a0CO_2 gas at NTP formed by burning 14gm of ethane",
                "correct_ans": "22.4 lit",
                "explanation": "28 gm of ethane gives 2*22.4 lit of CO2therefore,14 gm of ethane gives 22.4 litre of CO2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58943": {
                "ans1": "CH_3CHO",
                "ans2": "H_2O",
                "ans3": "CH_3COCH_3",
                "ans4": "CH_3COOCH_3",
                "question_text": "Which will form hydrocarbon with Grignard reagent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2O",
                "explanation": "Grignard reagent gives alkane with compound containing active hydrogen like H2\u200bO, NH3\u200b\u00a0,etc to give alkane.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55374": {
                "ans1": "H_2O",
                "ans2": "NH_3",
                "ans3": "SO_3",
                "ans4": "HCN",
                "question_text": "Which of these is non-polar molecule with polar bond?",
                "correct_ans": "SO_3",
                "explanation": "SO3\u200b\u00a0has polar S-O bond but due to symmetric geometry the net dipole is zero so molecule is non-polar.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55495": {
                "ans1": "1.5057 x 10^{22}",
                "ans2": "1.5057 x 10^{23}",
                "ans3": "6.023 x 10^{22}",
                "ans4": "6.023 x 10^{23}",
                "question_text": "The total number of atoms present in 5.6 litres of ammonia gas at STP is",
                "correct_ans": "6.023 x 10^{23}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53365": {
                "ans1": "NaH_2PO_2",
                "ans2": "NaHCO_3",
                "ans3": "NaNO_3",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "Which of the followings is an example of acid salt",
                "correct_ans": "NaHCO_3",
                "explanation": "The salt having replacable H-atom i.e. salt formed by partial replacement of hydrogen of acid is called acid salt.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53741": {
                "ans1": "O^{--}",
                "ans2": "F^-",
                "ans3": "Na^+",
                "ans4": "Mg^{++}",
                "question_text": "Which of these have larger size?",
                "correct_ans": "O^{--}",
                "explanation": "All species are iso electronic and size decreases with increase in nuclear charge.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58381": {
                "ans1": "20",
                "ans2": "32.5",
                "ans3": "12",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "0.325 gm of metal displaced 112ml of\u00a0H_2\u200b\u00a0at NTP. The eq.wt. of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "32.5",
                "explanation": "Eq. wt. of metal =\u00a0\\frac{0.325}{112} \\times 11200= 32.5",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59643": {
                "ans1": "hydrogenation",
                "ans2": "oxidation",
                "ans3": "reduction",
                "ans4": "sublimation",
                "question_text": "Loss of hydrogen atoms by an element is called",
                "correct_ans": "oxidation",
                "explanation": "Addition of oxygen = oxidationAddition of hydrogen = reductionRemoval of oxygen = reductionRemoval of hydrogen = oxidation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54794": {
                "ans1": " 3:1",
                "ans2": "1:3",
                "ans3": "1:4",
                "ans4": "4:3",
                "question_text": "The ratio of the water molecule in plaster of paris and gypsum is",
                "correct_ans": "1:4",
                "explanation": "CaSO_4.1/2H_2OCaSO_4.2H_2O\\dfrac{1}{2}:2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52884": {
                "ans1": "+6",
                "ans2": "+5",
                "ans3": "-10",
                "ans4": "+3",
                "question_text": "H_2\u200bO_2\u200b\u00a0\u00a0changes \u00a0Cr_2O_7^{2-}\u200b\u00a0ion to\u00a0CrO_5\u200b\u00a0in an acidic medium, the oxidation state of Cr in\u00a0CrO_3\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "+6",
                "explanation": "Cr2\u200bO5\u200b\u00a0has two O-O bonds. Hence its oxidation state is given as x+(-2)+ 2 x (-2)=0 i.e., x=6.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52316": {
                "ans1": "calcium hypo oxychloride",
                "ans2": "calcium oxychloride",
                "ans3": "calcium chloride",
                "ans4": "calcium chloro oxide",
                "question_text": "The chemical name for bleaching powder is",
                "correct_ans": "calcium oxychloride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57806": {
                "ans1": "nitric acid",
                "ans2": " sulfuric acid",
                "ans3": "phosphoric acid",
                "ans4": "hydrochloric acid",
                "question_text": "The acid used for the manufacture of fertilizers and explosives is",
                "correct_ans": " sulfuric acid",
                "explanation": "Nitric acid is used for a variety of purposes including manufacture of fertilizers and explosives.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58489": {
                "ans1": "NaOH",
                "ans2": "KOH",
                "ans3": "bleaching powder",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Brine is used for industrial production of",
                "correct_ans": "NaOH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59408": {
                "ans1": "MgO",
                "ans2": "CaO",
                "ans3": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "ans4": "Na_2O",
                "question_text": "Which one is the most acidic among these?",
                "correct_ans": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "explanation": "MgO, CaO and Na2O are alkalies whereas\u00a0Al_2O_3\u200b\u00a0is amphoteric(most acidic among four).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58961": {
                "ans1": " I > I- > I+",
                "ans2": "I > I+ > I-",
                "ans3": " I- > I > I+",
                "ans4": "I+ > I- > I",
                "question_text": "The correct order for the size of I, I+, I- is",
                "correct_ans": " I- > I > I+",
                "explanation": "I- has more number of valence electrons as compared to I and I+. Hence net nuclear force per unit charge is more for I+ , followed by I- and I. thus I+ has smallest size followed by I and I-",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55183": {
                "ans1": "reducing agent",
                "ans2": "oxidising agent",
                "ans3": "hydrogen",
                "ans4": "sublime",
                "question_text": "A reactant containing the element that is oxidised is called",
                "correct_ans": "reducing agent",
                "explanation": "Reducing agent reduces other compounds but itself gets oxidized",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59993": {
                "ans1": "Bromine",
                "ans2": "Selenium",
                "ans3": "Cesium",
                "ans4": "Telurium",
                "question_text": "Anamolous pair of iodine is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Telurium",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51994": {
                "ans1": " Cl > F > O > Br",
                "ans2": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "ans3": "F > Cl > Br > O",
                "ans4": "O > F > Cl > Br",
                "question_text": "The correct order of electronegativity is",
                "correct_ans": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "explanation": "Electronegativity of halogens decreases as we move down the group following the convention.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54091": {
                "ans1": "+3",
                "ans2": "+5",
                "ans3": "+7",
                "ans4": "+9",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The oxidation state of Cl in the compound\u00a0HClO_5",
                "correct_ans": "+7",
                "explanation": "Maximum O.S. of any element is equal to their group no.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54791": {
                "ans1": "methane",
                "ans2": "ethane",
                "ans3": "acetylene",
                "ans4": "propylene",
                "question_text": "The hydrocarbon formed by the hydrolysis of beryllium carbide is",
                "correct_ans": "methane",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59343": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The oxidation number of C in Fructose is",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "In fructose C6\u200bH12\u200b0\u00a0the O.N. of C is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55300": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "9",
                "ans3": "10",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "Total number of orbitals present in M shell is",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "For M shell, n=3hence no. of orbitals=n^2=9",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59108": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "\u00a0In the reaction\u00a0Cr_2O_7^{--} + H + ne \u2192 Cr^{++} + H_2O. The value of n in the balanced equation is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55446": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "-1",
                "question_text": "The O.N. of Co in a\u00a0K[Co(NH_3)_4 is",
                "correct_ans": "-1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50914": {
                "ans1": "CH_3CHO",
                "ans2": "H_2O",
                "ans3": "CH_3COCH_3",
                "ans4": "CH_3COOCH_3",
                "question_text": "Which will form hydrocarbon with Grignard reagent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2O",
                "explanation": "Grignard reagent gives alkane with compound containing active hydrogen like H2\u200bO, NH3\u200b\u00a0,etc to give alkane.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58718": {
                "ans1": "6.023\\times10^{23}",
                "ans2": "6.023\\times10^{16}",
                "ans3": "5.67\\times10^{19}",
                "ans4": "6.023\\times10^{24}",
                "question_text": "The number of Hydrogen atoms present in 4g of marsh gas is",
                "correct_ans": "6.023\\times10^{23}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55348": {
                "ans1": "carbocation",
                "ans2": "carbanion",
                "ans3": "free radical",
                "ans4": "carbene",
                "question_text": "The reaction intermediate formed by homolytic fission is",
                "correct_ans": "free radical",
                "explanation": "During homolytic fission the fragment gets one electron each to form free radical",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50378": {
                "ans1": "Van-Arkels method",
                "ans2": "Liquation",
                "ans3": "Poling",
                "ans4": "Zone refining",
                "question_text": "If metal contains it own oxide as its impurities it is refined by",
                "correct_ans": "Poling",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57356": {
                "ans1": "2.3",
                "ans2": "0.77",
                "ans3": "3.2",
                "ans4": "2.1",
                "question_text": "pH of 0.63%\u00a0HCl\u00a0solution is",
                "correct_ans": "0.77",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55982": {
                "ans1": "289500 C     ",
                "ans2": "96500 C     ",
                "ans3": "86850 C    ",
                "ans4": "28950 C",
                "question_text": "The amount of electricity required to liberate 0.3 mole of Al^{3+} is",
                "correct_ans": "86850 C    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56286": {
                "ans1": "Rhombic",
                "ans2": "Colloidal",
                "ans3": "Monoclinic  ",
                "ans4": "Milk of Sulphur",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is most stable allotrope of Sulphur?",
                "correct_ans": "Rhombic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59308": {
                "ans1": "Cu=\\lbrackAr\\rbrack4s^23d^{10}",
                "ans2": "Cu=\\lbrackAr\\rbrack4s^23d^{10}",
                "ans3": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^03d^5",
                "ans4": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^23d^5",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
                "correct_ans": "Cu=\\lbrack Ar\\rbrack4s^23d^5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51648": {
                "ans1": "chlorine gas   ",
                "ans2": "nitric acid    ",
                "ans3": "bromine water    ",
                "ans4": "sulphuric acid",
                "question_text": "Benzene does not reacts with",
                "correct_ans": "bromine water    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50149": {
                "ans1": "Hg",
                "ans2": "Au",
                "ans3": "Cd",
                "ans4": "Ca",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element lies in group\u00a0 of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Au",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52247": {
                "ans1": "Melting of ice into water.    ",
                "ans2": "Expansion of metal on heating.",
                "ans3": "Dissolving of sugar into water.    ",
                "ans4": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element is methylating agent?",
                "correct_ans": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58825": {
                "ans1": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans2": "positive & reduction centre ",
                "ans3": "negative & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans4": "negative & reduction centre ",
                "question_text": "Anode in electrolytic cell is",
                "correct_ans": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53268": {
                "ans1": "KMnO_4",
                "ans2": "Mn_2O_4",
                "ans3": "Mn_2O_3",
                "ans4": "MnO_2",
                "question_text": "Lowest oxidation state of manganese is found in",
                "correct_ans": "Mn_2O_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52191": {
                "ans1": "PO_3^{--}",
                "ans2": "H_2PO_3^{--}",
                "ans3": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "ans4": " H_2PO_3^{--} ",
                "question_text": "Conjugate acid of\u00a0HPO^{3--}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57318": {
                "ans1": "Fractional distillation",
                "ans2": "Sublimation",
                "ans3": "Steam distillation",
                "ans4": "crystallization ",
                "question_text": "Aniline can be purified by",
                "correct_ans": "Steam distillation",
                "explanation": "Because aniline is steam volatile",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51457": {
                "ans1": "Group I    ",
                "ans2": "Group II    ",
                "ans3": "Group III   ",
                "ans4": "Group zero ",
                "question_text": "The chloride of which group elements of periodic table form neutral solution in water?",
                "correct_ans": "Group I    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57720": {
                "ans1": "K_2O",
                "ans2": "K_2O_2",
                "ans3": "KO_2",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "The O.N of oxygen is\u00a0\\dfrac {-1}{2}\u200b\u00a0in",
                "correct_ans": "KO_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54476": {
                "ans1": "solved electrons",
                "ans2": "ammnonium ions",
                "ans3": "solvated sodium ions",
                "ans4": "sodium atoms",
                "question_text": "A solution of sodium in liquid ammonia is blue due to the presence of",
                "correct_ans": "solved electrons",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58908": {
                "ans1": "94 pm",
                "ans2": "94 nm",
                "ans3": "94 A",
                "ans4": "9.4 A",
                "question_text": "The wavelength of a neutron moving at a speed of\u00a04.32\\times 10^2\\dfrac{\\text{m}}{\\text{s}} \u200b(mass of neutron\u00a0 1.67\\times 10^{-27} kg) is",
                "correct_ans": "9.4 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57640": {
                "ans1": "45",
                "ans2": "60",
                "ans3": "70",
                "ans4": "90",
                "question_text": "0.45gm\u00a0of dibasic acid required 200ml of\u00a0\\dfrac{N}{20}\u00a0NaOH solution For neutralization. The molecular weight of the dibasic acid is",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55877": {
                "ans1": "cracking",
                "ans2": "polymerization",
                "ans3": "condensation",
                "ans4": "isomerisation",
                "question_text": "The method of converting high boiling hydrocarbon into low boiling hydrocarbons is known as",
                "correct_ans": "isomerisation",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54607": {
                "ans1": "alkylation",
                "ans2": "acylation",
                "ans3": " idonation",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Ethyl benzene is prepared by friedel Crafts reaction This is ___ reaction",
                "correct_ans": "alkylation",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54089": {
                "ans1": "cast iron",
                "ans2": "wrought iron",
                "ans3": "steel iron",
                "ans4": "all have same percentage",
                "question_text": "Which of the following has lowest percentage of carbon?",
                "correct_ans": "wrought iron",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54651": {
                "ans1": "isomers",
                "ans2": "isotones",
                "ans3": "allotropes",
                "ans4": "isomorphous",
                "question_text": "Compounds with identical crystal structure and analogous chemical formula are called.",
                "correct_ans": "isomorphous",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53425": {
                "ans1": "gem",
                "ans2": "ion exchanger",
                "ans3": "pigment",
                "ans4": "lubricant",
                "question_text": "Zeolite are used as",
                "correct_ans": "ion exchanger",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59797": {
                "ans1": "C",
                "ans2": "P",
                "ans3": "S",
                "ans4": "Si",
                "question_text": "Which is the main impurity in pig iron",
                "correct_ans": "C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51756": {
                "ans1": "0.0625",
                "ans2": "16",
                "ans3": "0.0156",
                "ans4": "64",
                "question_text": "In the dissociation of HI(g) it is found that 20% HI is dissociated . The equilibrium constant of the reaction\u00a0\\\\2\\text{HI(g)}\\leftrightarrow \\text{H}_2+\\text{I}_2\\text{(g)} will be",
                "correct_ans": "0.0156",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56832": {
                "ans1": "NH _4 \u200b",
                "ans2": "BF_3",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "HSO_4\\;^-\\;\u200b",
                "question_text": "Which of these is lewis acid but not Bronsted acid?",
                "correct_ans": "BF_3",
                "explanation": "BF3\u200b; has incomplete octet on Boron so it is electron acceptor (lewis acid) but it can't donate proton (Bronsted acid).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53587": {
                "ans1": "But-2-enal",
                "ans2": "propenal",
                "ans3": "propynal",
                "ans4": " But-2-ynal",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of acraldehyde is",
                "correct_ans": "propenal",
                "explanation": "CH_{2} = CH\u2212CHO\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57797": {
                "ans1": "ClF",
                "ans2": "PCl _3 \u200b",
                "ans3": "SiF _4 \u200b",
                "ans4": "CHCl _3 \u200b",
                "question_text": "Which one of the following has zero dipole moment?",
                "correct_ans": "SiF _4 \u200b",
                "explanation": "SiF4\u200b\u00a0is symmetrical molecule hence its dipole moment is 0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59589": {
                "ans1": "equal to meatal",
                "ans2": "greater than metal",
                "ans3": "less than metal",
                "ans4": "depends upon formation of slag",
                "question_text": "The density of slag is always",
                "correct_ans": "less than metal",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59324": {
                "ans1": "96500C",
                "ans2": " 1 mole of electron",
                "ans3": "6.022\\times10^{23}\\;\\times1.6\\times10\\;^{\\;-19\\;}\\;C",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "One Faraday is",
                "correct_ans": "all",
                "explanation": "1 Faraday is charge of 1 mole of electron so, 1F=1 mole\u00a0e^{-}e\u2212=96500C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51452": {
                "ans1": "35 gm",
                "ans2": " 36gm",
                "ans3": " 27gm",
                "ans4": "30gm",
                "question_text": "Mass of water formed by heating 3gm of\u00a0H_{2}\u200b\u00a0with 32gm of oxygen is",
                "correct_ans": " 27gm",
                "explanation": "H_{2} ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57069": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_{4\\;\u200b}",
                "ans2": "Na_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HCN",
                "ans4": "NH_4Cl",
                "question_text": "Which of these have all three types of bonds?",
                "correct_ans": "NH_4Cl",
                "explanation": "NH4\u200bCl\u00a0has all three types of bonds.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51070": {
                "ans1": "Pyramidal",
                "ans2": "Tetrahedral",
                "ans3": " Coplannar",
                "ans4": " Trigonal",
                "question_text": "Structure of ammonia is",
                "correct_ans": "Pyramidal",
                "explanation": "Due to repulsive force of lone pair of electron.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58948": {
                "ans1": "Halide",
                "ans2": "Oxide",
                "ans3": "Sulphide",
                "ans4": "Hydroxide",
                "question_text": "The principle ore of Zinc is",
                "correct_ans": "Sulphide",
                "explanation": "The principle ore of zinc is zinc blend which is a sulphide ore.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57716": {
                "ans1": "7",
                "ans2": "8",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "5",
                "question_text": "The number of s-electrons in Cr-atom is:",
                "correct_ans": "7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59938": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "10",
                "ans4": "N_A",
                "question_text": "Total no. of electrons present in 3.2 gm of\u00a0CH_4\u200b\u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "10",
                "explanation": "CH_4\u200b",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52931": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "4",
                "ans4": "3",
                "question_text": "The no. of unpaired electrons in Cr atom is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "From electronic configuration.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52228": {
                "ans1": "NaNO_3",
                "ans2": "LiNO_3",
                "ans3": "Pb(NO_3)_2",
                "ans4": "Cu(NO_3)_2",
                "question_text": "Nitrogen dioxide cannot be obtained by heating",
                "correct_ans": "NaNO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57123": {
                "ans1": "Na",
                "ans2": "Cl_2",
                "ans3": "Na\\;and\\;Cl_2",
                "ans4": "O_2",
                "question_text": "The products of Down's process",
                "correct_ans": "Na\\;and\\;Cl_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59046": {
                "ans1": "+1",
                "ans2": "+2",
                "ans3": "+3",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "O.N. of 'Fe' in sod. nitroprusside\u00a0Na_{2}[ Fe(CN)_5NO ] is",
                "correct_ans": "+2",
                "explanation": "+2+x\u22125+1=0;so,x=+2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59334": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The magnetic quantum number is -3 then what is the possible principle quantum number?",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "To have magnetic quantum number -3, the value of l should be 3 and principle quantum number should be 4.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58507": {
                "ans1": "increases",
                "ans2": "decreases",
                "ans3": "remain same",
                "ans4": "may increase or decrease",
                "question_text": "Along the period ionization potential\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "increases",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59004": {
                "ans1": "0",
                "ans2": "+3,-3",
                "ans3": "+3,-5",
                "ans4": "+5,-3",
                "question_text": "Oxidation number of nitrogen in\u00a0NH_4\u200bNO_3",
                "correct_ans": "+5,-3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53625": {
                "ans1": "Carbocation",
                "ans2": "Alkyl free radical",
                "ans3": "Carbanion",
                "ans4": "Carbene",
                "question_text": "Intermediate formed in Kharash effect is,",
                "correct_ans": "Alkyl free radical",
                "explanation": "Free radical mechanism",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59163": {
                "ans1": "BeCl_2",
                "ans2": "AlCl_3",
                "ans3": "BF_3",
                "ans4": "BCl_3",
                "question_text": "Which is not lewis acid?",
                "correct_ans": "BeCl_2",
                "explanation": "It needs two lone pair of electrons for make octet.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54472": {
                "ans1": "alcohol",
                "ans2": "water",
                "ans3": "ammonia",
                "ans4": "benzene",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The metal formed by electrolysis of molten rock salt can be stored in:",
                "correct_ans": "benzene",
                "explanation": "The metal formed by electrolysis of rock salt(NaCl) is Na and is stored in benzene as alcohol, water and ammonia reacts with sodium metal.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55036": {
                "ans1": "Bromine",
                "ans2": "Selenium",
                "ans3": "Cesium",
                "ans4": "Telurium",
                "question_text": "Anamolous pair of iodine is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Telurium",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55752": {
                "ans1": "NaOH",
                "ans2": "KOH",
                "ans3": "bleaching powder",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Brine is used for industrial production of",
                "correct_ans": "NaOH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59915": {
                "ans1": "MgO",
                "ans2": "CaO",
                "ans3": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "ans4": "Na_2O",
                "question_text": "Which one is the most acidic among these?",
                "correct_ans": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "explanation": "MgO, CaO and Na2O are alkalies whereas\u00a0Al_2O_3\u200b\u00a0is amphoteric(most acidic among four).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57548": {
                "ans1": "calcium hypo oxychloride",
                "ans2": "calcium oxychloride",
                "ans3": "calcium chloride",
                "ans4": "calcium chloro oxide",
                "question_text": "The chemical name for bleaching powder is",
                "correct_ans": "calcium oxychloride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56738": {
                "ans1": "hydrogenation",
                "ans2": "oxidation",
                "ans3": "reduction",
                "ans4": "sublimation",
                "question_text": "Loss of hydrogen atoms by an element is called",
                "correct_ans": "oxidation",
                "explanation": "Addition of oxygen = oxidationAddition of hydrogen = reductionRemoval of oxygen = reductionRemoval of hydrogen = oxidation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57026": {
                "ans1": "reducing agent",
                "ans2": "oxidising agent",
                "ans3": "hydrogen",
                "ans4": "sublime",
                "question_text": "A reactant containing the element that is oxidised is called",
                "correct_ans": "reducing agent",
                "explanation": "Reducing agent reduces other compounds but itself gets oxidized",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55810": {
                "ans1": "nitric acid",
                "ans2": " sulfuric acid",
                "ans3": "phosphoric acid",
                "ans4": "hydrochloric acid",
                "question_text": "The acid used for the manufacture of fertilizers and explosives is",
                "correct_ans": " sulfuric acid",
                "explanation": "Nitric acid is used for a variety of purposes including manufacture of fertilizers and explosives.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57860": {
                "ans1": " Cl > F > O > Br",
                "ans2": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "ans3": "F > Cl > Br > O",
                "ans4": "O > F > Cl > Br",
                "question_text": "The correct order of electronegativity is",
                "correct_ans": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "explanation": "Electronegativity of halogens decreases as we move down the group following the convention.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58582": {
                "ans1": " 3:1",
                "ans2": "1:3",
                "ans3": "1:4",
                "ans4": "4:3",
                "question_text": "The ratio of the water molecule in plaster of paris and gypsum is",
                "correct_ans": "1:4",
                "explanation": "CaSO_4.1/2H_2OCaSO_4.2H_2O\\dfrac{1}{2}:2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53021": {
                "ans1": "+6",
                "ans2": "+5",
                "ans3": "-10",
                "ans4": "+3",
                "question_text": "H_2\u200bO_2\u200b\u00a0\u00a0changes \u00a0Cr_2O_7^{2-}\u200b\u00a0ion to\u00a0CrO_5\u200b\u00a0in an acidic medium, the oxidation state of Cr in\u00a0CrO_3\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "+6",
                "explanation": "Cr2\u200bO5\u200b\u00a0has two O-O bonds. Hence its oxidation state is given as x+(-2)+ 2 x (-2)=0 i.e., x=6.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59653": {
                "ans1": " I > I- > I+",
                "ans2": "I > I+ > I-",
                "ans3": " I- > I > I+",
                "ans4": "I+ > I- > I",
                "question_text": "The correct order for the size of I, I+, I- is",
                "correct_ans": " I- > I > I+",
                "explanation": "I- has more number of valence electrons as compared to I and I+. Hence net nuclear force per unit charge is more for I+ , followed by I- and I. thus I+ has smallest size followed by I and I-",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55460": {
                "ans1": "chlorine gas   ",
                "ans2": "nitric acid    ",
                "ans3": "bromine water    ",
                "ans4": "sulphuric acid",
                "question_text": "Benzene does not reacts with",
                "correct_ans": "bromine water    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55737": {
                "ans1": "Rhombic",
                "ans2": "Colloidal",
                "ans3": " Monoclinic    ",
                "ans4": "Milk of Sulphur",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is most stable allotrope of Sulphur?",
                "correct_ans": "Rhombic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54776": {
                "ans1": "C_2H_5Br",
                "ans2": "C_2H_5Cl",
                "ans3": "CH_3I",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element is methylating agent?",
                "correct_ans": "C_2H_5Cl",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54728": {
                "ans1": "289500 C     ",
                "ans2": "96500 C     ",
                "ans3": "86850 C    ",
                "ans4": "28950 C",
                "question_text": "The amount of electricity required to liberate 0.3 mole of Al3+ is",
                "correct_ans": "86850 C    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59509": {
                "ans1": "KMnO_4",
                "ans2": "Mn_2O_4",
                "ans3": "Mn_2O_3",
                "ans4": "MnO_2",
                "question_text": "Lowest oxidation state of manganese is found in",
                "correct_ans": "Mn_2O_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56019": {
                "ans1": "Hg",
                "ans2": "Au",
                "ans3": "Cd",
                "ans4": "Ca",
                "question_text": "Which of the following element lies in group\u00a0 of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Au",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57443": {
                "ans1": "PO_3^{--}",
                "ans2": "H_2PO_3^{--}",
                "ans3": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "ans4": " H_2PO_3^{--} ",
                "question_text": "Conjugate acid of HPO_3^{--} is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2PO_3^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52294": {
                "ans1": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^10",
                "ans2": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^9",
                "ans3": "Cu=[Ar]4s^03d^5",
                "ans4": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^5",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
                "correct_ans": "Cu=[Ar]4s^23d^5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57679": {
                "ans1": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans2": "positive & reduction centre ",
                "ans3": "negative & oxidation centre     ",
                "ans4": "negative & reduction centre ",
                "question_text": "Anode in electrolytic cell is",
                "correct_ans": "positive & oxidation centre     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55794": {
                "ans1": "Group I    ",
                "ans2": "Group II    ",
                "ans3": "Group III   ",
                "ans4": "Group zero ",
                "question_text": "The chloride of which group elements of periodic table form neutral solution in water?",
                "correct_ans": "Group I    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58131": {
                "ans1": "Melting of ice into water.    ",
                "ans2": "Expansion of metal on heating.",
                "ans3": "Dissolving of sugar into water.    ",
                "ans4": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is chemical reaction?",
                "correct_ans": "Change of fluorine to its ion.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54240": {
                "ans1": "ore is concentracted",
                "ans2": "Metal is extracted  from ore",
                "ans3": "Pure metal is extracted",
                "ans4": "Alloy is matte",
                "question_text": "Metallugy is a process in which",
                "correct_ans": "Pure metal is extracted",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56007": {
                "ans1": "HF",
                "ans2": "HCl",
                "ans3": "HBr",
                "ans4": "HI",
                "question_text": "Which of this is most reducing ?",
                "correct_ans": "HI",
                "explanation": "HI is more reducing character\u00a0 because Iodine is more electropositive than other halogen",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54932": {
                "ans1": "Fe",
                "ans2": "Pt",
                "ans3": "Hg",
                "ans4": "graphite",
                "question_text": "The cathode used during manufacture of NaOH by Caster-Kellener's process is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Hg",
                "explanation": "Hg act as cathode in outer two\u00a0 compartments",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51226": {
                "ans1": "pig iron",
                "ans2": "cast iron",
                "ans3": "steel",
                "ans4": "wrought iron",
                "question_text": "The purest form of iron is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "wrought iron",
                "explanation": "wrought is purest form of iron , It contains (0.12-0.25)% of carbon",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50331": {
                "ans1": "sp",
                "ans2": "sp^2",
                "ans3": "sp^3",
                "ans4": "dsp^2",
                "question_text": "The type of hybridization on sulphur atom of sulphite ion is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "sp^3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57583": {
                "ans1": "C",
                "ans2": "P",
                "ans3": "S",
                "ans4": "Si",
                "question_text": "Which is the main impurity in pig iron",
                "correct_ans": "C",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57818": {
                "ans1": "solved electrons",
                "ans2": "ammnonium ions",
                "ans3": "solvated sodium ions",
                "ans4": "sodium atoms",
                "question_text": "A solution of sodium in liquid ammonia is blue due to the presence of",
                "correct_ans": "solved electrons",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53982": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "The total number of chain isomers of the formula\u00a0C_7H_{16}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "C_7H_{16}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50395": {
                "ans1": "MCl",
                "ans2": "MCl_2",
                "ans3": "MCl_3",
                "ans4": "MCl_4",
                "question_text": "The equivalent weight of a metal is\u00a025. The vapour density of its chloride is 91. The formula of the metal chloride is",
                "correct_ans": "MCl_3",
                "explanation": "Valency = \\frac{2*V.D}{Eq. wt. of M +35.5} = \\frac{2*91}{25+35.5}\\frac{182}{60.5}=3=MCl_3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59954": {
                "ans1": "German silver",
                "ans2": "Rold gold",
                "ans3": "Constantan",
                "ans4": "invar",
                "question_text": "Which of this is not an alloy of copper ?",
                "correct_ans": "invar",
                "explanation": "Invar contain 64% of Fe +35% of Ni + Trace of Mn\u00a0 and C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57040": {
                "ans1": "0.25 N_A",
                "ans2": "0.5 N_A",
                "ans3": "0.75 N_A",
                "ans4": " N_A",
                "question_text": "The number of electrons present in 1 gram of Helium is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 N_A",
                "explanation": "_A\\frac{2N_A}{4} = 0.5 N_A",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59845": {
                "ans1": "Increasing atomic number",
                "ans2": "Increasing atomic mass",
                "ans3": "Increasing no. of protons ",
                "ans4": "Increasing valency",
                "question_text": "Isotopes have no separate place in periodic table because elements are arranged in order of :",
                "correct_ans": "Increasing atomic number",
                "explanation": "Elements are arranged in the order of increasing atomic number in periodic table",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52219": {
                "ans1": "Mg",
                "ans2": "Al",
                "ans3": "Na",
                "ans4": "Fe",
                "question_text": "Which of the following metal is most abundant in earth's crust?",
                "correct_ans": "Al",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58755": {
                "ans1": "{\\mathrm H}_3{\\mathrm{PO}}_3",
                "ans2": "{\\mathrm H}_3{\\mathrm{PO}}_4",
                "ans3": "\\mathrm H2\\mathrm{PO}_4^-",
                "ans4": "\\mathrm{PO}_4^{---}",
                "question_text": "The conjugate acid of \\mathrm{HPO}_4^{--} is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\mathrm H2\\mathrm{PO}_4^-",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53371": {
                "ans1": "[Cu(NH_4)_3]SO_4",
                "ans2": "[Cu(NH_3)_2]SO_4",
                "ans3": "[Cu(NH_3)_4]SO_4",
                "ans4": "\\lbrack Cu(NH_3)_4\\rbrack{\\left(SO_4\\right)}_2",
                "question_text": "Molecular formula of Tetraammine copper sulphate is :",
                "correct_ans": "[Cu(NH_3)_4]SO_4",
                "explanation": "[Cu(NH_3)_4]SO_4",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54097": {
                "ans1": "v",
                "ans2": "{}_4Be^9",
                "ans3": "{}_2He^4",
                "ans4": "{}_4Li^8",
                "question_text": "If _3Li^7\u00a0absorbs a proton , the element formed is :",
                "correct_ans": "{}_2He^4",
                "explanation": "{}_3Li^7+p^+\\rightarrow\\;\\;_2He^4+17\\;Mev",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53614": {
                "ans1": "CaSO_4.",
                "ans2": "CaSO_4.H_2O",
                "ans3": "CaSO_4.2H_2O",
                "ans4": "CaSO_4.3H_2O",
                "question_text": "What is the molecular formula of Gypsum salt?",
                "correct_ans": "CaSO_4.2H_2O",
                "explanation": "CaSO_4.2H_2O",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56982": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "5",
                "ans3": "7",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "The total number of chain isomers of the formula\u00a0C_7H_{16}\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "9",
                "explanation": "C_7H_{16}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52553": {
                "ans1": "SO_2",
                "ans2": "N_2",
                "ans3": "O_2",
                "ans4": "HS_2",
                "question_text": "Which of the following gases cannot be collected over water?",
                "correct_ans": "SO_2",
                "explanation": "SO_2 + H_2O \\rightarrow H_2SO_3H_2O)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57078": {
                "ans1": "S^{--}",
                "ans2": "H_2S",
                "ans3": "H^+",
                "ans4": "HS_2",
                "question_text": "The conjugate acid of HS^-\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "H_2S",
                "explanation": "H^+HS^-+H^+\\rightarrow H_2S",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58016": {
                "ans1": "NaHCO_3",
                "ans2": "NH_4Cl",
                "ans3": "(NH_4)_2CO_3",
                "ans4": "NaCl",
                "question_text": "Which of the following compounds does not have smell?",
                "correct_ans": "NaCl",
                "explanation": "NaCl is an odorless compound",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59687": {
                "ans1": "Hard",
                "ans2": "Soft",
                "ans3": "Brittle",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "Wrought iron is :",
                "correct_ans": "Hard",
                "explanation": "Wrought is hard and ductile",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57021": {
                "ans1": "Bromine",
                "ans2": "Selenium",
                "ans3": "Cesium",
                "ans4": "Telurium",
                "question_text": "Anamolous pair of iodine is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Telurium",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52668": {
                "ans1": "NaOH",
                "ans2": "KOH",
                "ans3": "bleaching powder",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Brine is used for industrial production of",
                "correct_ans": "NaOH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59045": {
                "ans1": "MgO",
                "ans2": "CaO",
                "ans3": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "ans4": "Na_2O",
                "question_text": "Which one is the most acidic among these?",
                "correct_ans": "Al_2 O_3 \u200b",
                "explanation": "MgO, CaO and Na2O are alkalies whereas\u00a0Al_2O_3\u200b\u00a0is amphoteric(most acidic among four).",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55525": {
                "ans1": "calcium hypo oxychloride",
                "ans2": "calcium oxychloride",
                "ans3": "calcium chloride",
                "ans4": "calcium chloro oxide",
                "question_text": "The chemical name for bleaching powder is",
                "correct_ans": "calcium oxychloride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52524": {
                "ans1": "hydrogenation",
                "ans2": "oxidation",
                "ans3": "reduction",
                "ans4": "sublimation",
                "question_text": "Loss of hydrogen atoms by an element is called",
                "correct_ans": "oxidation",
                "explanation": "Addition of oxygen = oxidationAddition of hydrogen = reductionRemoval of oxygen = reductionRemoval of hydrogen = oxidation",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55426": {
                "ans1": "reducing agent",
                "ans2": "oxidising agent",
                "ans3": "hydrogen",
                "ans4": "sublime",
                "question_text": "A reactant containing the element that is oxidised is called",
                "correct_ans": "reducing agent",
                "explanation": "Reducing agent reduces other compounds but itself gets oxidized",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57316": {
                "ans1": "nitric acid",
                "ans2": " sulfuric acid",
                "ans3": "phosphoric acid",
                "ans4": "hydrochloric acid",
                "question_text": "The acid used for the manufacture of fertilizers and explosives is",
                "correct_ans": " sulfuric acid",
                "explanation": "Nitric acid is used for a variety of purposes including manufacture of fertilizers and explosives.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59243": {
                "ans1": " Cl > F > O > Br",
                "ans2": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "ans3": "F > Cl > Br > O",
                "ans4": "O > F > Cl > Br",
                "question_text": "The correct order of electronegativity is",
                "correct_ans": "F > O > Cl > Br",
                "explanation": "Electronegativity of halogens decreases as we move down the group following the convention.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58192": {
                "ans1": " 3:1",
                "ans2": "1:3",
                "ans3": "1:4",
                "ans4": "4:3",
                "question_text": "The ratio of the water molecule in plaster of paris and gypsum is",
                "correct_ans": "1:4",
                "explanation": "CaSO_4.1/2H_2OCaSO_4.2H_2O\\dfrac{1}{2}:2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56155": {
                "ans1": "+6",
                "ans2": "+5",
                "ans3": "-10",
                "ans4": "+3",
                "question_text": "H_2\u200bO_2\u200b\u00a0\u00a0changes \u00a0Cr_2O_7^{2-}\u200b\u00a0ion to\u00a0CrO_5\u200b\u00a0in an acidic medium, the oxidation state of Cr in\u00a0CrO_3\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "+6",
                "explanation": "Cr2\u200bO5\u200b\u00a0has two O-O bonds. Hence its oxidation state is given as x+(-2)+ 2 x (-2)=0 i.e., x=6.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55220": {
                "ans1": " I > I- > I+",
                "ans2": "I > I+ > I-",
                "ans3": " I- > I > I+",
                "ans4": "I+ > I- > I",
                "question_text": "The correct order for the size of I, I+, I- is",
                "correct_ans": " I- > I > I+",
                "explanation": "I- has more number of valence electrons as compared to I and I+. Hence net nuclear force per unit charge is more for I+ , followed by I- and I. thus I+ has smallest size followed by I and I-",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59429": {
                "ans1": "Dutch metal",
                "ans2": "Invar",
                "ans3": "Constantan",
                "ans4": "German silver",
                "question_text": "Which of this is not an alloy of copper?",
                "correct_ans": "Invar",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58915": {
                "ans1": "Na and Ca",
                "ans2": "Mg and Al",
                "ans3": "Na and Be",
                "ans4": "Be and Al",
                "question_text": "Which of this pair shows diagonal relation?",
                "correct_ans": "Be and Al",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53499": {
                "ans1": "\\;CH_4\\;",
                "ans2": "\\;CH_3Cl",
                "ans3": "\\;CH_3NO_2",
                "ans4": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest boiling point?",
                "correct_ans": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "explanation": "\\;CH_3OH",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52096": {
                "ans1": "n",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "n+1",
                "ans4": "n-1",
                "question_text": "The atomic orbitals are filled up in the order of",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "The energy of the atomic orbitals increase with increase on (n+l) value",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51822": {
                "ans1": "NH_4^+",
                "ans2": "H_2O",
                "ans3": "CN^-",
                "ans4": "HCl",
                "question_text": "Which of this is Bronsted acid but Lewis base?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2O",
                "explanation": "water is both bronsted acid and base",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58023": {
                "ans1": "F^-",
                "ans2": "Cl^-",
                "ans3": "Br^-",
                "ans4": "I^-",
                "question_text": "Which of these is most reducing?",
                "correct_ans": "F^-",
                "explanation": "Fluorine is most reducing agent",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55777": {
                "ans1": "0.1 mole of glucose",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}11.2\\;molecules\\;of\\;CO_2\\\\gas\\;at\\;STP\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "N_A\\;CH_4\\;molecule",
                "ans4": "20g\\;of\\;H_2O",
                "question_text": "Which of these have highest mass?",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}11.2\\;molecules\\;of\\;CO_2\\\\gas\\;at\\;STP\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}0.1\\;mole\\;C_4H_{12}O_6\\;=18g\\\\11.2\\;l\\;CO_{2\\;}\\;at\\;STP\\;=22g\\\\N_A\\;CH_4\\;molecules\\;=16g\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50123": {
                "ans1": "98",
                "ans2": "49",
                "ans3": "32.66",
                "ans4": "24.5",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;equivalent\\;weight\\;of\\;\\\\H_3PO_4,\\;in\\;the\\;reaction\\end{array}\\begin{array}{l}Ca(OH)_{2\\;}+\\;H_3PO_4\\;\\\\\\rightarrow CaHPO_4\\;+H_2O\\;\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "98",
                "explanation": "Basicity is 1 so, eq wt. is equal to molecular wt.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56299": {
                "ans1": "K_4Fe(CN)_6",
                "ans2": "FeO",
                "ans3": "Fe(CO)_5",
                "ans4": "Fe_3O_4",
                "question_text": "The oxidation number of Fe is least in",
                "correct_ans": "Fe(CO)_5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57599": {
                "ans1": "Carboniumion",
                "ans2": "Carbanion",
                "ans3": "Free-radical",
                "ans4": "carbocation",
                "question_text": "The intermediate formed during addition of HBr to propene in presence of peroxide is",
                "correct_ans": "Carboniumion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59900": {
                "ans1": "Fractional distillation",
                "ans2": "Sublimation",
                "ans3": "Steam distillation",
                "ans4": "crystallization ",
                "question_text": "Aniline can be purified by",
                "correct_ans": "Steam distillation",
                "explanation": "Because aniline is steam volatile",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55750": {
                "ans1": " N_A",
                "ans2": " 1.2N_A",
                "ans3": "0.2 N_A",
                "ans4": " 2N_A",
                "question_text": "Total\\;no.\\;of\\;electrons\\;present\\;in\\;3.2g\\;of\\;CH_4\\;is:",
                "correct_ans": " 2N_A",
                "explanation": "1\\;mole\\;of\\;CH_4=(6\\ast2+1\\ast4=16g)\\;of\\;CH_4=(6+1\\ast4=10)\\ast N_A\\;no.\\;of\\;electrons\\\\\\Rightarrow16g\\;of\\;CH_4\\;has\\;10\\;N_A\\;no.\\;of\\;elctrons.\\\\\\Rightarrow3.2g\\;of\\;CH_4\\;has\\;\\frac{10\\ast3.2}{16}\\;N_A=2\\;N_A\\;no.\\;of\\;elctrons.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56304": {
                "ans1": "Na_2O",
                "ans2": "CuO",
                "ans3": "Ag_2O",
                "ans4": "ZnO",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is thermally unstable?",
                "correct_ans": "Ag_2O",
                "explanation": "Ag_2O\\xrightarrow\\Delta 4Ag+O_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54827": {
                "ans1": "+1",
                "ans2": "+2",
                "ans3": "+3",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "O.N. of 'Fe' in sodium nitoprusside\u00a0Na_2[Fe(CN)_5NO]\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "+2",
                "explanation": "+2+x-5+1 = 0hence, x = +2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51902": {
                "ans1": "Dicyano ethane",
                "ans2": "Ethane dinitride",
                "ans3": "Methane dinitride",
                "ans4": "Dicyanide",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of\u00a0(CN)_2\u00a0is:",
                "correct_ans": "Methane dinitride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51997": {
                "ans1": "ethane = ethene = ethyne",
                "ans2": "ethane > ethene > ethyne",
                "ans3": "ethyne > ethene > ethane",
                "ans4": "ethene > ethyne > ethane",
                "question_text": "Electronegtivity order of carbon in hydrocarbon is",
                "correct_ans": "ethyne > ethene > ethane",
                "explanation": "Increase in 'S' character increases electronegativity.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54478": {
                "ans1": "Glyoxal",
                "ans2": "Glycol",
                "ans3": "Acetaldehyde",
                "ans4": "Acetic acid",
                "question_text": "The acetylene gas on pasing through\u00a0dil. HgSO_4 \\;and \\;dil. H_2SO_4\u00a0gives:",
                "correct_ans": "Acetaldehyde",
                "explanation": "CH\\equiv CH+H_2O\\xrightarrow[{dil.\\;HgSO_4}]{dil\\;H_2SO_4}CH_3-CHO\\\\",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50284": {
                "ans1": "Ca^{++}",
                "ans2": "Sn^{++}",
                "ans3": "Ba^{++}",
                "ans4": "all equal",
                "question_text": "Which of the follwoing cation generates maximum covalent character with\u00a0O^{--}ion?",
                "correct_ans": "Ca^{++}",
                "explanation": "Smaller cation has more tendency to develop covalent character.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59342": {
                "ans1": "NaH_2PO_2",
                "ans2": "Na_2CO_3",
                "ans3": "NH_4Cl",
                "ans4": "NaHCO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is an acid\u00a0salt?",
                "correct_ans": "NaHCO_3",
                "explanation": "NaHCO_3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56607": {
                "ans1": "cation",
                "ans2": "anion",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Basic resin of organic process removes",
                "correct_ans": "anion",
                "explanation": "RNH_3OH+Cl^-\\rightarrow RNH_3+O_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51899": {
                "ans1": "CuSO_4",
                "ans2": "ZnSO_4",
                "ans3": "MgSO_4",
                "ans4": "All",
                "question_text": "Which of the followings can oxidise\u00a0KI?",
                "correct_ans": "CuSO_4",
                "explanation": "CuSO_4+KI\\rightarrow CuI_2+K_2SO_4\\\\\nCuI_2\\rightarrow I_2+Cu_2I_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58430": {
                "ans1": "acidic",
                "ans2": "basic",
                "ans3": "neutral",
                "ans4": "any of the above",
                "question_text": "pH of boiling water is 6.5, its nature is:",
                "correct_ans": "neutral",
                "explanation": "Ionic product increases with increase in temp. Hence, pH decreases.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53151": {
                "ans1": "Increases",
                "ans2": "Decreases",
                "ans3": "does not change",
                "ans4": "NaCl is decomposed.",
                "question_text": "When HCl gas is passed through a saturated solution of NaCl the solubility of NaCl",
                "correct_ans": "Decreases",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53245": {
                "ans1": "Functional",
                "ans2": "Positional",
                "ans3": "Tautomerism",
                "ans4": "Metamerism",
                "question_text": "he isomerism exhibited by alkyl cyanide and alkyl isocyanide is",
                "correct_ans": "Functional",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51752": {
                "ans1": "He^{+} (n=2)",
                "ans2": "Li^{2+} (n=2)",
                "ans3": "Li^{2+} (n=3)",
                "ans4": "Be^{3+} (n=2)",
                "question_text": "The radius of which of the following orbit is same as that of the first Bohr's orbit of hydrogen atom",
                "correct_ans": "Be^{3+} (n=2)",
                "explanation": "r_{H} =0.529\\cfrac{n^{2} }{z} \u00c5For hydrogen ;\u00a0n=1\u00a0and\u00a0z=1\\thereforer Be^{3+} :\\,r_{Be^{3+} } =\\cfrac{0.529\\times 2^{2} }{4} =0.529\u00c5.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54982": {
                "ans1": "Frankland's reaction",
                "ans2": "Wurtz reaction",
                "ans3": "Cannizzaro reaction",
                "ans4": "Kolbe's reaction",
                "question_text": "Formation of alkane by the action of\u00a0Zn\u00a0on alkyl halide is called",
                "correct_ans": "Frankland's reaction",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55800": {
                "ans1": "Molecular formula",
                "ans2": "Structural formula",
                "ans3": "Empirical formula",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "Actual number of atoms of different elements present in a molecule of a compound is given by",
                "correct_ans": "Molecular formula",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57958": {
                "ans1": "460 \\textit{ml}",
                "ans2": "540 ml",
                "ans3": "480 ml",
                "ans4": "470 ml",
                "question_text": "25\u00a0ml\u00a0of a solution of\u00a0Na_2CO_3 having a specific gravity of 1.25 required 32.9\u00a0ml of a solution of\u00a0HCl containing 109.5\u00a0grams of the acid per litre for complete neutralization. Calculate the volume of 0.84\u00a0N\u00a0-\u00a0H_2SO_4\u00a0that will be completely neutralized by 125\u00a0grams of the\u00a0Na_2CO_3\u00a0\u00a0solution",
                "correct_ans": "470 ml",
                "explanation": "Na_2CO_3 = HClN_{1} V_{1} =N_{2} V_{2}\nN_{1} V_{1} =\\cfrac{ \\text{Weight of acid}}{\\text{Eq. Wt of acid}} \\times V_{2}\nN\\times 25=\\cfrac{109.5}{36.5}\\times 32.9 \\\\ \\Rightarrow N=\\cfrac{109.5\\times 32.9}{36.5\\times 25}\n\nNa_2CO_3 = H_2SO_4\nN_{3} V_{3} =N_{4} V_{4} (V_{3} =\\cfrac{m}{d} \\,\\,\\,\\,\\, V_{3} =\\cfrac{125}{1.25} )\n\\cfrac{109.5\\times 32.9}{36.5\\times 25} \\times 100=0.84\\times V\\Rightarrow V=470\\, ml",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59799": {
                "ans1": "oxygen",
                "ans2": "sulphur dioxide",
                "ans3": "sulphure trioxide",
                "ans4": "hydrogen sulphide",
                "question_text": "Gas obtained when copper is heated with concentrated sulphuric acid is:",
                "correct_ans": "sulphur dioxide",
                "explanation": "REACTION OF COPPER WITH SULPHURIC ACID",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54918": {
                "ans1": "Zinc ethyl",
                "ans2": "ethanol",
                "ans3": "ethane",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Ethyl iodide when reduced by Zn- Cu couple, which of following will be formed",
                "correct_ans": "ethane",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58500": {
                "ans1": "ZnO",
                "ans2": "ZnH_{2}",
                "ans3": "Zn(OH)_{2}",
                "ans4": "Na_{2}ZnO{2}",
                "question_text": "Excess of sodium hydroxide reacts with zinc to give:",
                "correct_ans": "Na_{2}ZnO{2}",
                "explanation": "Zinc dissolves in excess of alkali to give zincate salts of the alkali metals:Zn + 2NaOH \\to \\underset{\\text{Sodium zincate}}{Na_2ZnO_2} + H_2\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58868": {
                "ans1": "Ionisation potential",
                "ans2": "Electronegativity",
                "ans3": "Electron affinity",
                "ans4": "Number of electrons in the valence shell",
                "question_text": "The basis of keeping the elements in the group of a periodic table is",
                "correct_ans": "Number of electrons in the valence shell",
                "explanation": "The elements which having same number of electrons in the valence shell are placed in the same group of periodic table.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59525": {
                "ans1": "\\text{-\\(1.86^{0}\\)} c",
                "ans2": "\\text{-\\(0.93^{0}\\)} c",
                "ans3": "\\text{-\\(0.093^{0}\\)} c",
                "ans4": "0.93^{0} c",
                "question_text": "The freezing point of 0.05 molal solution of a non-electrolyte in water.\u00a0\\text{(K\\(_{f}\\)} for water = 1.85)\u00a0is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "\\text{-\\(1.86^{0}\\)} c",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52122": {
                "ans1": "\\text{Zinc with cold and dilute} HNO_3",
                "ans2": "\\text{Zinc with concentrated } HNO_3",
                "ans3": "\\text{Copper with cold and dilute } HNO_3",
                "ans4": "\\text{Heating}\\space \\mathrm { NH } _ { 4 } \\mathrm { NO } _ { 3 }",
                "question_text": "How can you synthesize nitric oxide in the laboratory ?",
                "correct_ans": "\\text{Copper with cold and dilute } HNO_3",
                "explanation": "3 C u + 8 N H O _ { 3 } \\rightarrow 3 C u \\left( N O _ { 3 } \\right) _ { 2 } + 4 H _ { 2 } O + \\underset {\\text{Nitric oxide}} {2NO}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56570": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2/7",
                "ans3": "5/7",
                "ans4": "2/5",
                "question_text": "When an ideal diatomic gas is heated at constant pressure, the fraction of heat energy supplied which increases the internal energy of the gas is",
                "correct_ans": "5/7",
                "explanation": "Q = nC \\Delta T\\because P = constant,Q = nC_p \\Delta T C_p = \\cfrac{7R}{2}Q = n \\times \\cfrac{7R}{2} \\times TAnd,\\Delta U = nC_v \\Delta T = n \\times \\cfrac{5R}{2} \\times T\\therefore \\cfrac{\\Delta U}{Q} = \\cfrac{n \\times \\cfrac{5R}{2} \\times T}{n \\times \\cfrac{7R}{2} \\times T} = \\cfrac{5}{7}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53772": {
                "ans1": "200cc",
                "ans2": "400cc",
                "ans3": "600cc",
                "ans4": "800cc",
                "question_text": "How much water should be added to 200 c.c of semi normal solution of to make it exactly deci normal",
                "correct_ans": "800cc",
                "explanation": "N_{1} V_{1} =N_{2} V_{2}{1\\over 2} \\times 200={1\\over 10} \\times V_{2}V_{2} =1000ml\\text{Volume of water added }=1000-200=800ml",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53756": {
                "ans1": "Froth floatation process",
                "ans2": "Magnetic separation",
                "ans3": "Gravity separation",
                "ans4": "By hand picking",
                "question_text": "Sulphide ores are generally concentrated by",
                "correct_ans": "Froth floatation process",
                "explanation": "Froth floatation method is based on the fact that the surface of sulphide ores is preferentially wetted by oil while that of gangue is wetted by water.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53637": {
                "ans1": "Mg",
                "ans2": "K",
                "ans3": "Na",
                "ans4": "Ba",
                "question_text": "The most powerful reducing agent is.\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "K",
                "explanation": "The electrochemical series from top to bottom order is:Li, K, Ca, Na, Mg, Al, Zn, Fe, Pb, H2, Cu, Ag, AuIt is the ascending order of tendency of being reduced. Thus the first ones in the series have the most tendency of being oxidized, thus having the most oxidizing power.Hence, K is the most powerful reducing agent among the four.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50097": {
                "ans1": "4 gm ",
                "ans2": "5gm",
                "ans3": "10gm",
                "ans4": "20gm",
                "question_text": "207Pb has half-life of 8 hrs. The amount remaining after one day starting with 40g of the isotope will be",
                "correct_ans": "5gm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50887": {
                "ans1": "annealing",
                "ans2": "quenching ",
                "ans3": "tempering",
                "ans4": " none",
                "question_text": "Iron is heated to res hot and cooled slowly in a heating process. The process is called",
                "correct_ans": "annealing",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52718": {
                "ans1": " It is covalent compound              ",
                "ans2": "It is weaker base than water ",
                "ans3": "It has lower reducing property than water ",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "During permutit process, sodium zeolite exchange ion with",
                "correct_ans": "It has lower reducing property than water ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53721": {
                "ans1": "Roasting",
                "ans2": "smelting",
                "ans3": "Bessimerization",
                "ans4": "calcination",
                "question_text": "The process of converting hydrated alumina to anhydrous alumina is called",
                "correct_ans": "calcination",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58378": {
                "ans1": "3,4,5   ",
                "ans2": "5,3,4    ",
                "ans3": "5,4,3    ",
                "ans4": "3,4,5",
                "question_text": "Oxidation number of Phosphorous in\u00a0H_4P_2O_5,\\;H_4P_2O_6\\;and\\;H_4P_2O_3\\;are respectively",
                "correct_ans": "3,4,5   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56277": {
                "ans1": "Shortest period   ",
                "ans2": "Short period   ",
                "ans3": "Long period  ",
                "ans4": "Longest period",
                "question_text": "What are the elements of second and third period called",
                "correct_ans": "Short period   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50402": {
                "ans1": "Zn",
                "ans2": "Mn",
                "ans3": "Cu",
                "ans4": "Mg",
                "question_text": "Which of the following does not produce hydrogen gas with dilute acids?",
                "correct_ans": "Cu",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53861": {
                "ans1": "increases in pH    ",
                "ans2": "decreases in pH   ",
                "ans3": "no change in pH   ",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "The addition of sodium carbonate in pure water causes",
                "correct_ans": "increases in pH    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54410": {
                "ans1": "11",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "13",
                "ans4": "14",
                "question_text": "Sum of pH and pOH is",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52579": {
                "ans1": "2-methyl pentane    ",
                "ans2": "2,2-dimethyl butane   ",
                "ans3": "hex-3,4-diene   ",
                "ans4": "2,3-dimethyl butane",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of (CH_3)_2CHCH(CH_3)CH_3\\;\\;is",
                "correct_ans": "2,3-dimethyl butane",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57043": {
                "ans1": "Strong affinity of HCl gas for moisture in air results in forming of droplets like a cloudy smoke.",
                "ans2": "Due to strong affinity for water, concentrated HCl pulls moisture of air towards itself and forms droplets like a cloudy smoke.",
                "ans3": "Concentrated HCl emits strongly smelling HCl gas all the time.",
                "ans4": "Oxygen in air reacts with emitted HCl gas to form a cloud of Cl2 gas.",
                "question_text": "Concentrated hydrochloric acid when kept in open air sometimes produces a cloud of white fumes because",
                "correct_ans": "Oxygen in air reacts with emitted HCl gas to form a cloud of Cl2 gas.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56184": {
                "ans1": "44.5",
                "ans2": "62.5",
                "ans3": "115.5",
                "ans4": "133.5",
                "question_text": "The equivalent weight of a trivalent metal is 9. The molecular weight of its chloride is",
                "correct_ans": "133.5",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54334": {
                "ans1": "Pressure is decreased",
                "ans2": "Temperature is increased",
                "ans3": "H^+are\\;added",
                "ans4": "OH^-\\;ions\\;are\\;added",
                "question_text": "The ionic product of water will increase if",
                "correct_ans": "H^+are\\;added",
                "explanation": "Temperature increases because ionic product of water is increased",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55991": {
                "ans1": "Roasting",
                "ans2": "smelting",
                "ans3": "Bessimerization",
                "ans4": "calcination",
                "question_text": "The process of converting hydrated alumina to anhydrous alumina is called",
                "correct_ans": "calcination",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59749": {
                "ans1": "F",
                "ans2": "Cl",
                "ans3": "Br",
                "ans4": "I",
                "question_text": "Oxidation state of which of the following elements doesn\u2019t change in its compound?",
                "correct_ans": "F",
                "explanation": "Flourine has constant O.S. in its compounds i.e. -1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55993": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "6",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "9",
                "question_text": "A gas is found to have the formula {\\left(CO\\right)}_x. Its vapour density of 70. The value of x must be",
                "correct_ans": "5",
                "explanation": "Molecular weight = 2 x vapour densityOr, (12 + 16) *x = 2*70Or, 28x = 140Therefore, x = 5 .",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51821": {
                "ans1": "Valency",
                "ans2": "atomicity",
                "ans3": "no. of electrons",
                "ans4": "valence electrons",
                "question_text": "Group number of an element indicates",
                "correct_ans": "valence electrons",
                "explanation": "In a given group , valance shell contains same number of electrons",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53169": {
                "ans1": "CaCl_2",
                "ans2": "Na_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "MgCO_3",
                "ans4": "KCl",
                "question_text": "Water sample on shaking with soap solution gave a ppt. The water sample contain",
                "correct_ans": "MgCO_3",
                "explanation": "MgCO_3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56439": {
                "ans1": "NO_2^+",
                "ans2": "Nascent O",
                "ans3": "Nascent H",
                "ans4": "Nascent Cl",
                "question_text": "The active species in aqua regia is",
                "correct_ans": "Nascent Cl",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}3\\;conc.\\;HCL\\;+\\;conc.\\;HNO_3\\;\\rightarrow\\;NOCl\\;+\\;2H_2O\\;+\\;2\\;\\lbrack Cl\\rbrack\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;Nascent\\;Chlorine\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56257": {
                "ans1": "NaCl ",
                "ans2": "H_2O",
                "ans3": "ZnO",
                "ans4": "CO_2",
                "question_text": "Dipole moment is zero in",
                "correct_ans": "CO_2",
                "explanation": "CO2 is linear . O = C = O i.e dipole moment of one C = O bond cancels that of other C = O bond,",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "52208": {
                "ans1": "K_2O",
                "ans2": "N_2O",
                "ans3": "ZnO",
                "ans4": "SO_2",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is neutral oxide?",
                "correct_ans": "N_2O",
                "explanation": "\u00a0 is neutral oxide.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51650": {
                "ans1": "Principal\t",
                "ans2": "azimuthal\t",
                "ans3": "magnetic\t",
                "ans4": "spin",
                "question_text": "The quantum number that can give the idea about shape of subshell is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 quantum number.",
                "correct_ans": "azimuthal\t",
                "explanation": "Azimuthal",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59017": {
                "ans1": "Birkland process",
                "ans2": "Solvay process\t",
                "ans3": "Haber\u2019s process",
                "ans4": "Ostwald\u2019s process",
                "question_text": "Process in which\u00a0\\;HNO_3 is manufactured by catalytic oxidation of NH_3 is",
                "correct_ans": "Ostwald\u2019s process",
                "explanation": "Ostwald\u2019s process",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56520": {
                "ans1": "10",
                "ans2": "20",
                "ans3": "40",
                "ans4": "80",
                "question_text": "One gram of hydrogen is found to combine with 80\u00a0\\textit{g}\u00a0of bromine one gram of calcium valency=2 combines with 4\u00a0\\textit{g}\u00a0of bromine the equivalent weight of calcium is",
                "correct_ans": "20",
                "explanation": "80\u00a0\\textit{gm}{\\mkern1mu\\raise4pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu\\raise1pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu\\raise4pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu}\u00a04\u00a0\\textit{gm }{\\mkern1mu\\raise1pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu\\raise4pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu\\raise1pt\\hbox{.}\\mkern1mu}\u00a080\u00a0\\textit{gm }",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57162": {
                "ans1": "Zinc ethyl",
                "ans2": "ethanol",
                "ans3": "ethane",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Ethyl iodide when reduced by Zn- Cu couple, which of following will be formed",
                "correct_ans": "ethane",
                "explanation": "Ethyl iodide when reduced by\u00a0Zn- Cu\u00a0couple, ethane is formed.CH_3 CH_2I \\xrightarrow[Reduction]{Zn-Cu}\\underset{Ethane}{CH_3CH_3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "51410": {
                "ans1": "32",
                "ans2": "68",
                "ans3": "128",
                "ans4": "256",
                "question_text": "\u00a00.16\u00a0\\textit{g}\u00a0of dibasic acid required 25\u00a0\\textit{ml}\u00a0of decinormal\u00a0\\textit{NaOH}\u00a0solution for complete neutralisation. The molecular weight of the acid will be",
                "correct_ans": "128",
                "explanation": "N_{1} V_{1} =N_{2} V_{2}\n\n\\cfrac{W}{E} \\times 1000=\\cfrac{1}{10} \\times 25\\\\\n\\cfrac{0.16}{E} \\times 1000=\\cfrac{25}{10}\\\\\n\nE=64\\\\\nM=2\\times E=2\\times 64=128. (Dibasic \\space acid)",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57103": {
                "ans1": "S",
                "ans2": "S_2",
                "ans3": "S_4",
                "ans4": "S_8",
                "question_text": "The molecular formula of sulphur is",
                "correct_ans": "S_8",
                "explanation": "S_8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "58362": {
                "ans1": "NaBr",
                "ans2": "KBr",
                "ans3": "RbBr",
                "ans4": "all equal",
                "question_text": "Which of these has maximum covalent character?",
                "correct_ans": "NaBr",
                "explanation": "\\propto \\cfrac{1}{\\text { polarizing power }}\\proptoNa has the smallest size.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55759": {
                "ans1": "Fe",
                "ans2": "Pb",
                "ans3": "Na",
                "ans4": "Ag",
                "question_text": "Electrometallurgical process is used to extract",
                "correct_ans": "Na",
                "explanation": "\\textit{C} , \\textit{CO}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55066": {
                "ans1": "Zn",
                "ans2": "Sn",
                "ans3": "Al",
                "ans4": "Cu",
                "question_text": "Which of following metal gives no amphoteric oxide",
                "correct_ans": "Cu",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59989": {
                "ans1": "32.5",
                "ans2": "65",
                "ans3": "22.4",
                "ans4": "5.6",
                "question_text": "The weight of zinc (Zn=\u00a0\\text{65)\\(\\,\\)displaced}\u00a0by the quantity of current which librated 11200 ml of\u00a0\\text{H\\(_{2}\\)}\u00a0at NTP will be",
                "correct_ans": "32.5",
                "explanation": "_2H_2Now, using Second law of electrolysis,\\cfrac{M_{Zn}}{M_{H_2}} = \\cfrac{E_{Zn}}{E_{H_2}}\\cfrac{M_{Zn}}{1} = \\cfrac{32.5}{1}\\therefore M_{Zn} = 32.5 gm",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "55717": {
                "ans1": "XO_{3}",
                "ans2": "X_{2} O_{3}",
                "ans3": "X_{2} O_{3}",
                "ans4": "XO_{2}",
                "question_text": "An element\u00a0\\textit{X }\u00a0which occurs in the first short period has an outer electronic structure\u00a0\u00a0s^{2} p^{1}\u00a0. What are the formula and acid-base character of its oxides",
                "correct_ans": "X_{2} O_{3}",
                "explanation": "B_{2} O_{3}\u00a0,\u00a0Al_{2} O_{3}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "59559": {
                "ans1": "Introducing an inert gas at constant vol",
                "ans2": "Introducing chlorine gas at constant volume",
                "ans3": "Introducing an inert gas at constant pressure",
                "ans4": "Decreasing the volume of the container",
                "question_text": "For the reactions\u00a0PCl_5 \\leftrightarrow PCl_3+Cl_2, forward reaction at constant temperature is favoured by\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "Introducing an inert gas at constant pressure",
                "explanation": "Introducing an\u00a0(Introducing inert gas at constant volume has no effect)So, forward reaction is favoured. [Since no. of moles of products (2) is greater than reactants (1)]*Introducing inert gas at constant pressure\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50825": {
                "ans1": "HF",
                "ans2": "HCl",
                "ans3": "HBr",
                "ans4": "HI",
                "question_text": "Which of these is most polar?",
                "correct_ans": "HF",
                "explanation": "Electronegativity \u221d PolarityException:- Order of polarity in C \u2212 X bond is",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "53182": {
                "ans1": "108.6",
                "ans2": "110.2",
                "ans3": "112.6",
                "ans4": "114.3",
                "question_text": "A chloride of an elements contains 49.5% chlorine. The specific heat of element is 0.056. The exact atomic weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "108.6",
                "explanation": "Eq. weight of element=\\cfrac{W_\\text {element }}{W_\\text {chlorine }} \\times E_\\text{chlorine}=\\cfrac{50.5}{49.5} \\times 35.5\\therefore=36.21 \\times 3=108.63",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54831": {
                "ans1": "\\text{2H\\(_{2}\\)} \\rightarrow \\text{CH\\(_{4}\\)}",
                "ans2": "\\text{2H\\(_{2}\\)(g)} \\rightarrow \\text{CH\\(_{4}\\)(l)}",
                "ans3": "\\text{2H\\(_{2}\\)} \\rightarrow \\text{CH\\(_{4}\\)(g)}",
                "ans4": "\\rightarrow \\text{CH\\(_{4}\\)} (g)",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Which of the following equations correctly represents the standard heat of formation\u00a0\\text{(\\(\\Delta \\)H\\(_{f}\\)\\(^{o}\\))}\u00a0of methane?",
                "correct_ans": "\\text{2H\\(_{2}\\)} \\rightarrow \\text{CH\\(_{4}\\)(g)}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56566": {
                "ans1": "-130Kcal",
                "ans2": "+130Kcal",
                "ans3": "-65Kcal",
                "ans4": "-24Kcal",
                "question_text": "From the followinga. C + O_{2}\u2192 CO_{2}; \u2206H = -95Kcalb. CO_{2}\u00a0+ C \u2192 ; \u2206H = +35Kcal\nthe heat of combustion of CO(g) is",
                "correct_ans": "-65Kcal",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "50710": {
                "ans1": "Lithium",
                "ans2": "Beryllium",
                "ans3": "Hydrogen",
                "ans4": "Boron",
                "question_text": "The quantum numbers for the outermost electron of an element are given below as\u00a0n=2,\\, l=0,\\, m=0,\\, s=+\\cfrac{1}{2}\u00a0. The atoms is",
                "correct_ans": "Lithium",
                "explanation": "1s^{2} \\, 2s^{1}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "54629": {
                "ans1": "0.25F",
                "ans2": "0.5F",
                "ans3": "1F",
                "ans4": "10F",
                "question_text": "The no. of charge required to deposit 10gm of calcium is",
                "correct_ans": "0.5F",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}{\\text { Gm. Eq. of } \\mathrm{Ca}=\\cfrac{\\text { Mass }}{\\text { eq. wt. }}=\\cfrac{ 10}{20}=0.5} \\\\ {\\text { No. of Faraday }=\\text { No. of } \\mathrm{gm} . \\text { Eq. }=0.5}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "57641": {
                "ans1": "ethyl alcohol",
                "ans2": "ethane",
                "ans3": "ethylene",
                "ans4": "ethanol",
                "question_text": "Alcoholic caustic potash reacts with ethyl iodide to form",
                "correct_ans": "ethylene",
                "explanation": "CH_3CH_2I + \\underset{alc}{KOH} \\to \\underset{Ethene}{CH_2=CH_2} +KI+H_2OThis is dehydrohalogenation reaction. A hydrogen and a halogen atom is removed from an organic compound in this reaction.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "56814": {
                "ans1": "N _ { 2 } O _ { 5 }",
                "ans2": "N _ { 2 } O _ { 4 }",
                "ans3": "N O _ { 2 }",
                "ans4": "NO",
                "question_text": "In the catalytic oxidation of ammonia, an oxide is formed which is used in the preparation of\u00a0H N O _ { 3 }. This oxide is",
                "correct_ans": "NO",
                "explanation": "4 \\mathrm { NH } _ { 3 } + 5 \\mathrm { O } _ { 2 } \\xrightarrow [ 1100 \\mathrm { K } ] { P _ { t } } 4 \\mathrm { NO } + 6 \\mathrm { H } _ { 2 } \\mathrm { O }\\\\\nN O \\text { is used in the preparation of } H N O _ { 3 }\\\\\n\\underset{\\text{Nitric Oxide}}{2 N O} + O _ { 2 } \\rightarrow 2 N O _ { 2 }\\\\\n4 N O _ { 2 } + 2 H _ { 2 } O + O _ { 2 } \\rightarrow \\underset{\\text{Nitric Acid}}{4 H N O _ { 3 }}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        },
        "2": {
            "61395": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans2": "H_2S_2O_7",
                "ans3": "H_2S_2O_8",
                "ans4": "SO_3",
                "question_text": "The absorbtion of gas formed by catalytic oxidation of SO\u2082 by oil of vitriol gives.\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "H_2S_2O_7",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}weight\\;of\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{NEV}{1000}=\\frac{\\left(200\\ast0.75-40\\ast0.5\\right)\\ast1\\ast50}{1000}=6.5g\\\\\\%\\;of\\;pure\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{6.5}7\\times100\\%=92.85\\%\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63938": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "0.91g of metal was deposited when 1.5 ampere current is passed through\u00a0Mn^+\u00a0ion for 20 minutes . The value of n is ( Atomic weight of M =195)",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60515": {
                "ans1": "1.18\\;x\\;10^{-6}M",
                "ans2": "6.5\\;x\\;10^{-6}M",
                "ans3": "7.5\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "ans4": "5.9\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;concentration\\;of\\;Ag^+\\\\\\;-\\;ion\\;in\\;saturated\\;so\\ln\\;of\\\\\\;Ag_2\\;CrO_4\\;in\\;presence\\;of\\;\\\\0.1M\\;\\;K\u2082CrO_4solution\\;is\\;\\\\\\;(Ksp\\;of\\;Ag\u2082CrO_4=1.4\\;x\\;10^{-13})\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "5.9\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65114": {
                "ans1": "Formaldehyde",
                "ans2": "Glycol",
                "ans3": "Glyoxal",
                "ans4": "Oxalic acid",
                "question_text": "The product formed by dehalogenation of 1,2-dihaloethane on ozonolysis gives",
                "correct_ans": "Formaldehyde",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64542": {
                "ans1": "0.47",
                "ans2": "1.47",
                "ans3": "1.82",
                "ans4": "2.82",
                "question_text": "The pH of a solution formed when 0.1 M KOH is added to 100ml of 0.1M HCl solution till the acid is half neutralized is",
                "correct_ans": "1.47",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61754": {
                "ans1": "95.42%",
                "ans2": "88.12%",
                "ans3": "92.85%",
                "ans4": "85.68%",
                "question_text": "7g of a piece of limestone was dissolved in 200ml of 0.75 N HCI. The excess acid required 40ml of 0.5N NaOH for complete neutralization. The percentage of CaCO, in limestone is",
                "correct_ans": "92.85%",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}weight\\;of\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{NEV}{1000}=\\frac{\\left(200\\ast0.75-40\\ast0.5\\right)\\ast1\\ast50}{1000}=6.5g\\\\\\%\\;of\\;pure\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{6.5}7\\times100\\%=92.85\\%\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60748": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a00.18g of a metal was deposited when 0.5 ampere current was passed through M^{n+} -\u00a0ion solution for 20 minutes. The value of n is (Atomic wt. of M=58.7)",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64860": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_5",
                "ans2": "H_2S_2O_7",
                "ans3": "H_2S_4O_6",
                "ans4": "H_2S_2O_8",
                "question_text": "The acid containing S-O-O-S bond is",
                "correct_ans": "H_2S_2O_8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65883": {
                "ans1": "33.25",
                "ans2": "3.325",
                "ans3": "12",
                "ans4": "20",
                "question_text": "3 gm of an oxide of a metal is converted to chloride completely and it yielded 5 gm of chloride . The eq. wt. of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "33.25",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61198": {
                "ans1": "8 gm KOH/100ml",
                "ans2": "0.5\\;M\\;H_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "6gm NaOH /100 ml",
                "ans4": "1\\;NH_3PO_4",
                "question_text": "Which of these solution has the highest normality?",
                "correct_ans": "6gm NaOH /100 ml",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64545": {
                "ans1": "1\\;\\times\\;10^{-32}",
                "ans2": "2\\;\\times\\;10^{-32}",
                "ans3": "3\\;\\times\\;10^{-32}",
                "ans4": "4\\;\\times\\;10^{-32}",
                "question_text": "The concentration of S^{--}ion in saturated solution of As_2S_3 is 6.2 x 10-7 moles Calculate the Ksp of\u00a0As_2S_3",
                "correct_ans": "4\\;\\times\\;10^{-32}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60388": {
                "ans1": "13",
                "ans2": "26",
                "ans3": "39",
                "ans4": "48",
                "question_text": "1 gm of a metal was dissolved in 50ml of 1.01N\u00a0H_2SO_4\u00a0. The excess acid required 15.1 ml of 0.8 N NaOH neutralization.Calculate the EW of metal",
                "correct_ans": "26",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64812": {
                "ans1": "1.06 gm",
                "ans2": "2.12 gm",
                "ans3": "3.2 gm",
                "ans4": "4.38 gm",
                "question_text": "Calculate the weight of 60%\u00a0H_2SO_4\u00a0solution required to react with 2.12 gm of\u00a0Na_2CO_3",
                "correct_ans": "3.2 gm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65695": {
                "ans1": "dehydrating agent",
                "ans2": "oxidizing agent",
                "ans3": "reducing agent",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "In the reaction\\begin{array}{l}HCOOH\\xrightarrow{H_2SO_4}\\\\CO+H_2SO_4.H_2O\\end{array}acts as",
                "correct_ans": "dehydrating agent",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62353": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}O_2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}Cl_2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}N_2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}H_2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "The gas formed by passing NH, over bleaching powder is",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}N_2\\\\\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\NH_3+CaOCl_2\\;\\rightarrow\\;N_2+CaCl_2\\;+H_2O\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62988": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "13",
                "question_text": "If 8g of NaOH in dissolved in 2 litre solution, the pH is",
                "correct_ans": "13",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}Normality\\;of\\;NaOH(N)=\\frac{W\\times1000}{E\\times V}\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;\\;\\frac{8\\times1000}{40\\times2000}\\;\\;\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;0.1\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61349": {
                "ans1": "Dicyanide",
                "ans2": "Cyanagen",
                "ans3": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "ans4": "Ethane dicyanide",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of (CN)_2, is",
                "correct_ans": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "explanation": "The IUPAC name of CN - CN is ethane dinitrile.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65967": {
                "ans1": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\K_2SO_4\\end{array}",
                "ans2": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\K_2S_2O_4\\end{array}",
                "ans3": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\K_2S_2O_2\\end{array}",
                "ans4": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\K_2S_2O_8\\end{array}",
                "question_text": "What is X in the following reaction?\\begin{array}{l}\\\\KHSO_4+F_2\\;\\rightarrow\\;HF+X\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\K_2S_2O_8\\end{array}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}\\\\2KHSO_4+F_2\\rightarrow2HF+K_2S_2O_8\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60511": {
                "ans1": "Rs. 22.5",
                "ans2": "Rs. 60",
                "ans3": "Rs. 30",
                "ans4": "Rs. 90",
                "question_text": "The cost of electricity required to deposit 2g of Mg is Rs. 10. The cost to deposit 4.5g of Al is",
                "correct_ans": "Rs. 30",
                "explanation": "12g Mg = 9g of A/ = Rs. 60\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a04.5g of A/= Rs. 30",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65717": {
                "ans1": "3.6\\;\\times\\;10^{22}",
                "ans2": "7.2\\;\\times\\;10^{21}",
                "ans3": "4.9\\;\\times\\;10^{22}",
                "ans4": "6.6\\;\\times\\;10^{22}",
                "question_text": "A person added 1.71g of sugar (mol. wt = 342) in tea. The no. of carbon atoms added is",
                "correct_ans": "3.6\\;\\times\\;10^{22}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}342g\\;of\\;C_{12}H_{22}O_{11}=\\;12\\times6.023\\times\\;10^{23}\\;C-\\;atoms\\;\\\\\\;1.71g\\;of\\;C_{12}H_{22}O_{11}\\;\\\\=\\frac{12\\;\\times\\;6.023\\;\\times\\;10\\;\\times\\;1.71}{342\\;}\\;\\;\\\\=\\;3.6\\;\\times\\;10^{22}\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62112": {
                "ans1": "0.5",
                "ans2": "0.4",
                "ans3": "0.2",
                "ans4": "0.1",
                "question_text": "5g of Zn was placed in 1 litre of dilute H_2SO_4\u00a0. After the reaction ceased, the excess Zn weighed 1.75g. The normality of H_2SO_4, solution is (Zn 65.4)",
                "correct_ans": "0.1",
                "explanation": "Mass of Zn used = 5-1.75 = 3.25g\\begin{array}{l}\\frac{\\;W}E=\\frac{\\;VXN}{1000}\\;\\;\\\\N=\\frac{W\\;\\times\\;1000}{E\\;\\times V}=\\;\\frac{3.25\\;\\times\\;1000\\;\\times\\;2}{\\;65.4\\;\\times\\;1000}\\;=\\;0.1N\\end{array}\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62407": {
                "ans1": "M",
                "ans2": "M/2",
                "ans3": "M/3",
                "ans4": "M/6",
                "question_text": "The mol. mass of\u00a0KMnO_4 \u00a0is M,when it reacts with KOH to give product , the EW of\u00a0KMnO_4 is",
                "correct_ans": "M",
                "explanation": "Change in oxidation no. of Mn is 7-6 =1therefore, EW=mol wt./ change in O.N\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0= M/1 =M",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68552": {
                "ans1": "An oxidizing agent",
                "ans2": "an reducing agent",
                "ans3": "an acid",
                "ans4": "a catalyst",
                "question_text": "A solution of\u00a0SO_2\u00a0is water reacts with\u00a0H_2S\u00a0precipitating sulphur. Here\u00a0SO_2\u00a0acts as\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "An oxidizing agent",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68031": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "21",
                "question_text": "Gastric juice contains 3gm of HCl per litre. If a person produces 2.5 litre of gastric juice per day,. how many antacid tablets each containing 400 mg of Al(OH)_3 are needed to neutralized all the HCl produced in one day?",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "The molar masses of HCl and Al(OH)3 are 36.5 g/mol and 78 g/mol respectively. In one day, a person produces 2.5 L of gastric juices which contain 2.5\u00d73.0=7.5g of HCl.This corresponds to 7.5/ 36.5 =0.20 moles of HCl.1 mole of Al(OH) 3 will neutralize 3 moles of HCl. Hence, 0.2 moles of HCl will be neutralized by 0.2/3 =0.068 moles of Al(OH)3 . This corresponds to 0.068\u00d778=5.34 g of Al(OH) 3\u200bEach antacid tablet contains 400 mg or 0.4 g of Al(OH)3 . hence, the number of antacid tablet required per day to neutralize HCl are",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67240": {
                "ans1": "Dicyanide",
                "ans2": "Cyanagen",
                "ans3": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "ans4": "Ethane dicyanide",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of (CN)_2, is",
                "correct_ans": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "explanation": "The IUPAC name of CN - CN is ethane dinitrile.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63622": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "29.2% (w/w) HCl stock solution was a density of 1.25 g/ml. The mol. wt. of HCl is 36.5g\u00a0mol^{-1}\u00a0. The volume of stock solution required to prepare a 200ml solution of 0.2M HCl is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66247": {
                "ans1": "But-3-en-1-yne",
                "ans2": "Butanoyl chloride",
                "ans3": "Pent-1-en-3-yne",
                "ans4": "Propenal",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Dehydrohalognation of 1, 1-dichloroethane gives compound X. X when treated with Cu_2Cl_2 containing NH_4Cl gives compound Y. IUPAC name of compound Y is.",
                "correct_ans": "But-3-en-1-yne",
                "explanation": "Dehydrohalognation of 1, 1-dichloroethane gives compound EthyneEthyne when treated with Cu2Cl2 containing NH4Cl gives compound But-3-en-1-yne",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60852": {
                "ans1": "6\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans2": "16.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans3": "13.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans4": "11.2\\times10^{-9}",
                "question_text": "The solubility of lead iodide at 25\u00b0C is 0.7gm litre^{-1}. Its solubility produce at given temperature is (Mol. wt. of  PbI_2= 461)",
                "correct_ans": "16.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61993": {
                "ans1": "2.09 litres",
                "ans2": " 4.17 litres",
                "ans3": " 6.26 litres",
                "ans4": "8.42 litres",
                "question_text": "The total volume of gases formed at STP by passing 5A through acidified water for 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": " 6.26 litres",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60518": {
                "ans1": "benzene",
                "ans2": "acetylene",
                "ans3": " propyne",
                "ans4": " butyne",
                "question_text": "The hydrocarbon which does not decolourise alkaline\u00a0KMnO_4\u200b\u00a0solution and does not give any precipitate with ammonical silver nitrate is",
                "correct_ans": "benzene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61640": {
                "ans1": "31.25g",
                "ans2": "38.42g",
                "ans3": "44.84g",
                "ans4": "53g",
                "question_text": "The mass of Na_2CO_3 required to produce 250ml of 10% by wt. of  Na_2CO_3 solution having density 1.25 g/m^3 is",
                "correct_ans": "31.25g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63364": {
                "ans1": " 30g",
                "ans2": "34g",
                "ans3": "36g",
                "ans4": "45.33g",
                "question_text": "The mass of NH_3 formed when 8g of hydrogen is reacted with 28g of N_2 is",
                "correct_ans": "34g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66040": {
                "ans1": "KClO_2",
                "ans2": "KClO_3",
                "ans3": "KClO",
                "ans4": "KClO_4",
                "question_text": "A gas formed by heating\u00a0MnO_2 with conc\u00a0HCl\u00a0is passed through hot and conc. Caustic potash solution to obtain",
                "correct_ans": "KClO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60997": {
                "ans1": "1.2046\\times10^{20}",
                "ans2": "1.2046\\times10^{21}",
                "ans3": "6.022\\times10^{21}",
                "ans4": "6.022\\times10^{22}",
                "question_text": "Calculate the number of\u00a0Na_2CO_3 molecules present in 100ml of 0.02 M sodium carbonate solutions",
                "correct_ans": "1.2046\\times10^{21}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68839": {
                "ans1": "oxidant",
                "ans2": "reductant",
                "ans3": "bleachant",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "The gas formed by heating conc. H_2SO_4 and Cu turning is a/an.",
                "correct_ans": "all of these",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61115": {
                "ans1": "310 gm",
                "ans2": "320 gm",
                "ans3": "390 gm",
                "ans4": "415 gm",
                "question_text": "What mass of zine is required to produce hydrogen by reaction with HCI which is enough to produce 4mole of\u00a0NH_3\u200b\u00a0with\u00a0N_2\u200b.(at wt of Zn=65)",
                "correct_ans": "310 gm",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69379": {
                "ans1": "M/2",
                "ans2": "M/4",
                "ans3": "M/6",
                "ans4": "M/8",
                "question_text": "In the above rxn. the eq. wt. of\u00a0HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is: (mol. wt. of\u00a0HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is M)\\begin{array}{l}Zn+HNO_3\u200b\u200b\\rightarrow\\\\Zn(NO_3\u200b)_{{}_{}2\u200b}+NH_4\u200bNO_3\u200b+H_2\u200bO\\;\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "M/8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62931": {
                "ans1": "benzene",
                "ans2": "acetylene",
                "ans3": " propyne",
                "ans4": " butyne",
                "question_text": "The hydrocarbon which does not decolourise alkaline\u00a0KMnO_4\u200b\u00a0solution and does not give any precipitate with ammonical silver nitrate is",
                "correct_ans": "benzene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63002": {
                "ans1": "27",
                "ans2": "40",
                "ans3": "54",
                "ans4": "72",
                "question_text": "71 g of chlorine combines with a metal giving 111 g of its chloride. The chloride is isomorphos with\u00a0MgCl_2.6H_2O. At. mass of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "40",
                "explanation": "wt. of Chlorine = 71 gwt. of chloride = 111 gwt of metal = 111 - 71 = 40 gEq.wt. of metal =\u00a0\\dfrac{40}{71} \\times 35.57140\u200b\u00d735.5\u00a0= 20Since chloride is isomorphous with\u00a0MgCl_2.6H_2O. Hence its formula will be\u00a0MCl_2.6H_2O. So, valency of metal (M) = 2Now, At. wt. = Eq.wt.\u00a0\\times\u00d7\u00a0valency = 40",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62378": {
                "ans1": "4.57\\times10^{\\;\\;2}",
                "ans2": "2.09\\times10^{-4}",
                "ans3": "4.01\\times10^{-6}",
                "ans4": "5.09\\times10^{-3}",
                "question_text": "The pH value of 0.1M solution of cyanic acid (HCNO) is 2.34. Calculate the ionization constant of the acid.",
                "correct_ans": "4.57\\times10^{\\;\\;2}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64894": {
                "ans1": "H _2 S",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HNO_3",
                "ans4": "H_2SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of the following act as both oxidizing and reducing agent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2SO_4",
                "explanation": "H2\u200bSO4\u200b\u00a0acts as oxidising agent, reducing agent and bleaching agent.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66411": {
                "ans1": "70",
                "ans2": "72",
                "ans3": "73",
                "ans4": "75",
                "question_text": "1.2 gm of a sample of washing soda was dissolved in water and volume was made up to 250 cc. 25 cc of diluted solution, when titrated against 0.1N HCl, required 17cc. The percentage of anhydrous sodium carbonate in the given sample is :",
                "correct_ans": "75",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62445": {
                "ans1": "60",
                "ans2": "44",
                "ans3": "38",
                "ans4": "20",
                "question_text": "1.78 g of metal carbonate gives 1 g of metal on decomposition. The equivalent weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "38",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67889": {
                "ans1": "Formaldehyde",
                "ans2": "Glycol",
                "ans3": "Glyoxal",
                "ans4": "Oxalic acid",
                "question_text": "The product formed by dehalogenation of 1,2-dihaloethane on ozonolysis gives",
                "correct_ans": "Formaldehyde",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61938": {
                "ans1": "methyl propene  ",
                "ans2": "methyl propyne   ",
                "ans3": "methyl but-2-ene   ",
                "ans4": "methyl but-2-yne",
                "question_text": "The compound which gives formaldehyde and acetone on ozonolysis is",
                "correct_ans": "methyl propene  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62283": {
                "ans1": "0.006%",
                "ans2": "0.013%",
                "ans3": "0.770%",
                "ans4": "1.600%",
                "question_text": "The equivalent weight of oxidizing agent in given redox reaction is\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0 SO_2+H_2S\\rightarrow S+H_2O",
                "correct_ans": "0.013%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62393": {
                "ans1": "6.023 \u00d7 10^{23}",
                "ans2": "3.011 \u00d7 10^{22}",
                "ans3": "6.023 \u00d7 10^{222}",
                "ans4": "1.505\u00d7 10^{22}",
                "question_text": "The total number of molecules of sulphuric acid in 0.5 N \u00a0\u00a0H_2SO_4\u00a0 of volume 100 ml is",
                "correct_ans": "1.505\u00d7 10^{22}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61532": {
                "ans1": "a)\tPhenol, Benzene   ",
                "ans2": "Toulene, Benzene   ",
                "ans3": "Toulene, Phenol  ",
                "ans4": "Benzene, Phenol ",
                "question_text": "The compound A and B in given chain of reaction are respectively:A\\xrightarrow{Reduction}B\\xrightarrow{V_2O_5} Maleic Anhydride",
                "correct_ans": "a)\tPhenol, Benzene   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65587": {
                "ans1": "31.3 g",
                "ans2": "31.7 g",
                "ans3": "32.1 g",
                "ans4": "32.3 g",
                "question_text": "32.1 g of metal reacts with dilute hydrochloric acid and formed hydrogen reacted with excess oxygen to give 9 g of water. The equivalent weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "32.3 g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67973": {
                "ans1": "Nitrous oxide",
                "ans2": "Nitrogen dioxide",
                "ans3": "Nitrogen hydroxide",
                "ans4": "Nitrogen peroxide",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Which of the following gas is also known as laughing gas?",
                "correct_ans": "Nitrous oxide",
                "explanation": "Nitrous oxide, commonly known as laughing gas is a colourless non-flammable gas, with a slight metallic scent and taste. It is also used in surgery and dentistry, for its anesthetic and pain reducing effects.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63705": {
                "ans1": "1.3",
                "ans2": "2.3",
                "ans3": "11.7",
                "ans4": "12.7",
                "question_text": "\u00a00.1 g of pure\u00a0NaOH was added to\u00a0100ml of\u00a0N/20\u00a0\u00a0H_2SO_4\u200b. The mixture was then diluted to 500ml. The\u00a0pH of the diluted solution is",
                "correct_ans": "12.7",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63739": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The number of Faradays of charge required to reduce 1 mole of\u00a0Cr_2O_7^{--} in acidic medium is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69441": {
                "ans1": "90",
                "ans2": "98",
                "ans3": "118",
                "ans4": "126",
                "question_text": "\u00a00.24g of Magnesium on reaction with a dibasic acid gave 1.12g of Magnesium salt. The molecular weight of acid is",
                "correct_ans": "90",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68616": {
                "ans1": "alkaline\\;NiSO_4",
                "ans2": "alkaline\\;MnSO_4",
                "ans3": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "ans4": "acidified\\;CuSO_4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A gas formed by reacting iron sulphide with\u00a0dil.H_2SO_4 doesn't give precipitate with",
                "correct_ans": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64112": {
                "ans1": "anhydrous AlBr3",
                "ans2": "mercuric chloride",
                "ans3": "ultraviolet light",
                "ans4": "zinc chloride",
                "question_text": "Chlorination of ethane is carried out in presence of",
                "correct_ans": "ultraviolet light",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62223": {
                "ans1": "1.8 V",
                "ans2": "0.8 V",
                "ans3": "2.8 V",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "Reduction or oxidation potential of standard hydrogen electrode is:",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63840": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_3\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans3": "S is precipitated",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "When a gas obtained by roasting iron pyrite is passed through acidic solution of hydride of Sulphur then",
                "correct_ans": "S is precipitated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61403": {
                "ans1": "10 mole of hydrogen",
                "ans2": "2\u00d7NA molecules of water",
                "ans3": "2.24 litre of oxygen",
                "ans4": "1 mole of SO2",
                "question_text": "Which of these has more mass?",
                "correct_ans": "1 mole of SO2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61915": {
                "ans1": "180 gm",
                "ans2": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "ans3": "180\\;N_A\\;gm",
                "ans4": "N_A\\;gm",
                "question_text": "The absolute wt. of one molecule of glucose is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60979": {
                "ans1": "Chlorobenzene",
                "ans2": "Acetophenone",
                "ans3": "Cyclohexane",
                "ans4": "Toulene",
                "question_text": "When Benzene treated with Methyl chloride in presence anhydrous Aluminium chloride, then it produces",
                "correct_ans": "Toulene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67879": {
                "ans1": "M/2",
                "ans2": "M/4",
                "ans3": "M/6",
                "ans4": "M/8",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Zn + HNO_3\u200b\u00a0\\longrightarrow Zn(NO_3\u200b)_2\u200b\u00a0+ NH_4\u200bNO_3\u200b\u00a0+ H_2\u200bO In the above rxn. the eq. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is: (mol. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is M)",
                "correct_ans": "M/8",
                "explanation": "Change in O.N. of N = 5 - (-3) = +8Eq. wt = Mol. Wt/ change in ON = M/8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61135": {
                "ans1": "H_2S",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HNO_3",
                "ans4": "H_2SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of the following act as both oxidizing and reducing agent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2SO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68651": {
                "ans1": "36",
                "ans2": "22",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "27",
                "question_text": "Metal oxide contains 53% metal and formula of metal oxide is M_2\u200bO_3\u200b. Atomic mass of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "27",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66973": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_3\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans3": "S is precipitated",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "When a gas obtained by roasting iron pyrite is passed through acidic solution of hydride of Sulphur then",
                "correct_ans": "S is precipitated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66174": {
                "ans1": "1.8 V",
                "ans2": "0.8 V",
                "ans3": "2.8 V",
                "ans4": "0",
                "question_text": "Reduction or oxidation potential of standard hydrogen electrode is:",
                "correct_ans": "0",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67745": {
                "ans1": "alkaline\\;NiSO_4",
                "ans2": "alkaline\\;MnSO_4",
                "ans3": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "ans4": "acidified\\;CuSO_4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A gas formed by reacting iron sulphide with\u00a0dil.H_2SO_4 doesn't give precipitate with",
                "correct_ans": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63145": {
                "ans1": "H_2S",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HNO_3",
                "ans4": "H_2SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of the following act as both oxidizing and reducing agent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2SO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62895": {
                "ans1": "Nitrous oxide",
                "ans2": "Nitrogen dioxide",
                "ans3": "Nitrogen hydroxide",
                "ans4": "Nitrogen peroxide",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Which of the following gas is also known as laughing gas?",
                "correct_ans": "Nitrous oxide",
                "explanation": "Nitrous oxide, commonly known as laughing gas is a colourless non-flammable gas, with a slight metallic scent and taste. It is also used in surgery and dentistry, for its anesthetic and pain reducing effects.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60995": {
                "ans1": "180 gm",
                "ans2": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "ans3": "180\\;N_A\\;gm",
                "ans4": "N_A\\;gm",
                "question_text": "The absolute wt. of one molecule of glucose is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64568": {
                "ans1": "M/2",
                "ans2": "M/4",
                "ans3": "M/6",
                "ans4": "M/8",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Zn + HNO_3\u200b\u00a0\\longrightarrow Zn(NO_3\u200b)_2\u200b\u00a0+ NH_4\u200bNO_3\u200b\u00a0+ H_2\u200bO In the above rxn. the eq. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is: (mol. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is M)",
                "correct_ans": "M/8",
                "explanation": "Change in O.N. of N = 5 - (-3) = +8Eq. wt = Mol. Wt/ change in ON = M/8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69860": {
                "ans1": "90",
                "ans2": "98",
                "ans3": "118",
                "ans4": "126",
                "question_text": "0.24 of magnesium on reaction with a dibasic acid gave 1.40g of magnesium salt. The molecular weight of acid is.",
                "correct_ans": "118",
                "explanation": "Mol. wt. of acid=59\u00a0\u00d7\u00a02=118",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68985": {
                "ans1": "1.97\\;\\times10^{-7}M",
                "ans2": "5.91\\;\\times10^{-7}M",
                "ans3": "1.73\\;\\times10^{-17}M",
                "ans4": "3.46\\;\\times10^{-17}M",
                "question_text": "The concentration of sulphide ion in saturated solution of\u00a0As_2S_3 is K_{sp}\u200b\u00a0of\u00a0As_2S_3=3.2 x 10^{-32}",
                "correct_ans": "5.91\\;\\times10^{-7}M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69527": {
                "ans1": "Baeyer's reagent",
                "ans2": "Tollen's reagent",
                "ans3": "both",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Ethene and Ethyne can be distinguished by passing through",
                "correct_ans": "Tollen's reagent",
                "explanation": "Ethyne forms a white ppt. of silver acetylide while ethane doesn't give ppt with Tollen's reagent.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68664": {
                "ans1": "0.93 A",
                "ans2": "1.93 A",
                "ans3": "2.93 A",
                "ans4": "0.965 A",
                "question_text": "The current required to reduce the concentration of 100ml of 0.1M AgNO_3\u200b\u00a0to 0.04M solution in 5 min is",
                "correct_ans": "1.93 A",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68384": {
                "ans1": "2.46\\;\\times10^{-14}M",
                "ans2": "1.36\\;\\times10^{-4}M",
                "ans3": "2.5\\times10^{-7}M",
                "ans4": "1.2\\;\\times10^{-10}M",
                "question_text": "If the solubility product\u00a0(k_{SP}\u200b) of a sparingly soluble salt\u00a0AB_2 at 25\u00b0C is\u00a01.0\u00d710^{-11}, the solubility of salt in mole/litre at this temperature will be",
                "correct_ans": "1.36\\;\\times10^{-4}M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60691": {
                "ans1": "NaClO",
                "ans2": "NaClO_2",
                "ans3": "NaClO_4",
                "ans4": "NaClO_3",
                "question_text": "A gas formed by heating conc. HCI with MnO_4\u200b\u00a0on passing into hot and conc. NaOH gives",
                "correct_ans": "NaClO_3",
                "explanation": "\u00a0Cl_2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63971": {
                "ans1": "1.163",
                "ans2": "2.36",
                "ans3": "11.63",
                "ans4": "2.163",
                "question_text": "200 ml of 0.01N NaOH is mixed with 500ml of 0.1N HNO_3, the pH of the resulting mixture is",
                "correct_ans": "1.163",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66178": {
                "ans1": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "ans2": "Thiosulphuric Acid",
                "ans3": " Sulphuric Acid",
                "ans4": "Sulphonic Acid",
                "question_text": "What is formed when SO_2 is dissolved in water?",
                "correct_ans": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63329": {
                "ans1": "5M",
                "ans2": "1/10 M",
                "ans3": "10M",
                "ans4": "1/5M",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the concentration of HCl, if 10 ml of 0.5 M Ca(OH)_2 is required to titrate 50 ml of HCl.",
                "correct_ans": "1/5M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64103": {
                "ans1": " 0.25 M",
                "ans2": "50 M",
                "ans3": "0.5 M",
                "ans4": "100 M",
                "question_text": "What is the concentration of the sulphuric acid solution, if 100 ml of the solution is neutralised by 50 ml of 0.5 M\u00a0Ba(OH)_2 solution?",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65907": {
                "ans1": "Br_2/CCl_4",
                "ans2": "cold\\;KMnO_4",
                "ans3": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "ans4": "Ag{\\left(NH_3\\right)}_2OH",
                "question_text": "Which among the following reagents can be used to distinguish between\u00a0CH_2BrCH=CH_2\u200b\u00a0from\u00a0CH_3CH=CHBr?",
                "correct_ans": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62229": {
                "ans1": "5.4g",
                "ans2": "10.8g",
                "ans3": "54.9g",
                "ans4": "108.0g",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The weight of silver displaced by a quantity of electricity which displaces 5600ml of O_2 at STP will be",
                "correct_ans": "108.0g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67364": {
                "ans1": "octahedral geometry",
                "ans2": "square planar geometry",
                "ans3": "tetragonal geometry",
                "ans4": "tetrahedral geometry",
                "question_text": "Sp3d2 hybridization is present in\u00a0[Co(NH_3)_6\\text{ }^{3+}], find its geometry",
                "correct_ans": "octahedral geometry",
                "explanation": "Sp3d2 hybridization gives octahedral geometry",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67201": {
                "ans1": "1^\\circ>2^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans2": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "ans3": "2^\\circ>1^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans4": "2^\\circ>3^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "question_text": "Find the correct order for the ease of formation of free radicals",
                "correct_ans": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "explanation": "More the number of steric alkyl groups around the central carbon atom, easy will be the formation of free radicals due to electronic repulsion.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66876": {
                "ans1": "1.23 litres",
                "ans2": "1.12 litres",
                "ans3": "0.84 litres",
                "ans4": "0.56 litres",
                "question_text": "The volume of\u00a0\u00a0CO_2  gas formed at STP when 5.3 of\u00a0Na_2CO_3\n\u200b\u00a0is added to a solution conatining 4g of HCl is",
                "correct_ans": "1.12 litres",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62498": {
                "ans1": "sodium acetate",
                "ans2": "sodium fumeratie",
                "ans3": " sodium succinate",
                "ans4": "sodium proponate",
                "question_text": "Ethene gas is produced by Kolbe's electrolysis of",
                "correct_ans": " sodium succinate",
                "explanation": "Electrolysis of sodium succinate gives ethane",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69050": {
                "ans1": "1.78 M",
                "ans2": "2.00 M",
                "ans3": "2.05 M",
                "ans4": "2.22 M",
                "question_text": "Dissolving 120g of urea (M.W. = 60) in 1000g of water gave a solution of density 1.15gm ml. The molarity of solution is",
                "correct_ans": "2.05 M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64564": {
                "ans1": "SO_3",
                "ans2": "S",
                "ans3": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans4": "H_2SO_3",
                "question_text": "The gas produced by combustion of iron pyrite on passing through acidified\u00a0KMnO_4\u200b\u00a0gets converted to",
                "correct_ans": "H_2SO_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67255": {
                "ans1": "78.7%",
                "ans2": "82.4%",
                "ans3": "86.5 %",
                "ans4": "91.8%",
                "question_text": "5ml of conc\u00a0H_2SO_4 is diluted to 1000ml. 20ml of the diluted solution required 15ml of 0.2 N NaOH for neutralization. The % of\u00a0H_2SO_4\u200b\u00a0in conc.\u00a0H_2SO_4 if its specific gravity is 1.7 is",
                "correct_ans": "86.5 %",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65119": {
                "ans1": "1:2:3",
                "ans2": "6:3:2",
                "ans3": "3:2:1",
                "ans4": "1:1:1",
                "question_text": "The ratio of volume of\u00a0Cl_2  gas evolved at NTP by electrolysis of an NaCl. aq. CuCl_2 & AuCl_3 is",
                "correct_ans": "1:1:1",
                "explanation": "As valency of chlorine is same in all cases and equivalent volume is same for all, the ratio would be 1 : 1 : 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67648": {
                "ans1": "acidified medium",
                "ans2": "alkaline medium",
                "ans3": "neutral medium",
                "ans4": "all medium",
                "question_text": "A gas formed by reaction\u00a0FeS with dilute\u00a0H_2SO_4\u200b\u00a0gives precipitate with\u00a0CuSO_4\u200b\u00a0solution in",
                "correct_ans": "acidified medium",
                "explanation": "The gas formed is H_2\u200bS and Cu^{++} being group II metal ion gives CuS precipitate in all medium.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68539": {
                "ans1": "60",
                "ans2": "44",
                "ans3": "38",
                "ans4": "20",
                "question_text": "1.78 g of metal carbonate gives 1 g of metal on decomposition. The equivalent weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "38",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63099": {
                "ans1": "Formaldehyde",
                "ans2": "Glycol",
                "ans3": "Glyoxal",
                "ans4": "Oxalic acid",
                "question_text": "The product formed by dehalogenation of 1,2-dihaloethane on ozonolysis gives",
                "correct_ans": "Formaldehyde",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63246": {
                "ans1": "methyl propene  ",
                "ans2": "methyl propyne   ",
                "ans3": "methyl but-2-ene   ",
                "ans4": "methyl but-2-yne",
                "question_text": "The compound which gives formaldehyde and acetone on ozonolysis is",
                "correct_ans": "methyl propene  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64707": {
                "ans1": "0.006%",
                "ans2": "0.013%",
                "ans3": "0.770%",
                "ans4": "1.600%",
                "question_text": "The equivalent weight of oxidizing agent in given redox reaction is\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0 SO_2+H_2S\\rightarrow S+H_2O",
                "correct_ans": "0.013%",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62652": {
                "ans1": "6.023 \u00d7 10^{23}",
                "ans2": "3.011 \u00d7 10^{22}",
                "ans3": "6.023 \u00d7 10^{222}",
                "ans4": "1.505\u00d7 10^{22}",
                "question_text": "The total number of molecules of sulphuric acid in 0.5 N \u00a0\u00a0H_2SO_4\u00a0 of volume 100 ml is",
                "correct_ans": "1.505\u00d7 10^{22}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60846": {
                "ans1": "a)\tPhenol, Benzene   ",
                "ans2": "Toulene, Benzene   ",
                "ans3": "Toulene, Phenol  ",
                "ans4": "Benzene, Phenol ",
                "question_text": "The compound A and B in given chain of reaction are respectively:A\\xrightarrow{Reduction}B\\xrightarrow{V_2O_5} Maleic Anhydride",
                "correct_ans": "a)\tPhenol, Benzene   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69818": {
                "ans1": "31.3 g",
                "ans2": "31.7 g",
                "ans3": "32.1 g",
                "ans4": "32.3 g",
                "question_text": "32.1 g of metal reacts with dilute hydrochloric acid and formed hydrogen reacted with excess oxygen to give 9 g of water. The equivalent weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "32.3 g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65360": {
                "ans1": "NaCl",
                "ans2": "KCl",
                "ans3": "NH_4Cl",
                "ans4": "AgNO_3",
                "question_text": "The electrolyte present in the salt bridge is",
                "correct_ans": "KCl",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62644": {
                "ans1": "NH_2NO_2",
                "ans2": "{(NH_4)}_2CO_3",
                "ans3": "{(CH_4)}_2SO_4",
                "ans4": "NH_4Cl",
                "question_text": "Ammonium compound which on heating does not give\u00a0NH_3\u200b\u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "NH_2NO_2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69637": {
                "ans1": "HF",
                "ans2": "HCl",
                "ans3": "HBr",
                "ans4": "HI",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is the weakest acid?",
                "correct_ans": "HF",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65690": {
                "ans1": "increases by 2",
                "ans2": "decreases by 10",
                "ans3": "increases by 1",
                "ans4": "decreases by 1",
                "question_text": "In a mixture of an aqueous solution of acetic acid and sodium acetate when the ratio of the concentration of the salt and acid is increased tenfold, the pH of the solution",
                "correct_ans": "decreases by 1",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61978": {
                "ans1": "H_2S_2O_2\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_3\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans3": "H_2SO_4\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans4": "sulphur is precipitated",
                "question_text": "When\u00a0SO_2 is pressed through acidified solution",
                "correct_ans": "sulphur is precipitated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66665": {
                "ans1": "1:2:3",
                "ans2": "6:3:2",
                "ans3": "3:2:1",
                "ans4": "1:1:1",
                "question_text": "The ratio of volume of\u00a0Cl_2  gas evolved at NTP by electrolysis of an NaCl. aq. CuCl_2 & AuCl_3 is",
                "correct_ans": "1:1:1",
                "explanation": "As valency of chlorine is same in all cases and equivalent volume is same for all, the ratio would be 1 : 1 : 1.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69585": {
                "ans1": "Zinc ethyl",
                "ans2": "ethanol",
                "ans3": "ethane",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "Ethyl iodide when reduced by\u00a0Zn-Cu couple, which of following will formed,",
                "correct_ans": "ethane",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60595": {
                "ans1": "6",
                "ans2": "12",
                "ans3": "14",
                "ans4": "21",
                "question_text": "Gastric juice contains 3gm of HCl per litre. If a person produces 2.5 litre of gastric juice per day,. how many antacid tablets each containing 400 mg of Al(OH)_3 are needed to neutralized all the HCl produced in one day?",
                "correct_ans": "14",
                "explanation": "The molar masses of HCl and Al(OH)3 are 36.5 g/mol and 78 g/mol respectively. In one day, a person produces 2.5 L of gastric juices which contain 2.5\u00d73.0=7.5g of HCl.This corresponds to 7.5/ 36.5 =0.20 moles of HCl.1 mole of Al(OH) 3 will neutralize 3 moles of HCl. Hence, 0.2 moles of HCl will be neutralized by 0.2/3 =0.068 moles of Al(OH)3 . This corresponds to 0.068\u00d778=5.34 g of Al(OH) 3\u200bEach antacid tablet contains 400 mg or 0.4 g of Al(OH)3 . hence, the number of antacid tablet required per day to neutralize HCl are",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68145": {
                "ans1": "An oxidizing agent",
                "ans2": "an reducing agent",
                "ans3": "an acid",
                "ans4": "a catalyst",
                "question_text": "A solution of\u00a0SO_2\u00a0is water reacts with\u00a0H_2S\u00a0precipitating sulphur. Here\u00a0SO_2\u00a0acts as\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "An oxidizing agent",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62228": {
                "ans1": "Dicyanide",
                "ans2": "Cyanagen",
                "ans3": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "ans4": "Ethane dicyanide",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of (CN)_2, is",
                "correct_ans": "Ethane dinitrile",
                "explanation": "The IUPAC name of CN - CN is ethane dinitrile.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68605": {
                "ans1": "M",
                "ans2": "M/2",
                "ans3": "M/3",
                "ans4": "M/6",
                "question_text": "The mol. mass of\u00a0KMnO_4 \u00a0is M,when it reacts with KOH to give product , the EW of\u00a0KMnO_4 is",
                "correct_ans": "M",
                "explanation": "Change in oxidation no. of Mn is 7-6 =1therefore, EW=mol wt./ change in O.N\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0= M/1 =M",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67566": {
                "ans1": "But-3-en-1-yne",
                "ans2": "Butanoyl chloride",
                "ans3": "Pent-1-en-3-yne",
                "ans4": "Propenal",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Dehydrohalognation of 1, 1-dichloroethane gives compound X. X when treated with Cu_2Cl_2 containing NH_4Cl gives compound Y. IUPAC name of compound Y is.",
                "correct_ans": "But-3-en-1-yne",
                "explanation": "Dehydrohalognation of 1, 1-dichloroethane gives compound EthyneEthyne when treated with Cu2Cl2 containing NH4Cl gives compound But-3-en-1-yne",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61352": {
                "ans1": "6\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans2": "16.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans3": "13.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "ans4": "11.2\\times10^{-9}",
                "question_text": "The solubility of lead iodide at 25\u00b0C is 0.7gm litre^{-1}. Its solubility produce at given temperature is (Mol. wt. of  PbI_2= 461)",
                "correct_ans": "16.5\\times10^{-9}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68895": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "6",
                "ans4": "8",
                "question_text": "29.2% (w/w) HCl stock solution was a density of 1.25 g/ml. The mol. wt. of HCl is 36.5g\u00a0mol^{-1}\u00a0. The volume of stock solution required to prepare a 200ml solution of 0.2M HCl is",
                "correct_ans": "8",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66927": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_3\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans3": "S is precipitated",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "When a gas obtained by roasting iron pyrite is passed through acidic solution of hydride of Sulphur then",
                "correct_ans": "S is precipitated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62799": {
                "ans1": "10 mole of hydrogen",
                "ans2": "2\u00d7NA molecules of water",
                "ans3": "2.24 litre of oxygen",
                "ans4": "1 mole of SO2",
                "question_text": "Which of these has more mass?",
                "correct_ans": "1 mole of SO2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63719": {
                "ans1": "Chlorobenzene",
                "ans2": "Acetophenone",
                "ans3": "Cyclohexane",
                "ans4": "Toulene",
                "question_text": "When Benzene treated with Methyl chloride in presence anhydrous Aluminium chloride, then it produces",
                "correct_ans": "Toulene",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67344": {
                "ans1": "H_2S",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans3": "HNO_3",
                "ans4": "H_2SO_3",
                "question_text": "Which of the following act as both oxidizing and reducing agent?",
                "correct_ans": "H_2SO_3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68189": {
                "ans1": "180 gm",
                "ans2": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "ans3": "180\\;N_A\\;gm",
                "ans4": "N_A\\;gm",
                "question_text": "The absolute wt. of one molecule of glucose is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65519": {
                "ans1": "36",
                "ans2": "22",
                "ans3": "24",
                "ans4": "27",
                "question_text": "Metal oxide contains 53% metal and formula of metal oxide is M_2\u200bO_3\u200b. Atomic mass of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "27",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62124": {
                "ans1": "M/2",
                "ans2": "M/4",
                "ans3": "M/6",
                "ans4": "M/8",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Zn + HNO_3\u200b\u00a0\\longrightarrow Zn(NO_3\u200b)_2\u200b\u00a0+ NH_4\u200bNO_3\u200b\u00a0+ H_2\u200bO In the above rxn. the eq. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is: (mol. wt. of HNO_3\u200b\u00a0is M)",
                "correct_ans": "M/8",
                "explanation": "Change in O.N. of N = 5 - (-3) = +8Eq. wt = Mol. Wt/ change in ON = M/8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63436": {
                "ans1": "anhydrous AlBr3",
                "ans2": "mercuric chloride",
                "ans3": "ultraviolet light",
                "ans4": "zinc chloride",
                "question_text": "Chlorination of ethane is carried out in presence of",
                "correct_ans": "ultraviolet light",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66576": {
                "ans1": "5.4g",
                "ans2": "10.8g",
                "ans3": "54.9g",
                "ans4": "108.0g",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The weight of silver displaced by a quantity of electricity which displaces 5600ml of O_2 at STP will be",
                "correct_ans": "108.0g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67121": {
                "ans1": "Br_2/CCl_4",
                "ans2": "cold\\;KMnO_4",
                "ans3": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "ans4": "Ag{\\left(NH_3\\right)}_2OH",
                "question_text": "Which among the following reagents can be used to distinguish between\u00a0CH_2BrCH=CH_2\u200b\u00a0from\u00a0CH_3CH=CHBr?",
                "correct_ans": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65358": {
                "ans1": "octahedral geometry",
                "ans2": "square planar geometry",
                "ans3": "tetragonal geometry",
                "ans4": "tetrahedral geometry",
                "question_text": "Sp3d2 hybridization is present in\u00a0[Co(NH_3)_6\\text{ }^{3+}], find its geometry",
                "correct_ans": "octahedral geometry",
                "explanation": "Sp3d2 hybridization gives octahedral geometry",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63593": {
                "ans1": " 0.25 M",
                "ans2": "50 M",
                "ans3": "0.5 M",
                "ans4": "100 M",
                "question_text": "What is the concentration of the sulphuric acid solution, if 100 ml of the solution is neutralised by 50 ml of 0.5 M\u00a0Ba(OH)_2 solution?",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61188": {
                "ans1": "1^\\circ>2^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans2": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "ans3": "2^\\circ>1^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans4": "2^\\circ>3^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "question_text": "Find the correct order for the ease of formation of free radicals",
                "correct_ans": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "explanation": "More the number of steric alkyl groups around the central carbon atom, easy will be the formation of free radicals due to electronic repulsion.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61133": {
                "ans1": "5M",
                "ans2": "1/10 M",
                "ans3": "10M",
                "ans4": "1/5M",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the concentration of HCl, if 10 ml of 0.5 M Ca(OH)_2 is required to titrate 50 ml of HCl.",
                "correct_ans": "1/5M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64921": {
                "ans1": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "ans2": "Thiosulphuric Acid",
                "ans3": " Sulphuric Acid",
                "ans4": "Sulphonic Acid",
                "question_text": "What is formed when SO_2 is dissolved in water?",
                "correct_ans": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64037": {
                "ans1": "alkaline\\;NiSO_4",
                "ans2": "alkaline\\;MnSO_4",
                "ans3": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "ans4": "acidified\\;CuSO_4",
                "question_text": "\u00a0A gas formed by reacting iron sulphide with\u00a0dil.H_2SO_4 doesn't give precipitate with",
                "correct_ans": "acidified\\;ZnSO_4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68852": {
                "ans1": "3",
                "ans2": "4",
                "ans3": "5",
                "ans4": "6",
                "question_text": "The number of Faradays of charge required to reduce 1 mole of\u00a0Cr_2O_7^{--} in acidic medium is",
                "correct_ans": "6",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64244": {
                "ans1": "octahedral geometry",
                "ans2": "square planar geometry",
                "ans3": "tetragonal geometry",
                "ans4": "tetrahedral geometry",
                "question_text": "Sp3d2 hybridization is present in\u00a0[Co(NH_3)_6\\text{ }^{3+}], find its geometry",
                "correct_ans": "octahedral geometry",
                "explanation": "Sp3d2 hybridization gives octahedral geometry",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62546": {
                "ans1": " 0.25 M",
                "ans2": "50 M",
                "ans3": "0.5 M",
                "ans4": "100 M",
                "question_text": "What is the concentration of the sulphuric acid solution, if 100 ml of the solution is neutralised by 50 ml of 0.5 M\u00a0Ba(OH)_2 solution?",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67657": {
                "ans1": "10 mole of hydrogen",
                "ans2": "2\u00d7NA molecules of water",
                "ans3": "2.24 litre of oxygen",
                "ans4": "1 mole of SO2",
                "question_text": "Which of these has more mass?",
                "correct_ans": "1 mole of SO2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67571": {
                "ans1": "180 gm",
                "ans2": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "ans3": "180\\;N_A\\;gm",
                "ans4": "N_A\\;gm",
                "question_text": "The absolute wt. of one molecule of glucose is",
                "correct_ans": "\\frac{180}{N_A}",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69270": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans2": "H_2SO_3\\;is\\;formed",
                "ans3": "S is precipitated",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "When a gas obtained by roasting iron pyrite is passed through acidic solution of hydride of Sulphur then",
                "correct_ans": "S is precipitated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64083": {
                "ans1": "KClO",
                "ans2": "KClO_2",
                "ans3": "KClO_3",
                "ans4": "KClo_4",
                "question_text": "The gas obtained \u00a0by treating bleaching powder with conc. HCL is passed through hot KOH then it gives KCL\u00a0H_2O\u00a0with one of the following",
                "correct_ans": "KClO_3",
                "explanation": "CaCl_2 + 2HCL \\rightarrow Ca(OH)_2 +Cl_2Cl_2 + HO  +",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68933": {
                "ans1": "10234 C",
                "ans2": "12345 C",
                "ans3": "13624 C",
                "ans4": "13624 C",
                "question_text": "The amount of current required to coat a 0.1 mm thick coat on 10 cm * 10cm surface by passing current through\u00a0AgNO_3solution is ,(density of Ag = 10.5 g/cc)",
                "correct_ans": "12345 C",
                "explanation": "W = ZItA*H*\\rho =\\frac{E}{F} * I *t10*10*0.01 * 10.5 = \\frac{108}{96500} * I * 30 *60I=\\frac{10*10*0.01*10.5*96500}{108*30*60}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61391": {
                "ans1": "50 gm of iron",
                "ans2": "N_2",
                "ans3": "O_2",
                "ans4": "10^{-3}\\\\",
                "question_text": "Which has the highest mass?",
                "correct_ans": "N_2",
                "explanation": "50 gm of iron = 50 gm\u00a0N_2N_21 gm atom of O = 16 gm0.1 gm atom of O = 16 *0.1 = 1.6gm6.022*10^{23}10^{23} = \\frac{12}{6.022}=1.99gmN_2 ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65403": {
                "ans1": "\u03b1-sulphur",
                "ans2": "\u03b2-sulphur",
                "ans3": "\u03b3-sulphur",
                "ans4": "\u03b4-sulphur",
                "question_text": "The Compound formed by passing\u00a0H_2S\u00a0gas through dilute\u00a0HNO_3\u00a0is ,",
                "correct_ans": "\u03b4-sulphur",
                "explanation": "3H_2S + 2HNO_3 (dil) \\rightarrow 2No + 4H_2O + 3\\delta sulphur",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63795": {
                "ans1": "ethylene glycol",
                "ans2": "formic acid",
                "ans3": "oxalic acid",
                "ans4": "acetaldehyde",
                "question_text": "The product obtained by treating ethanol with alcohol KOH is treated with alkaline\u00a0KMnO_4\u00a0 solution then one of the following is obtained .",
                "correct_ans": "ethylene glycol",
                "explanation": "C_2H_5OH + conc.H_2So_4 \\rightarrow C_2H_5 +H_2SO_4H_2O2KMnO_4 + 2KOH \\rightarrow KCl + KClO3 + H_2O",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62444": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "3.15g of an acid (molecular weight = 126) required 100ml of\u00a0\\frac{1}{2}\u00a0M NaOH for complete neutralization . The basicity of acid is .",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "100 ml of 1/2 MNaOH = 100 ml of 0.5N NaOH\\frac{W}{E} = \\frac{N_v}{1000}\\frac{3.15}{E}=\\frac{0.5*100}{1000}E= \\frac{3.15*1000}{0.5*100}=\\frac{3150}{50}=63Mol. wt = 126Basicity = \\frac{mol wt}{eq wt}\\frac{126}{63} = 2",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67235": {
                "ans1": "10^3\\\\",
                "ans2": "10^{-6}\\\\",
                "ans3": "6.022\\ast10^{20}\\\\",
                "ans4": "6.022\\ast10^{17}\\\\",
                "question_text": "The no. of hydrogen ions present in 1 ml solution having pH value 3 are",
                "correct_ans": "6.022\\ast10^{17}\\\\",
                "explanation": "pH= 3[H^+]=10^{-3} 10^{-3} 1ml = \\frac{10^{-3}}{1000} = 10^{-3} * 10^{-3} = 10^{-6} moles10^{-6} * 6.022 * 10^{23} = 6.022 * 10^{17} ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65981": {
                "ans1": "31.5",
                "ans2": "32.8",
                "ans3": "33.25",
                "ans4": "38.2",
                "question_text": "1g of\u00a0metal chloride on reaction with\u00a0AgNO_3 \u00a0\u00a0gave 2.11g of silver chloride. The equivalent weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "32.8",
                "explanation": "\\frac{Eq. Wt. of metal chloride}{Eq. wt. of silver chloride}=\\frac{Wt. of metal chloride}{wt. of silver chloride}\\frac{E_{metal}+E_{chloride}}{E_{silver}+E_{chloride}}=\\frac{1}{2.11}\\frac{x+35}{10835}=\\frac{1}{2.11}x=32.8",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69764": {
                "ans1": "63.5:65:60",
                "ans2": "31.75:32.5:30",
                "ans3": "1:1:1",
                "ans4": "1.5:1:2",
                "question_text": "The ratio\u00a0of no. of moles of Cu, Zn and Ni deposited by passing same amount of current for equal time respectively through\u00a0CuSO_4, ZnSO_4 and NiSO_4.",
                "correct_ans": "1:1:1",
                "explanation": "Their no. of moles is same . So the ratio =\u00a01:1:1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69507": {
                "ans1": "Acraldehyde",
                "ans2": "Glyceraldehyde",
                "ans3": "2-propanal",
                "ans4": "2-propenal",
                "question_text": "The IUPAC name of compound\u00a0CH_2  =CH-CHO \u00a0 is",
                "correct_ans": "2-propenal",
                "explanation": "_3CH_2= ^2CH-_1CHO 2-Propenal",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60718": {
                "ans1": "Cl_{2\\;}water",
                "ans2": "K_2Cr_2O_7/H_2O",
                "ans3": "O_2",
                "ans4": "All",
                "question_text": "The gas obtained by roasting of galena ,acts as oxidizing agent while it is reacting with\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "O_2",
                "explanation": "2PbS+3O_2 \\to 2PbO+2SO_2SO_2 ",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60739": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3V",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "50ml of 0.1N solution contain 0.31g of\u00a0Na_2CO_3xH_20\u00a0.Find the value of x of the hydrated salt.",
                "correct_ans": "1",
                "explanation": "Na_2CO_3.xH_2O (w)=Na_2CO_3.xH_2O (M)=Na_2CO_3.xH_2O (E)=\\frac{M}{2}Na_2CO_3.xH_2=2(106+18x)/2=53+9xvolule (v) =50ml=0.051 ltrNormality of sol=0.1N\\frac{W}{E}=NV\\frac{0.31}{53+9x}=0.05*0.19x+53=62x=1",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64257": {
                "ans1": "Benzyl chloride",
                "ans2": "Chlorobenzene",
                "ans3": "toulene",
                "ans4": "Benzene hexachloride",
                "question_text": "The product obtained by treating benzene with chlorine in presence of ultraviolet light is",
                "correct_ans": "Benzene hexachloride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "66632": {
                "ans1": "9650C",
                "ans2": "19300C",
                "ans3": "96500C",
                "ans4": "193000C",
                "question_text": "The amount of charge required to discharge 0.1 mole of magnesium by the electrolysis of\u00a0MgCl_2 \u00a0is",
                "correct_ans": "19300C",
                "explanation": "Mgcl \\iff Mg^{++} +2ClMg^{++}1 atom discharge of MG require 2e charge\u00a01 mole of Cl required 2F charge=2*96500C=13000Chence,0.1 mole of its require 193000*0.1C=19300C",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68471": {
                "ans1": "5.4g",
                "ans2": "10.8g",
                "ans3": "54.9g",
                "ans4": "108.0g",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The weight of silver displaced by a quantity of electricity which displaces 5600ml of O_2 at STP will be",
                "correct_ans": "108.0g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65324": {
                "ans1": "Br_2/CCl_4",
                "ans2": "cold\\;KMnO_4",
                "ans3": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "ans4": "Ag{\\left(NH_3\\right)}_2OH",
                "question_text": "Which among the following reagents can be used to distinguish between\u00a0CH_2BrCH=CH_2\u200b\u00a0from\u00a0CH_3CH=CHBr?",
                "correct_ans": "AgNO_3/C_2H_5OH",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65780": {
                "ans1": "octahedral geometry",
                "ans2": "square planar geometry",
                "ans3": "tetragonal geometry",
                "ans4": "tetrahedral geometry",
                "question_text": "Sp3d2 hybridization is present in\u00a0[Co(NH_3)_6\\text{ }^{3+}], find its geometry",
                "correct_ans": "octahedral geometry",
                "explanation": "Sp3d2 hybridization gives octahedral geometry",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65921": {
                "ans1": " 0.25 M",
                "ans2": "50 M",
                "ans3": "0.5 M",
                "ans4": "100 M",
                "question_text": "What is the concentration of the sulphuric acid solution, if 100 ml of the solution is neutralised by 50 ml of 0.5 M\u00a0Ba(OH)_2 solution?",
                "correct_ans": "0.5 M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60883": {
                "ans1": "1^\\circ>2^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans2": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "ans3": "2^\\circ>1^\\circ>3^\\circ",
                "ans4": "2^\\circ>3^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "question_text": "Find the correct order for the ease of formation of free radicals",
                "correct_ans": "3^\\circ>2^\\circ>1^\\circ",
                "explanation": "More the number of steric alkyl groups around the central carbon atom, easy will be the formation of free radicals due to electronic repulsion.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64124": {
                "ans1": "5M",
                "ans2": "1/10 M",
                "ans3": "10M",
                "ans4": "1/5M",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Find the concentration of HCl, if 10 ml of 0.5 M Ca(OH)_2 is required to titrate 50 ml of HCl.",
                "correct_ans": "1/5M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65945": {
                "ans1": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "ans2": "Thiosulphuric Acid",
                "ans3": " Sulphuric Acid",
                "ans4": "Sulphonic Acid",
                "question_text": "What is formed when SO_2 is dissolved in water?",
                "correct_ans": " Sulphurous Acid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64535": {
                "ans1": "4",
                "ans2": "3",
                "ans3": "2",
                "ans4": "1",
                "question_text": "\u00a00.18g of a metal was deposited when 0.5 ampere current was passed through M^{n+} -\u00a0ion solution for 20 minutes. The value of n is (Atomic wt. of M=58.7)",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63142": {
                "ans1": "95.42%",
                "ans2": "88.12%",
                "ans3": "92.85%",
                "ans4": "85.68%",
                "question_text": "7g of a piece of limestone was dissolved in 200ml of 0.75 N HCI. The excess acid required 40ml of 0.5N NaOH for complete neutralization. The percentage of CaCO, in limestone is",
                "correct_ans": "92.85%",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}weight\\;of\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{NEV}{1000}=\\frac{\\left(200\\ast0.75-40\\ast0.5\\right)\\ast1\\ast50}{1000}=6.5g\\\\\\%\\;of\\;pure\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{6.5}7\\times100\\%=92.85\\%\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69661": {
                "ans1": "1.18\\;x\\;10^{-6}M",
                "ans2": "6.5\\;x\\;10^{-6}M",
                "ans3": "7.5\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "ans4": "5.9\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "question_text": "\\begin{array}{l}The\\;concentration\\;of\\;Ag^+\\\\\\;-\\;ion\\;in\\;saturated\\;so\\ln\\;of\\\\\\;Ag_2\\;CrO_4\\;in\\;presence\\;of\\;\\\\0.1M\\;\\;K\u2082CrO_4solution\\;is\\;\\\\\\;(Ksp\\;of\\;Ag\u2082CrO_4=1.4\\;x\\;10^{-13})\\end{array}",
                "correct_ans": "5.9\\;x\\;10^{-7}M",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69013": {
                "ans1": "Formaldehyde",
                "ans2": "Glycol",
                "ans3": "Glyoxal",
                "ans4": "Oxalic acid",
                "question_text": "The product formed by dehalogenation of 1,2-dihaloethane on ozonolysis gives",
                "correct_ans": "Formaldehyde",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62448": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "0.91g of metal was deposited when 1.5 ampere current is passed through\u00a0Mn^+\u00a0ion for 20 minutes . The value of n is ( Atomic weight of M =195)",
                "correct_ans": "4",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61157": {
                "ans1": "0.47",
                "ans2": "1.47",
                "ans3": "1.82",
                "ans4": "2.82",
                "question_text": "The pH of a solution formed when 0.1 M KOH is added to 100ml of 0.1M HCl solution till the acid is half neutralized is",
                "correct_ans": "1.47",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "60057": {
                "ans1": "H_2SO_4",
                "ans2": "H_2S_2O_7",
                "ans3": "H_2S_2O_8",
                "ans4": "SO_3",
                "question_text": "The absorbtion of gas formed by catalytic oxidation of SO\u2082 by oil of vitriol gives.\n\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "H_2S_2O_7",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}weight\\;of\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{NEV}{1000}=\\frac{\\left(200\\ast0.75-40\\ast0.5\\right)\\ast1\\ast50}{1000}=6.5g\\\\\\%\\;of\\;pure\\;CaCO_3=\\frac{6.5}7\\times100\\%=92.85\\%\\\\\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64991": {
                "ans1": "90",
                "ans2": "98",
                "ans3": "118",
                "ans4": "126",
                "question_text": "0.24g of magnesium on reaction with a dibasic acid gave 1.40g of magnesium salt. The molecular weight of acid is:",
                "correct_ans": "118",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69429": {
                "ans1": "1.3",
                "ans2": "2.3",
                "ans3": "11.7",
                "ans4": "12.7",
                "question_text": "0.1g of pure NaOH was added to 100ml of\u00a0\\frac{N}{20} \\;H_2SO_4. The mixture was then diluted to 500ml. The pH of the diluted solution is:",
                "correct_ans": "2.3",
                "explanation": "40g \\;of \\;NaOH=1000ml\\; of \\; 1N\\; NaOH\\\\\n0.1g\\; NaOH=\\frac{1000}{40}*0.1=2.5ml\\; of \\; 1N\\; NaOH\\\\\n100ml\\; of \\; \\frac{N}{20}\\; H_2SO_4=5ml\\; of\\; 1N\\; H_2SO_4\\\\\n\\therefore N_{mix}=\\frac{2.5*1}{500}=0.005N\\\\\npH=-log(0.005)=2.3",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61378": {
                "ans1": "M",
                "ans2": "M/2",
                "ans3": "M/3",
                "ans4": "M/4",
                "question_text": "The mol. mass of\u00a0KMnO_4\u00a0is M.\u00a0When it reacts with water, the equivalent wt. of\u00a0KMnO_4\u00a0in\u00a0neutral medium is",
                "correct_ans": "M/3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "61547": {
                "ans1": "Silver nitrate",
                "ans2": "Barium chloride",
                "ans3": "Mercurous nitrate",
                "ans4": "Dilute hydrochloric acid",
                "question_text": "Which of the following reagent is used to test sulphate ion of the salt?",
                "correct_ans": "Barium chloride",
                "explanation": "Sulfate ions in solution, are detected using\u00a0",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69030": {
                "ans1": "2.09 liters",
                "ans2": "4.17 liters",
                "ans3": "6.26 liters",
                "ans4": "8.42 liters",
                "question_text": "The total volume of gases formed at STP by passing 5 ampere current through acidified water for 2 hours is",
                "correct_ans": "6.26 liters",
                "explanation": "H_2 \\;and \\;O_296500\\; C \\;charge \\rightarrow \\frac{16.8}{96500}*5*2*3600\\;liters=6.26\\;liters",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "65101": {
                "ans1": "0.696",
                "ans2": "0.22",
                "ans3": "1.1",
                "ans4": "1.528",
                "question_text": "500 \\;{cm}^3 \\; 0.5\\; NHCl\u00a0solution was heated till its colume left behind was\u00a0300ml, 1.5g o f HCl was evaporated. The normality of residual solution is",
                "correct_ans": "0.696",
                "explanation": "Total milli eq. of HCl = N*V = 0.5*500=250\\frac{1.5}{36.5}*1000=41.09\\\\Millie q. of GCl left behind = 250-41.09 = 208.91\\frac{208.91}{300}=0.696\\;N",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64735": {
                "ans1": "4*10^{-5}",
                "ans2": "4.6*10^{-5}",
                "ans3": "5*10^{-5}",
                "ans4": "5.6*10^{-5}",
                "question_text": "How many mol. of\u00a0Ca(OH)_2\u00a0must be dissolved to produce\u00a0250ml\u00a0of aqueous solution of pH=10.65? Assume complete dissociation.",
                "correct_ans": "5.6*10^{-5}",
                "explanation": "pH=10.65,\\; pOH=14-10.65=3.35\\\\\nlog[OH^-]=-3.35\\\\\nOH^-=4.47*10^{-4}\\\\\nIn \\;250ml\\;=\\frac{4.47*10^{-4}}{1000}*250\\\\\n=1.12*10^{-4}\\\\\nCa{(OH)}_2\\leftrightharpoons Ca^{2+}+2OH^-\n\\\\\n\\;\\;\\;\\;1\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;2\n\\\\\n1.12*10^{-4} mole \\;OH^-=\\frac12*1.12*10^{-4}=5.6*10^{-5} mol.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67234": {
                "ans1": "1 Kg",
                "ans2": "2 Kg",
                "ans3": "30 Kg",
                "ans4": "60 Kg",
                "question_text": "20 Kg of\u00a0N_{2\\;} and 3 Kg of\u00a0H_{2\\;} gives \u2026\u2026\u2026. NH_{3+\\;}",
                "correct_ans": "2 Kg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68656": {
                "ans1": "49 g",
                "ans2": "36.75 g",
                "ans3": "24.5 g",
                "ans4": "9.8 g",
                "question_text": "The amount of sulphuric acid present in 500 cc of its 1.5 N solution is",
                "correct_ans": "36.75 g",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64290": {
                "ans1": "12.65",
                "ans2": "11.65",
                "ans3": "2.35",
                "ans4": "1.35",
                "question_text": "The pH pf the resulting solution obtained by mixing 0.1M NaOH and 0.01M HCl in equal volume is",
                "correct_ans": "12.65",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "67165": {
                "ans1": "propanol",
                "ans2": "propanal ",
                "ans3": "propanone ",
                "ans4": "propanoic acid",
                "question_text": "The product formed by heating ethyl iodide with alcoholic potassium cyanide is hydrolyzed\u00a0 then the final compound obtained is",
                "correct_ans": "propanoic acid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63721": {
                "ans1": "24",
                "ans2": "26",
                "ans3": "30",
                "ans4": "40",
                "question_text": "The vapor density of metal chloride is 29.25. If oxide of metal contain 75% of metal, the atomic weight of metal is",
                "correct_ans": "24",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63424": {
                "ans1": "formaldehyde  ",
                "ans2": "acetic acid   ",
                "ans3": "ethanol  ",
                "ans4": "ethanal ",
                "question_text": "The product obtained after hydration of ethyne is",
                "correct_ans": "ethanal ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68595": {
                "ans1": "5 hours",
                "ans2": "4 hours",
                "ans3": "3 hours",
                "ans4": "2 hours",
                "question_text": "The time required to deposit 1 millimole of Aluminium when 0.965 A current is passed through the solution is",
                "correct_ans": "5 hours",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "68566": {
                "ans1": "6.023\\times10^{-23}",
                "ans2": "60.23\\times10^{-23}",
                "ans3": "0.6023\\times10^{-23}",
                "ans4": "602.3\\times10^{-23}",
                "question_text": "The number of hydrogen ions in 1ml of solution whose pH is 13 is",
                "correct_ans": "6.023\\times10^{-23}",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}No.\\;of\\;H^+\\;ion\\;=\\;volume\\;in\\;litre\\;x\\;10^{-pH}x\\;6.023\\;x10^{23}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=1\\;x10^{-3}x10^{-13}x6.023x10^{23}\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=6.023\\;x10^7\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "69937": {
                "ans1": "18 gm",
                "ans2": "9 gm",
                "ans3": "12 gm",
                "ans4": "6 gm",
                "question_text": "6 moles of Al reacts with HCl to give how many grams of H_2?",
                "correct_ans": "18 gm",
                "explanation": "\\begin{array}{l}2Al\\;+\\;6HCl\\;\\rightarrow2AlCl_3\\;+3H_2\\\\2\\;mole\\;\\;\\;6mole\\;\\;\\;2mole\\;\\;\\;3\\;mole\\;\\\\2moles\\;of\\;Al\\;reacts\\;with\\;HCl\\;to\\;give\\;3\\;moles\\;of\\;H_2\\\\6\\;moles\\;of\\;Al\\;reacts\\;with\\;HCl\\;to\\;give\\;9\\;moles\\;of\\;H_2\\\\Therefor,9\\;moles\\;of\\;H_2\\;=\\;9\\;x\\;2\\;=18\\;gm\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64479": {
                "ans1": "2",
                "ans2": "1",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "zero",
                "question_text": "Iron sulphide is heated in air to form A, an oxide of sulphur .A is dissolved in water to give an acid . The basicity of that acid is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "63466": {
                "ans1": "Hydrolysis",
                "ans2": "Hydration",
                "ans3": "Decolourization",
                "ans4": "dehydration",
                "question_text": "When\\;conc.\\;H_2SO_4\\;comes\\;in\\;contact\\;with\\;black\\;sugar\\;it\\;becomes\\;black\\;due\\;to",
                "correct_ans": "dehydration",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62850": {
                "ans1": "N_2",
                "ans2": "NO",
                "ans3": "N_2O",
                "ans4": "NO_2",
                "question_text": "A gas is formed by heatingNH_4Cl\\;with\\;slaked\\;lime\\;on\\;catalytic\\;oxidation\\;gives",
                "correct_ans": "NO",
                "explanation": "The\\;gas\\;formed\\;is\\;NH_3\\;which\\;is\\;catsalytic\\;pxidation\\;gives\\;NO",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "62584": {
                "ans1": "300 ml",
                "ans2": "150 ml",
                "ans3": "75 ml",
                "ans4": "38 ml",
                "question_text": "75 ml of 0.2 HCl will neutralize how many milliliters of 0.1 M Ba(OH)_2?",
                "correct_ans": "75 ml",
                "explanation": "At Neutalization point,\\begin{array}{l}V_{A\\;}X\\;N_A\\;=\\;V_{B\\;}X\\;N_B\\\\or,\\;75\\;\\ast\\;0.2\\;=\\;Vb\\ast(2\\ast0.1)\\\\normality=2\\;X\\;molarity,\\;Gor\\;Ba(OH)_2\\\\\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;\\;=\\;molarity\\;,\\;for\\;HCl\\\\therefore\\;,\\;Vb=\\;75\\;ml\\end{array}",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "64985": {
                "ans1": "ethane , propane and butane ",
                "ans2": "ethane , propane and ethyne",
                "ans3": "ethane , ethene  and ethyne",
                "ans4": "ethane ,ethyne and ethanol",
                "question_text": "Electrolysis of sodium salt of ethanoic acid , succinic acid maelic\u00a0 and produces ....... respectively",
                "correct_ans": "ethane , ethene  and ethyne",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        }
    },
    "english": {
        "1": {
            "75118": {
                "ans1": "Had valued, valued",
                "ans2": "is valuing, values",
                "ans3": "has valued, values",
                "ans4": "valued, values",
                "question_text": "She______ his friendship more than she ____ mine.",
                "correct_ans": "valued, values",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77139": {
                "ans1": "shall pass",
                "ans2": "may pass",
                "ans3": "will pass",
                "ans4": "could pass",
                "question_text": "She wrote so well that she \u2026\u2026\u2026. the exam.",
                "correct_ans": "could pass",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72489": {
                "ans1": "Human",
                "ans2": "minute",
                "ans3": "faituge",
                "ans4": "water",
                "question_text": "Which of the following word gets stress in its first syllable?",
                "correct_ans": "water",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70480": {
                "ans1": "Noun ",
                "ans2": "verb",
                "ans3": "adverb",
                "ans4": "adjective",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018deceptive\u2019 functions as a/an \u2026\u2026\u2026..",
                "correct_ans": "adjective",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73777": {
                "ans1": "A buried city is excavated by the workers.",
                "ans2": "A buried city is being excavated by the workers.",
                "ans3": "A buried city was being excavated by the workers.",
                "ans4": "A buried city are being excavated by the workers.",
                "question_text": "The workers are excavating a buried city.",
                "correct_ans": "A buried city is excavated by the workers.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72774": {
                "ans1": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "ans2": "They wanted to know where the zoo was.",
                "ans3": "They asked where the zoo is.",
                "ans4": "The inquired where the zoo is.",
                "question_text": "They said,\u201d Where is the zoo?\u201d",
                "correct_ans": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79072": {
                "ans1": "at, for ",
                "ans2": "in, in",
                "ans3": "to, for ",
                "ans4": "by, for",
                "question_text": "I am grateful \u2026\u2026\u2026. You \u2026\u2026.. your help.",
                "correct_ans": "to, for ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75149": {
                "ans1": "is thinking ",
                "ans2": "think",
                "ans3": "through",
                "ans4": "thinks",
                "question_text": "He \u2026\u2026 that the law may be changed.",
                "correct_ans": "thinks",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78982": {
                "ans1": " Insite of his luck, he did not win the award.",
                "ans2": "You can go home or go with him to the library.",
                "ans3": " I said that I could do it.",
                "ans4": " She goes to collage every day.",
                "question_text": "Which is a compound sentence?",
                "correct_ans": "You can go home or go with him to the library.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72756": {
                "ans1": "Liberate",
                "ans2": "emancipate",
                "ans3": "free ",
                "ans4": "confine",
                "question_text": "Release",
                "correct_ans": "confine",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78249": {
                "ans1": "Ram received a pen; Hari ,a pencil",
                "ans2": "He has been to England ,France ,Germany & Sweden",
                "ans3": "We should be devoted and humble, cheerful and serene",
                "ans4": "What a terrible mistake this is!",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is incorrectly punctuated?",
                "correct_ans": "He has been to England ,France ,Germany & Sweden",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71118": {
                "ans1": "Liked",
                "ans2": "likes",
                "ans3": "like",
                "ans4": "had liked",
                "question_text": "She liked him more than she \u2026\u2026.. her friend.",
                "correct_ans": "likes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70603": {
                "ans1": "This medicine is expensive.     ",
                "ans2": "This is not cheap.",
                "ans3": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "ans4": "This medicine is never cheap.",
                "question_text": "\u201cThis medicine is cheap.\u201d Transformation of this sentence to negative yields",
                "correct_ans": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72823": {
                "ans1": "appoint",
                "ans2": "appointed",
                "ans3": "to appoint",
                "ans4": "appointing",
                "question_text": "Why don't you have him ...... your secretary?",
                "correct_ans": "appoint",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72230": {
                "ans1": "was,will",
                "ans2": "were,would ",
                "ans3": "was,would have ",
                "ans4": "was,would",
                "question_text": "If I ............ thirsty , I ....... drink water.",
                "correct_ans": "was,would",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71926": {
                "ans1": "start",
                "ans2": "starts",
                "ans3": "will start",
                "ans4": "has started",
                "question_text": "Our exams ....... in the 5th of July.",
                "correct_ans": "start",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74537": {
                "ans1": "black horse",
                "ans2": "black sheep",
                "ans3": "white elephant",
                "ans4": "lazy dog",
                "question_text": "'An unwanted person' can also be called a",
                "correct_ans": "black sheep",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75860": {
                "ans1": "them, me",
                "ans2": "he, me",
                "ans3": "me, her",
                "ans4": "him , me",
                "question_text": "She distributed the mangoes between ............ and ...........",
                "correct_ans": "him , me",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76138": {
                "ans1": "you going",
                "ans2": "your going",
                "ans3": "you to go",
                "ans4": "your gone",
                "question_text": "I object to ...... early.",
                "correct_ans": "your going",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73995": {
                "ans1": "two hundreds runs",
                "ans2": "two hundred runs",
                "ans3": "two-hundred runs",
                "ans4": "two-hundred run",
                "question_text": "I made ........ in yesterday's match.",
                "correct_ans": "two-hundred runs",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78216": {
                "ans1": "aggressive",
                "ans2": "nonassertive",
                "ans3": "stubborn",
                "ans4": "militant",
                "question_text": "The antonym of 'vehement'",
                "correct_ans": "nonassertive",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72684": {
                "ans1": "from",
                "ans2": "of",
                "ans3": "for",
                "ans4": "off",
                "question_text": "The old man has been cured ........ cancer.",
                "correct_ans": "of",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71587": {
                "ans1": "The doctor warned me to smoke.",
                "ans2": "The doctor forbade me not to smoke.",
                "ans3": "The doctor forbade me to smoke.",
                "ans4": "The doctor suggested me not to smoke .",
                "question_text": "The doctor said to me , \" Don't smoke \" can be reported as",
                "correct_ans": "The doctor forbade me to smoke.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78188": {
                "ans1": "simple",
                "ans2": "complex",
                "ans3": "compound",
                "ans4": "compound - complex",
                "question_text": "'I watched TV while he did his homework' is a ......... sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "compound",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75254": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The word 'contaminate' has its primary stress on the... syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77296": {
                "ans1": "fragile",
                "ans2": "brittle",
                "ans3": "hard",
                "ans4": "breakable",
                "question_text": "Dainty",
                "correct_ans": "hard",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74566": {
                "ans1": "are",
                "ans2": "is",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "You and he.....good friends.",
                "correct_ans": "are",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74889": {
                "ans1": "said",
                "ans2": "delivers speech.",
                "ans3": "told that",
                "ans4": "has told",
                "question_text": "G.P. Koirala...we are going to bring peace in our country very soon.",
                "correct_ans": "told that",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76472": {
                "ans1": "I help him",
                "ans2": "I shall help him",
                "ans3": "help him",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "If John comes, .......",
                "correct_ans": "all of these",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79657": {
                "ans1": "The poor should be helped",
                "ans2": "The poor must be helped",
                "ans3": "Let the poor be helped",
                "ans4": "The poor were helped",
                "question_text": "Choose the correct sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "The poor should be helped",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71848": {
                "ans1": "for",
                "ans2": "on",
                "ans3": "at",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "They all wait...the patient.",
                "correct_ans": "on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75705": {
                "ans1": "leave",
                "ans2": "left",
                "ans3": "to leave",
                "ans4": "has left",
                "question_text": "I heard him......the house.",
                "correct_ans": "leave",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75331": {
                "ans1": "V+ Present Participle",
                "ans2": "S+V+ Gerund",
                "ans3": "V + Gerund",
                "ans4": "S+V",
                "question_text": "Don't keep saying that",
                "correct_ans": "S+V+ Gerund",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77267": {
                "ans1": "singing",
                "ans2": "sing",
                "ans3": "sung",
                "ans4": "sang",
                "question_text": "She did nothing but ......",
                "correct_ans": "sing",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75818": {
                "ans1": "fascinating pursuit",
                "ans2": "fantastic ",
                "ans3": "hunting game",
                "ans4": "lofty ideal",
                "question_text": "To find real happiness in the world is a wild goose chase.",
                "correct_ans": "hunting game",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70566": {
                "ans1": "start",
                "ans2": "starts",
                "ans3": "will start",
                "ans4": "has started",
                "question_text": "Our exams ....... in the 5th of July.",
                "correct_ans": "start",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79913": {
                "ans1": "complex",
                "ans2": "compound",
                "ans3": "simple",
                "ans4": "mixed",
                "question_text": "After the completion of his college he decided to go to his hometown to meet his parents and relatives. This is a _____sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "simple",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77471": {
                "ans1": "has rained",
                "ans2": "is raining",
                "ans3": "rains",
                "ans4": "rained",
                "question_text": "Look! It ____ outside.",
                "correct_ans": "is raining",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79979": {
                "ans1": "stubborn",
                "ans2": "obduracy",
                "ans3": " barrage",
                "ans4": "complaint",
                "question_text": "The opposite meaning of the \"obdurate' is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "complaint",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79505": {
                "ans1": "beg",
                "ans2": "begging",
                "ans3": "to beg",
                "ans4": "to begging",
                "question_text": "I am ready to live a simple life rather than_____.",
                "correct_ans": "beg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70581": {
                "ans1": "would collect",
                "ans2": "shall collect",
                "ans3": "would have collected",
                "ans4": "could have collected",
                "question_text": "If you have finished your exam, I ____ your papers.",
                "correct_ans": "shall collect",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77869": {
                "ans1": "short,shrill cry",
                "ans2": "unsuccessful",
                "ans3": "disappointing event",
                "ans4": "dis-witted",
                "question_text": "The correct meaning of the word 'a damp squib' is",
                "correct_ans": "disappointing event",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75856": {
                "ans1": "commander-in-chief",
                "ans2": "commanders-in-chief",
                "ans3": "commander-in-chiefs",
                "ans4": "commanders-in-chiefs",
                "question_text": "They are ..........",
                "correct_ans": "commanders-in-chief",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71966": {
                "ans1": "on",
                "ans2": "with",
                "ans3": "in",
                "ans4": "at",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The president conferred the title of Dirga Sewa Padak ..........\u00a0 him.",
                "correct_ans": "on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78483": {
                "ans1": "friend has",
                "ans2": "friends have",
                "ans3": "friend have",
                "ans4": "friends has",
                "question_text": "One of my ___ bought a new car.",
                "correct_ans": "friends has",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76863": {
                "ans1": " This room needs painting.",
                "ans2": "This room needs to be painted.",
                "ans3": "This room wants to be painted.",
                "ans4": " I want this room to paint.",
                "question_text": "This room wants painting. The passive of this sentence is.",
                "correct_ans": "This room wants to be painted.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71028": {
                "ans1": "she says she could not help me.",
                "ans2": "she says she can't help me.",
                "ans3": "she says she could not help you. ",
                "ans4": "she said she can't help me.",
                "question_text": "She say, 'I can't help you.' This sentence can be reported as",
                "correct_ans": "she says she can't help me.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71383": {
                "ans1": "one",
                "ans2": "one's",
                "ans3": "ones",
                "ans4": "once",
                "question_text": "Some good ____ are selected the competition.",
                "correct_ans": "ones",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72939": {
                "ans1": "on",
                "ans2": "upon",
                "ans3": "at",
                "ans4": "onto",
                "question_text": "Pounce ____ a thing.",
                "correct_ans": "on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73716": {
                "ans1": "hoped",
                "ans2": "had hoped",
                "ans3": "hope",
                "ans4": "have hope",
                "question_text": "We ____ that you would solve this problem.",
                "correct_ans": "had hoped",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70051": {
                "ans1": " 1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018fratricide\u2019 has its primary stress on ____ the syllable.",
                "correct_ans": " 1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74906": {
                "ans1": "Can she",
                "ans2": "can't she",
                "ans3": "do I",
                "ans4": "am I",
                "question_text": "I don't think she can do the work, _ ?",
                "correct_ans": "Can she",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76077": {
                "ans1": "S + v + o + adjective",
                "ans2": "s + v + o",
                "ans3": "s + v + adjective",
                "ans4": "s+v",
                "question_text": "The sun keeps us warm.",
                "correct_ans": "S + v + o + adjective",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78213": {
                "ans1": "gloomy",
                "ans2": "implicit",
                "ans3": "hasty",
                "ans4": " rigid",
                "question_text": "Explicit:",
                "correct_ans": " rigid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70963": {
                "ans1": "/fr\u0259m/",
                "ans2": "/fr\u028cm/",
                "ans3": "/fr\u0254m/",
                "ans4": "/fr\u0292m/",
                "question_text": "The word - 'from' is",
                "correct_ans": "/fr\u0259m/",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73636": {
                "ans1": "informal",
                "ans2": "sympathetic",
                "ans3": "uncooperative",
                "ans4": "charitable",
                "question_text": "All his neighbours are aware of his acrimonious nature.",
                "correct_ans": "sympathetic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79708": {
                "ans1": "of",
                "ans2": "for",
                "ans3": "against",
                "ans4": "off",
                "question_text": "There is no cure _ go out.",
                "correct_ans": "for",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79568": {
                "ans1": "to frighten",
                "ans2": "to throw out",
                "ans3": "to behave in an unbecoming manner",
                "ans4": "to jeer at",
                "question_text": "To make one's flesh creep",
                "correct_ans": "to frighten",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78434": {
                "ans1": "saw",
                "ans2": " had seen",
                "ans3": "was seen",
                "ans4": "was seeing",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I ______ the movie before.",
                "correct_ans": "saw",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79746": {
                "ans1": "to move",
                "ans2": "move",
                "ans3": "moved",
                "ans4": "moves",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I feel the room",
                "correct_ans": "move",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72550": {
                "ans1": "/i:koun\u1d4amaIz/",
                "ans2": "/ikonmaiz/",
                "ans3": "/ik\u1d4aunomaiz/",
                "ans4": " /ik\u1d4anomaiz/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word 'Economize' is.",
                "correct_ans": "/i:koun\u1d4amaIz/",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74370": {
                "ans1": "advice",
                "ans2": "advices",
                "ans3": "advise",
                "ans4": "adviced",
                "question_text": "He gave me ...",
                "correct_ans": "advice",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79152": {
                "ans1": "has lived",
                "ans2": "lives",
                "ans3": "lived",
                "ans4": "is living",
                "question_text": "He _ the life of a Chiristian.",
                "correct_ans": "is living",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76405": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "The word Edition' has its primary stress on the _ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71494": {
                "ans1": "a feather",
                "ans2": "a butterfly",
                "ans3": "air",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "\u00a0As light as",
                "correct_ans": "all of these",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77272": {
                "ans1": "over",
                "ans2": "on",
                "ans3": "for",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Let us spread cloth _ the table .",
                "correct_ans": "over",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78687": {
                "ans1": "Few politician",
                "ans2": "A few politicians",
                "ans3": "politicians",
                "ans4": "both (a) & (b)",
                "question_text": "_ can be relied on.",
                "correct_ans": "A few politicians",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72394": {
                "ans1": "off",
                "ans2": "up",
                "ans3": "on",
                "ans4": "from",
                "question_text": "Keep _ the grass.",
                "correct_ans": "off",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72196": {
                "ans1": " to sit up late at night to work or study",
                "ans2": "to burn the candle at midnight",
                "ans3": " to illuminate the house",
                "ans4": "to burn oil in a lamp at midnight",
                "question_text": "To burn the midnight oil:",
                "correct_ans": " to sit up late at night to work or study",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75239": {
                "ans1": " tell",
                "ans2": "have told",
                "ans3": "told",
                "ans4": "am telling",
                "question_text": "\u00a0There is the museum I__ you about.",
                "correct_ans": "told",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75503": {
                "ans1": "hippophile",
                "ans2": "dendrophile",
                "ans3": "philologist",
                "ans4": "cheirophile",
                "question_text": "Lover of houses:",
                "correct_ans": "hippophile",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71771": {
                "ans1": "Can she",
                "ans2": "can\u2019t she",
                "ans3": "do I",
                "ans4": "am I",
                "question_text": "I don't think she can do the work, _ ?",
                "correct_ans": "Can she",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75194": {
                "ans1": ";&,",
                "ans2": ",&;",
                "ans3": ";&!",
                "ans4": ",&,",
                "question_text": "It\u2019s too cold hot here () indeed () it\u2019s summer.",
                "correct_ans": ",&,",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70852": {
                "ans1": "for, on    ",
                "ans2": "of, on   ",
                "ans3": "of, in    ",
                "ans4": "for, in",
                "question_text": "Technology has been a subject \u2026\u2026. Discussion \u2026\u2026. Philosophy.",
                "correct_ans": "of, in    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72329": {
                "ans1": "/\u0261\u0259s\u026ap/  ",
                "ans2": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026ap/   ",
                "ans3": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026a:p/  ",
                "ans4": "/\u0261\u0259s\u026a:p/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word \u2018gossip\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026ap/   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72216": {
                "ans1": "greed",
                "ans2": "voracity",
                "ans3": "avarice ",
                "ans4": "generosity",
                "question_text": "The antonym of the word \u2018cupidity\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "generosity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70514": {
                "ans1": "S+V+O+C       ",
                "ans2": "S+V+IO+DO  ",
                "ans3": "S+V+O+Adverbial  ",
                "ans4": "S+V+O",
                "question_text": "The sentence structure of \u2018She presented him a warm welcome.\u2019 Is",
                "correct_ans": "S+V+IO+DO  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78112": {
                "ans1": "learned",
                "ans2": "won\u2019t learn     ",
                "ans3": "didn\u2019t learn    ",
                "ans4": "doesn\u2019t learn",
                "question_text": "If you \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026Physics and math at school, you would find engineering difficult to understand.",
                "correct_ans": "didn\u2019t learn    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72830": {
                "ans1": "This medicine is expensive.     ",
                "ans2": "This is not cheap.",
                "ans3": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "ans4": "This medicine is never cheap.",
                "question_text": "\u201cThis medicine is cheap.\u201d Transformation of this sentence to negative yields",
                "correct_ans": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79139": {
                "ans1": "She said, \u201cOh! I am undone.\u201d       ",
                "ans2": "She said, \u201cAlas! I am undone.\u201d",
                "ans3": "She said, \u201cUgh! I am undone.\u201d     ",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "She exclaimed sorrowfully that she was undone. The direct form of this statement is",
                "correct_ans": "She said, \u201cAlas! I am undone.\u201d",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74917": {
                "ans1": "unerring",
                "ans2": "faulty",
                "ans3": "peccable",
                "ans4": "imperfect",
                "question_text": "The synonym of the word \u2018infallible\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "unerring",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78531": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018bolero\u2019 gets its primary stress on its \u2026\u2026\u2026syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75205": {
                "ans1": "Listen to the music.",
                "ans2": "They should listen to music.",
                "ans3": "They are listening music.",
                "ans4": "They listen to music.",
                "question_text": "The active form of \u201cMusic is listened to.\u201d Is",
                "correct_ans": "They listen to music.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77515": {
                "ans1": "comfortable around people",
                "ans2": "not comfortable around people",
                "ans3": "who solves problems through discussion    ",
                "ans4": "both (a) & (c)",
                "question_text": "An introvert person is",
                "correct_ans": "not comfortable around people",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77797": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "both 1st and 2nd",
                "question_text": "The word fraction has its primary stress on the _ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72771": {
                "ans1": "Do as you like.",
                "ans2": "Waste not, want not.",
                "ans3": "If he comes to me, I will help him.",
                "ans4": "Whatever you do, be just.",
                "question_text": "Choose the compound sentence",
                "correct_ans": "If he comes to me, I will help him.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73097": {
                "ans1": "She said to me that she is busy",
                "ans2": "She told that she was busy",
                "ans3": "She told me that Gallilio once said the Earth was flat",
                "ans4": "She says to me that let's have fun",
                "question_text": "Tick the correct indirect speech",
                "correct_ans": "She told me that Gallilio once said the Earth was flat",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70546": {
                "ans1": "/i:koun\u1d4amaIz/",
                "ans2": "/ikonmaiz/",
                "ans3": "/ik\u1d4aunomaiz/",
                "ans4": "/ik\u1d4anomaiz/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word 'Economize' is.",
                "correct_ans": "/ikonmaiz/",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72673": {
                "ans1": "s+v+o",
                "ans2": "s+v+preposition phase",
                "ans3": "s+vi+o",
                "ans4": " s+vi+n",
                "question_text": "You may rely on that man",
                "correct_ans": "s+v+preposition phase",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74539": {
                "ans1": "with",
                "ans2": "up",
                "ans3": "of",
                "ans4": "by",
                "question_text": "The bullet missed him ________ the fraction of an inch",
                "correct_ans": "by",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71717": {
                "ans1": "weak",
                "ans2": "lavish",
                "ans3": "idiotic",
                "ans4": "erring",
                "question_text": "Flaccid:",
                "correct_ans": "weak",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76328": {
                "ans1": "meet",
                "ans2": "meeting",
                "ans3": "have met",
                "ans4": "to be met",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I look forward to ______ my old friend next month.",
                "correct_ans": "meet",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74346": {
                "ans1": "in",
                "ans2": "with",
                "ans3": "at ",
                "ans4": "for",
                "question_text": "I am engaged _ writing on article.",
                "correct_ans": "in",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74618": {
                "ans1": "descendant",
                "ans2": "bleak",
                "ans3": "bitter",
                "ans4": "humble",
                "question_text": "Arrogant:",
                "correct_ans": "humble",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74897": {
                "ans1": "tell",
                "ans2": "have told",
                "ans3": "told",
                "ans4": "am telling",
                "question_text": "There is the museum I ____ you about.",
                "correct_ans": "told",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74852": {
                "ans1": "It is done.",
                "ans2": "It is being done.",
                "ans3": " It was done.",
                "ans4": "It has been done.",
                "question_text": "What is the passive of \"I did it\"?",
                "correct_ans": " It was done.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72736": {
                "ans1": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "ans2": "They wanted to know where the zoo was.",
                "ans3": "The asked where was the zoo.",
                "ans4": "The enquired where the zoo was.",
                "question_text": "The said,\"Where is the zoo?\"",
                "correct_ans": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70909": {
                "ans1": "Humble",
                "ans2": "Appetite",
                "ans3": "Release",
                "ans4": "Differ",
                "question_text": "Arrogrant:",
                "correct_ans": "Humble",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74831": {
                "ans1": "upon",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "with",
                "ans4": "on",
                "question_text": "Fate smiles ....... him in all his ventures.",
                "correct_ans": "upon",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72495": {
                "ans1": "Estimate",
                "ans2": "Notify",
                "ans3": "Attack",
                "ans4": "Invade",
                "question_text": "Appraise:",
                "correct_ans": "Estimate",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72185": {
                "ans1": "am not feeling",
                "ans2": "am not",
                "ans3": "did not feel",
                "ans4": "have not felt",
                "question_text": "I ...... well today.",
                "correct_ans": "am not",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74545": {
                "ans1": "for",
                "ans2": "of",
                "ans3": "from",
                "ans4": "by",
                "question_text": "He is born ........ rich parents.",
                "correct_ans": "of",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78577": {
                "ans1": "hypermania",
                "ans2": "monomia",
                "ans3": "paranoia",
                "ans4": "nostalgia",
                "question_text": "Mental disorder marked by fixed delusions.",
                "correct_ans": "paranoia",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73581": {
                "ans1": "hanged",
                "ans2": "hung",
                "ans3": "has hunged",
                "ans4": "will have hunged",
                "question_text": "He ........ the lamp on the wall.",
                "correct_ans": "hung",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74786": {
                "ans1": "to frighten away",
                "ans2": "to throw out",
                "ans3": "to behave in an unbecoming manner",
                "ans4": "to jeer at",
                "question_text": "To make one's flesh creep:",
                "correct_ans": "to frighten away",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70055": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'discrimination' has its primary stress on the ........ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "3rd",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73055": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "are",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "What ...... your politics?",
                "correct_ans": "are",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76530": {
                "ans1": "is working",
                "ans2": "has worked",
                "ans3": "works",
                "ans4": "will have worked",
                "question_text": "He ...... in the morning.",
                "correct_ans": "works",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77901": {
                "ans1": "by",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "on",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "You must complete the work__________2 O'clock.",
                "correct_ans": "by",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74723": {
                "ans1": "fail",
                "ans2": "to fail",
                "ans3": "failing",
                "ans4": "failed",
                "question_text": "I regret_______the exam.",
                "correct_ans": "failing",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70796": {
                "ans1": "submissive",
                "ans2": "proud",
                "ans3": "pompous",
                "ans4": "pompous",
                "question_text": "Rebellions:",
                "correct_ans": "submissive",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74336": {
                "ans1": "wash",
                "ans2": "washed",
                "ans3": "washing",
                "ans4": "to wash",
                "question_text": "She get him_______her clothes.",
                "correct_ans": "to wash",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76003": {
                "ans1": "two",
                "ans2": "three",
                "ans3": "four",
                "ans4": "five",
                "question_text": "The word \"knock\" has_______sounds.",
                "correct_ans": "three",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75774": {
                "ans1": "print",
                "ans2": "prints",
                "ans3": "printing",
                "ans4": "have printed",
                "question_text": "This is the only one of the local\u00a0papers\u00a0that _______\u00a0a weekly horoscope.",
                "correct_ans": "prints",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76411": {
                "ans1": "do you",
                "ans2": "do I",
                "ans3": "am I",
                "ans4": "aren't I",
                "question_text": "I don't think I am tall, ...?",
                "correct_ans": "am I",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78209": {
                "ans1": "free",
                "ans2": "punctual",
                "ans3": "even",
                "ans4": "calm",
                "question_text": "Erratic:",
                "correct_ans": "even",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71655": {
                "ans1": "is, his",
                "ans2": "are, their",
                "ans3": "is, their",
                "ans4": "are, his",
                "question_text": "Each man and boy______expected to meet obligation.",
                "correct_ans": "is, his",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79550": {
                "ans1": "had valued, valued",
                "ans2": "is valuing, values",
                "ans3": "has valued, values",
                "ans4": "valued, values",
                "question_text": "She______his friendship more than she____mine.",
                "correct_ans": "valued, values",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72450": {
                "ans1": "has, his",
                "ans2": "have, their",
                "ans3": "has, their",
                "ans4": "have, his",
                "question_text": "My best friend and adviser__________ charged ________ mind again.",
                "correct_ans": "has, his",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73427": {
                "ans1": "syllable",
                "ans2": "vowel",
                "ans3": "consonant",
                "ans4": "letter",
                "question_text": "Stress falls on a______of a word.",
                "correct_ans": "syllable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75041": {
                "ans1": "in",
                "ans2": "of",
                "ans3": "to",
                "ans4": "with",
                "question_text": "We are accustomed \u2026.. doing hard work.",
                "correct_ans": "to",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70579": {
                "ans1": "Detest",
                "ans2": "Assist",
                "ans3": "Futile",
                "ans4": "Shorten",
                "question_text": "Abhor:",
                "correct_ans": "Detest",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79338": {
                "ans1": "cheating",
                "ans2": "to cheat",
                "ans3": "being cheated",
                "ans4": "cheated",
                "question_text": "He felt \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. .",
                "correct_ans": "cheated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75824": {
                "ans1": "is,appearing",
                "ans2": "does ,appear",
                "ans3": "has ,appeared",
                "ans4": "was, appeared",
                "question_text": "Why \u2026\u2026 she \u2026.. so sad?",
                "correct_ans": "does ,appear",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73412": {
                "ans1": "It is 10 of the clock. ",
                "ans2": "It is 10 on the clock.",
                "ans3": " Both a and b",
                "ans4": " It is 10 over the clock.",
                "question_text": "It is 10 O\u2019clock means:",
                "correct_ans": "It is 10 of the clock. ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76516": {
                "ans1": "very",
                "ans2": "much",
                "ans3": "very much",
                "ans4": "many",
                "question_text": "She is \u2026\u2026.. slower than Reecha.",
                "correct_ans": "much",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77572": {
                "ans1": "To resort to fishing in stormy waters.",
                "ans2": "To pay in stormy waters",
                "ans3": "To remain in natural surroundings",
                "ans4": "To take intrest in anything.",
                "question_text": "To fish in troubled waters:",
                "correct_ans": "To take intrest in anything.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78060": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018discount\u2019 has its primary stress on the \u2026\u2026 syllable",
                "correct_ans": "2nd",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74463": {
                "ans1": "Mar",
                "ans2": "Discord",
                "ans3": "Amplify",
                "ans4": "Assent",
                "question_text": "Adorn:",
                "correct_ans": "Mar",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78661": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "will",
                "ans3": "shall",
                "ans4": "will be",
                "question_text": "The headquarters of the police \u2026.. in Kathmandu.\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "is",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70868": {
                "ans1": "Tom asked if she had arrived.",
                "ans2": "Tom asked whether she had been arrived.",
                "ans3": "Tom enquired if she had arrived.",
                "ans4": "Tom enquired of if she had been arrived",
                "question_text": "Tom said,\u201dHas she arrived?\u201d",
                "correct_ans": "Tom asked if she had arrived.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71045": {
                "ans1": "in,for",
                "ans2": "on,for",
                "ans3": "at,for",
                "ans4": "on,off",
                "question_text": "The house \u2026. Fire! Send \u2026. the fire brigade",
                "correct_ans": "on,for",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78239": {
                "ans1": "don't I",
                "ans2": "do I",
                "ans3": "haven't I",
                "ans4": "have I",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I have two brothers,__________?",
                "correct_ans": "don't I",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79430": {
                "ans1": " if more care",
                "ans2": "more care had been taken",
                "ans3": "had taken more care",
                "ans4": "had more care been taken",
                "question_text": "The agenda would have been accepted ........... in looking into the topics of the meeting.",
                "correct_ans": "more care had been taken",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74592": {
                "ans1": "On someone's game",
                "ans2": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "ans3": "Caught by someone",
                "ans4": "In a state of hopelessness",
                "question_text": "'On tenterhooks' means",
                "correct_ans": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78836": {
                "ans1": "complex sentence",
                "ans2": "Compound Sentence",
                "ans3": "Compound Complex",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "\"If I do not get this job, I will start a business.\" is ........",
                "correct_ans": "complex sentence",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72402": {
                "ans1": "quarter",
                "ans2": "nickel",
                "ans3": "dime",
                "ans4": "cent",
                "question_text": "one : penny :: five :_____",
                "correct_ans": "dime",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77282": {
                "ans1": "It is done.",
                "ans2": "It is being done.",
                "ans3": " It was done.",
                "ans4": "It has been done.",
                "question_text": "What is the passive of \"I did it\"?",
                "correct_ans": " It was done.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72089": {
                "ans1": "Hypocrite",
                "ans2": "Platonic",
                "ans3": "Stoic",
                "ans4": "Nihilist",
                "question_text": "What do you call A person who is indifferent to the pains and pleasures of life?",
                "correct_ans": "Stoic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71369": {
                "ans1": "upon",
                "ans2": "up",
                "ans3": "above",
                "ans4": "over",
                "question_text": "The bridge is ________the Bagmati river.",
                "correct_ans": "over",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76747": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'orderly' has stress on its _____ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72721": {
                "ans1": "were",
                "ans2": "is",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "The police ............... at the scene of the murder.",
                "correct_ans": "were",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70298": {
                "ans1": "of lifting the box",
                "ans2": "at lifting the box",
                "ans3": "with lifting the box",
                "ans4": "for lifting the box",
                "question_text": "She has the capacity ...........\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "of lifting the box",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71951": {
                "ans1": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "ans2": "a learner to use mental images",
                "ans3": "that a learner use mental images",
                "ans4": "that a learner used mental images",
                "question_text": "\u00a0It is the recommendation of many psychologists ............... to associate words and remember names.",
                "correct_ans": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75202": {
                "ans1": "Come tomorrow, when we will have a chat",
                "ans2": "I will call you when you reach there",
                "ans3": " I couldn't come for I was busy  ",
                "ans4": "None",
                "question_text": "Which of the sentences is a complex sentence?",
                "correct_ans": "I will call you when you reach there",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73515": {
                "ans1": "come",
                "ans2": "to come",
                "ans3": "having come",
                "ans4": "came",
                "question_text": "We saw him ______ out.",
                "correct_ans": "come",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73740": {
                "ans1": "a secret or hidden enemy",
                "ans2": "nor reliable person",
                "ans3": " very ferocious snake",
                "ans4": "unrecognizable danger",
                "question_text": "A snake in the grass:",
                "correct_ans": "unrecognizable danger",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78466": {
                "ans1": "Flying planes is dangerous",
                "ans2": "A flying plane is dangerous",
                "ans3": "I had some sleeping pills",
                "ans4": "I love eating chocolates",
                "question_text": "Which of the sentences has 'Present Participle'?",
                "correct_ans": "A flying plane is dangerous",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74759": {
                "ans1": "Adjunct+S+V+O",
                "ans2": "Adverbial+ V + S + O",
                "ans3": "O+S+Vd",
                "ans4": "S+V+O",
                "question_text": "Boys, did you have your book?",
                "correct_ans": "Adjunct+S+V+O",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71201": {
                "ans1": "It cost me ten thousand rupee.",
                "ans2": " It cost me ten thousand rupees.",
                "ans3": " It cost me ten thousands rupee.",
                "ans4": "It cost me ten thousands rupees.",
                "question_text": "Tick on the correct",
                "correct_ans": " It cost me ten thousand rupees.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70148": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "are",
                "ans3": "were",
                "ans4": "have",
                "question_text": "Much pains _____ being taken to maintain law and order.",
                "correct_ans": "is",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75665": {
                "ans1": " He informed me that everybody went against him",
                "ans2": "He informed me that everybody had gone against him",
                "ans3": "He had informed me that everybody had gone against him",
                "ans4": "He informed me that everybody to gone against him",
                "question_text": "Choose on the correct:",
                "correct_ans": " He informed me that everybody went against him",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70807": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "The word 'divinity' has its primary stress on the _____ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2nd",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78602": {
                "ans1": "over",
                "ans2": "on",
                "ans3": "for",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Let us spread cloth _ the table .",
                "correct_ans": "over",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71846": {
                "ans1": "right to vote",
                "ans2": "prohibited",
                "ans3": "disqalified",
                "ans4": "unqualified",
                "question_text": "Synonym of 'Franchise'",
                "correct_ans": "right to vote",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76714": {
                "ans1": "transient",
                "ans2": "glory",
                "ans3": "harmony",
                "ans4": "discord",
                "question_text": "Eternal:",
                "correct_ans": "transient",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71246": {
                "ans1": ";&,",
                "ans2": ",&;",
                "ans3": ";&!",
                "ans4": ",&,",
                "question_text": "It\u2019s too cold hot here () indeed () it\u2019s summer.",
                "correct_ans": ",&,",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76592": {
                "ans1": "for, on    ",
                "ans2": "of, on   ",
                "ans3": "of, in    ",
                "ans4": "for, in",
                "question_text": "Technology has been a subject \u2026\u2026. Discussion \u2026\u2026. Philosophy.",
                "correct_ans": "of, in    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79546": {
                "ans1": "/\u0261\u0259s\u026ap/  ",
                "ans2": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026ap/   ",
                "ans3": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026a:p/  ",
                "ans4": "/\u0261\u0259s\u026a:p/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word \u2018gossip\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "/\u0261\u0252s\u026ap/   ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71600": {
                "ans1": "greed",
                "ans2": "voracity",
                "ans3": "avarice ",
                "ans4": "generosity",
                "question_text": "The antonym of the word \u2018cupidity\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "generosity",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77805": {
                "ans1": "S+V+O+C       ",
                "ans2": "S+V+IO+DO  ",
                "ans3": "S+V+O+Adverbial  ",
                "ans4": "S+V+O",
                "question_text": "The sentence structure of \u2018She presented him a warm welcome.\u2019 Is",
                "correct_ans": "S+V+IO+DO  ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70307": {
                "ans1": "learned",
                "ans2": "won\u2019t learn     ",
                "ans3": "didn\u2019t learn    ",
                "ans4": "doesn\u2019t learn",
                "question_text": "If you \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026Physics and math at school, you would find engineering difficult to understand.",
                "correct_ans": "didn\u2019t learn    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75560": {
                "ans1": "This medicine is expensive.     ",
                "ans2": "This is not cheap.",
                "ans3": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "ans4": "This medicine is never cheap.",
                "question_text": "\u201cThis medicine is cheap.\u201d Transformation of this sentence to negative yields",
                "correct_ans": "This medicine is not expensive.     ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79147": {
                "ans1": "She said, \u201cOh! I am undone.\u201d       ",
                "ans2": "She said, \u201cAlas! I am undone.\u201d",
                "ans3": "She said, \u201cUgh! I am undone.\u201d     ",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "She exclaimed sorrowfully that she was undone. The direct form of this statement is",
                "correct_ans": "She said, \u201cAlas! I am undone.\u201d",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71807": {
                "ans1": "unerring",
                "ans2": "faulty",
                "ans3": "peccable",
                "ans4": "imperfect",
                "question_text": "The synonym of the word \u2018infallible\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "unerring",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71782": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018bolero\u2019 gets its primary stress on its \u2026\u2026\u2026syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73341": {
                "ans1": "Listen to the music.",
                "ans2": "They should listen to music.",
                "ans3": "They are listening music.",
                "ans4": "They listen to music.",
                "question_text": "The active form of \u201cMusic is listened to.\u201d Is",
                "correct_ans": "They listen to music.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74020": {
                "ans1": "comfortable around people",
                "ans2": "not comfortable around people",
                "ans3": "who solves problems through discussion    ",
                "ans4": "both (a) & (c)",
                "question_text": "An introvert person is",
                "correct_ans": "not comfortable around people",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71472": {
                "ans1": "pay",
                "ans2": "paid",
                "ans3": "had paid",
                "ans4": "should pay",
                "question_text": "If I ........... for it, I should have demanded a receipt.",
                "correct_ans": "had paid",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79469": {
                "ans1": "Get someone to break the box.",
                "ans2": "Breaking is being done to box.",
                "ans3": "The box has been broken.",
                "ans4": "Break the box.",
                "question_text": "Have the box broken ?",
                "correct_ans": "Get someone to break the box.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78064": {
                "ans1": "felt",
                "ans2": "to feel",
                "ans3": "had felt",
                "ans4": "feel",
                "question_text": "The death of Mr. Lama made us...............sorry.",
                "correct_ans": "feel",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71794": {
                "ans1": "ended",
                "ans2": "inquire",
                "ans3": "search",
                "ans4": "examine",
                "question_text": "The government put an end to the violence in the city.",
                "correct_ans": "ended",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78808": {
                "ans1": "do they",
                "ans2": "didn't they",
                "ans3": "did they",
                "ans4": "hadn't they",
                "question_text": "They used to swim often, ______?",
                "correct_ans": "didn't they",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75288": {
                "ans1": "to",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "with",
                "ans4": "by",
                "question_text": "I attribute my success _____ my parents and teachers.",
                "correct_ans": "to",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77220": {
                "ans1": "The dessert trolley featured several kinds of puddings",
                "ans2": "Bread and butter pudding, crumble and sticky toffee pudding.",
                "ans3": "The dessert trolley featured several kinds of puddings bread and butter pudding, crumble and sticky toffee pudding.",
                "ans4": "The dessert trolley featured several kinds of puddings, bread and butter pudding, crumble and sticky toffee pudding.",
                "question_text": "Choose the correct sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "Bread and butter pudding, crumble and sticky toffee pudding.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75268": {
                "ans1": "one ",
                "ans2": "two",
                "ans3": "three",
                "ans4": "four",
                "question_text": "The word \u201csolar\u201d is a \u2026........ syllabled word.",
                "correct_ans": "two",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78464": {
                "ans1": "want",
                "ans2": "wants",
                "ans3": "are wanting",
                "ans4": "have wanted",
                "question_text": "Her father, as well as I,.............. the support for the project.",
                "correct_ans": "wants",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76302": {
                "ans1": "honorable",
                "ans2": "horizontal",
                "ans3": "hunble",
                "ans4": "supine",
                "question_text": "Synonym of upright",
                "correct_ans": "honorable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78380": {
                "ans1": "each",
                "ans2": "any",
                "ans3": "nither",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "........... of them is brave and does not deserve an award.",
                "correct_ans": "none",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79452": {
                "ans1": "to disturb",
                "ans2": "disturbing",
                "ans3": "disturbed",
                "ans4": "disturb",
                "question_text": "I'm sorry............you. Could I speak to you for a moment.",
                "correct_ans": "to disturb",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79174": {
                "ans1": "she says she could not help me.",
                "ans2": "she says she can't help me.",
                "ans3": "she says she could not help you. ",
                "ans4": "she said she can't help me.",
                "question_text": "She say, 'I can't help you.' This sentence can be reported as",
                "correct_ans": "she says she can't help me.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71572": {
                "ans1": "one",
                "ans2": "one's",
                "ans3": "ones",
                "ans4": "once",
                "question_text": "Some good ____ are selected the competition.",
                "correct_ans": "ones",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76379": {
                "ans1": "stubborn",
                "ans2": "obduracy",
                "ans3": " barrage",
                "ans4": "complaint",
                "question_text": "The opposite meaning of the \"obdurate' is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "complaint",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74240": {
                "ans1": "commander-in-chief",
                "ans2": "commanders-in-chief",
                "ans3": "commander-in-chiefs",
                "ans4": "commanders-in-chiefs",
                "question_text": "They are ..........",
                "correct_ans": "commanders-in-chief",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74711": {
                "ans1": " This room needs painting.",
                "ans2": "This room needs to be painted.",
                "ans3": "This room wants to be painted.",
                "ans4": " I want this room to paint.",
                "question_text": "This room wants painting. The passive of this sentence is.",
                "correct_ans": "This room wants to be painted.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78557": {
                "ans1": "beg",
                "ans2": "begging",
                "ans3": "to beg",
                "ans4": "to begging",
                "question_text": "I am ready to live a simple life rather than_____.",
                "correct_ans": "beg",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70155": {
                "ans1": "friend has",
                "ans2": "friends have",
                "ans3": "friend have",
                "ans4": "friends has",
                "question_text": "One of my ___ bought a new car.",
                "correct_ans": "friends has",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70541": {
                "ans1": "has rained",
                "ans2": "is raining",
                "ans3": "rains",
                "ans4": "rained",
                "question_text": "Look! It ____ outside.",
                "correct_ans": "is raining",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78067": {
                "ans1": "complex",
                "ans2": "compound",
                "ans3": "simple",
                "ans4": "mixed",
                "question_text": "After the completion of his college he decided to go to his hometown to meet his parents and relatives. This is a _____sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "simple",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75816": {
                "ans1": "would collect",
                "ans2": "shall collect",
                "ans3": "would have collected",
                "ans4": "could have collected",
                "question_text": "If you have finished your exam, I ____ your papers.",
                "correct_ans": "shall collect",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72406": {
                "ans1": "short,shrill cry",
                "ans2": "unsuccessful",
                "ans3": "disappointing event",
                "ans4": "dis-witted",
                "question_text": "The correct meaning of the word 'a damp squib' is",
                "correct_ans": "disappointing event",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75732": {
                "ans1": "on",
                "ans2": "with",
                "ans3": "in",
                "ans4": "at",
                "question_text": "\u00a0The president conferred the title of Dirga Sewa Padak ..........\u00a0 him.",
                "correct_ans": "on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71890": {
                "ans1": "Humble",
                "ans2": "Appetite",
                "ans3": "Release",
                "ans4": "Differ",
                "question_text": "Arrogrant:",
                "correct_ans": "Humble",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71043": {
                "ans1": "upon",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "with",
                "ans4": "on",
                "question_text": "Fate smiles ....... him in all his ventures.",
                "correct_ans": "upon",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70707": {
                "ans1": "to frighten away",
                "ans2": "to throw out",
                "ans3": "to behave in an unbecoming manner",
                "ans4": "to jeer at",
                "question_text": "To make one's flesh creep:",
                "correct_ans": "to frighten away",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74140": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'discrimination' has its primary stress on the ........ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "3rd",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78751": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "are",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "What ...... your politics?",
                "correct_ans": "are",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76799": {
                "ans1": "am not feeling",
                "ans2": "am not",
                "ans3": "did not feel",
                "ans4": "have not felt",
                "question_text": "I ...... well today.",
                "correct_ans": "am not",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70002": {
                "ans1": "is working",
                "ans2": "has worked",
                "ans3": "works",
                "ans4": "will have worked",
                "question_text": "He ...... in the morning.",
                "correct_ans": "works",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76263": {
                "ans1": "Estimate",
                "ans2": "Notify",
                "ans3": "Attack",
                "ans4": "Invade",
                "question_text": "Appraise:",
                "correct_ans": "Estimate",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79099": {
                "ans1": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "ans2": "They wanted to know where the zoo was.",
                "ans3": "The asked where was the zoo.",
                "ans4": "The enquired where the zoo was.",
                "question_text": "The said,\"Where is the zoo?\"",
                "correct_ans": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70232": {
                "ans1": "hypermania",
                "ans2": "monomia",
                "ans3": "paranoia",
                "ans4": "nostalgia",
                "question_text": "Mental disorder marked by fixed delusions.",
                "correct_ans": "paranoia",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79405": {
                "ans1": "for",
                "ans2": "of",
                "ans3": "from",
                "ans4": "by",
                "question_text": "He is born ........ rich parents.",
                "correct_ans": "of",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78964": {
                "ans1": "hanged",
                "ans2": "hung",
                "ans3": "has hunged",
                "ans4": "will have hunged",
                "question_text": "He ........ the lamp on the wall.",
                "correct_ans": "hung",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72487": {
                "ans1": "It is done.",
                "ans2": "It is being done.",
                "ans3": " It was done.",
                "ans4": "It has been done.",
                "question_text": "What is the passive of \"I did it\"?",
                "correct_ans": " It was done.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76129": {
                "ans1": "On someone's game",
                "ans2": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "ans3": "Caught by someone",
                "ans4": "In a state of hopelessness",
                "question_text": "'On tenterhooks' means",
                "correct_ans": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72895": {
                "ans1": "were",
                "ans2": "is",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "The police ............... at the scene of the murder.",
                "correct_ans": "were",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71250": {
                "ans1": "of lifting the box",
                "ans2": "at lifting the box",
                "ans3": "with lifting the box",
                "ans4": "for lifting the box",
                "question_text": "She has the capacity ...........\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "of lifting the box",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71260": {
                "ans1": " if more care",
                "ans2": "more care had been taken",
                "ans3": "had taken more care",
                "ans4": "had more care been taken",
                "question_text": "The agenda would have been accepted ........... in looking into the topics of the meeting.",
                "correct_ans": "more care had been taken",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74732": {
                "ans1": "Hypocrite",
                "ans2": "Platonic",
                "ans3": "Stoic",
                "ans4": "Nihilist",
                "question_text": "What do you call A person who is indifferent to the pains and pleasures of life?",
                "correct_ans": "Stoic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79523": {
                "ans1": "don't I",
                "ans2": "do I",
                "ans3": "haven't I",
                "ans4": "have I",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I have two brothers,__________?",
                "correct_ans": "don't I",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79567": {
                "ans1": "complex sentence",
                "ans2": "Compound Sentence",
                "ans3": "Compound Complex",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "\"If I do not get this job, I will start a business.\" is ........",
                "correct_ans": "complex sentence",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74451": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'orderly' has stress on its _____ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76029": {
                "ans1": "upon",
                "ans2": "up",
                "ans3": "above",
                "ans4": "over",
                "question_text": "The bridge is ________the Bagmati river.",
                "correct_ans": "over",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70377": {
                "ans1": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "ans2": "a learner to use mental images",
                "ans3": "that a learner use mental images",
                "ans4": "that a learner used mental images",
                "question_text": "\u00a0It is the recommendation of many psychologists ............... to associate words and remember names.",
                "correct_ans": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72393": {
                "ans1": "quarter",
                "ans2": "nickel",
                "ans3": "dime",
                "ans4": "cent",
                "question_text": "one : penny :: five :_____",
                "correct_ans": "dime",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74430": {
                "ans1": "has, his",
                "ans2": "have, their",
                "ans3": "has, their",
                "ans4": "have, his",
                "question_text": "My best friend and adviser__________ charged ________ mind again.",
                "correct_ans": "has, his",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75814": {
                "ans1": "syllable",
                "ans2": "vowel",
                "ans3": "consonant",
                "ans4": "letter",
                "question_text": "Stress falls on a______of a word.",
                "correct_ans": "syllable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74818": {
                "ans1": "print",
                "ans2": "prints",
                "ans3": "printing",
                "ans4": "have printed",
                "question_text": "This is the only one of the local\u00a0papers\u00a0that _______\u00a0a weekly horoscope.",
                "correct_ans": "prints",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70749": {
                "ans1": "by",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "on",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "You must complete the work__________2 O'clock.",
                "correct_ans": "by",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78061": {
                "ans1": "free",
                "ans2": "punctual",
                "ans3": "even",
                "ans4": "calm",
                "question_text": "Erratic:",
                "correct_ans": "even",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74498": {
                "ans1": "submissive",
                "ans2": "proud",
                "ans3": "pompous",
                "ans4": "pompous",
                "question_text": "Rebellions:",
                "correct_ans": "submissive",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78742": {
                "ans1": "wash",
                "ans2": "washed",
                "ans3": "washing",
                "ans4": "to wash",
                "question_text": "She get him_______her clothes.",
                "correct_ans": "to wash",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79591": {
                "ans1": "fail",
                "ans2": "to fail",
                "ans3": "failing",
                "ans4": "failed",
                "question_text": "I regret_______the exam.",
                "correct_ans": "failing",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72597": {
                "ans1": "two",
                "ans2": "three",
                "ans3": "four",
                "ans4": "five",
                "question_text": "The word \"knock\" has_______sounds.",
                "correct_ans": "three",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72767": {
                "ans1": "do you",
                "ans2": "do I",
                "ans3": "am I",
                "ans4": "aren't I",
                "question_text": "I don't think I am tall, ...?",
                "correct_ans": "am I",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75589": {
                "ans1": "had valued, valued",
                "ans2": "is valuing, values",
                "ans3": "has valued, values",
                "ans4": "valued, values",
                "question_text": "She______his friendship more than she____mine.",
                "correct_ans": "valued, values",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76824": {
                "ans1": "is, his",
                "ans2": "are, their",
                "ans3": "is, their",
                "ans4": "are, his",
                "question_text": "Each man and boy______expected to meet obligation.",
                "correct_ans": "is, his",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73802": {
                "ans1": "tells",
                "ans2": "was telling",
                "ans3": "told",
                "ans4": "had been telling",
                "question_text": "Mohan .............. me all about this.",
                "correct_ans": "told",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77063": {
                "ans1": "opponent",
                "ans2": "helper",
                "ans3": "prayer",
                "ans4": "worker",
                "question_text": "The synonym of adversary is ................",
                "correct_ans": "opponent",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73215": {
                "ans1": "He told good buy to all the friends.",
                "ans2": "He exclaimed good bye to all the friends",
                "ans3": "He bade good bye to all the friends.",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is acceptable?",
                "correct_ans": "He bade good bye to all the friends.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70158": {
                "ans1": "illicit",
                "ans2": "eliminated",
                "ans3": "elicited",
                "ans4": "illegitimate",
                "question_text": "During the interrogation of the criminal important information was ................",
                "correct_ans": "elicited",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74106": {
                "ans1": "your",
                "ans2": "his",
                "ans3": "their",
                "ans4": "our",
                "question_text": "You and he did not do ................ duties well.",
                "correct_ans": "your",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78022": {
                "ans1": "with",
                "ans2": "by",
                "ans3": "for",
                "ans4": "in",
                "question_text": "He is just now occupied .................... translating some documents.",
                "correct_ans": "with",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75343": {
                "ans1": "Her court was pure ; her life serene.",
                "ans2": "If he comes to me , I will help him.",
                "ans3": "I don't think he will come.",
                "ans4": "All of these",
                "question_text": "Tick on the compount sentence",
                "correct_ans": "Her court was pure ; her life serene.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71240": {
                "ans1": "/ho\u03c5m/",
                "ans2": "/h\u2202\u03c5m/",
                "ans3": "/h\u03c5m/",
                "ans4": "/h\u2228\u03c5m/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word\u00a0 'home' is .........................",
                "correct_ans": "/ho\u03c5m/",
                "explanation": "/h\\lor\\upsilon m/",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73052": {
                "ans1": "I am surprised at the result.",
                "ans2": "I am surprised to the result.",
                "ans3": "I am surprised with the result.",
                "ans4": "None of these.",
                "question_text": "The passive voice of - ' The result surprises me\u00a0 ' is ...............................................",
                "correct_ans": "I am surprised at the result.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76116": {
                "ans1": "make",
                "ans2": "has made",
                "ans3": "have made",
                "ans4": "are making",
                "question_text": "My feelings .............. it difficult to speak .",
                "correct_ans": "make",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73579": {
                "ans1": "commanding",
                "ans2": "command",
                "ans3": "to command",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "He waas more willing to obey than ...............",
                "correct_ans": "command",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73429": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "The word - 'Friction' has its primary stress on .......... syllable?",
                "correct_ans": "1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73293": {
                "ans1": "from",
                "ans2": "with",
                "ans3": "to ",
                "ans4": "for",
                "question_text": "I parted ............. my friends.",
                "correct_ans": "with",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75893": {
                "ans1": "worring",
                "ans2": "to worry",
                "ans3": "worried",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "They seemed............",
                "correct_ans": "worried",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71239": {
                "ans1": "read",
                "ans2": "to read",
                "ans3": "being read",
                "ans4": "reading",
                "question_text": "He wanrs me ............... that book.",
                "correct_ans": "to read",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72124": {
                "ans1": "but",
                "ans2": "son",
                "ans3": "sun ",
                "ans4": "fur",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is different in middle sound?",
                "correct_ans": "fur",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73969": {
                "ans1": "metrelogy",
                "ans2": "analogy",
                "ans3": "doxology",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "A hymn , praising God is called................",
                "correct_ans": "doxology",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73889": {
                "ans1": "for",
                "ans2": "to",
                "ans3": "of",
                "ans4": "off",
                "question_text": "Ram use a slave .............. drink.",
                "correct_ans": "to",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79827": {
                "ans1": "The room was felt moving.",
                "ans2": "The room was felt move.",
                "ans3": "The room was felt to be moved.",
                "ans4": "The room was felt to move.",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is acceptable?",
                "correct_ans": "The room was felt to move.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72607": {
                "ans1": "know the secret",
                "ans2": "be ware of the tric",
                "ans3": "know the antecedents",
                "ans4": "learn the aim",
                "question_text": "Nobody could see through the design of that willy fellow.",
                "correct_ans": "be ware of the tric",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74805": {
                "ans1": "first",
                "ans2": "second",
                "ans3": "third",
                "ans4": "fourth",
                "question_text": "In the word 'fraction' the primary stress fall on the ............ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "first",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70187": {
                "ans1": "for ",
                "ans2": "about",
                "ans3": "in ",
                "ans4": "on",
                "question_text": "The doctor should wait ........... the patient.",
                "correct_ans": "on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76390": {
                "ans1": "are",
                "ans2": "were",
                "ans3": "have been",
                "ans4": "was",
                "question_text": "Many a boy ...... present.",
                "correct_ans": "was",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73611": {
                "ans1": "s+V+N/pronoun + present participle",
                "ans2": "S+vt+N/pronoun + gerund",
                "ans3": "s+vt+N/pronoun + participle",
                "ans4": "none of these",
                "question_text": "The structure for - \"We saw the thief running away\" is ...................",
                "correct_ans": "s+V+N/pronoun + present participle",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74190": {
                "ans1": "It is done.",
                "ans2": "It is being done.",
                "ans3": " It was done.",
                "ans4": "It has been done.",
                "question_text": "What is the passive of \"I did it\"?",
                "correct_ans": " It was done.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70286": {
                "ans1": "On someone's game",
                "ans2": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "ans3": "Caught by someone",
                "ans4": "In a state of hopelessness",
                "question_text": "'On tenterhooks' means",
                "correct_ans": " In a state of suspense and anxiety",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76722": {
                "ans1": "were",
                "ans2": "is",
                "ans3": "was",
                "ans4": "has been",
                "question_text": "The police ............... at the scene of the murder.",
                "correct_ans": "were",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72001": {
                "ans1": "of lifting the box",
                "ans2": "at lifting the box",
                "ans3": "with lifting the box",
                "ans4": "for lifting the box",
                "question_text": "She has the capacity ...........\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "of lifting the box",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75008": {
                "ans1": " if more care",
                "ans2": "more care had been taken",
                "ans3": "had taken more care",
                "ans4": "had more care been taken",
                "question_text": "The agenda would have been accepted ........... in looking into the topics of the meeting.",
                "correct_ans": "more care had been taken",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70227": {
                "ans1": "Hypocrite",
                "ans2": "Platonic",
                "ans3": "Stoic",
                "ans4": "Nihilist",
                "question_text": "What do you call A person who is indifferent to the pains and pleasures of life?",
                "correct_ans": "Stoic",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74564": {
                "ans1": "don't I",
                "ans2": "do I",
                "ans3": "haven't I",
                "ans4": "have I",
                "question_text": "\u00a0I have two brothers,__________?",
                "correct_ans": "don't I",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77183": {
                "ans1": "complex sentence",
                "ans2": "Compound Sentence",
                "ans3": "Compound Complex",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "\"If I do not get this job, I will start a business.\" is ........",
                "correct_ans": "complex sentence",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74909": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'orderly' has stress on its _____ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "1st",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79734": {
                "ans1": "upon",
                "ans2": "up",
                "ans3": "above",
                "ans4": "over",
                "question_text": "The bridge is ________the Bagmati river.",
                "correct_ans": "over",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72354": {
                "ans1": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "ans2": "a learner to use mental images",
                "ans3": "that a learner use mental images",
                "ans4": "that a learner used mental images",
                "question_text": "\u00a0It is the recommendation of many psychologists ............... to associate words and remember names.",
                "correct_ans": "that a learner uses mental images",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75095": {
                "ans1": "quarter",
                "ans2": "nickel",
                "ans3": "dime",
                "ans4": "cent",
                "question_text": "one : penny :: five :_____",
                "correct_ans": "dime",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72078": {
                "ans1": "Had valued, valued",
                "ans2": "is valuing, values",
                "ans3": "has valued, values",
                "ans4": "valued, values",
                "question_text": "She______ his friendship more than she ____ mine.",
                "correct_ans": "valued, values",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78776": {
                "ans1": "shall pass",
                "ans2": "may pass",
                "ans3": "will pass",
                "ans4": "could pass",
                "question_text": "She wrote so well that she \u2026\u2026\u2026. the exam.",
                "correct_ans": "could pass",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70529": {
                "ans1": "Noun ",
                "ans2": "verb",
                "ans3": "adverb",
                "ans4": "adjective",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018deceptive\u2019 functions as a/an \u2026\u2026\u2026..",
                "correct_ans": "adjective",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77562": {
                "ans1": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "ans2": "They wanted to know where the zoo was.",
                "ans3": "They asked where the zoo is.",
                "ans4": "The inquired where the zoo is.",
                "question_text": "They said,\u201d Where is the zoo?\u201d",
                "correct_ans": "They asked where the zoo was.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75831": {
                "ans1": "is thinking ",
                "ans2": "think",
                "ans3": "through",
                "ans4": "thinks",
                "question_text": "He \u2026\u2026 that the law may be changed.",
                "correct_ans": "thinks",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79596": {
                "ans1": "Human",
                "ans2": "minute",
                "ans3": "faituge",
                "ans4": "water",
                "question_text": "Which of the following word gets stress in its first syllable?",
                "correct_ans": "water",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72892": {
                "ans1": "Ram received a pen; Hari ,a pencil",
                "ans2": "He has been to England ,France ,Germany & Sweden",
                "ans3": "We should be devoted and humble, cheerful and serene",
                "ans4": "What a terrible mistake this is!",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is incorrectly punctuated?",
                "correct_ans": "He has been to England ,France ,Germany & Sweden",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79331": {
                "ans1": "A buried city is excavated by the workers.",
                "ans2": "A buried city is being excavated by the workers.",
                "ans3": "A buried city was being excavated by the workers.",
                "ans4": "A buried city are being excavated by the workers.",
                "question_text": "The workers are excavating a buried city.",
                "correct_ans": "A buried city is excavated by the workers.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78831": {
                "ans1": "Liked",
                "ans2": "likes",
                "ans3": "like",
                "ans4": "had liked",
                "question_text": "She liked him more than she \u2026\u2026.. her friend.",
                "correct_ans": "likes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78615": {
                "ans1": " Insite of his luck, he did not win the award.",
                "ans2": "You can go home or go with him to the library.",
                "ans3": " I said that I could do it.",
                "ans4": " She goes to collage every day.",
                "question_text": "Which is a compound sentence?",
                "correct_ans": "You can go home or go with him to the library.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73617": {
                "ans1": "Liberate",
                "ans2": "emancipate",
                "ans3": "free ",
                "ans4": "confine",
                "question_text": "Release",
                "correct_ans": "confine",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70735": {
                "ans1": "at, for ",
                "ans2": "in, in",
                "ans3": "to, for ",
                "ans4": "by, for",
                "question_text": "I am grateful \u2026\u2026\u2026. You \u2026\u2026.. your help.",
                "correct_ans": "to, for ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73399": {
                "ans1": "rise",
                "ans2": "rice",
                "ans3": "raise",
                "ans4": "risk",
                "question_text": "Choose the appropriate option 'ra\u026as' is the phonetic transcription of -",
                "correct_ans": "rice",
                "explanation": "International Phonetic Alphabet (IPA): An alphabet used to accurately represent the pronunciation of languages. IPA helps in improving language pronunciation and feeling more confident speaking in the language.Phonetic Symbols: These symbols are used to describe the phonemes (sounds).Phonetic transcription of some words:-Rise: /r\u028c\u026az/Rice: /ra\u026as/Raise: /re\u026az/Risk: /r\u026ask/Hence, /ra\u026as/ is the phonetic transcription of the word 'rice'.",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76010": {
                "ans1": "Adjunct + S + V +O",
                "ans2": "Adverbial + V + S + O",
                "ans3": "O + S + V",
                "ans4": "S + V + O",
                "question_text": "Boys, did you have your book?",
                "correct_ans": "Adjunct + S + V +O",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71399": {
                "ans1": "makes",
                "ans2": "has made",
                "ans3": "made",
                "ans4": "has to make",
                "question_text": "She________ a living by teaching.",
                "correct_ans": "makes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77082": {
                "ans1": "with",
                "ans2": "by",
                "ans3": "at",
                "ans4": "for",
                "question_text": "Twenty divided_________five is equal to four.",
                "correct_ans": "at",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74222": {
                "ans1": "intensity",
                "ans2": "opulence",
                "ans3": "comfound",
                "ans4": "alertness",
                "question_text": "Alacrity:",
                "correct_ans": "alertness",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76192": {
                "ans1": "in",
                "ans2": "at",
                "ans3": "through",
                "ans4": "for",
                "question_text": "He failed but his brother got_________.",
                "correct_ans": "through",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73198": {
                "ans1": "reveal",
                "ans2": "destroy",
                "ans3": "callous",
                "ans4": "derogatory",
                "question_text": "Clandestine:",
                "correct_ans": "derogatory",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75763": {
                "ans1": "make",
                "ans2": "makes",
                "ans3": "both (a) & (b)",
                "ans4": "had made",
                "question_text": "Five and Five_______ten.",
                "correct_ans": "make",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76028": {
                "ans1": "1st",
                "ans2": "2nd",
                "ans3": "3rd",
                "ans4": "4th",
                "question_text": "The word 'Incorrigible' has its primary stress on the_______ syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "2nd",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71302": {
                "ans1": "He informed me that everybody went against him.",
                "ans2": "He informed me that everybody had gone against him.",
                "ans3": "He had informed me that everybody had gone against him.",
                "ans4": "He informed me that everybody to gone against him.",
                "question_text": "Choose on the correct:",
                "correct_ans": "He informed me that everybody had gone against him.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79420": {
                "ans1": "simple",
                "ans2": "complex",
                "ans3": "compound",
                "ans4": "compound-complex",
                "question_text": "\"John, who is wearing sun glasses, is my relative.\" This is a ______ sentence.",
                "correct_ans": "compound",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73312": {
                "ans1": "to act in a childish way",
                "ans2": "acting in a foolish way",
                "ans3": "to have desired unbacked by effort",
                "ans4": "anything which eludes or deceive",
                "question_text": "Will-o'-the-wisp:",
                "correct_ans": "anything which eludes or deceive",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72778": {
                "ans1": "a",
                "ans2": "an",
                "ans3": "the",
                "ans4": "none",
                "question_text": "He has climbed ____ Mt. Everest three times.",
                "correct_ans": "none",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70069": {
                "ans1": "didn\u2019t they",
                "ans2": "do they",
                "ans3": "did they",
                "ans4": "can they",
                "question_text": "Barking dogs seldom bite, ........?",
                "correct_ans": "do they",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76534": {
                "ans1": "invasion",
                "ans2": "contribution",
                "ans3": "motion",
                "ans4": "precious",
                "question_text": "Which of the following does not have\u00a0/\u0283/\u00a0sound?",
                "correct_ans": "invasion",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78727": {
                "ans1": "to do",
                "ans2": "do",
                "ans3": "did",
                "ans4": " doing",
                "question_text": "She got me _____ her homework.",
                "correct_ans": "to do",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70115": {
                "ans1": "earthquake",
                "ans2": "storm",
                "ans3": "flood",
                "ans4": "down pour",
                "question_text": "If breeze is to cyclone in the same way as drizzle is to .....",
                "correct_ans": "down pour",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79484": {
                "ans1": "cloth",
                "ans2": "clothing",
                "ans3": "cloths",
                "ans4": "clothes",
                "question_text": "The ____has been used to dust the furniture.",
                "correct_ans": "cloths",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72770": {
                "ans1": "A building complex is being built by them.",
                "ans2": "A building complex is going to be built.",
                "ans3": "They are going to be building a building complex.",
                "ans4": "A building complex will be built by them.",
                "question_text": "They are going to build a building complex.",
                "correct_ans": "A building complex is going to be built.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "71830": {
                "ans1": "liked",
                "ans2": "likes",
                "ans3": "like",
                "ans4": "had liked",
                "question_text": "She liked him more than she ______ her friend.",
                "correct_ans": "likes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73683": {
                "ans1": "All nasals are uttered by making use of soft palate and back of the tongue",
                "ans2": "All nasals occur in all positions in English words",
                "ans3": "/\u014b/ is uttered by making use of the same speech organs as /k/",
                "ans4": "While uttering nasals, air passes through the mouth",
                "question_text": "Tick the best option",
                "correct_ans": "All nasals are uttered by making use of soft palate and back of the tongue",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77596": {
                "ans1": "shall we",
                "ans2": "could we",
                "ans3": "can we",
                "ans4": "would we",
                "question_text": "Let us go, ........?",
                "correct_ans": "can we",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77190": {
                "ans1": "the occupants\u2019 getting",
                "ans2": "them getting",
                "ans3": "the occupants\u2019 get",
                "ans4": "the occupants\u2019 to get",
                "question_text": "After the fire had been put out the firefighters recommended ....... an alarm device.",
                "correct_ans": "the occupants\u2019 getting",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70094": {
                "ans1": "intent to",
                "ans2": "intent on",
                "ans3": "intent at",
                "ans4": "intent with",
                "question_text": "She is ....... doing the job.",
                "correct_ans": "intent on",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72615": {
                "ans1": "will have read",
                "ans2": "will be reading",
                "ans3": "had been reading",
                "ans4": "shall read",
                "question_text": "She ______ this novel the by tomorrow.",
                "correct_ans": "will have read",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74597": {
                "ans1": "relevant",
                "ans2": "load",
                "ans3": "correct",
                "ans4": "conception",
                "question_text": "The prefix mis\u2013 can be used with",
                "correct_ans": "conception",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79989": {
                "ans1": "is participating",
                "ans2": "was participating",
                "ans3": "have participated",
                "ans4": "has participated",
                "question_text": "She is one of the women who \u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013 in the concert.",
                "correct_ans": "have participated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77795": {
                "ans1": "laying",
                "ans2": "lying",
                "ans3": "lain",
                "ans4": "lie",
                "question_text": "The purse was ........ on the way.",
                "correct_ans": "lying",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75064": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "are",
                "ans3": "have been",
                "ans4": "is been",
                "question_text": "Phonetics \u2026\u2026\u2026 difficult to understand.",
                "correct_ans": "is",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73307": {
                "ans1": ".",
                "ans2": "-",
                "ans3": ":",
                "ans4": ",",
                "question_text": "Ram told Sita () \u201cPlease, listen to me\u201d.",
                "correct_ans": ",",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78514": {
                "ans1": "at, near",
                "ans2": "on, by",
                "ans3": "on, beside\t",
                "ans4": "in, near",
                "question_text": "He sat \u2026\u2026.. the armchair \u2026\u2026. the door.",
                "correct_ans": "in, near",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70154": {
                "ans1": "S+V+O+C",
                "ans2": "S+V+IO+DO",
                "ans3": "S+V+O+ Adverbial",
                "ans4": "S+V+O+C",
                "question_text": "The sentence structure of \u2018I am doing my homework, however .\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "S+V+O+ Adverbial",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77429": {
                "ans1": "Cloud",
                "ans2": "grass",
                "ans3": "maiden",
                "ans4": "silver",
                "question_text": "Which of the following word doesn\u2019t take \u2018y\u2019 suffix when transformed into adjective?",
                "correct_ans": "maiden",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72339": {
                "ans1": "1",
                "ans2": "2",
                "ans3": "3",
                "ans4": "4",
                "question_text": "The word \u2018advantageous\u2019 gets its primary stress on its \u2026\u2026\u2026.. syllable.",
                "correct_ans": "3",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72833": {
                "ans1": "These fruits had been good for health.",
                "ans2": "These fruits are said to be good for health.",
                "ans3": "These fruits were said good for health.",
                "ans4": "These fruits were been said good for health.",
                "question_text": "The passive voice of \u201cThey say these fruits are good for health. \u201d is",
                "correct_ans": "These fruits are said to be good for health.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76457": {
                "ans1": "These fruits had been good for health.",
                "ans2": "These fruits are said to be good for health.",
                "ans3": "These fruits were said good for health.",
                "ans4": "These fruits were been said good for health.",
                "question_text": "The passive voice of \u201cThey say these fruits are good for health. \u201d is",
                "correct_ans": "These fruits are said to be good for health.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74700": {
                "ans1": "Renounce",
                "ans2": "adherent",
                "ans3": "culprit\t",
                "ans4": "famous",
                "question_text": "The synonym of the word \u2018abandon\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "Renounce",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78848": {
                "ans1": "/l\u0259l/     ",
                "ans2": "/l\u026a\u0259l/    ",
                "ans3": "/l\u0259\u026a\u0259l/    ",
                "ans4": "/l\u0259\u026a\u0259/",
                "question_text": "The phonemic transcription of the word \u2018loyal\u2019 is",
                "correct_ans": "/l\u0259\u026a\u0259l/    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77038": {
                "ans1": "She said that she had to work hard.",
                "ans2": "She said she might to work hard.",
                "ans3": "She said that she must have to work hard.",
                "ans4": "She said that she may work hard.",
                "question_text": "She said, \u201cI must work hard.\u201d Its indirect speech is",
                "correct_ans": "She said that she had to work hard.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78231": {
                "ans1": "had had",
                "ans2": "had",
                "ans3": "have taken",
                "ans4": "would have",
                "question_text": "If we \u2026\u2026\u2026. a camera, he would have taken the photographs.",
                "correct_ans": "had had",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77211": {
                "ans1": "shall do ",
                "ans2": "was doing",
                "ans3": "will do ",
                "ans4": "am doing",
                "question_text": "She\u2026\u2026\u2026. her work when the bell rang.",
                "correct_ans": "was doing",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73649": {
                "ans1": "was watching",
                "ans2": "watched",
                "ans3": "had watched",
                "ans4": "an watching",
                "question_text": "I went to bed after I \u2026\u2026\u2026. Television.",
                "correct_ans": "had watched",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74081": {
                "ans1": "He said to bring his book",
                "ans2": "He told ram to bring your book",
                "ans3": "He told Ram to bring his book",
                "ans4": "He told Ram not to bring his book",
                "question_text": "He said,\u201dBring your book Ram.\u201d",
                "correct_ans": "He told Ram to bring his book",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74815": {
                "ans1": "to arrest",
                "ans2": "arrest",
                "ans3": "arresting",
                "ans4": "all of these",
                "question_text": "Mary got her husband \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.(arrest).",
                "correct_ans": "to arrest",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72704": {
                "ans1": "Comb",
                "ans2": "Thumb",
                "ans3": "some",
                "ans4": "all of the above",
                "question_text": "Locate the word with /m/ sound in the final position.",
                "correct_ans": "Comb",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77837": {
                "ans1": "Thicken",
                "ans2": "impoverish",
                "ans3": "mercantile",
                "ans4": "mercy",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is a noun?",
                "correct_ans": "mercy",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72338": {
                "ans1": "About",
                "ans2": "over",
                "ans3": "in",
                "ans4": "on",
                "question_text": "The lady takes pride \u2026\u2026\u2026. Her beauty.",
                "correct_ans": "in",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70359": {
                "ans1": "effective; dedicated; and honest",
                "ans2": "effective, dedicated; and honest",
                "ans3": "effective, dedicated and honest",
                "ans4": "effective, dedicated, and honest",
                "question_text": "Which sentence is correctly punctuated?The company needs \u2026\u2026\u2026 employees.",
                "correct_ans": "effective, dedicated and honest",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75368": {
                "ans1": "He works the whole day through.",
                "ans2": "It is a known fact that the earth rotates around its axis",
                "ans3": "Besides completed the work he also corrected it.",
                "ans4": "In spite of the weather, she went out",
                "question_text": "Which of the following is a compound sentence?",
                "correct_ans": "Besides completed the work he also corrected it.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72783": {
                "ans1": "The students suggested playing",
                "ans2": "The students requested him to let them play.",
                "ans3": "The students requested his to let us play.",
                "ans4": "The students requested him to play.",
                "question_text": "The students said,\u201dLet us play Sir.\u201d",
                "correct_ans": "The students requested him to let them play.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "78289": {
                "ans1": "King",
                "ans2": "Nany",
                "ans3": "mine",
                "ans4": "crown",
                "question_text": "Identify the odd option in case of nasal sound .",
                "correct_ans": "mine",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75249": {
                "ans1": "Swimming is a good form of exercise.",
                "ans2": "They are walking on the lawn.",
                "ans3": "He likes smoking .",
                "ans4": "She is taking knitting classes .",
                "question_text": "Which of the underlined word is an adjective?",
                "correct_ans": "She is taking knitting classes .",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75429": {
                "ans1": "He was seen conducting the rehearsal.",
                "ans2": "I saw the rehearsal being conducted.",
                "ans3": "I conducting the rehearsal saw him.",
                "ans4": "The rehearsal was being conducted.",
                "question_text": "I saw him conducting the rehearsal.",
                "correct_ans": "He was seen conducting the rehearsal.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72004": {
                "ans1": "staff",
                "ans2": "clergy",
                "ans3": "audience",
                "ans4": "organization",
                "question_text": "Which noun is plural?",
                "correct_ans": "clergy",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79515": {
                "ans1": "with",
                "ans2": "by",
                "ans3": "on",
                "ans4": "to",
                "question_text": "I prefer tea ........ coffee.",
                "correct_ans": "to",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "70146": {
                "ans1": "ornithology",
                "ans2": "orology",
                "ans3": "philology",
                "ans4": "philanthropy",
                "question_text": "The study of birds",
                "correct_ans": "ornithology",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "75595": {
                "ans1": "need",
                "ans2": "needs",
                "ans3": "is needing",
                "ans4": "has needed",
                "question_text": "The blind ______jobs.",
                "correct_ans": "need",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "72139": {
                "ans1": "is",
                "ans2": "are",
                "ans3": "have",
                "ans4": "were",
                "question_text": "It is one of the best books that \u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013 highly demanded.",
                "correct_ans": "are",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "77089": {
                "ans1": "it\u2019s",
                "ans2": "their",
                "ans3": "it",
                "ans4": "its",
                "question_text": "Wine tends to lose ______flavour when it has not been properly sealed.",
                "correct_ans": "its",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "76874": {
                "ans1": "hasn\u2019t neither",
                "ans2": "hasn\u2019t either",
                "ans3": "neither hasn\u2019t",
                "ans4": "either hasn\u2019t",
                "question_text": "Ram and Sita have not completed the job yet and Radha ........",
                "correct_ans": "hasn\u2019t either",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79327": {
                "ans1": "touches",
                "ans2": "touch",
                "ans3": "touching",
                "ans4": "to touch",
                "question_text": "She suddenly felt something \u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013 her on the shoulder.",
                "correct_ans": "touch",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "74135": {
                "ans1": "can he",
                "ans2": "will he",
                "ans3": "can't he",
                "ans4": "is he",
                "question_text": "He can swim, ........?",
                "correct_ans": "can't he",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "73884": {
                "ans1": "see on",
                "ans2": "see off",
                "ans3": "see about",
                "ans4": "see into",
                "question_text": "We planned to\u00a0consider\u00a0the proposal.",
                "correct_ans": "see about",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "79903": {
                "ans1": "was, him",
                "ans2": "were, him",
                "ans3": "was, them",
                "ans4": "were, them",
                "question_text": "Either of the students \u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013 given an award which pleased \u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013\u2013 very much.",
                "correct_ans": "was, them",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        },
        "2": {
            "88596": {
                "ans1": "objective of the welding ",
                "ans2": "importance of flux in welding",
                "ans3": "different types of welding",
                "ans4": "process of pressure welding",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.Moreover the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the center of the weld.The best suitable title of this text is:",
                "correct_ans": "process of pressure welding",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82608": {
                "ans1": "The metal looks like plastics",
                "ans2": "The metal is converted into plastics",
                "ans3": "The metal can be molded into shapes",
                "ans4": "The metal behaves like plastics",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld. The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.The metal becomes plastics, means",
                "correct_ans": "The metal can be molded into shapes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81785": {
                "ans1": "welding temperature of iron",
                "ans2": "taking care for surface",
                "ans3": "oxidation of metal in high temperature",
                "ans4": "use of different types of weld",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.Moreover, the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the center of the weld.One statement of advice is made for",
                "correct_ans": "welding temperature of iron",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85080": {
                "ans1": "another method of weld",
                "ans2": "methods of joining metals",
                "ans3": "welding steel",
                "ans4": "importance of welding",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt well weaken the weld.Moreover the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the centre of the weld.What might be the topic of the following paragraph?\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "another method of weld",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80904": {
                "ans1": "move up and down",
                "ans2": "move from side to side ",
                "ans3": "move backward and forward",
                "ans4": "move round and round",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the follow:The lathe is one of the earliest examples of questions that machine tool. It consists of following parts a bed or framework- which carries the diff. components. The accuracy of machine is dependent on the rigidity of this bed. A 'head stock' for holding the work. This headstock and of course the work are rotated by a motor. Nowadays this is usually an electric motor.'rotate' means",
                "correct_ans": "move round and round",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81858": {
                "ans1": "lathe",
                "ans2": "bed",
                "ans3": "headstock",
                "ans4": "all",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the follow:The lathe is one of the earliest examples of questions that machine tool. It consists of following parts a bed or framework- which carries the diff. components. The accuracy of machine is dependent on the rigidity of this bed. A 'head stock' for holding the work. This headstock and of course the work are rotated by a motor. Nowadays this is usually an electric motor.What is used as electric motor?",
                "correct_ans": "headstock",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85929": {
                "ans1": "instructive ",
                "ans2": "narrative",
                "ans3": "informative",
                "ans4": "expository",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the follow:The lathe is one of the earliest examples of questions that machine tool. It consists of following parts a bed or framework- which carries the diff. components. The accuracy of machine is dependent on the rigidity of this bed. A 'head stock' for holding the work. This headstock and of course the work are rotated by a motor. Nowadays this is usually an electric motor.This passage is\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "informative",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85715": {
                "ans1": "consists",
                "ans2": "part",
                "ans3": "objects",
                "ans4": "framework",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the follow:The lathe is one of the earliest examples of questions that machine tool. It consists of following parts a bed or framework- which carries the diff. components. The accuracy of machine is dependent on the rigidity of this bed. A 'head stock' for holding the work. This headstock and of course the work are rotated by a motor. Nowadays this is usually an electric motor.Components means",
                "correct_ans": "part",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82907": {
                "ans1": "nations become aware of their own failings and discard pride",
                "ans2": "charitable organizations are encouraged",
                "ans3": "different races are treated on the basis of equality",
                "ans4": "nations guilty of immoral actions are exposed",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the given questions.\nThe awareness of equal corruption will be a better emotional basis for the so-called multi-racial commonwealth, of which much is made, than its professed principle the pursuit of common aims in world politics, aims which are so rarefied that a large volume of artificial political oxygen is needed to keep that body-politic breathing. After all, it cannot be denied that even the United States and the Soviet Union are pursuing common aims in world affairs, such as peace, disarmament, democracy, technological progress, as well as freedom as understood by each. But that is not. preventing them from doing things which might lead to the destruction or near destruction of mankind. Thus, common aims would seem to be very undependable as guarantees for goodwill and co-operation among nations. On the contrary, a frank admission of being equal sinners would at least encourage charity and discourage moral arrogance. That would be a better foundation for integration for international and multi-racial co-operation.\nInternational co-operation can come about, if ",
                "correct_ans": "nations become aware of their own failings and discard pride",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89387": {
                "ans1": "do not ensure international co-operation ",
                "ans2": "lead to unnecessary tensions",
                "ans3": "encourage rivalry between super powers",
                "ans4": "lead to destruction of mankind",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the given questions.\nThe awareness of equal corruption will be a better emotional basis for the so-called multi-racial commonwealth, of which much is made, than its professed principle the pursuit of common aims in world politics, aims which are so rarefied that a large volume of artificial political oxygen is needed to keep that body-politic breathing. After all, it cannot be denied that even the United States and the Soviet Union are pursuing common aims in world affairs, such as peace, disarmament, democracy, technological progress, as well as freedom as understood by each. But that is not. preventing them from doing things which might lead to the destruction or near destruction of mankind. Thus, common aims would seem to be very undependable as guarantees for goodwill and co-operation among nations. On the contrary, a frank admission of being equal sinners would at least encourage charity and discourage moral arrogance. That would be a better foundation for integration for international and multi-racial co-operation.\nCommon goals are desirable, but these",
                "correct_ans": "do not ensure international co-operation ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83910": {
                "ans1": "do not work earnestly to achieve them",
                "ans2": "undo each other's efforts ",
                "ans3": "still act against the interests of mankind",
                "ans4": "do not see them in the right perspective",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the given questions.\nThe awareness of equal corruption will be a better emotional basis for the so-called multi-racial commonwealth, of which much is made, than its professed principle the pursuit of common aims in world politics, aims which are so rarefied that a large volume of artificial political oxygen is needed to keep that body-politic breathing. After all, it cannot be denied that even the United States and the Soviet Union are pursuing common aims in world affairs, such as peace, disarmament, democracy, technological progress, as well as freedom as understood by each. But that is not. preventing them from doing things which might lead to the destruction or near destruction of mankind. Thus, common aims would seem to be very undependable as guarantees for goodwill and co-operation among nations. On the contrary, a frank admission of being equal sinners would at least encourage charity and discourage moral arrogance. That would be a better foundation for integration for international and multi-racial co-operation.\nThe super powers may claim to have the same laudable objectives, but",
                "correct_ans": "still act against the interests of mankind",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88825": {
                "ans1": "the failure of the constituents to work for the same goals",
                "ans2": "the racial nature of its membership",
                "ans3": "uniform lack of moral standards ",
                "ans4": "constant redefining of objectives",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the given questions.\nThe awareness of equal corruption will be a better emotional basis for the so-called multi-racial commonwealth, of which much is made, than its professed principle the pursuit of common aims in world politics, aims which are so rarefied that a large volume of artificial political oxygen is needed to keep that body-politic breathing. After all, it cannot be denied that even the United States and the Soviet Union are pursuing common aims in world affairs, such as peace, disarmament, democracy, technological progress, as well as freedom as understood by each. But that is not. preventing them from doing things which might lead to the destruction or near destruction of mankind. Thus, common aims would seem to be very undependable as guarantees for goodwill and co-operation among nations. On the contrary, a frank admission of being equal sinners would at least encourage charity and discourage moral arrogance. That would be a better foundation for integration for international and multi-racial co-operation.\nThe Commonwealth is characterized by",
                "correct_ans": "uniform lack of moral standards ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83317": {
                "ans1": "south direction",
                "ans2": "countryside",
                "ans3": "a city",
                "ans4": "a band.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What does the phrase \"rural south' refers to?",
                "correct_ans": "a city",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84758": {
                "ans1": "street corners",
                "ans2": "country stores",
                "ans3": "city stage",
                "ans4": "saloons",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.According to the passage, where do jug bands not perform?",
                "correct_ans": "city stage",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81946": {
                "ans1": "A change in role of blue harp.",
                "ans2": "Role of Jug bands.",
                "ans3": "Invention of blues harp",
                "ans4": "Performance of Jug bands.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What does this passage mainly discuss?",
                "correct_ans": "Role of Jug bands.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80962": {
                "ans1": "He belongs to Jug bands.",
                "ans2": "He was a musician.",
                "ans3": "He used to play harp.",
                "ans4": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What can be inferred about George 'Bullet' Williams?",
                "correct_ans": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81419": {
                "ans1": "He belongs to jug bands.",
                "ans2": " He was a musician.",
                "ans3": " He used to play harp.",
                "ans4": "He used to play harp.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the following questions\u00a0Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these ands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 2910s, as heard in the recordings of George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams. Other good harp men such as Sony Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harps role as a lead instrument.What can be inferred about George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams?",
                "correct_ans": " He was a musician.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81384": {
                "ans1": "A  change in role of blue harp",
                "ans2": "Role of Jug bands",
                "ans3": " Invention of blues harp.",
                "ans4": "Performance of jug bands.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the following questions\u00a0Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these ands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 2910s, as heard in the recordings of George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams. Other good harp men such as Sony Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harps role as a lead instrument.What does this passage mainly discuss?",
                "correct_ans": "A  change in role of blue harp",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87111": {
                "ans1": " street comers",
                "ans2": "country stores",
                "ans3": "eity stage",
                "ans4": "saloons",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the following questions\u00a0Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these ands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 2910s, as heard in the recordings of George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams. Other good harp men such as Sony Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harps role as a lead instrument.According to the passage, where to jug bands not perform?",
                "correct_ans": "eity stage",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85331": {
                "ans1": "a blues instrument",
                "ans2": " other role of blues harp",
                "ans3": "history of blues harp",
                "ans4": "a music band",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the following questionsAnother common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these ands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 2910s, as heard in the recordings of George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams. Other good harp men such as Sony Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harps role as a lead instrument.What would most likely be the topic of the above paragraph?",
                "correct_ans": "a blues instrument",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84692": {
                "ans1": "is being drafted",
                "ans2": "has been discussed in the Union cabinet",
                "ans3": " has been made a law",
                "ans4": " is going to create a lot of controversy",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:\u00a0The report the Union Cabinet considered the draft of a bill to prohibit the denigration of women in photographs. Advertisements and films are welcome. There has been for some time growing criticism of the projection of women in these three media. Advertisements in the print media, as well as in films and television, frequently rely on feminine sex appeal to attract attention to the products or to suggest that these products make Casanovas of ordinary mortals. Things are even worse in films. Some of these unabashedly rely on sex for box-office success, showing scantily attired women in provocative postures. In these, as well as in many advertisements, women clearly appear as objects of erotic stimulation. By showing heroes misbehaving with heroines and getting away with it, films invite emulation in real life, resulting in the molestation of women in public places.The passage says that the bill to prohibit media exploitation of women",
                "correct_ans": "has been discussed in the Union cabinet",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88679": {
                "ans1": "distract the customer's attention",
                "ans2": "entertain the customers",
                "ans3": " get the attention of prospective customers",
                "ans4": "show how women at home would like the product",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:\u00a0The report the Union Cabinet considered the draft of a bill to prohibit the denigration of women in photographs. Advertisements and films are welcome. There has been for some time growing criticism of the projection of women in these three media. Advertisements in the print media, as well as in films and television, frequently rely on feminine sex appeal to attract attention to the products or to suggest that these products make Casanovas of ordinary mortals. Things are even worse in films. Some of these unabashedly rely on sex for box-office success, showing scantily attired women in provocative postures. In these, as well as in many advertisements, women clearly appear as objects of erotic stimulation. By showing heroes misbehaving with heroines and getting away with it, films invite emulation in real life, resulting in the molestation of women in public places.Femine sex appeal is used in advertisements to",
                "correct_ans": " get the attention of prospective customers",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80020": {
                "ans1": " ill-treatment",
                "ans2": "abuse",
                "ans3": "scandalizing",
                "ans4": "tarnishing the good image",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:\u00a0The report the Union Cabinet considered the draft of a bill to prohibit the denigration of women in photographs. Advertisements and films are welcome. There has been for some time growing criticism of the projection of women in these three media. Advertisements in the print media, as well as in films and television, frequently rely on feminine sex appeal to attract attention to the products or to suggest that these products make Casanovas of ordinary mortals. Things are even worse in films. Some of these unabashedly rely on sex for box-office success, showing scantily attired women in provocative postures. In these, as well as in many advertisements, women clearly appear as objects of erotic stimulation. By showing heroes misbehaving with heroines and getting away with it, films invite emulation in real life, resulting in the molestation of women in public places.'Denigration' in the phrase 'denigration of women' means",
                "correct_ans": "tarnishing the good image",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84928": {
                "ans1": "openly",
                "ans2": "with great skill",
                "ans3": "indifferently",
                "ans4": " with no sign of being ashamed",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:\u00a0The report the Union Cabinet considered the draft of a bill to prohibit the denigration of women in photographs. Advertisements and films are welcome. There has been for some time growing criticism of the projection of women in these three media. Advertisements in the print media, as well as in films and television, frequently rely on feminine sex appeal to attract attention to the products or to suggest that these products make Casanovas of ordinary mortals. Things are even worse in films. Some of these unabashedly rely on sex for box-office success, showing scantily attired women in provocative postures. In these, as well as in many advertisements, women clearly appear as objects of erotic stimulation. By showing heroes misbehaving with heroines and getting away with it, films invite emulation in real life, resulting in the molestation of women in public places.\u00a0'Unabashedly' means",
                "correct_ans": " with no sign of being ashamed",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84271": {
                "ans1": "Promoted",
                "ans2": "Accelerated",
                "ans3": "Intruded",
                "ans4": "Inhibited",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Out of the following which one has the opposite meaning to the word \u2018restrained\u2019 by the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "Accelerated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89870": {
                "ans1": "Law protects those who respect it.",
                "ans2": "Law ensures people\u2019s religious and social rights absolutely and unconditionally.",
                "ans3": "A criminal is deterred from committing crimes only for fear of the law.",
                "ans4": "The forces of law help to transform irresponsible citizens into responsible ones.",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Which of the following is not implied in the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "Law ensures people\u2019s religious and social rights absolutely and unconditionally.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84128": {
                "ans1": "fairs and festivals       ",
                "ans2": "habits and traditions",
                "ans3": "usual practices and religious rites    ",
                "ans4": "superstitions and formalities",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.61. The expression \u2018customs and ceremonies\u2019 means",
                "correct_ans": "usual practices and religious rites    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83820": {
                "ans1": "Peaceful citizens seldom violet the law, but bad citizens have to be restrained by the police.",
                "ans2": "Criminals, who flout the law, are seldom brought to book.",
                "ans3": "The police hardly succeed in converting bad citizens into good citizens .",
                "ans4": "The police check the citizens, whether they are good or bad, from violating the law.",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Which of the following is implied in the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "The police check the citizens, whether they are good or bad, from violating the law.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81062": {
                "ans1": "One should read some books",
                "ans2": "Collecting books in the hobby",
                "ans3": "A library of books is stimulating and refreshing",
                "ans4": "Books are friends",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that followsEveryone should being collecting a private library in youth; the instinct of private property, which is fundamental in human beings, can here be cultivated with every advantage and no evils. One should have one's own bookshelves, which should not have door, glass-windows or keys, they should be free and accessible to the hand as well as to the eye. The best of mural decoration is books; they are more varied in color and appearance in any wallpaper. They are more attractive in design and they have the prime advantage of being separate personalities, so that if you sit alone in the room in the firelight you are surrounded with intimate friends. The knowledge that they are there in plain view in both stimulating and refreshing. You do not have to read them all. Most of indoor life is spent in the room containing six thousand books and I have a stock answer to the invariable question that comes from strangers; \"Have you read all of these books?\" \"Some of them twice\"; this reply is both true and unexpected.The main idea of the passage is",
                "correct_ans": "Collecting books in the hobby",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85369": {
                "ans1": "Books are literature",
                "ans2": "One must buy books",
                "ans3": "Books are better companies",
                "ans4": "Books satisfy our natural instincts",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that followsEveryone should being collecting a private library in youth; the instinct of private property, which is fundamental in human beings, can here be cultivated with every advantage and no evils. One should have one's own bookshelves, which should not have door, glass-windows or keys, they should be free and accessible to the hand as well as to the eye. The best of mural decoration is books; they are more varied in color and appearance in any wallpaper. They are more attractive in design and they have the prime advantage of being separate personalities, so that if you sit alone in the room in the firelight you are surrounded with intimate friends. The knowledge that they are there in plain view in both stimulating and refreshing. You do not have to read them all. Most of indoor life is spent in the room containing six thousand books and I have a stock answer to the invariable question that comes from strangers; \"Have you read all of these books?\" \"Some of them twice\"; this reply is both true and unexpected.The implications of the passage is.....",
                "correct_ans": "Books satisfy our natural instincts",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81100": {
                "ans1": "true question",
                "ans2": "false question",
                "ans3": "general question",
                "ans4": "fixed question",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that followsEveryone should being collecting a private library in youth; the instinct of private property, which is fundamental in human beings, can here be cultivated with every advantage and no evils. One should have one's own bookshelves, which should not have door, glass-windows or keys, they should be free and accessible to the hand as well as to the eye. The best of mural decoration is books; they are more varied in color and appearance in any wallpaper. They are more attractive in design and they have the prime advantage of being separate personalities, so that if you sit alone in the room in the firelight you are surrounded with intimate friends. The knowledge that they are there in plain view in both stimulating and refreshing. You do not have to read them all. Most of indoor life is spent in the room containing six thousand books and I have a stock answer to the invariable question that comes from strangers; \"Have you read all of these books?\" \"Some of them twice\"; this reply is both true and unexpected.What is meant by invariable question?",
                "correct_ans": "general question",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85774": {
                "ans1": "Having a private library",
                "ans2": " Decorations",
                "ans3": "Indoor life",
                "ans4": "True and unexpected",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that followsEveryone should being collecting a private library in youth; the instinct of private property, which is fundamental in human beings, can here be cultivated with every advantage and no evils. One should have one's own bookshelves, which should not have door, glass-windows or keys, they should be free and accessible to the hand as well as to the eye. The best of mural decoration is books; they are more varied in color and appearance in any wallpaper. They are more attractive in design and they have the prime advantage of being separate personalities, so that if you sit alone in the room in the firelight you are surrounded with intimate friends. The knowledge that they are there in plain view in both stimulating and refreshing. You do not have to read them all. Most of indoor life is spent in the room containing six thousand books and I have a stock answer to the invariable question that comes from strangers; \"Have you read all of these books?\" \"Some of them twice\"; this reply is both true and unexpected.The title of the passage is ......",
                "correct_ans": "Having a private library",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88089": {
                "ans1": "Cyhclospoirne",
                "ans2": "Alzheimer's diseases",
                "ans3": "DIDS",
                "ans4": "Cholesterol level",
                "question_text": "According to some of the research findings, coffee is responsible for the rise in",
                "correct_ans": "Cholesterol level",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85445": {
                "ans1": "has no impact on people's lives in general",
                "ans2": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "ans3": "fills people's lives with death and destruction",
                "ans4": "makes people aware of the diseases",
                "question_text": "The undue publicity given to such research",
                "correct_ans": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88480": {
                "ans1": " to make people aware of possible health hazards",
                "ans2": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "ans3": " to dispel people's fears about unknown diseases.",
                "ans4": "to report major medical discoveries",
                "question_text": "The role of the media has been",
                "correct_ans": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88469": {
                "ans1": "sound and dependable",
                "ans2": "utterly unconvincing",
                "ans3": " of questionable",
                "ans4": "of no value at all",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and give the answer of the questionAt a time when we are enjoying longer, more healthful lives, ominous headlines announces: \u2018Researchers Tie Aluminium to Alsheimer's Disease\u2019 and \u2018Coffee linked to Cholesterol Rise\u2019. As a result of alarming and something ambiguous bulletins, worriers often become major threats, and speculations about disease prevention become \u2018proven\u2019 curs. Par to the problem is that the media often trumpet questionable research findings as major medical breakthroughs. In 1985, three French scientists told reporters at a press that the drug cyclosporine appeared to halt the growth of the AIDS virus. They asked the announcement on their observation of two AIDS patients treated for eight days. Never mind that no actual study had been done; for the media, the announcement was enough, and the story became front-page news around the world. Unfortunately, one of the patients died within days. Cyclosporine was no miracle. cure.According to the writer, a lot presented day medical research is",
                "correct_ans": " of questionable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87268": {
                "ans1": "sound and dependable",
                "ans2": "utterly unconvincing",
                "ans3": " of questionable",
                "ans4": "of no value at all",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and give the answer of the questionAt a time when we are enjoying longer, more healthful lives, ominous headlines announces: \u2018Researchers Tie Aluminium to Alsheimer's Disease\u2019 and \u2018Coffee linked to Cholesterol Rise\u2019. As a result of alarming and something ambiguous bulletins, worriers often become major threats, and speculations about disease prevention become \u2018proven\u2019 curs. Par to the problem is that the media often trumpet questionable research findings as major medical breakthroughs. In 1985, three French scientists told reporters at a press that the drug cyclosporine appeared to halt the growth of the AIDS virus. They asked the announcement on their observation of two AIDS patients treated for eight days. Never mind that no actual study had been done; for the media, the announcement was enough, and the story became front-page news around the world. Unfortunately, one of the patients died within days. Cyclosporine was no miracle. cure.According to the writer, a lot presented day medical research is",
                "correct_ans": " of questionable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84966": {
                "ans1": "has no impact on people's lives in general",
                "ans2": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "ans3": "fills people's lives with death and destruction",
                "ans4": "makes people aware of the diseases",
                "question_text": "The undue publicity given to such research",
                "correct_ans": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87287": {
                "ans1": " to make people aware of possible health hazards",
                "ans2": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "ans3": " to dispel people's fears about unknown diseases.",
                "ans4": "to report major medical discoveries",
                "question_text": "The role of the media has been",
                "correct_ans": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82151": {
                "ans1": "Cyhclospoirne",
                "ans2": "Alzheimer's diseases",
                "ans3": "DIDS",
                "ans4": "Cholesterol level",
                "question_text": "According to some of the research findings, coffee is responsible for the rise in",
                "correct_ans": "Cholesterol level",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89444": {
                "ans1": "solemn",
                "ans2": "verbosity",
                "ans3": "promposity",
                "ans4": "irony",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and give the answer of the question\u00a0Speech is a great blessing but it can also be a great curse, for while it helps us to make out intentions and desires known to our fellows, it can also, if we use it carelessly, make our attitude completely understood. A slip of the tongue, the use of an unusual word, or of an ambiguous had hoped to win a friend. Again, different classes of people use different vocabularies, and the ordinary speech of an educated man may strike an uneducated listener as pompous. Unwittingly, we may use a word which bears a different meaning to our listener from what is does to men of our own class. Thus, speech is not a gift to use lightly without thought, but one which demands careful handling. Only a fool will express himself alike to all kinds and conditions of men.what's the meaning of pompous?",
                "correct_ans": "solemn",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84867": {
                "ans1": "unintentionally",
                "ans2": "wrongly by chance",
                "ans3": "without giving proper thought",
                "ans4": "to hurt another person",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and give the answer of the question.Speech is a great blessing but it can also be a great curse, for while it helps us to make out intentions and desires known to our fellows, it can also, if we use it carelessly, make our attitude completely understood. A slip of the tongue, the use of an unusual word, or of an ambiguous had hoped to win a friend. Again, different classes of people use different vocabularies, and the ordinary speech of an educated man may strike an uneducated listener as pompous. Unwittingly, we may use a word which bears a different meaning to our listener from what is does to men of our own class. Thus, speech is not a gift to use lightly without thought, but one which demands careful handling. Only a fool will express himself alike to all kinds and conditions of men.A \u2018slip of the tongue\u2019 means something said:",
                "correct_ans": "without giving proper thought",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82311": {
                "ans1": " polite language",
                "ans2": "ordinary speech",
                "ans3": "his vocabulary",
                "ans4": "simple words",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and give the answer of the question\u00a0Speech is a great blessing but it can also be a great curse, for while it helps us to make out intentions and desires known to our fellows, it can also, if we use it carelessly, make our attitude completely understood. A slip of the tongue, the use of an unusual word, or of an ambiguous had hoped to win a friend. Again, different classes of people use different vocabularies, and the ordinary speech of an educated man may strike an uneducated listener as pompous. Unwittingly, we may use a word which bears a different meaning to our listener from what is does to men of our own class. Thus, speech is not a gift to use lightly without thought, but one which demands careful handling. Only a fool will express himself alike to all kinds and conditions of men.The best way to win a friend is to avoid _____",
                "correct_ans": "his vocabulary",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "86697": {
                "ans1": "reveal our intentions",
                "ans2": "lead to carelessness",
                "ans3": "hurt others",
                "ans4": "create misunderstanding",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and give the answer of the question.Speech is a great blessing but it can also be a great curse, for while it helps us to make out intentions and desires known to our fellows, it can also, if we use it carelessly, make our attitude completely understood. A slip of the tongue, the use of an unusual word, or of an ambiguous had hoped to win a friend. Again, different classes of people use different vocabularies, and the ordinary speech of an educated man may strike an uneducated listener as pompous. Unwittingly, we may use a word which bears a different meaning to our listener from what is does to men of our own class. Thus, speech is not a gift to use lightly without thought, but one which demands careful handling. Only a fool will express himself alike to all kinds and conditions of men.Speech can be a curse, because it can:",
                "correct_ans": "create misunderstanding",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85887": {
                "ans1": "Depending on size of the owner",
                "ans2": "Type of jacket",
                "ans3": "Requirement of owner",
                "ans4": "Situation around people",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The ability of zipping up or not is",
                "correct_ans": "Requirement of owner",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "86727": {
                "ans1": "Sponsor",
                "ans2": " Follow",
                "ans3": "Authorize",
                "ans4": "Recommend",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.'Endorse\u2019 has the closest meaning to:",
                "correct_ans": "Recommend",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80281": {
                "ans1": "There is no room for movement",
                "ans2": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "ans3": "extreme movements can be done",
                "ans4": "daily activities cannot be done easily",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.In slim fit:",
                "correct_ans": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81476": {
                "ans1": "Person",
                "ans2": "Jacket",
                "ans3": "Preference",
                "ans4": "Slimness",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The passage is talking about fit of a",
                "correct_ans": "Jacket",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80762": {
                "ans1": "Christ was evil.",
                "ans2": "Satan was good.",
                "ans3": "black was good",
                "ans4": "All white was good",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the given questionUntil very recently, it was universally believed that men ar congenitally more intelligent than women, even so enlightened a man as Spinoza decided against votes o women on this ground. Among white men, it is held that white men are by nature superior to men of other colors and is the best colour. In Haiti, when they make statues of Christ and Satan, so innately superior to barbarians that slavery was justified so long as the master was was Green and the slave a barbarian.I Haiti, Christ's statue is black and satan white because the people there believe that",
                "correct_ans": "All white was good",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80435": {
                "ans1": "the Greek to be superior to barbarians",
                "ans2": " the barbarians to be superior to Greeks",
                "ans3": "slaves to be inferior",
                "ans4": "that the barbarian belonged to Greece",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the given questionUntil very recently, it was universally believed that men ar congenitally more intelligent than women, even so enlightened a man as Spinoza decided against votes o women on this ground. Among white men, it is held that white men are by nature superior to men of other colors and is the best colour. In Haiti, when they make statues of Christ and Satan, so innately superior to barbarians that slavery was justified so long as the master was was Green and the slave a barbarian.Aristotle and Plato supported slavery because the thought",
                "correct_ans": "the Greek to be superior to barbarians",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84952": {
                "ans1": " Certainly",
                "ans2": "innately",
                "ans3": "fantastically",
                "ans4": " falsely",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the given question\u00a0Until very recently, it was universally believed that men ar congenitally more intelligent than women, even so enlightened a man as Spinoza decided against votes o women on this ground. Among white men, it is held that white men are by nature superior to men of other colors and is the best colour. In Haiti, when they make statues of Christ and Satan, so innately superior to barbarians that slavery was justified so long as the master was was Green and the slave a barbarian.Congenitally means.",
                "correct_ans": "innately",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82424": {
                "ans1": "they were less educated than men",
                "ans2": " they were generally unintelligent.",
                "ans3": "they were naturally less gifted with intelligence",
                "ans4": "they did not deserve to have votes",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the given questionUntil very recently, it was universally believed that men ar congenitally more intelligent than women, even so enlightened a man as Spinoza decided against votes o women on this ground. Among white men, it is held that white men are by nature superior to men of other colors and is the best colour. In Haiti, when they make statues of Christ and Satan, so innately superior to barbarians that slavery was justified so long as the master was was Green and the slave a barbarian.Spinoza decided against votes for women because according to him",
                "correct_ans": "they were naturally less gifted with intelligence",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87524": {
                "ans1": "Promoted",
                "ans2": "Accelerated",
                "ans3": "Intruded",
                "ans4": "Inhibited",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Out of the following which one has the opposite meaning to the word \u2018restrained\u2019 by the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "Accelerated",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80645": {
                "ans1": "Law protects those who respect it.",
                "ans2": "Law ensures people\u2019s religious and social rights absolutely and unconditionally.",
                "ans3": "A criminal is deterred from committing crimes only for fear of the law.",
                "ans4": "The forces of law help to transform irresponsible citizens into responsible ones.",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Which of the following is not implied in the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "Law ensures people\u2019s religious and social rights absolutely and unconditionally.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88633": {
                "ans1": "fairs and festivals       ",
                "ans2": "habits and traditions",
                "ans3": "usual practices and religious rites    ",
                "ans4": "superstitions and formalities",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.61. The expression \u2018customs and ceremonies\u2019 means",
                "correct_ans": "usual practices and religious rites    ",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82862": {
                "ans1": "Peaceful citizens seldom violet the law, but bad citizens have to be restrained by the police.",
                "ans2": "Criminals, who flout the law, are seldom brought to book.",
                "ans3": "The police hardly succeed in converting bad citizens into good citizens .",
                "ans4": "The police check the citizens, whether they are good or bad, from violating the law.",
                "question_text": "Click on the best option of the following questions based on the reading comprehension below.True, it is the function of the army to maintain law order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their\u00a0 customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others.Now the good citizens, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is same with due regards to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizens is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequences of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizens to act as good citizens are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in as State is at the hands of a Minister who is responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.Which of the following is implied in the passage?",
                "correct_ans": "The police check the citizens, whether they are good or bad, from violating the law.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84710": {
                "ans1": "globe",
                "ans2": "round",
                "ans3": "aspects",
                "ans4": "items",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.The synonym of the word \"sphere\" can be ?",
                "correct_ans": "aspects",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89843": {
                "ans1": "arts",
                "ans2": "oratory",
                "ans3": "bravery",
                "ans4": "science",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.What has enabled man to harness the forces of nature of the advantage of mankind?",
                "correct_ans": "science",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88744": {
                "ans1": " The impact of science can be felt in every sphere of life.",
                "ans2": "Science is an anathema",
                "ans3": "Nothing is beyond the preview of science.",
                "ans4": " Science can work miracles.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.The main idea of the passage is",
                "correct_ans": "Science is an anathema",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84030": {
                "ans1": "Gravitational forces, electrostatic forces, weak forces etc.",
                "ans2": "Seasons and weathers",
                "ans3": "Lands and Oceans",
                "ans4": "Naturally occurring phenomenons",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.What are the forces of nature according to the paragraph?",
                "correct_ans": "Naturally occurring phenomenons",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88680": {
                "ans1": "A change in role of blue harp.",
                "ans2": "Role of Jug bands.",
                "ans3": "Invention of blues harp",
                "ans4": "Performance of Jug bands.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What does this passage mainly discuss?",
                "correct_ans": "Role of Jug bands.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89172": {
                "ans1": "street corners",
                "ans2": "country stores",
                "ans3": "city stage",
                "ans4": "saloons",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.According to the passage, where do jug bands not perform?",
                "correct_ans": "city stage",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87555": {
                "ans1": "south direction",
                "ans2": "countryside",
                "ans3": "a city",
                "ans4": "a band.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What does the phrase \"rural south' refers to?",
                "correct_ans": "a city",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84975": {
                "ans1": "He belongs to Jug bands.",
                "ans2": "He was a musician.",
                "ans3": "He used to play harp.",
                "ans4": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What can be inferred about George 'Bullet' Williams?",
                "correct_ans": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80184": {
                "ans1": " to make people aware of possible health hazards",
                "ans2": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "ans3": " to dispel people's fears about unknown diseases.",
                "ans4": "to report major medical discoveries",
                "question_text": "The role of the media has been",
                "correct_ans": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89038": {
                "ans1": "sound and dependable",
                "ans2": "utterly unconvincing",
                "ans3": " of questionable",
                "ans4": "of no value at all",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and give the answer of the questionAt a time when we are enjoying longer, more healthful lives, ominous headlines announces: \u2018Researchers Tie Aluminium to Alsheimer's Disease\u2019 and \u2018Coffee linked to Cholesterol Rise\u2019. As a result of alarming and something ambiguous bulletins, worriers often become major threats, and speculations about disease prevention become \u2018proven\u2019 curs. Par to the problem is that the media often trumpet questionable research findings as major medical breakthroughs. In 1985, three French scientists told reporters at a press that the drug cyclosporine appeared to halt the growth of the AIDS virus. They asked the announcement on their observation of two AIDS patients treated for eight days. Never mind that no actual study had been done; for the media, the announcement was enough, and the story became front-page news around the world. Unfortunately, one of the patients died within days. Cyclosporine was no miracle. cure.According to the writer, a lot presented day medical research is",
                "correct_ans": " of questionable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89449": {
                "ans1": "has no impact on people's lives in general",
                "ans2": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "ans3": "fills people's lives with death and destruction",
                "ans4": "makes people aware of the diseases",
                "question_text": "The undue publicity given to such research",
                "correct_ans": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "88483": {
                "ans1": "Cyhclospoirne",
                "ans2": "Alzheimer's diseases",
                "ans3": "DIDS",
                "ans4": "Cholesterol level",
                "question_text": "According to some of the research findings, coffee is responsible for the rise in",
                "correct_ans": "Cholesterol level",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81047": {
                "ans1": "There is no room for movement",
                "ans2": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "ans3": "extreme movements can be done",
                "ans4": "daily activities cannot be done easily",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.In slim fit:",
                "correct_ans": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81713": {
                "ans1": "Depending on size of the owner",
                "ans2": "Type of jacket",
                "ans3": "Requirement of owner",
                "ans4": "Situation around people",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The ability of zipping up or not is",
                "correct_ans": "Requirement of owner",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81723": {
                "ans1": "Sponsor",
                "ans2": " Follow",
                "ans3": "Authorize",
                "ans4": "Recommend",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.'Endorse\u2019 has the closest meaning to:",
                "correct_ans": "Recommend",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "89748": {
                "ans1": "Person",
                "ans2": "Jacket",
                "ans3": "Preference",
                "ans4": "Slimness",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The passage is talking about fit of a",
                "correct_ans": "Jacket",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83351": {
                "ans1": "sound and dependable",
                "ans2": "utterly unconvincing",
                "ans3": " of questionable",
                "ans4": "of no value at all",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and give the answer of the questionAt a time when we are enjoying longer, more healthful lives, ominous headlines announces: \u2018Researchers Tie Aluminium to Alsheimer's Disease\u2019 and \u2018Coffee linked to Cholesterol Rise\u2019. As a result of alarming and something ambiguous bulletins, worriers often become major threats, and speculations about disease prevention become \u2018proven\u2019 curs. Par to the problem is that the media often trumpet questionable research findings as major medical breakthroughs. In 1985, three French scientists told reporters at a press that the drug cyclosporine appeared to halt the growth of the AIDS virus. They asked the announcement on their observation of two AIDS patients treated for eight days. Never mind that no actual study had been done; for the media, the announcement was enough, and the story became front-page news around the world. Unfortunately, one of the patients died within days. Cyclosporine was no miracle. cure.According to the writer, a lot presented day medical research is",
                "correct_ans": " of questionable",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85798": {
                "ans1": "has no impact on people's lives in general",
                "ans2": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "ans3": "fills people's lives with death and destruction",
                "ans4": "makes people aware of the diseases",
                "question_text": "The undue publicity given to such research",
                "correct_ans": "adds to people's worries and gives them false hopes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82418": {
                "ans1": " to make people aware of possible health hazards",
                "ans2": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "ans3": " to dispel people's fears about unknown diseases.",
                "ans4": "to report major medical discoveries",
                "question_text": "The role of the media has been",
                "correct_ans": "to give publicity to questionable research findings",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "81939": {
                "ans1": "Cyhclospoirne",
                "ans2": "Alzheimer's diseases",
                "ans3": "DIDS",
                "ans4": "Cholesterol level",
                "question_text": "According to some of the research findings, coffee is responsible for the rise in",
                "correct_ans": "Cholesterol level",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84368": {
                "ans1": "globe",
                "ans2": "round",
                "ans3": "aspects",
                "ans4": "items",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.The synonym of the word \"sphere\" can be ?",
                "correct_ans": "aspects",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82787": {
                "ans1": "Gravitational forces, electrostatic forces, weak forces etc.",
                "ans2": "Seasons and weathers",
                "ans3": "Lands and Oceans",
                "ans4": "Naturally occurring phenomenons",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.What are the forces of nature according to the paragraph?",
                "correct_ans": "Naturally occurring phenomenons",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82818": {
                "ans1": "arts",
                "ans2": "oratory",
                "ans3": "bravery",
                "ans4": "science",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.What has enabled man to harness the forces of nature of the advantage of mankind?",
                "correct_ans": "science",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80867": {
                "ans1": " The impact of science can be felt in every sphere of life.",
                "ans2": "Science is an anathema",
                "ans3": "Nothing is beyond the preview of science.",
                "ans4": " Science can work miracles.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions in context of the passage.\u00a0The achievements of science in the twentieth century has been very great. Its influence can be felt in every sphere of life. From the small pins and needles to the huge iron sheets and joints, most of the things we required for our everyday use, comes out of factories where scientific principles are utilized for practical ends. Science has enabled man to bring forces of nature under control and to use them for his own advantages. It has brought the distant parts of the world closer together. Our knowledge of the universe has been much widened on account of the untiring efforts of the astronomers like Jeans and Eddington. Remarkable cures of human diseases have been possible owing to the discovery of some wonderful medicines.The main idea of the passage is",
                "correct_ans": "Science is an anathema",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84568": {
                "ans1": "He belongs to Jug bands.",
                "ans2": "He was a musician.",
                "ans3": "He used to play harp.",
                "ans4": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What can be inferred about George 'Bullet' Williams?",
                "correct_ans": "He influenced some of the latter harpmen.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80734": {
                "ans1": "A  change in role of blue harp",
                "ans2": "Role of Jug bands",
                "ans3": " Invention of blues harp.",
                "ans4": "Performance of jug bands.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the following questions\u00a0Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these ands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 2910s, as heard in the recordings of George \u2018Bullet\u2019 Williams. Other good harp men such as Sony Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harps role as a lead instrument.What does this passage mainly discuss?",
                "correct_ans": "A  change in role of blue harp",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85993": {
                "ans1": "south direction",
                "ans2": "countryside",
                "ans3": "a city",
                "ans4": "a band.",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.What does the phrase \"rural south' refers to?",
                "correct_ans": "a city",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83548": {
                "ans1": "street corners",
                "ans2": "country stores",
                "ans3": "city stage",
                "ans4": "saloons",
                "question_text": "\u00a0Read the passage and answer the questions that follow:Another common blues instrument that flourished in the rural south during the 1920s and 1930s was the blue harp or harmonica. It was played mainly in bands called jug bands that commonly performed on street corners, in saloons, and at country stores. Jug bands used a variety of instruments including the banjo, guitar, washboard, fiddle, jugs and blue harp. In these bands, the blue harp is used primarily for melodic and rhythmic support. The earliest evidence of the harp use as a solo or lead instrument in the jug bands was in the late 1920s, as heard in the recordings of George Bullet' Williams. Other good harpmen such as Sonay Terry, Little Walter and Sony Boy followed Williams harp's role as a lead instrument.According to the passage, where do jug bands not perform?",
                "correct_ans": "city stage",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85828": {
                "ans1": "There is no room for movement",
                "ans2": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "ans3": "extreme movements can be done",
                "ans4": "daily activities cannot be done easily",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.In slim fit:",
                "correct_ans": " there's no wobbly feel",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85108": {
                "ans1": "Depending on size of the owner",
                "ans2": "Type of jacket",
                "ans3": "Requirement of owner",
                "ans4": "Situation around people",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The ability of zipping up or not is",
                "correct_ans": "Requirement of owner",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80021": {
                "ans1": "Sponsor",
                "ans2": " Follow",
                "ans3": "Authorize",
                "ans4": "Recommend",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.'Endorse\u2019 has the closest meaning to:",
                "correct_ans": "Recommend",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85371": {
                "ans1": "Person",
                "ans2": "Jacket",
                "ans3": "Preference",
                "ans4": "Slimness",
                "question_text": "Read the following passage and answer the questions:\u00a0In this category, your body measurements and your jacket measurements go side by side very closely. There\u2019s no loose feel anywhere around the jacket, but that being said, there\u2019s enough room for movements leading to your daily activities (however we endorse that extreme movements be avoided). The seekers of this fit also prefer to leave their zipper open. So, sometime the sizes under this fit are by default set in a way that the zipper cannot be zipped up and it accommodates the unzipped cool look. But again, this is highly subjective to the wearer\u2019s desires and the need for the ability or inability to zip up can be well communicated to us as per the requirement.The passage is talking about fit of a",
                "correct_ans": "Jacket",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84977": {
                "ans1": "objective of the welding ",
                "ans2": "importance of flux in welding",
                "ans3": "different types of welding",
                "ans4": "process of pressure welding",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.Moreover the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the center of the weld.The best suitable title of this text is:",
                "correct_ans": "process of pressure welding",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "86937": {
                "ans1": "The metal looks like plastics",
                "ans2": "The metal is converted into plastics",
                "ans3": "The metal can be molded into shapes",
                "ans4": "The metal behaves like plastics",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld. The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.The metal becomes plastics, means",
                "correct_ans": "The metal can be molded into shapes",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "86846": {
                "ans1": "welding temperature of iron",
                "ans2": "taking care for surface",
                "ans3": "oxidation of metal in high temperature",
                "ans4": "use of different types of weld",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt will weaken the weld.Moreover, the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the center of the weld.One statement of advice is made for",
                "correct_ans": "welding temperature of iron",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "80935": {
                "ans1": "another method of weld",
                "ans2": "methods of joining metals",
                "ans3": "welding steel",
                "ans4": "importance of welding",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:The simplest method of welding two pieces of metal together is known as pressure welding. The ends of the metal are heated to a white heat-for iron the welding temperature should be about 1300\u00b0c in a flame. At this temperature the metal becomes plastic. The ends are then pressed together, and the joint is smoothened off. Care must be taken to ensure the surfaces are thoroughly clean first, for dirt well weaken the weld.Moreover the heating of the iron to a high temperature causes oxidation, and a film of oxide is formed on the heated surface. For this reason, a flux is applied to the heated metal. At welding beat, the flux melts, and the oxide particles as dissolved in it together with any others impurities which may be present. The metal surfaces are pressed together, and the flux is squeezed out from the centre of the weld.What might be the topic of the following paragraph?\u00a0",
                "correct_ans": "another method of weld",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82524": {
                "ans1": "Charlie Chaplin",
                "ans2": "Americans",
                "ans3": "Man",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "Read the passage and answer the questions:Some people conside that man is becoming the slave of the machines. Certainly machines are playing an every-increasing part in our lives. Let us hope that they will never become more impotant than men they are invented to serve. Charlie Chaplin, in his film 'Modern Times' drew attention to this danger. In the film he got a job in a factory that used mass production methods He had to stand by a machine with a spanner in his hand. An endless belt passed infront of him carrying slowly an endless line of articles. As each one passed, he tightened one nut one bolt with his spanner. His work was done with one turn of the wrist repeated throughout the day. Very soon his mind became affected and the film shows the amusing things, which he did as a result of his mental disorder. Although it was funny, the film had a serious side. It showed that the kind of work which many people do, far from giving them pride and pleasure, is more likely to fit the for the lunatic asylum.We must all hope that means will be found to retain the advantages arising out of mass production, while at the same time giving the worker some of the pride and pleasure of the old craftsmen.\u00a0Who is becoming the slave of machines?",
                "correct_ans": "Man",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "87825": {
                "ans1": "Machines and their role in human life.",
                "ans2": "Machines and their bad effect.",
                "ans3": "Machines save time.",
                "ans4": "None of these",
                "question_text": "The apropriate title for the passage will be:",
                "correct_ans": "Machines and their role in human life.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82043": {
                "ans1": "Machines are more important than the men they are intended to serve.",
                "ans2": "Machines play a pivotal role in our lives.",
                "ans3": "There is not pride and pleasure in work that men do.",
                "ans4": "The mundane works that people do make them lunastics.",
                "question_text": "Which of these is correct in the context of the given passage?",
                "correct_ans": "Machines play a pivotal role in our lives.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "83890": {
                "ans1": "Work is worship.",
                "ans2": "Such works as do not give one pride and pleasure make him fit for the lunatic asylum.",
                "ans3": "Work makes our body strong.",
                "ans4": "None of these.",
                "question_text": "Which of these is in tune with the thoughts of the writer?",
                "correct_ans": "Such works as do not give one pride and pleasure make him fit for the lunatic asylum.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84806": {
                "ans1": "Thailand, Singapore, Korea, Hong Kong and India",
                "ans2": "Thailand, Afghanistan, Korea and Pakistan",
                "ans3": "Korea and Indonesia",
                "ans4": "Taiwan, Hong Kong, Korea, Thailand and Singapore",
                "question_text": "Not only does the lack of education among women make the dissemination of nutrition education difficult, it appears also to be a major obstacle to campaigns for family planning. It is significant that one of the more successful family planning efforts has been in Korea, where literacy is over 80%. Thailand, Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan have also had more satisfactory results than, for example, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Bangladesh, India or Indonesia, where a large proportion of the female population is illiterate. The education level of women is significant also because it has a direct impact on their chances of employment; and the number of employed women. The country\u2019s total labor force has a direct bearing on both the gross national product and the disposable income of individual family.Q)The countries where family planning programs have been satisfactory are",
                "correct_ans": "Taiwan, Hong Kong, Korea, Thailand and Singapore",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "85593": {
                "ans1": "Well employed",
                "ans2": "Well educated",
                "ans3": "Literate enough to understand its significance",
                "ans4": "Exposed to nutrition education",
                "question_text": "Not only does the lack of education among women make the dissemination of nutrition education difficult, it appears also to be a major obstacle to campaigns for family planning. It is significant that one of the more successful family planning efforts has been in Korea, where literacy is over 80%. Thailand, Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan have also had more satisfactory results than, for example, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Bangladesh, India or Indonesia, where a large proportion of the female population is illiterate. The education level of women is significant also because it has a direct impact on their chances of employment; and the number of employed women. The country\u2019s total labor force has a direct bearing on both the gross national product and the disposable income of individual family.Q)The passage suggests that Korea has been successful in family planning because Korean women are",
                "correct_ans": "Literate enough to understand its significance",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "84475": {
                "ans1": "The GNP of the country.",
                "ans2": "Her chances of getting a job.",
                "ans3": "The total labor force of the country.",
                "ans4": "Her knowledge of nutritional value of food.",
                "question_text": "Not only does the lack of education among women make the dissemination of nutrition education difficult, it appears also to be a major obstacle to campaigns for family planning. It is significant that one of the more successful family planning efforts has been in Korea, where literacy is over 80%. Thailand, Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan have also had more satisfactory results than, for example, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Bangladesh, India or Indonesia, where a large proportion of the female population is illiterate. The education level of women is significant also because it has a direct impact on their chances of employment; and the number of employed women. The country\u2019s total labor force has a direct bearing on both the gross national product and the disposable income of individual family.Q)\u00a0According to this passage, a women\u2019s lack of education has a direct bearing on",
                "correct_ans": "The GNP of the country.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            },
            "82780": {
                "ans1": "Cannot be persuaded to plan their families",
                "ans2": "Do not know how to cook nutritious food.",
                "ans3": "Cannot earn more money.",
                "ans4": "Cannot communicate well.",
                "question_text": "Not only does the lack of education among women make the dissemination of nutrition education difficult, it appears also to be a major obstacle to campaigns for family planning. It is significant that one of the more successful family planning efforts has been in Korea, where literacy is over 80%. Thailand, Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan have also had more satisfactory results than, for example, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Bangladesh, India or Indonesia, where a large proportion of the female population is illiterate. The education level of women is significant also because it has a direct impact on their chances of employment; and the number of employed women. The country\u2019s total labor force has a direct bearing on both the gross national product and the disposable income of individual family.Q)\u00a0One of the main disadvantages of the lack of education among women is that they",
                "correct_ans": "Cannot earn more money.",
                "explanation": "",
                "total_attempts": "0",
                "correct_attempts": "0"
            }
        }
    }
}